<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<title>A Slave Ship.</title>
<!--subtitle-->
<title>THE LATEST SENSATION IN THE SANDWICH 
ISLANDS</title>

<p>(Honolulu Correspondence N.Y. Herald.)</p>
<p>Another sensation has disturbed the usual quiet which pervades this community -- no less than the arrival of a veritable slaver at this port. On Sunday, the 15th ult., a ship appeared in the ofting flying a flag which seemed a parody, if I may so use the word on the glorious Stars and Stripes. The stripes were blue and white, and the stars were set in a red field. The vessel was evidently of American build. On being boarded, the Captain stated that it was the San Salvador ship Callao from Macao, China with emigrants, bound to Callao. A friend of mine visited the ship, and at my request prepared the following statement: On the morning of the 17th of August, I went on board the Coolic ship called the Callao, lying at anchor outside of the Honolulu harbor. The captain and officers were at breakfast, and I asked an introduction, as I have come off in the water boat which was supplying the ship. Upon coming from the breakfast table, the Captain (Lavarello, a Genoese) went ashore with two or three other welldressed persons. There was a barricade, or iron railing, about seven feet high, at the break fo the deck, and separating the forward part of the ship from aft. At each of the two gates in this barricade stood a guard with a bayonet in his hand, who fastened the gate immediately when any one passed through. One of them may have had a cutlass. On each side of the deck a gun, about a six-pounder, was pointed forward. I entered into conversation with one of the guards, who could speak some English. He could not tell me the name of the Captain, but said the ship's name was Number One. The carpenter, a Swede, also told me the same subsequently. The guard said the flag was Central American; said that hey had 650 coolics on board; that they mutinied when about a week at sea, about noon, and that the ringleader was killed and several others badly wounded. Fourteen were in irons at the present time. Breakfast was served out to the coolics between 10 and 11 o'clock. There were about sixty baskets of good white rice, and with each basket a dish of greens and a dish of potatoes and meat. This was sent below. There were iron gratings over the hatchways. Between twelve and twenty Chinese were provided with short double pieces of rope. They acted as police. Saw several persons struck. After breakfast, about one third of the coolies came up on deck. The prisoners, chained two and two by the ankles, were marched backward and forward about an hour before I left the ship. At least two of them showed their uncovered buttocks, the whole surface perfectly raw. I was told they had been flogged. "How many lashes?" "Oh, one or two hundred," was the answer. I did not ask how many had been flogged. A large gang was set to scouring the ship's brass, all along inside the rail. I went below and found tolerbly clean quarters. The coolics were most of them nearly naked. None that I saw had cues. Some looked quite skeleton like' others were in good condition. There were not very many sick. There had ben seven deaths, including the one killed. The chained leaders appeared to be of a different race, taller, blacker, and of a commanding carriage of body. The carpenter, who could talk some English, corroborated what the guard told me. The passage-way leading to the cabin was well provided with lances and cutlasses. I did not go astern to see if any name was painted on the ship.</p>
<p>This statement proves clearly as to the character of the traffic in which the ship was engaged. It is said that the ship was formerly the American ship Twilight. A newspaper of your city, in an article on the Coolie trade between Macao and South American ports, said that the Governor of Macao. "after having been convinced of the truth of the charges of cruelty made against the Spanish-American shippers of coolies and against South American planters, revoked the licenses of those engaged in the traffic to that part of the world from Macao." On this  point, and in regard to the presence of the ship, the Advertiser says:</p>
<p>"The presence of the Catlao at this port, direct from Macao, bound to Peru, proves the falsity of the last assertion, or, if true, we have a right to infer that the 650 Chinese were kidnapped. We trust that his Majesty's Government will use every endeavor to publish this matter to those Governments which should be interested in the matter. Let the San Salvador Government know to what base uses its flag is put, and notify the Governor of Macao of this infringement of laws which govern emigration in civilized communities. By a prompt disavowal of sympathy for parties concerned in this traffic, and use of every means to prevent its continuance, our Government will do much to make its record sound on this particular point. England spent hundreds of lives and millions of treasure to break up the African slave traffic. Can not the England of today, or America, make one effort to break up the iniquitous "emigrant" traffic, which differs from the African slave trade in but one particular -- the color of its victims?"</p>

