<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0427.001"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title></title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0427.001</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main"></title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11"></date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date></term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Junius Rochester</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Richard A. Jones</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName></placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020" who="#ini">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.000.000"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->


<fw type="footer"> &amp;</fw>

<p>FILE No.5567</p>

<p>KING 1887</p>

<p>TERRITORIAL COURT PROJECT
CASE FILE DATA ENTRY FORM</p>

<p>000        CONTROL NUMBER ______/3    120    ACESS CODE
140          KING                                                    200      DATE: 1887
36X

37X      NAME OF DEFENDANT (S)

38x PROBATE CASE NAME(S)

39X SUBJECTS (S) 
                                    Habeas Corpus, Wbit

401 SEX OF DEFENDANT IN CRIMIAL CASE   410  TYPE OF CASE     420    DECISION OF COURT
                                                                                                 Misc.                                        
700 COUNTRY CODE                                                               711    type - - - -  - (PRO, CIV, CRI, ADM, EQU)
90X DESCRIPTION 
    Application of Thomas Brown for a Wait of Habeas Corpus 




910 LOCATION (BOX NUMBER, REEL NUMBER)
</p>

<pb/>
<p>
IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE THIRD JUDICAL DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON 
TERRITORY, HOLDING TERMS AT SEATTLE,</p>

<p>  In the matter of the application
of Thomas S. Brown, G. Geods, George 
Dowing, Chas. Schubarb, Carl Jong
Matson named in the process as
C.J. Young and Peter J. Wegner for
a Writ of Habaes Corpus and discharge. </p>

<p>TO THE HON.RICHARD A. JONES, JUDGE OF THE ABOVE STYLED COURT: </p>

<p>Your petitonior Jumius Rochester petions the Court an dsays-
That in this petition he appears in behalf of and as the agent of 
Thomas S. Brown, G. Geods, George Dowing, Chas. Schubarb, Carl Jong Matso
named in the processes as C.J. Young and Peter J.Wegner. </p>

<p>That the said persons above named well defendant in cases of the
United States against them before Hon. C. D. Emery, United States Commissioner 
at Seattle in King County, with jurisdiction to hear and try certain 
caused at law.</p>

<p>That the above named persons are and each of them is illegally
wringfully and wihtout any authority of law restrained of his liberty 
by Thomas Jefferson Hamilion United States Harshal for Washingtion
Territory, at McNeils Island at the United States Penitentiary in the 
County of Washingtion Territory. </p>

<p>That the caused and pretese of the restraint of the liberty of
said persons and each of them is the alleged commission of acts which
are in no wise a violation of any law of the United States or of the 
Territory of Washington, and which conestitues no crime, misdemanor or 
offense whatever.</p>

<p>That the illegality of the restraint herein complained of consists
in the wrongful, unlawful and unwarranted defention of each of said
persons named herein as detained by the said Hamiltion upon an alleged
commitment issued by C.D. Emery as aforesaid, which charges no offense
against the laws of the United States or Territory of Washingtion and </p>

<pb/>

<p>your petitioner futher says, that the recitals in said commintments and
in each of them, upon which the said Hamilton holds th esaid persons
show that there has been no crime or offense committed by said persons
or either of them, and that the acts with which they and each of them is
charged do no constitute any offense against the laws of the United 
States or Washingtion Territory, or any crime, misdemanor or offense 
whatever: that the several commitments in the case of each of said
persons are idential except the names of the several defendants 
are different in each: a true exact copy of one of each of said 
persons are identical except th enames of the several defendants 
are different in each: a true exact copy of one of said commitments, 
to wit: commitment in the case of Thomas S. Brown  upon which said 
Thomas S. Brown is held as aforesaid, and which is the sale and only
authorty of the said Hamilton for detaining the said persons or any
of them is hereto annemed as part hereof and made a part of this
petiton marked exhibit and peeitioner futher says that the only 
offense charged  against the said Thomas S. Brown or against any of
said persons herein named as unlawfully restrained of their liberty,
is that each of said perons, on or above teh 10th, day of October
1887, in the Territory aforesaid, disoeyed th eorders of the Master of 
the American ship Ivanhoe.</p>

<p>Petitioner says that ther is no other or further cause for 
such detention save as above stated: 
</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays your Honor to grant unto the said 
Thomas S. Brown, G. Geods, Gerorge Downing, Chas. Schubarb, Carl Jong Matson
named in the processes as C.J. Young and Peter J. Wegner a Mrist of Habeas
Corpus commanding and ordering the said Thomas Jefferson Hamilton to
produce before your Honor at such time and place as your Honor deems 
wise an dmeet the bodies of the said Thomas S. Brown,   G. Geods, Gerorge 
Downing, Chas. Schubarb, Carl Jong Matson named  in the processes as
O.J Young and  Peter J. Wegner, and that your Honor will hear and determine whether theey are or either of them is illegally detained or restrained
of his liberty and that they and each of them be discharged and permitted to go their way without further delay detention, </p>

<pb/>


TERRITORY OF WASHINGTON 
COUNTY OF KING
------------------ - S. S. 

PERSONALLY APPEARED BEFORE ME JUNIUS ROCHESTER 
WHO UPON OATH DEPOSES AND SAYS THAT HE APPEARS HEREIN UPON THE
HALF AND AS THE AGENT OF THOMAS S. BROW., G. GEODS GERORGE DOWPETER
J. WEGENER, THAT HE IS THE PETEETIN ON THEIR BEHALF NAMED
HEREIN AND IN THE AFORE SAID AND HEREIN PETITOIN, THAT HE HAS READ
THE SAID PETITION AND KNOWS THE CONTENTS THEREOF AND BELEIVES 
THE SAME TO BE TRUE. 
                                                                            Jamius Rochester
   SWORN  TO AND SUVSCRIBED
BEFORE ME THIS 15TH. DAY OF OCTOBER 1887.


Jacob Mctrafe
Habaus Petition

<pb/>

FINAL MITTIMUS                                                                                      NO.________
United States of America,
Terriotry  of Washingtion,
City  of Seattle

The President of the United States of America to the Marshal of said Territory,
and  to the Keeper of the Jail of King County, in the Territory 
of Washington, Greeting: 

Whereas, Thos S. Brown
has been arrested upon the oath of D.A. oarter
for having, on  oor about the 10th day  of October A.D. 1887, at
Disobeyed the orders of the master of the 
American ships franhve 
and has been examined by me, CHARLES D. EMERY a Commissioner of the United States for said Territory of Washington, upoon the aforesaid charge, and has been required to give bail in the sum of  $500.00/100 Dollars for ______ appearance before the 
District  Court for the 3rd Judicial District of said Territory, on the first dayof the next regular term thereof, which requisition he__ ha___ failed to comply  with: 

These are, therefore, to Command you, In the name and by  the authority of aforesaid,  to receive the said  Thos S. Brown prisoner__ of the United States of America, into your custody, to remain ni confinement until__ he__ be dicharged by due course of  law.

Given under my hand and seal in the City and Territory aforesaid, this
11th day of October A.D. 1887
(sigues) 
L. D. Emery
U.S. Commissioner.

<pb/>

In Re affliation of 
Thos S Brown 
for Habeas Corpus 

Exhibit A

THE UNITED STATES of AMERICA
vs.
Thos S. Brown

final Mittimus. 

Issued...................18......
Returned and filed
..........................18......
.................................
U.S. Commissioner Washington Terr.

Return. 
Received this MITTIMUS with the within named
Prisoner, on the......day  of.............
A.D. 18....., and on the same day I committed the
said Prisoner to the custody of the  within named
Jail Keeper, with whom I left at the same time a 
certified copy of this Mittimus.
Dated...............18........
....................................
U.S. Marshal Washington Tex.
By.................................Deputy. 

<pb/>

1500 No 5567
In the metter of 
the affliation 
of Thomas S Brown
eralfna
wrat of Habeas 
Corpus

Field of 
WELeague

<pb/>

IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION OF
THOMAS S. BROWN ET AL.
FOR A WRIT OF HEABAS CORPUS ETC.

N. 511

UPON READING THE PETITION OF JUNIUS ROCEHESTER WHO PETITIONS
UPON THE BEHALF AND AS THE AGENT OF THOMAS  S. BROWN, G. GEODS
GEORGE DOWNING CHARLES SCHUBARD CARL JOHN MATSON KNOWN AS C.J. YOUNG AND PETER J. WEGENER PRAYING FOR A WRIT OF HEABEAS CORPUS 
FOR THE REASONS AND CAUSES NAMED THEREIN AND COMPLAINED THEREIN
AND THE COURT BEING FULLY ADVISED IN THE PREMISES AND THE PETITIONER
EVER PRAYING NOW IT IS ORDERED THAT THE SAID WRIT OF
HABEAS CORPUS ISSUE DIRECTED TO T.J. HAMILTON MARSHAL OF WASHINGTON 
TERRITORY COMMANDING HIM TO PRODUCE THE BODIIES OF THOMAS
MATSON (KNOWN AS C.J YOUNG) AND PETER J. WEGENER BEFORE ME AT
THE DISTRICT COURT ROOM IN THE CITY OF SEATTLE W.T. AT THE HOUR 
OF TWO O CLOCK IN THE AFTERNOON  OF THE 17TH DAY OF OCTOBER 
A.D. 1887. THAT THEN AND THERE I MAY ENGUIRE IN THE CAUSES 
COMPLAINED OF AND SAY IF THE SAID PETIONERS ARE SO ILLEGALLY RESTRAINED 
AS COMPLAINED, AND THAT I MAY DO AND DIRECT AS PROPEH IN 
THE PREMISES. AND THE CLERK OF THE HEREIN MANED COURT IS ORDERED
TO ISSUE THE HEREIN NAMED WRIT.
DONE AT SEATTLE H. T. OCTOBER 15TH. 1887.

RA JOUES


<pb/>

no 5367

In the matter of 
the afflication
of Thomas S Brown
writ of Habus Corpus 

Field of 7/8

<pb/>

N. 512

In the District of Washington
Territory, holding terms at Seattle

In the matter of 
the afflicatoin of
Thomas S Brown
etal. for Habeas 
Corpus and Discharge.   


No. 5567
Order discharging
Defendants 

This cause coming on to be heard
upon the retrival of TSB familtion
the Writ of Habeas Corpus here to
fore issued herein, and Thomas S Brown, G Geods, George Douning, Chas Schuford, Loare Jong Mats on
known as C.J Young and Peter J Wegner
being in often court attended
by their Consel Miss Metcalfe
of Rochester and Lewis and Gulinace
and the United States appearing 
by its Counsel Charles F. Monday
Easy Assistaur United States District
attorney, and said TJS familetion
having returned said unit into 
Court writ his doings. Therefore
and the cause of the detention
of said. Defeudants herein 

<pb/>

and if appearing to the Court
that  said fersois were and are illegally and wrongfully
restrained of their Liberty
by said TJ Hamilton and 
the court being suffieiently
advised this considered
by the court that said 
Thomas S Brown, J Jeods, 
George Dounigng, Charles Schubord,
Core Jong Matsern
known as  CJ Young and 
Pter J Wegner be and they are hereby discharged from
 custody and that they go 
here michour day and
that day recover their
costs herein expendure
and may have execution. 

Field out 7/87
W E Seugerurnd Rleel

<pb/>

IN THE DISTRICT COURT,

Of the Third Judicial District of Washington Territory, holdin




</div1>

    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
