<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0462.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ah Jack vs. C.D. Emery. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weekly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weekly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0462.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ah Jack vs. C.D. Emery. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1894-06-13">June 13, 1894</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1894-06">June 1894</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>China</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Jack, Ah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Emery, C. D.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Canoll, P. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Binker, William H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, Cornelius H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington, Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2021-05" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT FOR THE DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>To the Hon. C.H.HANFORD, Judge of said District:-</p>

<p>The petition and application of Ah Jack, a China
-man, respectively <del>follows</del> show:</p>

<p>That your petitioner is thirty-eight years 
of age and was born in China; that he has been twenty-one years
in the United States of America; that he was about seventeen
years of age when he come to the United States, and that he has ever
since resided therein; that he has never been out of the United 
States since his arrival and landing therein,about twenty-one
years ago.</p>

<p>That it is and was his bona-fide intention to become a 
citizen of the United States, but that by reason of the laws, he
has been prevented from so doing; that he knows no other home or
country than United States, and that he has resided, off and on, in
the City of Seattle, for a number of years; that he was not in-
formed as to the necessity of registering his name in accordance
with the laws of the United States.</p>

<p>That by reason of his absence from the City of Seattle,
and other places wherein he might have obtained information, that
he was not informed as to the matters and things required of him 
that he might remain in the United States.</p>

<p>That he has not registered,has been no fault of his; that
it was his intention to do so and to comply with the laws re-
quiring registration of the Chinese; but that from information</p>

<ab>(1)</ab>

<pb/>

<p>obtained from others upon whose information and advise your
petitioner relied, he was informed and believed that having come
to this country over twenty-one years agoand when he was only
about seventeen years of age, it was not necessary for him to
register.</p>

<p>That on or about the 27th of April, 1894, he was apprehended
for being unlawfully in the country, and that thereafter, to-wit:
On or about the 30th day of April, 1894, he was, by the Hon. C.D.
Emery, United States Commissioner, ordered tobedeported from the
United States of America, and returned to China.</p>

<p>That he does not want to return to China; that it is his
bona-fide intention to comply with the laws of the United States;
that he has no other country or home; that he is now unlawfully
and wrongfully detained in the County Jail of King County by
virtue of the writ of commitment of the said United States Com-
missioner, and unlawfully and illegally, by reason thereof, deprived
of his liberty; that said commitment is annexed hereto and made
part hereof.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas
corpus issue, to the Jailer of said jail ; that he be ordered to
produce and have the body of your petitioner, who is confined in
said jail, and as aforesaid, deprived of his liberty, in Court be-
fore your honor on the <gap></gap> day of June, 1894, at the hour
of <gap></gap> O'clock.</p>

<p>That after all due proceedings, had your petitioner been discharged from the custody of said jail, that he be permitted to go
hence without day. </p>

<ab><unclear>Ah</unclear> Jack</ab>

<pb/>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 13th day of
June, 1894.</p>

<ab>P P <unclear>Camoll</unclear></ab>

<p>Notary public in and for 
the State of Washington
residing at Seattle.</p>

<pb/>

<ab>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
CITY OF SEATTLE.</ab>

<ab>SS.</ab>

<ab>NO.684.</ab>

<p>The President of the United States
of America to the Marshal of said District
and to the Keeper of the Jail of King County,
in the State of Washington, Greeting:-</p>

<p>Whereas, Ah Jack has been arrested upon oath of F.D. Schuyler, for having on or about the 27th day of April, A.D. 1894,
at the District aforesaid, unlawfully entered the United States,
and has been by me remanded for further hearing.</p>

<p>These are, therefore, to Command you, in the name and by the 
authority aforesaid, to receive the said Ah Jack, Prisoner of the
United States of America, into your custody, to remain in con-
finement until he be discharged by due course of law.</p>

<p>Given under my hand and seal in the
City and District aforesaid, this 30th
day of April, A.D. 1894.</p>

<ab>C.D.Emery,</ab>
<ab>U.S.Commissioner</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>