<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<note>Page - 3 906</note>

<p>Thomas Horn sworn testifies as follows: Resides a Elk Plains, was at Mr H.E. Bradley's house on Sunday August 18th; was there from 12 1/2 P.M. till evening; Mr. Gorich John M Leod, Dom Coorcoran, Mich Eustice, Jas Riley &amp; Mr Bradley were there also; Mrs H. E. Bradley was absent during the day; but returned home toward evening; does not know at what time Mrs. Bradley retuned home He were drinking of ardent spirits; had some fighting late in the evening, was about the house all day; Saw two or three squaws and one Indian; did not know the Indian. Saw another wounded in the wood about three hundred hards from Bradley's home in the evening: Saw Riley there conversing with the Indian: did not know what they were talking about; understands the language, but paid not the least attention to what they were saying; was some distance off; did not see Riley wound the Indian. Saw Riley before the alarm; helped the Indian over the fense. Had no conversation with Riley relative to Indian being wounded at any time since the occurrances does not know who wounded the Indian; knows nothing at all about it</p>

<p>Did not know the Indian; never saw him to his knowledge before he saw him wounded. Does not know whether Riley was on horse back or not; did not see him with either knife or pistol; did not see Riley fire any shots.</p>

<p>Robert White: sworn testifies as follows. Knew the Indian. The Indian, who was wounded, was well acquainted with all the whites around; worked for several; was an honest industrious man. Reached Bradley's house about an hour before sun-down; John Walmskey was with him. Walmsley did not go up to the</p>

<pb...></pb...>

<note>906</note>

<p>house, on account of disorderly appearance of some men there, afterward believes he did go into Jas Riley bears a bad character. He is so desperate a man that deponent believes there are men who fear for their lives to testify against him. He has threatened Walmesley's life</p>

<p>Knows nothing about the Killing of the Indian.</p>

<p>John J Walmsley sworn testifies Reached H.E. Bradley's house at night, after sun-down; did not go up to the house for fear of a drunken crowd, delayed half an hour. White went up to the house, came back, with them went up &amp; shortly afterwards White went home, and only delayed about 3/4 of an hour.</p>

<p>The Indian was wounded in the barn, did not see him wounded, Saw Riley fifteen minutes before the Indian was wounded, saw him about the bard. Did not see Riley at the time of the row, he was not at the house.</p>

<p>Riley in a wild reckless character, and from his wild recless character believes there are men who fear to testify against him.</p>

<p>H.E Bradley Recalled. Heard shots about dark, Riley was at my house Did not see any person wound the Indian, but Riley acknowledged to me he killed the Indian; because the Indian attacked him (Riley) with a knife which he pulled out of his hand and then stabbed him. Riley said he would have to give something to the Indian to make it up. There was blood on his person.</p>

<pb...></pb...>

<note>page . 5 906</note>

<p>Allen MLeod sworn testifies was Bradleys in Sunday evening, Aug 18h was coming home after dark: Riley overtook <unclear>me</unclear> on the way: he had a pistol in his hand and a knife in the other; heard the noises; the Indians told me that a man was killed saw it was Jim Riley that killed him; went over to see <unclear>theran</unclear> they were about 300 yards from Bradleys house in a corner of the woods, from Thos Horn sitting down with the Indians The Indian spoke to me, said he did not expect to live until morning, asked him who killed him, said twas Jim Riley. Spoke to Horn, who did not know anything about the matter.</p>

<p>Riley is a bad man, of a very bad character.</p>

<p>Michael Eustice, sworn in was at Bradley's on Sunday; was drunk: does not recollect anything which happened in the evening. Saw James Riley at Bradley's the Sunday.</p>

<p>Riley is a wild rough man, by general reputation. He was drinking.</p>

<p>Carl Gorich Sworn in was at Bradley's on Sunday James Riley who was some what under the influence of liquor, watched him pretty sharply on account of his general bad character &amp; for a practice he has of getting others to whom he owe ill will drunk &amp; remaining sober himself, so that he can do them harm.</p>

<p>He is a dangerous bad man and men are afraid to testify against him

<pb...></pb...>

<note>906</note>

<note>Carl Gorich (continued)</note>

knows the Indian who was killed. He was good man quite <unclear>speacable</unclear> in his manner</p>

<p>Thos. Horn knew him too. can swear positively that Horn was well acquainted with the Indian</p>

<p>Alex McDonald sworn in was at Bradley on Sunday evening saw Kiley then, was too drunk in the evening to recollect anything that transpired.</p>

<p>Dominick Corcoran sworn in was at Bradley on Sunday, left there at about 3 o'c p.m; knows nothing about the killing of the Indian.</p>

<p>Mrs H.E. Bradley, sworn testifies was absent from home in forenoon of Sunday, come back late in the evening, saw people at the home, who were disordelry and quarrelsome, shortly after returning heard the <unclear>Indians</unclear> shouting in the <unclear></unclear> was in the house at the time Riley was about then out whne the noise was made saw Riley run after the Indians <unclear>hand</unclear> of the Indians being wounded, shortly Riley returned to the house, he had a knife in one hand and a pistol in the other. Riley got in his <unclear>house</unclear> and ride off; he fired two shots; does not know at what he fired He did not seem much excite; the time all this occurred was about <unclear>duih</unclear> in the evening of Sunday August 18th, 1861 in the County of Pierce, W.T. John Walmsley was standing with deponent at the time; Riley was not under the influence of lager. Riley was the only person missin from the home by deponent

<pb...></pb...>

<note>page 7- 906</note>

Mrs H.E Bradley continued. Saw two squaws carry an Indian away; saw Riley run after them; the Indian seemed scarcely able to walk, Riley did not pursue very far, then he came to the house. He had blood in his person He is a very bad character and is in the habit of carrying a knife</p>

<p>Thomas Horn, recalled Saw the Indian first in the pastures; he was weak and was helped along by Indian women. He went across into the woods, about 300 yards from the house, Saw no man run after him; did not know the Indian: Was in the house building a fire when the row comenced Mrs. Bradley <unclear>who</unclear> of witness to do so, did not see the Indianbeing wounded, He said Riley cut him; went back to the house to get a bucket of water Did not delay <unclear>saw</unclear> Riley in an hour afterwards. He is in the habit of carrying a knife, a common sheath knife. He bears a bad character.</p>