<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0154.001"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0154.001</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">October 14, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date></term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Clifford, Peter A.
Long (Clifford, Williams), Grace E.
Clifford, Alice B.
Burt. J.  J.
White, W. H. </term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Georgetown, King County, Washington
San Francisco, California
Seattle, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Clifford, Peter A.</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Long (Williams, Clifford), Grace E.
Williams, Herbert O.</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>White, W. H.
Burt, J. J. </persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0154.001"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL CIRCUIT,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>PETER A. CLIFFORD,
PETITIONER,
vs.
HERBERT O. WILLIAMS and
GRACE E. WILLIAMS,
Respondents.</p>
<p>Petition for Writ of 
Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>To the Honorable the Circuit Court
of the United States for the District of Washington, Northern
Division:-</p>
<p>The petition of Peter A. Clifford respectfully shows:</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>That at all the times herein stated he was and now is a citizen
and resident of the State of California, and that respon-
dents are and for more than eight months last past have been
citizens and residents of the State of Washington, in the 
County of King.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>That on the 17th day of October, A. D. 1899, one Grace E.
Long was a citizen and resident of the State of California, and
on that day your petitioner and the said Grace E. Long, at the
City and County of San Francisco, in the said State of Califor-
nia, intermarried, and bacame husband and wife, and the said
Grace E. Long thereby became Grace E. Clifford.</p>
<p>III.</p>
<p>That thereafter your petitioner and his said wife lived
together in the City and County of San Francisco, State of Cal-
ifornia until about the 7th day of March, A. D. 1901, and
that on or about the said last named day the said Grace E. Clif-
ford deserted and abandoned your petitioner without any just cause
and without his consent.
</p>
<p>IV.</p>
<p>That during the marriage of your petitioner and the said
Grace E. Clifford, there was born to them, as the issue of said
marriage, a female child, now living, and of the age of four
years, named Alice B. Clifford.</p>
<p>V.</p>
<p>That on the 24th day of March, A. D. 1902, the said Grace E.
Cliffored commenced an action in the Superior Court in and for
the City and County of San Francisco, State of California, for
an absolute divorce from your petitioner, and therein prayed
for the custody of said child of said mariage, and your petit-
ioner appeared in said action and filed his answer, and also a
cross-complaint for a divorce from said Grace E. Clifford there-
in, and in said cross-complaint prayed that the custody of said
child should be awarded to him by said Court.</p>
<p>VI.</p>
<p>That thereafter such proceedings were had in such action
and cross-action that the judgment of said court was given, made and
entered therein, denying a divorce to said Grace E. Clifford and
granting a divorce to your petitioner, and awarding the custody
of said child to said Grace E. Clifford until the further order
of the court; and providing that your petitioner should be al-
lowed to see said child once a week and to take the same out
with him once in every two weeks.</p>
<p>VII.</p>
<p>That at the time of the commencement of said action and from
thenoe on down and including the time of the entry of said judg-
ment, your petitioner, thhe said Grace E. Clifford, and said 
child were all citizens and bona fide residents of the said City
and County of San Francisco, in said State of California, and
actually present therein, and your petitioner and the said Grace
E. Clifford had been such citizens and residents of said City
and County continuously since the date of their said marriage,
and said child had been such citizen and resident continuously
since the date of her birth, and within the jurisdiction of said
Superior Court in said acion and cross-section, and said Superior
Court was then and yet is a court of record and of superior jur-
isdiction.</p>
<p>VIII.</p>
<p>That after the date of entry of said judgment by said
Superior Court, the said Grace E. Clifford continued to reside
in said City and County of San Francisco until some time in 
September, A. D. 1903, the exact time being unknown to your
petitioner, and that during said moth she secretly and surrepti-
tiously and without the permission of said Superior Court,
and in contempt thereof, and without the knowledge or consent
of your petitioner, took said child out of the State of Califor-
nia.</p>
<p>IX.</p>
<p>That on the 27th day of November, A. D. 1903, your petition-
er fled in said Superior Court a verified petition in said ac-
tion and cross-action for a modification of the judgment there-
in by taking away from the custody of the said Grace E. Clifford
the said child and awarding the custody thereof to your petit-
ioner, and such proceedings were thereupon had that an order was
made and entered therein modifying and changing said judgment
and taking the custody of said child from said Grace E. Clifford
 and awarding the same to your petitioner until the further order
of the said Superior Court, and said order ever since has been
and still is standing and not set aside, and in full force and
effect, and under the laws of the State of California, at the 
time of the commencement of said action, and at the time of the 
entry of said judgment, and at the time of the making of the
said order, said child was a ward of said Court and under the 
control thereof; and it is provided by the laws of the said
State that said Court could at any tme after the entry of said
judgment make any order with or without notice modifyig said
judgmet as to the custody of said child.</p>
<p>X.</p>
<p>That since the said judgment of divorce, the said Grace E.
Clifford and one Herbert O. Williams above named, intermarried
in said State of California, and became and ever since have
been and now are husband and wife and evrer since their
said marriage have had in the State of California and elsewhere
and now at the town of Georgetown, in said County of King,
saod child in their custody and posession.</p>
<p>XI.</p>
<p>That on the 19th day of January, 1904, at the said town of
Georgetown, your petitioner presented to the said Herbet O.
Williams and also to the said Grace E. Williams, a copy of the
record and proceedings of the said Superior Court of said City
and County of San Francisco, in said acion and cross-section,
certified under and in pursuance of an Act of the Congress of
the United Sates in such case made and provided, and demanded
from them and eachof them the immediate delivery of the said
child to him, said petitioner, but they refused and still do 
refuse to give up said child, and said child ever since has been
and now is imprisoned and restrained of her liberty by them at 
said town of Georgettown, and that according to the best of your
petitioner's knowledge and belief, the cause of pretense of the
aforesaid confinement or restraint of the said child, Alice B.
Clifford, is that under the said judgment of said Superior Court
of said City and County of San Francisco, the custody of said
child was given to said Grace E. Clifford, now Grace E. Williams,
umtil further order of the Court, and that after she took said
child beyond the limits of said State of California, as afore-
saod, said Superior Court lost all jurisdiction to make any fur-
ther order in said action and cross-section in regard to any mod-
ification of said judgment as to the custody of said child, and
that she had the right to take said child beyond the jurisdic-
tion of the State of California without first obtaining therefor
the permission of said Court, and that after said child was
taken into said State of Washington said Herbet O. Williams
and without the knowledge or consent of said Superior Court of
said City and County of San Francisco, and without giving any
notice thereof, undertook, under the laws of the said State of
Washington, to adpot said child as husband and wife, as theor
own. And your petitioner further states that he believes and
therefore alleges, ad he is advised by counsel W. H. White, Esq.,
residing at the City of Seattle, State of Washington, and J. J. 
Burt, Esq., residing at the City and County of San Francisco,
State of California, that the said imprisonment of the said
child, Alice B, Clifford, is illegal, and that the illegality
consists in this, to-wit:-
</p>
<p>That said Superior Court of the said City and County of San
Francisco had jurisdiction under the laws of the State of Calif-
ornia, to award the custody of said child upon the fact here-
onbefore alleged until the further order of that Court, and to
thereinafter change and modify the judgment as to the custody
of said child with or without notice to any or either of the 
parties to said action, and that the said Grace E. Williams and 
Herbert O. Williams had no, nor had either of them any, right or 
power under the laws of California, to remove said child from
the State of California or change its placee of residence there-
from to any other place without the permission of said Superior
Court of said City and County of San Francisco, and that under
Art. IV, Sec 1 of the Constitution of the United States, and
Section 905 Revised statutes if the United States enacted i
pursuance thereof, full faith and credit must be given in the
State of Washington to the acts and proceedings of said Super-
ior Court of the City and County of San Francisco, and all per-
sons and courts must recognize (page 7)</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>