<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0213.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Taichi Hiura v. Henry M. White. Petition for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0213.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Taichi Hiura v. Henry M. White. Petition for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1920-08-12">August 12, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-08">August 1920</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hiura, Taichi</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Kiefer, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-02" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>No. 5487</p>

<p>Petition for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of Hiura,Teiichi for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE THE JUDGES OF THE ABOVE ENTITLED COURT:</p>

<p>The petition of Hiura,Teiichi respectfully represents as follows:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That he came to the United States April 1st, 1914, and continuously resided in the United States up to November 1919, when he went to Japan upon a visit, during all of said time residing in Tacoma, Washington; that on the first day of July, 1920, he arrived in the United States on the steamship AFRICA MARU and after a hearing and examination before the United States Commissioner of Immigration at the Port of Seattle and Board of Special inquiry convened for that purpose, your petitioner was excluded from the United States for the reason that his passport for his return was obtained surreptitiously, and for the further alleged reason that he is a person likely to become a public charge, and an appeal was taken from such decision to the Secretary of Labor, who on the 11th day of August, 1920, dismissed, refused and denied said appeal.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>That your petitioner is a duly domiciled alien residing in the United States for five and one-half years and upwards before returning to Japan, and that he is able to support himself, having in his possession in money and securities to the value of $300 and has a regular and lawful occupation, that of <unclear></unclear> Steel Mill</p>

<pb/>

<p>III.</p>

<p>That your petitioner was denied a just and fair hearing, but was arbitrarily excluded and denied admission because of prejudice and in utter disregard of the testimony and the board of special inquiry which heard the case of your petitioner was not legally constituted.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus may issue herein to the said Henry M. White, United States Immigration Commissioner for the Port of Seattle, commanding him that he do produce your petitioner before this court, together with the cause of his detention, and that upon the hearing your petitioner be discharged and be permitted to land and be admitted into the United States of America, and for such other and further relief as to the court may seem meet in the premises.</p>

<p>Hiura, Taichi.</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>

<p>James Kiefer</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner.</p>

<pb/>

<p>United States of America,</p>
<p>Western District of Washington,</p>
<p>County of King,</p>

<p>ss.</p>

<p>Hiura, Teiichi being duly sworn, according to law, says: That he is the petitioner above named; that the foregoing petition has been explained and interpreted to him and that the facts therein stated are true, as he verily believes</p>

<p>Hiura, Taichi</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 12th day of August, A.D. 1920.</p>

<p>James Kiefer</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>