<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0373.013">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Alfonso Gagliardi v. T.W. Lynch. Affidavit of Alfonso Gagliardi</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0373.013</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Alfonso Gagliardi v. T.W. Lynch. Affidavit of Alfonso Gagliardi</title>
<date when="1921-12-13">December 13, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-12">December 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Gagliardi, Alfonso</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Lynch, T.W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Allen, Clay</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Frater, John A.</persName>
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-08" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>No. 6443</p>

<p>Affidavit of Alfonso Gagliardi</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Alfonso Gagliardi for Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>United States of America,</p>
<p>Western District of Washington,</p>
<p>Northern Division.</p>

<p>SS</p>

<p>ALFONSO GAGLIARDI, being first duly sworn upon his oath, says: That there has been read to him the Petition filed in the above entitled matter and that he believes the allegations therein made to be true, and he adopts the statements therein made and each oth them as part of this affidavit to the same extent and purpose as though they were set out herein. That heretofore to Secretary of Labor of the United States, acting by and through the <add>Acting</add> Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, and Arthur J. Kahl, Immigration Inspector at Seattle, Washington, caused a Warrant of Arrest of this affiant to be issued upon the pretended charge:</p>

<p>"That he was a person likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry; and that he entered without inspection by means of false and misleading statements."</p>

<p>That thereafter an additional and supplemental charge was laid against this affiant:</p>

<p>"That you were unable at the time of entering the United States to read the English language or some other language or dialect including Hebrew and Yiddish although at that time over sixteen years</p>

<p>-1-</p>

<pb/>

<p>of age and physically capable of reading and not exempted from the literacy test by any of the Provisions of Section 3 of the Immigration Act."</p>

<p>That at a purported hearing had in the City of Seattle, this affiant was examined touching the matter of his entry and re-entry into the United States; that no evidence was introduced and none was submitted at any hearing to which this petitioner was a party in support of the above described charges. That the action of the said Secretary of Labor, Acting Commissioner of Immigration and Immigration Inspector and each of them directing the arrest and deportation of this affiant was illegal and without warrant in law.</p>

<p>That this affiant had been at the time of his re-entry into the United States for more than five years continuously a lawful resident of the United States and he is now a person qualified under the laws of the United States and regulations made pursuant thereto to be in and remain within the United States.</p>

<p>Further deponent sayeth not.</p>

<p>Alfonso Gagliardi</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 13th day of December, 1921.</p>

<p>AW <unclear>Hordall</unclear></p>

<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington residing at Seattle.</p>

<p>-2-</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 6443</p>

<p>In the United States District Court for the Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Alfonso Gagliardi for Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Affidavit of Alfonso Gagliardi</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Dec 13 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<p>Allen, Martin &amp; Wardall</p>

<p>Clay Allen</p>

<p>Attorney for Petitioner</p>

<p>703-4-5-10</p> 
<p>New York Block</p>
<p>Seattle</p>
<p>Main 7465</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>