<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0494.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>In Re: Petition of H. C. Littooy for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Yu, Jingming" xml:id="jy">Jingming Yu</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0494.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">In Re: Petition of H. C. Littooy for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="2022-06-09">June 9, 2022</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1904-06">June 1904</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>H. C. Littooy</term>
<term>H. C. Hanford</term>
<term>W. T. Scott</term>
<term>Frank Barlett</term>
<term>E. B. Edgars</term>
<term>Charles A. Custer</term>
<term>G. McGregor</term>
<term>J. W. Ball</term>
<term>W. J. Lawrie</term>
<term>A. B. Palmer</term>
<term>James Agnew</term>
<term>Parker Brown</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
<term>Seattle, King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>H. C. Littooy</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>H. C. Littooy</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Parker Brown</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>H. C. Hanford</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Ninth Judicial Circuit Court</orgName>
<placeName>District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#jy">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0494.001"/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT of the NINTH CIRCUIT, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE PETITION OF H. C. LITTOOY FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS</p>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE C. H. HANFORD,
Judge,</p>

<p>Your petitioner, H.C. Littooy, respectfully represents:</p>
<p>1. That he is a citizen of the United States and of the State of Washington, anad a resident of the City of Seattle and by profession a dentist.</p>
<p>2. That he has been engaged in teh practice of dentistry for <add>ten</add> years and taht it is the only means of support of himself and his family.</p>
<p>3. That the Legislature of the State of Washington in 1901 passed an act or part of an act in words and figures as follows to-wit:</p>
<p>"Any person or persons seeking to practicse dentistry in the State of Washington, or to own, operate, or cause to be operated, or to run or manage a dental office or place for the practice of dentistry in the State of Washington after the passage of this act shall file his or her name, together with an application for examination, with the secretary of the State Board of Dental Examiners, and at the time of making such application shall pay to the secretary of the board a fee of twenty-five dollars, and to present him or herself at the first regular meeting thereafter of said board to undergo examination before that body. No person shall be eligible for such an examination unless he or she shall be of good moral character ad and shall present to said board his or her diploma from some dental college in good standing and shall give satisfactory evidence of his or her rightful possession of the same: Provided, This section shall not apply to persons engaged in the practice of dentistry at the time of the passage of this act who are bona fide citizens of the State of Washington. All persons successfully passing such examination shall be registered as licensed dentists in the board register as hereinafter provided, and also receive a certificate, said certificate to be signed by the president and secretary of said board.</p>
<p>4. That on the 3rd day of June, 1904 the prosecuting attorney of King County, State of Washington, lodged an information in the Superior Court of the State of Washington for said King County against your petitioner, charging him with practising dentistry in violation of said act which said information is in wordsa nd figures as follows:</p>

<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON.</p>
<p>-:For King County:-</p>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON,</p>

<p>Plaintiff,    No. 3076</p>

<p>vs.</p>
<p>H. C. LITTOOY,     INFORMATION.</p>
<p>Defendant.</p>


<p>H. C. Littooy is hereby accused by W.T. Scott, the Prosecuting Attorney in and for the County of King, State of Washington, in the name of and by the authority of said State of Washington, and on oath by this Information, of the crime of PRACTISING DENTISTRY WITHOUT A LICENSE, committed as follows, to-wit:</p>

<p>He, the said H. C. Littooy, in the County of King, State of Washington, on the 7th day of May, 1904, then and there being, did then and there willfully and unlawfully practise dentistry, and did perform operations, or parts of operations, and did treat diseases of lesions of the human teeth and of the jaws, and did correct malpositions thereof without registering or procuring a license, as required by law, in that he, the said H.C. Littooy, did then and there willfully and unlawfully for a fee, salary and reward, paid to himself, for the acts and opeartions, and parts of operations herein mentione treat a disease and lesion of the human teeth, and did correct malpositions fo the human teeth and jaws, of one Mrs. Frank Barlett, said Mrs. Frank Barlett, then and there being a living human being, and then and there being afflicted with a disease and lesion of her said teeth and malpositions of said teeth and jaws, said defendent then and there not having, as required by law, first procured and filed for record in the office of the County Auditor of and for said King County, a certificate permitting and authorizing the asid defendant to practise dentistry within the State of Washington.</p>
<p>Contrary to the form of the statute in such cases made and provided, and against the peace and dignity of the State of Washington.</p>
<p>Dated at Seattle, King County, Washington, this 4th day of June, 1904.</p>

<p>W. T. Scott <!--Signed--></p>
<p>Prosecuting Attorny in and for the County of King, State of Washington.</p>

<p>State of Washington:</p>
<p>:ss.</p>
<p>County of King, :</p>

<p>Cha. S. GLEASON, being first duly sworn, on oath deposes and says: That he is one of the Deputy Prosecuting Attorneys in and for the County of King, State of Washington; that he has read the foregoing Information, knows the contents thereof, and believes the same to be true.</p>

<p>Chas. S. Gleason</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 4th day of June, 1904.</p>

<p>C. A. Keepfli.</p>
<p>Clerk of the Superior Court for the County of King, State of Washington.</p>

<p> By J.W. Brewster. 
Deputy.</p>

<p>WITNESSES FOR THE STATE:</p>
<p>Mrs. Frank Barlett, 
Dr. E. B. Edgars, 
Dr. Charles A. Custer, 
Dr. G. McGregor, 
Dr. J. W. Ball, 
Dr. W. J. Lawrie, 
Dr. A. B. Palmer, 
James Agnew.</p>

<p>5. That on the 3rd day of June a awrrant was issued out of the Clerk's office of the said Superior Court upon said information against said petitioner; that on said warrant your petitioner was arrested by the sheriff of said county and taken and held in custody by said sheriff and deprived of his liberty under and by virtue of said warrant of arrest so issued as aforesaid.</p>
<p>6. That your petitioner has been arrested five times for the same alleged offense, to-wit: practising dentistry without complying with said act and the prosecuting attorney by his deputies has declared and has made threats, that he will continue to cause the arrest of your petitioner until he leaves this State or ceases to do business in this State and refuses to wait until the validity of the said act can be tested in Court.</p>
<p>7th. That your petitioner made application in manner prescribed by law, to be examined for license to practise dentistry in this State by the Board of Dental Examiners of the State of Washington, but said Board would not permit him to take said examination for the reason taht your petitioner has not a diploma from a dental college.</p>
<p>8. That your petitioner studied dentistry under the direction of a preceptor for six years and is a well qualified and competent dentist. <add>and practiced with <!--fix later--></add></p>
<p>9. That the said action of the prosecuting attorney is malicious and unlawful.</p>
<p>10. That said act is being administered as an unjust and arbitrary manner by the Board of Dental Examiners, and taht their action is in no way regulated and controlled by law; and that licenses to practise dentistry are issued or withheld according to the whim or caprice fo said examining board and they are seeking to drive out of the State all who do not below to a certain Society of Dentists contrary to the law of the land with which <del>reserves</del><add>secures</add> to everyone the equal protection of the law.</p>
<p>11. That the detention of your petitioner under and by virtue of the proceedings herein set forth, is illegal and that the deprivation of his liberty and his detention is the custody of said sheriff are each and all in violation of his rights secured to him by the constitution of the United States and the laws of Congress; that the above described act of Congress of the Legislature of this State under and by virtue of which your petitioner is now held in custody is unconstitutional and void the same being the conflict with Section <del>2</del><add>one</add> of the 14th Amendment of the Constitution of the United States which secures to your petitioner the enjoyment of life, liberty, and property and protection againt the violation of personal rights.</p>
<p>12. That the said act is invalid and confers no jurisdiction upon the said Superior Court to issue said warrant and the arrest and holding in custody as described of your petitioner deprives him of the right to pursue his lawful occupation and profession and of his mean asof procuring a livlihood for himself and his family; that it is class legislation; that it confers special favors upon a class of citizens not conferred on another, and dperived him of his property without due process of law. It confers upon an inferior tribunal to-wit: the so called Board of Dental Examiners fo the State of Washington, arbitrary power, and attempts to delegate to said Board legislative powaer, to-wit: the police power of the State, and the said Dental Board is not exercising the said police power fo the State contrary to the fundamental law of the land and your petitioner togethe riwth all the dentists of this State are subject to the arbitrary control, dictation and government of the said Board; that said act presribes no qualificiations to be required of dentists tending to protect the public but attempts to place the right to practise dentistry in this State upon the mere caprice and discretion of the said Board uncontrolled by law all of which is contrary to the fundamental law of the land.</p>
<p>Your petitioner therefore prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus be issued directed to the said Sheriff of said King County commanding him that the have the body of the said H. C. Littooy by him imprisoned and detained together with the time and cause of said imprisonment and detention before Hon. C. H. Hanford, Judge of the aforesaid Court at the United State's Court, Corner Fourth Avenue and Marion Street, in said City of Seattle on some special and convenient day to be fixed by the Court and then and there to show cause why this petitioner is restrained of his liberty and why he should not be forthwith and immediately discharged from said custody.</p>
<p>2. That pending the return of said Writ at the date to be fixed by this Court, your petitioner be admitted to bail in some sum to be fixed by this court to assume his appearance at the said return date.</p>
<p>3. That your petitioner be discharged from custody and receive all his proper costs and disbusements in the premises.</p>

<p>H. C. Littoy, Petitioner</p>

<p>Parker Brown, atty for Petitioner</p>


<p>Let writ issue according to <unclear/> foregoing petitions <unclear>witnessed</unclear> on the 20th day of June 1904
C. H. Hanford, Judge</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>