<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0364.004">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Bail Bond and Supersedeas Bond</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0364.004</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Bail Bond and Supersedeas Bond</title>
<date when="1921-10-08">October 8, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-10">October 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Decker, Fletcher</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, Adam</persName>
<persName>Sullivan</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-07" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the United States District Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>No. 6215.</p>

<p>Bail Bond and Supersedeas Bond.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Fletcher Decker for a Writ of Habeas Corpus and a Writ of Certiorari.</p>

<p>WHEREAS, Fletcher Decker, by and through his attorneys, Beeler &amp; Sullivan, filed an application in the above entitled court for a writ of Habeas Corpus, which said writ was after hearing discharged by the Honorable Jeremiah Neterer, Judge in and for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division, and said petitioner remanded to the custody of the United States Marshal; and</p>

<p>WHEREAS the said Petitioner, Fletcher Decker, by and through his attorneys, Beeler &amp; Sullivan, has appealed from said order and judgment, entered on the 14th day day of September, 1921, to the Circuit Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit; and</p>

<p>WHEREAS, pending said appeal, the above entitled court has required the said petitioner, Fletcher Decker, to be enlarged upon furnishing a bond which shall operate as a bail bond, appeal bond and supersedeas bond, in the sum of One Thousand Dollars ($1,000.00) cash or Liberty Bonds, for the appearance of the said Fletcher Decker in the above entitled court in case said decree and order and judgment be affirmed.</p>

<p>NOW, THEREFORE, know all men by these presents, that Fletcher Decker, as principal, has caused to be deposited with the clerk of the above entitled court, the sum of one thousand Dollars ($1,000.00) in Liberty bonds of the United States, as surety, is held and firmly bound unto the United States in the penal sum of One Thousand Dollars ($1,000.00) as designated by the deposit of the said Liberty Bonds with the United States Government as said surety, for the payment of which, well and truly to be made, he binds himself, his heirs, executors, administrators and assigns, jointly and severally, by these</p>

<p>-1-</p>

<pb/>

<p>presents.</p>

<p>Signed and sealed and dated this 8th day of October, 1921.</p>

<p>The condition of the above obligation is such that if the above mentioned Fletcher Decker shall at all times render himself amenable to the orders and processes of the above entitled court, in case said order or judgment of the above entitled court be affirmed by the Circuit Court of Appeals of the Ninth Circuit, and will appear for judgment in case it be ultimately determined that said petitioner is not entitled to a writ of habeas corpus, and is remanded to the custody of the United States Marshal at Seattle, Washington, and shall pay all costs that may be awarded against him if he fail to make his plea good on said appeal including expenses of the guard who came from Canada to return him to that jurisdiction, whose expenses were ordered by the court to be paid providing they were full and approved within fifteen days from the sending of said order if it should be determined that said costs in addition to such other costs as may be levieda are properly taxable, then the above obligation to be void, otherwise to remain in full force and virtue.</p>

<p>F <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear></p>

<p>O.K.</p>
<p>Robt C Saunders</p>
<p>United States Attorney.</p>

<p>approved</p>
<p>Edward E Curham</p>
<p>Judge</p>

<pb/>

<p>no. 6215</p>

<p>B. 8 #1- Page 364-</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Oct 8 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>