<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0187.014">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
    <title>Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0187.014</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1914">1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-07">July 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term></term>
<term></term>
<term></term>

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Oregon</term>
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Marie Robina Grayson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Noah Shakespeare</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>George P. Fishburne</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
    <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRIT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN RE MARIE ROBINA GRAYSON, 
alias MARIE ROBINA, for writ 
of habeas corpus )
No. 2780.
STIPULATION.</p>
<p>Front</p>

<p>It is agreed by the attorneys for the petitioner
and for the respondent that they may put in a general 
denial to the return to the writ of such pleading as they
may desire, a ta later date, and that such pleading may be 
considered as having been put in this morning, prior to the 
hearing, and it is further stipulated that the signing of 
the return by G. P. Fishburn, the attorney for Henry M. 
White, is a sufficient verification of the return, and shall
be the same as if signed by Henry M. White, and duly 
acknowledged before a proper official with seal attached.</p>
<p>(The foregoing stipulation is between Noah Shakespeare, 
attorney for petitioner and George P. Fishburne, attorney for 
respondent, and was dictated in open court, July 3, 1914,
morning session, by the attorney for respondent)</p>
<p>FURTHER PROCEEDINGS)</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: I understand there is no testimony 
to be offered.</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: Nothing further, Your Honor.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: The matter is submitted upon the 
record?</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: Yes, the matter is submitted upon
the record. The only matter that we might show is this:
There is one thing before the stenographer goes that I would
like to call to counsel's attention. The files of the Immigration
office show the first hearing, and to sustain the 
return to our writ, we stated in there that she was arrested
on a certain date; that she had a hearing on a certain date;
<fw>--1--</fw>
<pb/>
that her bond was given on a certain date, and that she 
was discharged on a certain date. Unless the attorneys will 
admit that, we will state that the files in the Immigration
office show that fact. At these hearings, as we understand
the law, all the files of the Immigration office there are
considered as bearing on the issue. But I expect they will 
admit that.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Now, I am unable to apply the 
answer to this petition because the petition is not paragraphed
by number, and this refers to paragraphs.</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: Your Honor, I have numbered those
in the way they come. I intended to call the court's attention
to that before.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Well, now we have there paragraphs
seven, eight, nine and ten deied, and then we have the 
affirmative defense all denied, and you say there is no evidence 
to be presented.</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: The only evidence, as I understand
it, is what I am just calling your attention to with 
reference to what I understand to be the evidence in the 
files in the Immigration hearing, and that is that a former 
hearing of a person who is being deported is a part of the records
of this hearing.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: You had better introduce the former,
if you have anything.</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: I thought possibly that as 
having been a part of the original hearing, the files of 
the former hearing would show when the bond was given, when
the petition was rested, and when she was discharged, and 
when her hearing was had, and we will state that we believe 
the Immigration files are admissable in evidence at the
hearing here, and in addition to that, in her testimony she 
refers to the former hearing.</p>
<fw>--2--</fw>
<pb/> 
<p>BY THE COURT: Has counsel any objection to that?</p>
<p>BY MR. SHAKESPEARE: Yes. I would object to it as 
being irrelevant to any issue in this proceeding. Now it 
seems to me to be wholly irrelevant and immaterial as to what 
was done prior to the proceedings under which she is now held. 
That was a proceeding that was institued in Oregon.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Let it stand then. I will pass upon 
it later, when I pass upon the whole question. Is there 
anything else to be offered?</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: That is all on either side.
I think the attorney on the other side and myself both rely 
on the record that was taken at the hearing.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: You had better identify it so there 
will be no question. Have you the record here?</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: Yes, Your Honor, Now this is 
the record: The whole of the Immigration record we offer in 
evidence.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Any objections?</p>
<p>BY MR. SHAKESPEARE: No, Your Honor.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Very well, admit it.</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: That is the record of this 
proceeding, Your Honor.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Is that all?</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: Yes.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Very well, you may proceed with your 
argument.</p>
<pb/>
    <p><unclear/> X</p>
<p>No. 2780.</p>
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT 
OF THE UNITED STATES
FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington.
JUL 6 1914</p>
<ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk
By EML Deputy</ab>
    
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>