<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0156.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J" xml:id="sjs">Salma Silva</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0156.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Snyder, Vestal</term>
<term>Lince, W.I.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Yakima, State of Washington</term>
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Walton, Fred S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Boyle, John G.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The United States Circuit Court, Northern Division, State of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Northern Division, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<ab>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT, <del>SOUTHERN DIVISION</del> Northern Division. STATE OF 
WASHINGTON.</ab>

<ab>In the matter of the application
of F. S. Walton, for a writ of 
habeas corpus.</ab>

<p>To the Honorable C. H. Hanford, Judge of said Court:
The petition of F. S. Walton respectfully shows that
he is unlawfully imprisoned, detained, confined and restrained of his 
liberty by John G. Boyle, at North Yakima, in the county of Yakims,
State of Washington. That the said imprisonment, detention, confinement
and restraint are illegal, and that the illegality thereof
consists in this, to-wit; your said petitioner is a resident of Portland
in the state of Oregon, and is and has for a long time past been
a citizen of said city of Portland and state of Oregon. That upon
the fifth day of September, A.D., 1901, he proceeded upon a certain
lot in the city of North Yakima, and within the incorporated limits
of said city, which he had duly and regularly leased from the owner
thereof for the purpose, to sell and to hawk and to vend a certain
medicinal preparation known as "Quaker Botanical Herbs", the trade
mark of which is "Quaker medicine" with the head and shoulders of a
quaker, and the word "Company underneath same, a trade mark for which
has long since been taken out in the United States Patent Office under
the laws of the United States. That said medicine is composed of various
vegetable preparations, the products of the soil in various parts
of the United States, but it is not composed of any products of the
soil or vegetables grown in the county of Yakima, State of Washington
or at any other point in the state of Washington, but is exclusively
composed of medical herbs and extractions thereof grown in various
states of the United States other than the state of Washington. That
on the said fifth day of September, A.D., 1901, whilst engaged in vending
and hawking said preparations on a lot aforesaid within the corporate
limits of the city of North Yakima aforesaiid, a complaint was filed
by one Vestal Snyder, City Attorney of North Yakima, Washington, before
one W. I. Lince, Police Judge of the city of North Yakima, charging your
petitioner with violating an ordinance of the city of North Yakima,</p>

<pb/>

<p>or that part of an ordinance which reads as follows, to-wit:-</p>

<p>"Sec.7. Each hawker or peddler of goods, wares, and merchandise
shall pay a license of $400.00 dollars per quarter provided that such
license fee may be taken our for a term less than one quarter at the 
rate of $25.00 per day, and provided further that no person shall be 
required to take out a license for peddling newspapers, books, magainzes,
fruit, breat, meat, milk, ice or other products of Yakima County."</p>

<p>That thereafter the petitioner was arrested and brought before
the said Police Judge and upon a motion for a change of venue in
behalf of the petitioner said cause was transferred to the Justice's
Court of J.A.Taggard, Justice of the Peace in and for North Yakima
Precinct, Yakima County, state of Washington. That thereupon a
trial of said cause before said justice J.A.Taggard, the said J. A.
Taggard did under said ordinance assess a fine against the petitioner
in the sum of five dollars and the costs thereof, and did order and
direct as part of his judgment that this petitioner should be committed
to the custody of one John G. Boule, the city marshal of North Yakima
aforesaid, until said fine and costs were paid, and your petitioner
was accordingly taken into the custody of the said John G. Boyle under
and by virtue of said order of commitment and is now in the custody of the said John G. Boyle under and by virtue of the judgment of the
said J. A. Taggard and the said order of commitment made by the said 
justice in pursuance thereof That the said ordinance is null and void
and is in violation of the constitution and laws of the United States
in this to-wit; lst. The sum of $400.00 4s a license for three months
is a prohibitive and unreasonable license as is also $25.00 per day as
provided by said ordinance. That petitioner's profits from the sale
of said medicine would never equal the amount of said licenses. That
the effect of this is to prohibit him from doing business within the
city of North Yakima, and infringes his right under the constitution
of the United States to engage in business in North Yakima upon equal
terms with the persons selling products of Yakima County and interferes
with the right of commerce as guaranteed by the constitution of the
United States between the citizens of the different states, and is
therefore null and void. 2nd. That the said ordinance is in violation</p>

<pb/>

<p>of the constitution and laws of the United States in this, to-
wit:- that the said ordinance discriminates against residents
and citizens and products of all other portions of the United States
in favor of the products and citizens of Yakima County, which is in
violation of the constitutional right of the petitioner as a citizen
of the state of Oregon, and which is in violation of the right of
Congress to regulate commerce, and which is in violation of that potion
of the constitution of the United States which gives to the citizens
of each state of the union like privileges, rights and immunities
in every other state in said union had by the citizens of such state;
for which reason said ordinance is null and void.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus
may be granted directed to the said John G. Boyle commanding him to
have the body of your petitioner before your Honor at a time and
place therein to be specified, to do and receive what shall then and
there be considered by your Honor concerning him, together with the
time and cause of petitioner's detention and said writ and that he may
be restored to his liberty.</p>

<p>Dated on this 7th day of September, 1901.</p>

<ab>H. G. <unclear></unclear></ab>
<ab>Attorney for Petitioner</ab>

<ab>Fred S Walton</ab>
<ab>Petitioner.</ab>

<ab>State of Washington,
County of Yakims</ab>

<ab>SS</ab>

<p>F. S. Walton being first duly sworn by me said upon oath that he 
is the petitioner named in the foregoing petition that he has read the
same, knows the contents thereof and that the same are true.</p>

<p>Taken, sworn to and subscribed before
me this 5th day of September, A. D., 1901</p>

<ab>Fred S. Walton</ab>

<ab>J. W. Conett</ab>
<ab>Notary Public in and for the state
of Washington, residing at North
Yakima, Washington.</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>957</ab>

<ab>TX.</ab>

<ab>In the United States
<del>District</del> Circuit Court, District
of Washington, <del>State
<unclear>Southern</unclear></del> Division
State of Washington</ab>

<ab>In the matter of the 
application of F. S.
Walton - for a 
writ of Habeas
Corpus</ab>

<ab>Petition</ab>

<ab>FILED IN THE
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
SEP 7 1901
A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk

RM Hopkins
Dep.</ab>


<ab>In the United </ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>