<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0100.002"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Territory of Washington v. Sock and Sam. Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0100.002</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Territory of Washington v. Sock and Sam. Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1884-08-18">August 18, 1884</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1884-08">August 1884</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Ah Sock, Jim</term>
<term>Hoyt, John P.</term>
<term>Morres, John</term>
<term>Harris, W.T.</term>
<term>Sam</term>
<term>Smurthevach, Thomas</term>
<term>Winsar, Henry</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Pierce County, Washington Territory</term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Lock</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Jim</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Sam</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Judson, John P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Smurthevach, Thomas</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Harris, W.T.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of 2nd Judicial District of Washington Territory</orgName>
<placeName>Tacoma, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018" who="nl">transcribed.</change> 
<change when="2019" who="sab">encoded, edited transcription.</change> 
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0100.002"/> 

<p>1236</p>

<p>Territory of Washington}</p>
<p>County of Pierce}SS</p>

<p>In the matter of the 
application of Sam Sock and 
Jim for writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>To Hon John P Hoyt Judge of the second 
Judicial District of Washington Territory.</p>

<p>County of Pierce ss.</p>

<p>Your petitioners Sam Sock and Jim res-
pectfully show unto your honor that they are 
residents of said County and Territory 
That they are illegally restrained of their liberty 
by one Henry <unclear>Wisar</unclear> Sheriff of said County of Pierce 
at the City of Tacoma in said County of Pierce</p>

<p>That the cause or pretense of the restraint of
their liberty of your <del></del> petitioners is as your 
petitioners are informed and believe a certain 
commitment or commitments under pretended 
sentence issued and executed by one W.H. 
Harris a Justice of the Peace of said County 
of Pierce</p>

<p>That said restraint of the liberty of your petitioners 
and said pretended commitment under said

<pb...></pb...>

<sic>pretended</sic> sentence and all proceedings 
in the cause hereinafter specified to and includ-
ing the issuences of said pretended commitment or 
commitments are and were wholly illegal, null 
and void for reasons hereinafter stated</p>

<p>Your petitioners further show that they were 
arrested without any process of law whatever 
and were afterwards to wit on the 16th day of 
August AD 1884 taken before one W. H. Harris 
a Justice of the Peace of said County of Pierce where 
a complaint was made against them and a 
warrant issued thereon charging them with being 
on the 15th day of August AD 1884 guilty of the 
offense created by section 2073 of the Code of 
Washington of the year 1881 as amended 
by Act <del>No</del> of the laws of 1883.</p>

<p>That on the 18th day of August 1884 your 
petitioners appeared before said Justice of the Peace 
for examination of the matters alleged against 
them in said complaint and warrant.</p>

<p>The said Justice of the Peace then and there 
refused to examine your petitioners in accordance 
with law he the said Justice stating that he was in

<pb...></pb...>

1236 

doubt as to whether he should examine your 
petitioners or proceed to a trial of the cause</p>

<p>Your petitioners by their counsel therefore 
requested the said Justice of the Peace to elect 
then and there whether he could examine or 
by the cause that your petitioners and their 
counsel might be informed whether they were 
being held for said offense or merely examined 
as to the probable cause to believe them guilty 
of said offense which request the said Justice 
of the Peace did then and there refuse to 
grant but on the contrary decided that 
he would hear the evidence and determine 
then whether he should call it an examina-
tion or trial. Said Justice thereupon asked 
your petitioners if they desired a Jury and 
your petitioners and their counsel not knowing 
and being wholly unable to ascertain whether your 
petitioners were to be tried for said offense 
then and there or be merely examined as to whether 
there was probable cause to believe them guilty of 
said offence were unable to decide whether or 
not a jury were desired or needed and so

<pb...></pb...>

did not determine and did neither demand 
or waive a Jury Whereupon said Justice of 
the Peace proceeded to examine witnesses 
and hear evidence against your petitioners 
After hearing all the evidence produced by 
himself the said Justice was informed by coun-
sel for your petitioners that he had no jurisdiction 
to try said offense and was again requested to elect 
whether the proceeding was a trial or an 
examination and was further requested 
<del>to</del> in cause he thought there was probable cause 
to believe the defendants your petitioners guilty 
to <unclear>bind</unclear> them over for trial to the District 
Court <del></del>. The said Justice of the 
Peace then and there asked your petitioners if they 
had any evidence to offer your petitioners by 
their counsel replied that not knowing whether 
the proceeding was a trial or an examination 
no evidence would be offered/authorized your 
petitioners have as they are informed by their coun-
sel after fully and fairly stating their case to them 
a good defense to said offense on the marks thereof</p>

<p>Whereupon the said . Justice of the Peace stated

<pb...></pb...>

1236

that he determined to call the proceeding 
a trial that he found your petitioners guil-
ty as charged and passed judgment thereupon 
that your petitioners pay a fine of <del>fifteen</del> 
Thirty Dollars each binds the costs of pros-
ecution which Judgment and sentence your 
petitioners then and there refused to <unclear>propurcer</unclear> 
and were then &amp; there committed by said Justice of the 
Peace to the common jail of said county.</p>

<p>Your Petitioners therefore allege <sic>that that</sic> 
the said restraint of their liberty as 
aforesaid by the said Henry <unclear>Weiser</unclear> sheriff as aforesaid is illegal for the following reason:</p>

<p>1st For that chapter 149 of the Code of Washington 
Territory for the year 1881 and especially 
the second section of said Chapter being section 
2073 of said code and the amendment thereof 
passed by the Legislature assembly of said 
Territory at the session of 1883 is null 
and void in that it is contrary to the Con-
stitution of the United States and so 
creates no offence whatever</p>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>2d That the offence created by said section 
2073 if an offence at all is not an 
offense within the Jurisdiction of a Justice 
of the Peace of said Territory to hear try &amp; 
determine in that it is an offence 
punishable by imprisonment.</p>

<p>3d That said Justice of the Peace had no 
Jurisdiction to hear try and determine said 
cause for the reason that your petitioners were 
charged in the complaint and warrant 
aforesaid and were tried guilty as for 
a joint offence whereas the offence charged 
if an offense at all was one that could be 
committed only in <unclear>severalty</unclear></p>

<p>4 That the proceedings had by and before 
said Justice of the Peace were harsh, arbitrary 
and unjust and deprived your orator 
of his constitutional right of a trial by Jury.</p>

<p>5 That said Justice of the Peace in refusing to 
inform your petitioner whether he was being 
tried or examined till the case was closed 
deprived him him of a trial by Jury in that 
Your petitioners could not determine

<pb...></pb...>

1236

the use or necessity for a jury until the 
trial was closed.</p>

<p>6h That said Justice of the Peace had no 
Jurisdiction to try &amp; determine said cause 
without a Jury or at least an express 
Waiver of a Jury by your petitioners which 
said waiver of Jury trial your petitioners 
did not at any time express.</p>

<p>7th That all the proceedings of said 
Justice of the Peace were without Jurisdiction 
and the Judgement of said Justice of the 
Peace so rendered in said cause was 
without Jurisdiction and is void both as 
to matters of force and substance and gave 
him no authority whatever to issue 
any commitment</p>

<p>Your petitioners therefore pray that the 
Most Gracious Writ of Habeas Corpus issue directed 
to the said Henry Ausor and his deputies and all 
other persons under him commanding him and 
them to have the bodies of your petitioners before 
Your Honor at a time and place to be therein spec-
ified and to do and receive what shall then

<pb...></pb...>

and there be considered by Your Honor 
concerning your petitioners together with 
the time and cause of their detention and 
that your petitioners may be restored to 
their liberty and your petitioners will ever pray to.</p>

<p>Said</p>

<p>by Thomas <unclear>Smurthevach</unclear> his attorney</p>

<p>Sock</p>

<p>by Thomas <unclear>Smurthevach</unclear> his attorney</p>

<p>Jim</p>

<p>by Thomas <unclear>Smurthevach</unclear> his attorney</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>