<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0152.003"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0152.003</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">December 1, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date></term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>
Corbin, Jerome C.
Corbin, Frank E. 
Hanford, C. H.
Root, Elihu
Rowan, A. S.
Lueders, H. W.
Ayres, A. Reeves
Matthew, H. M.
Roberts, A. H.
Matthews, W. F.
Huston, J. F. 
Frye, Jesse A.
Durham, Edmund E.
Bethel, W. A. 
Taylor, R. E. 
Evans, R. K.
Goe, James B.
Murphy, Truman O.
Hawthorne, Harry L.
Enoche, Berkeley
Hadsell, Arthur
Morse, Arthur W.
Micthell, Harry E.
Screws, William P.
Allen, Charles M.
Wilson, Walter K.
Nalle, James B.
Taylor, Reuben C.
FUNSTON
Mitchell, B. J. 
Cushman, Edward E.
Moors, A. N.
Drake, James C.
Wright, B. O. 
</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington'
Vancouver, Washington
Tacoma, Pierce County, Washington
Clarke County
County of King
</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Corbin, Jerome C.</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Corbin, Frank E.</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName> Lueders, H. W.
</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>
Bethel, W. A., Frye, Jesse A., Cushman, Edward E. </persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H. </persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Circuit Court of Washington, 9th District</orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0152.001"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->


<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT, NINTH CIRCUITM DISTRICT
OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In re Frank E. Corbin
(Writ of habeas corpus--Return of respondent.)</p>

<p>To the Honorable Judge of the said Court.</p>

<p>The respondent, Colonel Joseph F, Huston, 19th Infantry,
upon whom hasbeen served a writ of habeas corpus for the pro-
duction of Frank E. Corbin, respectfully makes return and
states that as Commanding Officer of the Military Port of Van-
couver Barracks, Washington, he holds the said Frank E. Corbin
by authority of the United States under the following circum-
stances:</p>

<p>That on the 30th day of November, 1903, at Seattle Wash-
ington, the said Frank E. Corbin, being then a minor, did fraud-
ulently enlist in the military service of the United States for
the term of three years by falsely representing that he was
twenty-one years and four months old, and that the said
Frank E. Corbin has since the said fraudulent enlistment received
pay and allowance thereunder.</p>

<p>That the said Frank E. Corbin has been placed in confine-
ment, charged with said offense, and formal charge against him
therefor have been preferred, a copy of which is hereto annexed,
and that he will be brought to trial thereon as soon as practic-
able before a general court-martial convened by Special Orders,
No. 6, dated Headquarters Department of Columbia, Vancouver
Barracks, Washington, January 11th, 1904, a copy of which is hereto
annexed.</p>

<p>In obedience, however, to the said writ of HABEAS CORPUS,
the respondent herewith produces before the Court the body of
the said Frank E. Corbin, respectfully refers to the decisions
cited in the annexed brief, and for the reasons set forth in
this return prays this honorable Court to dismiss the said writ.</p>

<p>J. F. Huson
Colonel, 19th U. S. Infantry.</p>

<p>Dated, Vancouver Barracks, Washington
January 16, 1904</p>

<p>Jesse Attys
U. S. Atty</p>

<p>Edward E. Cushman
Asst. US Atty
W. A. Bethel
Attorney for respondent.</p>

<p>CHARGES AND SPECIFICATION PREFERRED AGAINST Private
Frank E. Corbin, Company "D", 19th Infantry.</p>

<p>CHARGE: Fradualent enlistment in violatoin of the 62nd Article 
of War.</p>

<p>Specification; In that Private Frank E. Corbin, Company "D", 19th 
Infantry, did at Seattle, Washington, on the 30th day of
November 1903, he being a minor, fraudulently enlist as
a soldier in the service of the United States by falsely
representing himself to befoore over 21 years, to wit, 21 years and 4
months of age, and that he has since said fraudulent
enlistment received pay and allowances thereunder.</p>

<p>Ths at Seattle, Washingotn, and Vancouver Barracks,
Washington, on and after about November 30th 1903.</p>

<p>GSW Herberts
Cap't and Adj't 19th Infantry
Officer Preferring Charges.</p>

<p>WITNESSES:
Sergeant Mohr, Recruiting Station, Seattle, Wash.
Corbin, (Father of accused)</p>

<p>PREVIOUS CONVICTIONS: one (1)</p>

<p>(duplicant)</p>

<p>THE UNITED STATES
VERSUS
FRANK E. CORBIN,
Private Company "D" 19th 
Infantry.</p>

<p>Violation of the 62nd A. W.
(Fraudulent Enlistment)
The Specification.</p>

<p>1st Indorsement.</p>

<p>Vancouver Barracks, Washington,
January 16, 1904.</p>

<p>Respectfully forwarded to
the Adjutant General, Depart-
ment of the Columbia, recommend-
ing trial by general court mar-
tial.</p>

<p>I have investigated this
case and believe the charges 
can be sustained.</p>

<p>Statements of service and
record of previous convictions
inclosed.</p>

<p>J. F. Huston
Colonel 19th Infantry,
Commanding.
(2 Incl's.)
(application)</p>

<p>2nd Indorsement.
HEADQRS. DEPT, OF THE COLUMBIA,
VANCOUVER BARRACKS, WASH.,
JAN, 16, 1904.
To the Judge Advocate, D. C.</p>

<p>3rd Endorsement
HEADQUARTERS DEPT OF THE COLUMBIA.
JUDGE ADVOCATE'S OFFICE,
VANCOUVER BARRACKS WASH.
Jany 16 1904
Respectfully returned recommended for trial
by General Court- Martial</p>

<p>W. A. Bethel</p>

<p>Major and Judge advocate, U. S. Army,
Judge Advocate.</p>

<p>4th Indorsement
HEADQUARTERS DEPT OF THE COLUMBIA
VANCOUVER BARRACKS, WASH.,
JAN, 16, 1904.</p>

<p>Respectfully referred to 2nd Lt. R.
E. Taylor, 19th Infantry,
judge advocate of the general court-martial
convened by paragraph 1 Special Orders
No. 6 current series, from these head-
quarters, for trial.</p>

<p>By command of Brigadjer General FUNSTON</p>

<p>R. K. Evans</p>

<p>Major, Adjutant General</p>

<p>I certify that the within 
charges together with the
endorsements hereon are true
copies of papers in the case
of the United States vs.
Frank C. Corbin, which have
been refered from this of-
fice to a general court-mar-
tial for trial.</p>

<p>R. K. Evans
Major, Adjutant General,
Department of the Colum-
bia.</p>

<p>HEADQUARTERS DEPARTMENT OF THE COLUMBIA,
VANCOUVER BARRACKS, WASH., JANUARY 11, 1904.</p>

<p>SPECIAL ORDERS</p>

<p>NO. 6</p>

<p>1.- A general court-martial is appointed to meet at Vancouver
Barracks, Wash., at 10 o'clock, a. m. on Friday, January 15,
1904, or as soon thereafter as practicable, for thee trial of such
persons as may be properly brought before it.</p>

<p>Detail for the Court.</p>

<p>Major James B. Goe, 19th Infantry</p>

<p>Captain Truman O. Murphy, 19th Infantry</p>

<p>Captain Harry L. Hawthorne, Artillery Corps.</p>

<p>Captain Berkeley Enochs, 19th Infantry.</p>

<p>1st Liuetenant G. Arthur Hadsell, 19th Infantry.</p>

<p>1st Lieutenant Arthur W. Morse, Assistant Surgeon, U. S. 
Army.</p>

<p>1st Lieutenant Harry E. Mitchell, Artillery Corps.</p>

<p>1st Lieutenant William P. Screws, Batallion Adjutant 19th
Infantry.</p>

<p>2d Lieutenant Charles M. Allen, Artillery Corps.</p>

<p>2d Lieutenant Walter K. Wilson, Artillery Corps.</p>

<p>2d Lieutenant James B. Nalle, 19th Infantry.</p>

<p>2d Lieutenant Reuben C. Taylor, 19th Infantry, judge
advocate.</p>

<p>A greater number of officer cannot be assembled without man-
ifest injury to the service.</p>

<p>By command of Brigader General FUNSTON:</p>

<p>R. K. Evans
Major, Adjutant General</p>

<p>Official:
B. J. MITCHELL,
1st Lieut. 12th Infantry,
Aid-de-Camp.</p>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT, NINTH CIRCUIT, DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In re Frank E. Corbin.</p>

<p>B R I E F O F R E S P O N D E N T .</p>

<p>A CONTRACT OF ENLISTMENT IS NOT VOIDABLE BY PARENTS OR GUARD-
IANS IF THE SOLDIER IS HELD PURSUANT TO A SENTENCE OF A COURT-
MARTIAL OR ANY STEP HAS BEEN TAKEN WITH A VIEW TO BRINGING HIM
BEFORE SUCH COURT.</p>

<p>In re Kaufman, 41 Federal Reporter, 876; In re Dohrendorf,
et al., 40 Federal Reporter, 148; In re Cosenow, 37 Federal Re-
porter, 668; In re Dowd, 90 Federal Reporter, 718; Ex parte
Anderson, 16 Iowa.</p>

<p>In the Kaufman case, the father sought the discharge of
his son, who was held by the military authorities and had been
ordered before a military court for trial as a deserter. Quot-
ing from the syllabus:</p>

<p>A minor who enlists in the United States Army upon hs rep=
resentation that he is of age, and receives pay and clothing and
afterwards deserts and is arrested as a deserter, and at the time
of his petition is held by the United States awaiting trial by a 
court-martial for the crime of desertion, will not be released
under a writ of HABEAS CORPUS upon the ground that being a minor
his enlistment was unlawful contrary to the Revised Statutes
of the United States.</p>

<p>In the Cosenow case the minor swore that he was twenty-one
years and seven months old at the time of enlistment. He
deserted, and at the time of the filing of the petition was held
in custody awaiting the action of the reviewing authority on the
proceedigs of the court-martial. His father sought the discharge
of his son on the ground of infancy at the time of enlistment.
The court refused to discharge him, holding that "an enlistment
contrary to law is not void, but voidable;" that the court-mar-
tial had jurisdiction of the offense, and the soldier "must be
remanded to await the result of his trial."</p>

<p>The Dowd case arose on the application of the mother for the
release of her son, who was held under sentence of a summary
of court. The court held, quoting from the syllabus:</p>

<p>The enlistment of a minor in the Army without the consent of
his parents or guardian, required by Revised Statutes, section
1117, is not void, but voidable only, and while he remains in the
service under such enlistment the mino is amendable to the Ar-
ticles of War, and can not be remanded to the custody of his par-
ents by a civil court on a writ of HABEAS CORPUS while undergong
a sentence imposed on him by a court-martial for a violation of
such articles.</p>

<p>In the Anderson cas,e the father procured a writ of HABEAS
CORPUS for the purpose of obtaining the discharge of his minor
son from the military custody in which he was held. It was ad-
mitted by the pleadings that the relator's son was a minor when
he enlisted and that he enlisted without his parents consent.</p>

<p>The Judge's decision was as follows:</p>

<p>I therefore hold that the return of the respondent in this
case, that he holds the prisoner for the crime of desertion, and
that heis now awaiting his trial before a court-martial is suf-
ficient, and that he must abide by the decision of the latter
court, before the question of the validity of his enlistment can be
determined by the civil courts on HABEAS CORPUS.</p>

<p>Section 3 of an act of Congress amending the Articles of 
War and for others purposes, approved July 27, 1892, provides:
"That fraudulent enlistment, and the receipt of anypay or allow-
ance thereunder, is hereby declared a military offense and made
punishiable by court-martial under the Sixty-second Article of
War."</p>

<p>In Circular No. 13 of the War Department for 1892, the Acting
Secretary of War decided that cases of fraudulent enlistment
should be tried before a general court-martial. That circular
declared fraudulent enlistment to be "an enlistment procured by
means of a willful misrepresentation in regard to a qualifica-
tion or disqualification for enlistment, or by an intentional
concealment of a disqualification which has had the effect of
causing the enlistment of a man not qualified to be a soldier,
and who but for such false representation or concealment would
have been rejected.</p>

<p>Section 1117, Revised Statutes, provides that: "No person
under the age of twenty-one years shall be enlisted or mustered
into the military service of the United States without the 
written consent of his parents or guardian; PROVIDED, That such
minor has such parens or guardians entitled to his custody
and control."</p>

<p>A minor who obtains his enlistment into the military ser-
vice of the United States by falsely representing that he is
twenty-one years old is guilty of fraudulent enlistment and is
amendable to trial by a military court-martial which has exclus-
ive jurisdiction in such case.</p>

<p>Should a civil court discharge from the Army a minor who is
under charges and awaiting trial by court-martial for desertion,
fradulent enlistment, or any other offense prescribed by the Ar-
ticles of War or other acts of Congress, it would disregard the
Constitutional power of Congress "To make rules for the Govern-
ment and Regulation of the land and naval forces."</p>

<p>Under the custom of the service the parents or guardian of a 
minor who enlists without their consent can obtain his discharge
upon application to the Secretary of War, prior to the commis-
sion of a military offense. Their right under section 1117,
Revised Statutes are thus sufficiently protected; but when the
minor has committed a military offense the interests of the pub-
lic in the administration of justice are paramount to the right
sequence of his offense before the right to his dischagr be
passed upon. (Digest Opin. J. A. G., SS 1258 and 1204, and notes.)</p>

<p>The soldier should not be allowed to escape punishment for his
offense, even though his parents assert their right to his ser-
vices. A minor in civil life is liable to punishment for a crime
or misdemeanor, even though his confinement nay interfere with
the rights of his parents.</p>

<p>Jesse A Nye
U.S. Atty</p>

<p>Edward E. Cushman
</p>

<p>W. A. Bethel
Attorney for respondent.</p>

<p>1166</p>

<p>In The U. S. Circuit Courtm
District of Washington</p>

<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>In re Frank E. Corbin -habeas
Corpus</p>

<p>Return of Respondent</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. Cicruit Court.</p>

<p>DIST. OF WASHINGTON.</p>

<p>JAN 18 1904</p>

<p>A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk.</p>

<p>HM Matthew
Deputy</p>

</div1>

    

    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>