<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE UNITED DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT 
OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE 
UNLAWFUL DETENTION OF 
SEVENTY-THREE HINDOO
ALIENS.</p>
<p>) ) ) )</p>
<p>2532</p>
<p>TO THE HONORABLE JEREMIAH NETERER, 
UNITED STATES DISTRICT JUDGE, 
SEATTLE, WASHINGTON;</p>
<p>SECTION 20.</p>
<p>It is an admitted fact that the aliens are held 
on warrants of deportation issues by authority of 
Section 20. It will be noted that Section 2 of the Act 
states that persons likely to become a public charge are 
subject to be excluded, but under the admission and 
authority of the Gonzales case, 192 U.S. 1, and the 
case of Suekichi, 199 Fed. 750, Section 2 is not to be 
applied to alien residents, but only alien immigrants.</p>
<p>These aliens are held under authority of the 
deportation warrants and these warrants give as the only 
ground for holding and deporting said aliens in that they</p>
<p>HERBERT W. MEYERS 
ATTORNEY 
430-3 PIONEER BUILDING 
SEATTLE</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>were likely to become public charges at the time of their 
entry, and those warrants have taken the place of the 
warrants of arrest (see heading at top of warrants) and
the authorities hold that these warrants must be 
substantially correct and must be taken at their face value, 
and if errors have been made of a substantial nature, 
that the alien should be released on habeas corpus.</p>
<p>The courts have gone to the extent of holding 
that where the place where the aliens was to be deported 
was not stated in the warrant, but that there was a 
mere statement in said warrant that the alien should 
be deported to the country from whence he came, that 
that was insufficient, and the alien should be released 
on habeas corpus.</p>
<p>Attention is called to the affidavit of the 
interpreter attached hereto, who was present when about 
half the number of aliens in this case were examined 
by the immigration board at Manila, and passed, and this 
interperter furnishes letters from government officials,
showing that he was the official interpreter. He testifies 
that these men were lawfully admitted at Manila 
and that they could not have received the certificates 
attached hereto, which it is an admitted fact in the 
record that all of the aliens possessed, unless they had 
first had a certificate signed by the immigration 
officials in Manila, which were presented to the aliens 
after a proper examination and an admission at a regular 
port of entry.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>In all the cases that have come before the 
courts, it has been shown that the alien ran across the
border at a place other than a regular port of entry or 
that the alien testified falsely to be admitted, or 
that in some surreptitious or clandestine manner the 
alien unlawfully entered. In this case there is not 
a word or a line of the testimony to show any unlawful 
entry, but there is a testimony to show that they went 
to Manila in a boat operated by one of the regular steamship
lines, and the court will take judicial notice
of the fact that these big ocean liners do not land 
their passengers at some hidden shore, but that they 
are met before landing at the port of Manila by the
government officers and not a man is permitted to land
until after he is inspected and examined by the immigration 
and custom officers. They testified they were 
examined regularly and passed, and described, apparently
to the satisfaction of the government agents at Seattle, 
as they did not question the fact of the examination, 
that they had received an examination similar 
to the one received in Seattle, and had been passed
as entitled to enter, from six months to three years ago 
at the port of Manila.</p>
<p>It will be noted by referring to Section 12 
that the master or commanding officer of a steamer is 
required to make a report and to pay $4.00 head tax for
every man on board who comes within the requirements, and 
about midway of that paragraph it is stated that no 
master of any vessel shall be granted clearance papers</p>
<p>HERBERT W. MEYERS 
ATTORNEY 
430-2 PIONEER BUILDING 
SEATTLE</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>for his vessel until he has deposited such list or lists 
with the collecter of customs, and further that the 
collecter of customs with whom such list has been 
deposited, in accordance with the provisions of 
this section, shall promptly notify the commissioner 
general of immigration. This is for the purpose of 
having alines who are about to land, examined properly
by the proper board of immigration officers. After 
they were examined, as appears in the affidavit attached 
hereto, of the interperter, they are given the certificate 
marked "A", which it will be noted is signed 
by the immigration officals who conducted the examination, 
and that this certificate of identification, 
which shows proper admission and examination is then 
surrendered for the certificate marked "B", which it is 
an admitted fact, were held and surrendered to the 
government in every case, and special attention is 
called to the same interpreter's affidavit, in which he
tells of having lost his original certificate which showed 
his having been admitted, and having to get a duplicate, 
in order to get the certificate which was held and surrendered 
to the government by each one of the aliens
in this hearing. The government not only has failed 
to show an unlawful entry, but lawful entry, so far as 
it was in the power of the aliens to show, has been 
shown. It is preposterous to suppose that if the alien 
would send a cable to the immigration officer at Manila 
that he would look at his said records and tell said 
alien that his name was on the manifest showing him to</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>have lawfully arrived at Manila on a certain date, but 
the government, owning and controlling the records, 
could have gotten that information without any 
difficulty. The records are in the possession of the government, 
and it would tke this Honorable Court, or some 
other court, in order to secure this information from 
the government from their official records.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>It seems conclusive that by reference to Section 
36, page 17 of the immigration pamphlet, where it provides 
"that all aliens who shall enter the United States except 
at the seaports thereof, or at such place or places 
as the Secretary of Labor may from tiem to time designate, 
shall be adjudged to have entered the country unlawfully
and shall be deported as provided by Sections 
20 and 21 of this Act," especially inasmuch as the same 
section provides that the provision shall not effect the 
power of the commissioner general to regulate the entry 
and inspection of aliens along the borders of Canada 
and Mexico. After setting out in this section what the 
government deems to be an unlawful entry, and the aliens 
having all testifed and show evidence of an admission 
at Manila, and an examination, and as there is a total 
lack of evidence showing any kind of an unlawful entry, 
and further, inasmuch as the government did not demand 
a head tax from these aliens on entering Seattle, and 
as paragraph "E" of subdivision 3, page 22 of the pamphlet
states that a head tax is not demanded from aliens 
who have been lawfully admitted to the United States who</p>
<p>HERBERT W. MEYERS 
ATTORNEY 
430-3 PIONEER BUILDING 
SEATTLE</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>later shall go entransit from one part of the United 
States to another, it seems doubtful to us if the court 
can find that the government has complied with section 
20 of the law, and especially do these aliens not come 
within the provision of Section 2, as subdivision 4 of 
rule 14, page 33 of the pamphlet states that a failure 
to present a certificate shall be deemed presumptive 
evidence that an examination has not occured unless 
he shows that his presence in the country is lawful or 
that the limitation of the statute has expired, and 
certainly this provision is complied with when the alien 
has testified under oath that he was lawfully admitted 
and passed at Manila and resided there after such lawful 
admission for from six months to several years, in view 
of the faact that he was duly sworn and could be convicted 
of perjury for falsely swearing, and in view of the further
fact that the courts have held that alien residents 
have the same protection and have the same status as 
citizens in these matters, and it will not be denied that
the oath of a citizen or an alien resident, as the courts 
have unanimously decided these men to be, who has testifed 
definitely and positively of the lawful examination 
and admission, that that when connected with the fact
of the furnishing of a certificate only granted after 
the surrender of a certificate signed by the immigration 
official, showing a proper examination, and when connected 
with the further fact that the interpreter who has 
testified herein, who is a resident of the city of 
Seattle, testifies that he was present when more than half
<pb></pb>
of these men were examined by the immigration board at 
Manila, it seems preposterous to permit the government
to say that these men entered the country unlawfully.</p>
<p>Subdivision 2 of rule 14 page 33, states that
a certificate shall be furnished as evidence of regular
entry, meaning that if this certificate is not furnished, 
other evidence should be furnished, which has been in 
this case, and further, in subdivision 3, the alien
producing a certificate shall be admitted without further
examination, indicating that the certificate simply 
did away with the examination altogether and failure
to have a certificate meant that the alien would have
to go through another grilling and tedious examination.</p>
<p>Attention of the Court is called, however, to 
the fact that this entire supposed presumption as to 
the failure to have a certificate is not law, and is simply
a ruling of the department, which is in no sense 
controlling upon the court. As to the only other portion
of section 20, which is material herein, and which 
reads as follows, "such as become public charges from 
causes existing prior to landing", it is plain to see
is entirely different language from that used in Section 
2, which provides for a liklehood to become a charge, and 
that the language in Section 20 is mandatory and means 
that they must have become charges in order to come within
Section 20.</p>
<p>Then when we turn to page 36 of the pamphlet,
the 7th line from the bottom, of the fine print, and find
that the secretary has ruled as follows, "usual instances
in which an alien becomes a public charge are where he 
<pb></pb>
enters a public alms house, or hospital or is sent to
jail" that the court will readily see that no evidence 
has been produced, and that the petition for the writ 
should be granted, as the courts have held that where no 
evidence is produced on a material point, that the court
must discharge the alien. When the Secretary cited instances
when an alien becomes a public charge he certainly
meant to say that some happenstance out of the 
ordinary must have occurred to the alien in order to 
make him a public charge. Then by referring to page 37 
of the pamphlet, subdivision cites "Proof in cases 
which have become public charges from prior causes, 
physical or mental" and then the Secretary states what 
should be found in the case of an alien who has become 
a public charge as follows, "an explicit statement that
the alien is a public charge, where and how, and if in 
an institution, the date of admission thereto". And 
further, "wether or not the disabilities described 
constitute the sole causes why the alien is a public charge",
and "wheter the causes which render the alien a public 
charge, existed prior to landing".</p>
<p>Subdivision 4, page 37 shows that this procedure is 
the necessary procedure in these warrant hearings under
Section 20, as is this case. Then at the bottom of 
page 38, this language is found, "but as to aliens who
have become public charges from causes existing prior
to landing, etc." and then further in that same paragraph
we find the language, "removal from the institution", 
<pb></pb>
indicating that the Secretary did not believe that the 
alien had become a public charge unless he was in some 
institution, either a jail, an alms house, or workhouse, 
or in some poor farm.</p>
<p>UNLAWFUL ENTRY</p>
<p>By referring to the bottom of page 29, the fine 
print, this language is found, "any alien who enters the 
United States, across the Canadian border at any other
place than those named in subdivision 1 of this rule as 
a port of entry is subject to deportation under Section 
20, etc", showng again that the government admits that
aliens entering at Manila or any other designated port
of entry, that this is a sufficient showing that there
ws no unlawful entry.</p>
<p>Unlawful entry was an entry at night, avoiding 
and inspection, in re. Dick, 174 Fed. 674</p>
<p>Unlawful entry was clandestine entry, in re. 
Prentiss 192 Fed. 467.</p>
<p>Unlawful entry was falsely representing self
to be a citizen, in re. Williams, 186, Fed. 476.</p>
<p>An alien who becomes a charge within a year
shall be deemed to have came in violation of law, in 
re. Dick, 174 Fed. 674.</p>
<p>Entering surreptitiously is violation of Sec.
20, in re. Dick 176 Fed. 998.</p>
<p>Falsely represents himself to be a citizen, in 
re. Williams 186 Fed. 479.</p>
<p>LAWFUL ENTRY SHOWN ALMOST CONCLUSIVELY.</p>
<p>The record will show that in each case the
<pb></pb>
passport from the British government was handed to the 
immigration inspector at Seattle and surrendered to the 
government by the alien, and that the said passport was
returned to the said alien, and one of these passports
is attached hereto, and it will be noticed that on the 
back thereof is stamped, "landed at Manila January 9,
1912, Immigration division", and that said stamp bears
an American eagle, and was doubtless stamped at the 
time of this man's examination by the immigration board 
at Manila. These passports are all in the possession 
of the aliens, as the government did not desire to keep 
the same, but the fact that they were presented to the 
government at Seattle will not be denied by counsel for 
the government, and it seems with that stamp on the 
passports, that an unlawful entry at Manila can hardly be
consistently urged. </p> 
<p>Further, the blue and pink papers which are
attached hereto were given to the aliens by the trans-
portationcompany and these in each instance, were also
presented to the government, and returned to the aliens
by the immigration inspector, showing that they took 
passage on a regular line of a steamships subject to the 
immigration laws, and did not approach the shores of 
Manila in a launch or in a row boat for the purpose of
making a surreptitious entry.</p>
<p>If there was a clandestine or surreptitious 
entry in these cases, how was it that the government got 
$4.00 head tax from each man, which is an admitted fact
in the record?</p>
<p>If not once lawfully admitted, then the government
<pb></pb>
would have excluded or attempted to exclude the 
aliens under Section 2, as they would then have been 
subject to that Section, and the government admits 
a priro lawful admission by endeavoring to take the
aliens under Section 20.</p>
<p>The Court will take judicial notice of the
fact that the head tax money goes in the immigration 
fund and is collected at the time of the examination 
by the immigration board.</p>
<p>RETURN SHOULD BE QUASHED.</p>
<p>The petition sets up the faact that no evidence 
has ever been introduced showing the aliens to be
within Section 20, and as the government in its
return has not set up any evidence and as the record
does not show that there was any evidence, the return 
should be quashed.</p>
<p>WARRANTS SHOULD BE QUASHED</p>
<p>As the warrant does not substantially comply
with law and particularly with Section 20, and as the
warrant does not show a compliance with Section 20, but
is drawn up in accordance with the language of Section 
2, which is not applicable in this case, Section 20
making it mandatory that the aliens have become charges, 
whereas the warrant specified that they might likely 
become, the warrant should be quashed.</p>
<p>GOVERNMENT CASES.</p>
<p>The cases cited by counsel for the government
<pb></pb>
were cases in which an unlawful and surreptitious
entires were made, as was the Yamatayo case. In that
case the alien was found to be a pauper at the time and 
was also found to have surreptitously and unlawfully 
entered without authority, which is not true in the 
present case.</p>
<p>CERTIFICATES HELD BY FOUR OF THE ALIENS.</p>
<p>Although all of the seventy-three aliens were
admitted and passed and had a certificate issued by the 
immigration board after examination, still the certificate 
which may be obtained after an alien has lived for a 
year or two in Manila, in leaving there for the mainland
of the United States, was not asked for or obtained by 
the majority of the aliens, because they did not know 
of the law permitting them to obtain the said certificates, 
and no government informed them of this fact, 
but four of the men did make application and get these 
certificate, which they subsequently lost on board the
boat. These men were Moola Singh, Ram Singh, Ali Bux and 
Baggu Khan, the first three of whom testified in their 
examination that they had these certificates, but lost
them. The fourth was not asked the question and on that
account could not tell the government inspector of his 
having held such a certificate.</p>
<p>ALIEN RESIDENTS OF MANILA.</p>
<p>The testimony shows that these men lived in 
Manila for from varying periods of five or six months to 
two or three years, and that most of them were employed
<pb></pb>
either by the city government of Manila or in some
official capacity, in some cases on the police force, 
of that city, and the court will take judicial notice
of the fact that in order to get these positions and 
in order to hold them they would have certainly receive 
sufficient attention and examination in order for the government 
immigration officers to have taken them up, had
they unlawfully entered, before they had been there a 
matter of several years.</p>
<p>INCORRECT CONCLUSION REACHED.</p>
<p>In the case of TOM YONG, found in 193 U.S. 
page 517, there was a reversal of the order of the deportation, 
and the court said, "It is true that the findings 
of the commissioner and in the district court in cases
of this character should ordinarly be followed in this 
court, and will only be reconsidered when it is clear
that an incorrect conclusion has been reached". "In this
state of the record an examination thereof satisfied us 
that the appellants adduced testimony which established 
that they were bone fide merchants within the meaning
of the law at the time the registration was required 
of laborers by the act od Congress, and, as the orders 
of deportation were made on the sole ground that the 
appellants failed to show that fact, the judgments are 
reversed and the appellants discharged".</p>
<p>BURDEN ON GOVERNMENT.</p>
<p>In the case of Castro v. Williams, 203 Fed. 
155, the court said, "The burden is upon the immigration 
authorities to show that any alien denied the right to 
enter does not fall within one of those exception to the 
<pb></pb>
general privilege. Although an alien who has not yet 
entered may not enjoy constitutional guaranties of 
citizens, he has rights under the law which must be
respected." By interference, this decision shows that an alien who has entered does enjoy constitutional guaranties.</p>
<p>ACT TO BE STRICTLY CONSTRUED.</p>
<p>In the case of U.S. v. Redfern, 186 Fed. 150 
the courtstates that the immigration statute should be
strictly construed. There are one or two other cases 
which have decided the same point, but I am unable to 
give the reference at this time.</p>
<p>In one case the court stated that the statutes
were very drastic and should be strictly construed.</p>
<p>If the court will read the first few lines of 
Section 20, the petitioners believe that he will see at 
a glance that the aliens do not come within the confines 
of the section on which the warrants were based.</p>
<p>The government admits that there has been no 
evidence produced or attempted to be produced, showing 
any unlawful entry. On the other hand, there has been 
much evidence produced showing a lawful entry.</p>
<p>The government admits that the men have never 
become public charges and Section 20 makes it mandatory 
that before a warrant can issue, they must become public 
charges, the government's contention being that a likliehood
or a possibility or a probability, that in the distant 
future they might become, is a compliance with 
Section 20, which we are sure cannot be urged with much
<pb></pb>
force to this Honorable Court.</p>
<p>BECOME CHARGES.</p>
<p>By referring to the 3rd line in the last paragraph
of the fine print at the bottom of page 36, the 
language is used, "those who have become", and it is
evident from this wording that the government in the past has read
Section 20 in the same manner as counsel for petitioners 
has read this language to the court, as those who have 
already become, and that those who are likely to become. 
This same wording is found in subdivision 7, the third 
line thereof on page 38.</p>
<p>EXILE ON PRESUMPTION OF GOVERNMENT CLERK, NOT OF LAW, NEVER.</p>
<p>In this free country of ours, when the law 
requires that some evidence be produced to send an alien 
who has presumably properly landed, and who has the 
rights of a resident of this country, out of the country,
that some evidence of a material nature will be required, 
the presumption of the government clerk, who 
might possibly be a labor leader, is certainly not going
to be sufficient for this Honorable Court.</p>
<p>LAWFUL. ENTRY.</p>
<p>In face of all the facts called to the attention 
of the court, showing a lawful entry of the 
aliens at a regular port of entry, Manila, and in 
view of the further facts, it seems that it would be out 
of the question to hold that there had not been a lawful
entry made, and when not a word of testimony is before 
the court showing an unlawful entry, which is required 
by law.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>Attached hereto and marked Exhibit 1, will be 
found a receipt for the head tax, signed by the steamship
company, showing a sailing on one of the largest
vessels making Manila, and showing a regular passage to
Manila, which shows conclusively that an examination 
must have been held at Manila, as these boats are not
permitted to land until the immigration officer has 
passed said alien. The court will take judicial 
notice of the fact that the government makes these 
investigations. On the back of Exhibit 1 is found the 
immigration requirements as instruction to the alien.</p>
<p>Marked Exhibit 2 will be found receipts from 
the steamship line for $19.00 which was taken from 
four of the aliens and others of the party had some of 
these similar receipts, showing this money to have been 
collected, as they were likely to be quarantined at
Manila, showing again the fact that they were proceeding 
in a lawful manner on a regular steamship line, and 
were being subjected to every precaution taken in the
event of their rejection.</p>
<p>Exhibit 3 was taken from one of the aliens and 
similar papers were held by some of the others, in 
which the United States surgeon general passed the alien 
at Singapore as being free from disease and it will be 
noted that the government's stamp is on the document as 
follows, which appears to be, "landed at Manila, P. I. 
July 22, 1912, Immigration division".</p>
<p>Exhibit 4 is a surgen general's certification
which the record will show was presented to the government 
<pb></pb>
by every alien in the number held at the detention
office, this certificate showing that the men were proceeding
in a lawful manner. It will be noted on these 
certificates that the consul general's seal appears.</p>
<p>Two marked Exhibit 5 are certificates of registration 
at Manila in the office of the British consulate.
It is submitted that if these men had unlawfully entered, 
as was suggested by the government, they certainly would 
not register in the consulate's office on arrival.</p>
<p>Exhibit 6 shows some of the men to have been 
disinfected and the official stamps of the vessel and 
the dates appear thereon. These documents were also 
presented to the government and surrendered by the
government to the aliens.</p>
<p>Exhibit 7 is a document similar to one held by 
the other men and shows the alien to have been proceeding 
lawfully. He received this paper from the American 
consulate, showing him to have been disinfected and 
entitled to proceed.</p>
<p>Exhibit 8 was presented to the government and 
surrendered back to the alien and is similar to those held 
by other aliens and is similar to those
held by other aliens and was stamped by the assistant 
Supt. of Indian immigration at Singapore showing him to 
have been regularly travelling from Singapore to Manila.</p>
<p>Exhibit 9 was also presented to the government 
and surrendered by the government back to the 
alien. In that it will be noted said document is 
stamped "landed at Manila, P. I, July 22, 1912, Immigration 
Division", showing clearly a lawful entry.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>Exhibit 10 are post office receipts showing
money to have been sent by registered mail and 
documents showing money to have been sent by some of 
the aliens from Manila to Hong King.</p>
<p>GOVERNMENT'S RECORDS NOT ACCESSIBLE TO ALIENS</p>
<p>It would be impossible for the aliens to get
the information from the government officials and 
access is not given to the aliens. To further prove this 
point, if proof be necessary, the commissioner of 
immigration at Seattle, Hon. Ellis Debruler, informed 
counsel for petitioners on the morning of August 28, 
1913, that the Honorable Federal Court sitting in 
Seattle, and the Circuit Court of Appeals and no other
court, could compel the government to furnish its original
record, but that the best of the court could do would be
to request a copy of the same, this statement being 
made when counsel for petitioners requested that the 
original record be furnished to this Honorable Court,
as there were pictures, material affidavits, and 
documents, which were not in the carbon copy of the 
record furnished to the court.</p>
<p>The following citations are furnished to the 
court in showing that the decisions of the immigration officer
in this case is not final, but that the court should go into 
the record to find if evidence has been produced, and if the 
finding is based upon some material evidence, and if the law 
has been complied with, and if the alien in question comes
within the requirements of the section of the Act under which 
the said aliens were taken into custody.
<pb></pb></p>
<p>In view of the failure of the government to 
produce any evidence and in view of the overwhelming 
amount of evidence in the record, produced by the aliens, 
and in view of the facilites at the government's hands 
to produce the evidence, which should have been furnished, 
and the inability of the aliens to get access to the 
government's records, it is urged that the warrants 
should be quashed, as not in compliance with Section 20 
upon which section it is admitted they are based.</p>
<p>AUG 28 1913</p>
<p>Respectfully submitted, 
Herbert W. Meyers
Attorny for petitioners.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>