<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0467.002"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John Leonard v. State of Washington. Notice. </title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Ibrahim, Meyri" xml:id="mi">Meyri Ibrahim</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0467.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">John Leonard v. State of Washington. Writ of Habeus Corpus. </title>
<date when="1896-07-29">July 22nd, 1897</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1890-1901, vol 1</collection>
<idno>Case 625</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1896-07"> July 1896</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Whitman County, Washington</term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName> John Leonard</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName> State of Washington </persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>J. E. Fenton</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Ninth Judicial Circuit Court</orgName>
<placeName>County of Whitman, Washington</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2021-09" who="mi">transcribed.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0467.002"/>

<p> IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.
NORTHERN DIVISION. </p>
<p> IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION
OF JOHN LEONARD FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS                N O T I C E.
CORPUS.</p>
<p> To R. A. Simms, Sheriff of Whitman County, State of Washington.
You will please take notice hereby that John Leonard is now in
your custody, duly petititoned the United States Circuit Court for
Writ of Habeus Corpus, seeking relief thereupon and <del/> </p>
<p> Whereas, the said Writ and relief was denied, and whereas,
said petitioner duly moved for a Writ of appeal and for the transfer
of his whole <del/> cause to the Supreme Court of the United States 
and </p>
<p> Whereas, the said cause came on for argument as to the granting
of the said appeal and the transfer of the whole cause to the Appellate
Court, and was heard upon the 22nd day of June, 1897 by the
Honorable C. H. Hanford, Circuit Judge. and </p>
<p> Whereas, after hearing said application Order of Appeal was
duly granted and the said cause was so order <add> ed </add> transferred to the Supreme Court of the United States and full copy of the aforesaid proceedings and the orderallowing said appeal, being duly certified, is hereunto annexed for your information and advice and </p>
<p> Whereas, under the Revised Statutes of the United States being the Laws of the United States particularly Section 766 of the Revised Statutes reads as follows, to-wit: </p>
<p> Section 766. "Pending the proceedings of appeal in the cases
mentioned in the three preceeding sections, and until final judgement
therein, and after final judgment of discharge, <del/> any proceeding
against the person so imprisoned or confined or restrained of his
liberty, in any State Court, or by or under the authority of any

<pb/> 

State, for any matter so heard and determined, or in process of being heard and determined, <del/> <add> under </add> such Writ of Habeus Corpus, shall be deemed null and void. *and </p>
<p> Whereas, the Supreme Court of the United States In Re Jugiro
140 United States 295 construing the said Section defined the same
to mean, "in cases where the appellant was held in custody under the
authority of the State Court, or by authority of a state, to stay
the hands of said Court or state, while the question <del/> <add> a </add> s to whether
his detention was in violation of the Constitution, laws, or treaties
of the Unted States was being examined by the courts of the United
States having jurisdiction in the premises, which said decision is
more fully referred to in the case of In Re. M'Kane 61 Fed. 205
where it was held to mean that until final decision in the Supreme
Court of the United States no disturbance of the condition of the
person as he was at the time of the denying of the Writ can in
any wise be had. </p>
<p> Therefore, you are hereby notified that you are to hold possession or custody of the said Petitioner John Leonard now in your keeping at Coalfax, in the County of Whitman, State of Washington in <del/> <add> such manner </add> as to your discre <del/> <add> t </add> ion shall seem meet and proper in no wise <del/> assuming for any cause to execute any sentence of death whatsoever upon the said Petitioner John Leonard and you <del/> will be duly notified of any further proceeding in the premises. </p>
<p>You will please govern yourself accordingly. </p>
<p> John F. Dor
J. E. Fenton
Del Leary Smith
UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
COUNTY OF WHITMAN.</p>

<pb/>


<fw type="footer"> &amp;</fw>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>