<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0176.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Marie Miler v. Washington State. Return and Answer.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0176.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Mary Miler v. Washington State. Return and Writ.</title>
<date when="1913-04-20">April 20, 1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno>2457MarieMiler</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-04">April 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>DeBruler, Ellis</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fisher, Thomas M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Cabel, Ben J.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Wilson, W. B.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Uhl, Bryan H.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Hunter, B. A.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>White, A. T.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Larken, Eden</term>
</keywords>


<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Miler, Marie</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Washington State</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Riddell, C. F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Beakway, E. B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Cushman, Edward E.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>United States District Court
Western District of Washignton
Nothern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of The Application
of Marie Miler for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus. } No. 2457</p>
<p>Answer and Return
to Writ and Petition Therefor.</p>
<p>To the Honorable Edward E. Cushman, Judge of the above entitled 
Court:</p>
<p>Comes now Ellis DeBruler, Commissioner of Immigration
at Seattle, Washington, and for answer to the Writ of Habeas
Corpus issued herein, and for answer to the petition
filed herein, states as follows:</p>
<p> I
That for answer to Paragraph One of said petition, said
Ellis DeBruler admits the same.</p>
<p>II
That for answer to Paragraph Two of said petition, said
Ellis DeBruler admits that the petitioner came to the United 
States about the year 1909, where she has since redided, but
denies each and every other allegation therein contained.</p>
<p>III
That for answer to Paragraph Three of said petition, said 
Ellis DeBruler admits that complaint was made by him in his
official capacity at Seattle, Washington, against the said
alien, and that as the result thereof, certain proceedings
<pb/>
were had, and that on or about March 18, 1913, the petitioner
was ordered deported and sent from the United States of America,
and denies each and every other allegation contained in
said paragraph.</p>
<p>IV
That for answer to Paragraph Four of said petition,
said Ellis DeBruler denies each and every allegation therein
contained, except such as are specifically admitted in
the further and separate answer and return herein contained.</p>
<p>V
That for answer to Paragraph Five of said petition,
said Ellis DeBruler denies each adn every allegation therein
contained.</p>
<p>VI
That for answer to Paragraph Six of said petition,
said Ellis DeBruler admits that the government of the United
States was about to deport said petitioner, and would have so deported her on or about April 16, 1913, unless the Court
had issued its Writ of Habeas Corpus, and denies each and
every other allegation therein contained.</p>
<p>VII
That for answer to Paragraph Seven of said petition,
said Willis DeBruler admits that he is detaining said petitioner
in his official capacity as United States Commissioner
of Immigration, at the Dentention Station in Seattle, and refuses
to release her from custody, and denies each and every
other allegation therein contained.</p>
<p>VIII
And for a further and separate answer and return to 
said application for a Writ of Habeas Corpu, and for further
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
return to said Writ, said Ellis DeBruler alleges:</p>
<p>That on or about the 8th day of January, 1913, siad
Maria, or Mary, Miler, was arrested by one Thos M. Fisher,
and Inspector of Immigration, stationed at Seattle, Washington,
under authority from the Department of Labor of the 
United States in violatio of the Act of Congress of Feburary
20, 1907, as amended by the Act approved March 26, 1910,
to-wit: That she is and was a member of one of the classes
of aliens required to be deported under the laws of the United
States, to-wit: (That the said alien was connected with a
house of prostitution, and practiced prostitution and derived
benefits therefrom after she entered the United States.) 
That said authority for said arrest and detention is found
in the warrant duly and regularly issued on the 7th dat of
January, 1913, by Ben J. Cabel, Acting Secretary of Commerce
and Labor, copy of said warrant being attached hereto and 
made a part of this return.</p>
<p>That on January 13, 1913, siad Marie, or Mary, Miler
was duly and regularly examined by said Thos. M. Fisher, who
was then and there a duly qualified and acting Inspector of
Immigration, stationed at Seattle, Washington, acting under
the authority of the laws of the United States, and the rules
and regulations of the Bureau of Immigration and Department
of Commerce and Labor of the United States, and as such Inspector,
had power to examine said Marie, or Mary, Miler,
under oath as to her right to remain in the United States.
That at said hearing the said Marie, or Mary, Miler was
duly informed that she might, if she wished, employ an attorney,'
and that she then stated that she would have a friend
<fw>3</fw>
of hers get an attorney, and that she afterwards did employ
an attorney, to-wit: One Roger Marchetti, to represent her,
and that thereafter on numerous and sundry occasions said
Inspector, Thos. M. Fisher, and other members of the Department
of Commerce and Labor, stationed at Seattle, Washington,
endeavored toinduce the said Roger Marohetto to present
any other or further evidence which he might have touching the 
matter of said deportation, and finally, on March 5, 1913,
A.T. White, Inspector of said Bureau, personally delievered
to said Rover Marchetti a letter notifying him, the said
Roger Marchetti, that further proceedings would be had in siad matter on March 7, 1913, at the Dentention House in
Seattle, Washington, and a failure on his part to appear
would be considered as notice that he had no further evidence
to produce, adn that the record would then be submitted
to the Secretary of Commerce and Labor for his decision,
a copy of which letter is hereto attached and made
a part hereof.</p>
<p>That on March 7, 1913, the said Rogert Marchetti, informed
the Inspector that he could not take the matter up
that day, but would take it up the next morning without fail,
and neither the next morning, nor at any other time, did the
said Marie, or Mary, Miler, at anhy time offer to produce 
or procure any other or further evidence, and that thereupon
the record of said proceeding, together with the report of
the examining Inspector, and with the report of Commissioner
Ellis DeBruler, was forwarded to the Department of Labor
at Washington, D.C., and recieved by it, and said Department
<fw>4</fw>
<pb/>
did then and there carefully consider said matters, and on
the 18th day of March, 1913, siad Department, and also W. B.
Wilson, Secretary of Labor, ceame and were satified that 
said alien was one who had been found practicing prostitution
and was a prostitute after her entry to the United
States, and decided adversely to said alien, and ordered her 
deported to the county from whence she same.</p>
<p>That a copy of the testimony so taken at the hearing 
aforesaid is attached hereto and made a part hereof, and
that in addition, other documents considered in said examination
of the matter are attached hereto, and made a part hereof.</p>
<p>Special attention is called to the following documents,
found on pages of the record indicated:</p>
<p>1. Copy of complaint by Commissioner, Ellis DeBruler,
(p.79), with Report of Inspector Fisher attached
thereto (80-81).</p>
<p>2. Original warrant by Ben J. Cable, Acting Secretary
of Commerce and Labor, for arrest of the alien,
Mary Miler, and hearing on charge as to deportation
(p.77)</p>
<p>3. Original report of Acting Commissioner Bryn H. Uhl,
as to record of landing of alien, Mary Miller (p.72)</p>
<p>4. Copyof proceedings had and testimony taken before
Insepctor Thos. M. Fisher, on the hearing held 
under the complaint and warrant. (pp 36-44 inc).</p>
<p>5. Copy of affidavits of Angelo Bassinni, G. Polet 
and Vincent Petrosini, submitted to the Department
to be used in the matter of Marie or Mary Miler,
and which were so used (pp32,33, and 34).</p>
<fw>5</fw>
<p>6. Copy of Certificate of the Medical Inspector 
showing alien aafflicted with Gonorrhoea (p.48)</p>
<p>7. Copy of Report of Immigrant Inspector, B.A. Hunter,
to Commissioner DeBruler, showing steps taken to
induce the attorney of Marie Miler to Proceed with
the matter and present evidence why she should not
be deported, which steps respondent alleges were
actually taken (p. 46)</p>
<p>8. Copy of letter which Respondent alleges was personally
handed to the attorney for Mary or Marie 
Miller, by inspector A. T. White, on March 5, 1913
(p. 60)</p>
<p>9. Copy of findings by Inspector Thos. M. Fisher,
after March 8, 1913, when alien's attorney had
agreed to present his evidence, but in spite of
verbal and written notices, and promises, had 
failed so to do (p.45)</p>
<p>10. copy of letter of Ellis DeBruler, Commissioner,
to the Commissioner General at Washington, enclosing
the record, containing all the above matters,
and recommending the deportation of Mary or Marie
Miller (pp 19,20).</p>
<p>11. Letter of the Commissioner General, Daul J. Keege,
to Commissioner ellis DeBruler, announcing the
decision which the department reached on the record
and recommendation referred to above, said decision
being that the alien was in the United States
contrary to law. (p.8).</p>
<p>12. Copy of warrant by W.B. Wilson, Secreatry of Labor,
stating that he is satisfied that the alien is a
<fw>6</fw>
<pb/>
prostitute and has been found practicing prostitution
subsequent to her entry into United 
States, and ordering her deportation (p. 1)</p>
<p>13. Letter to Commissioner DeBruler, from Commissioner
Williams, based on above warrant, and authorizing
Commissioner DeBruler to bring the alien to Ellis
Island at any time (p. 12).</p>
<p>That the foregoing are the reasons why the said Marie,
or Mary, Miler, is detained by Ellis DeBruler, in custody,
and why the said Ellis DeBruler now detains her in custody
pending the orders of the above entitled court in the premises;
that by reason of the premises, this Court has no
jurisidiction to review the acts of the Secretary of Commerce
and Labor, or the acts of the Secretary of Labor, who now
has charge of said matter.</p>
<p>Wherefore, siad Ellis DeBruler prays the above entitled
Court that the said writ be dismissed and the application
and petition denied.</p>
<ab>C.F. Riddell
United States Attorney</ab>
<ab>EB Beakway
Assistant United States Attorney</ab>
<p>The United States of America
Western District of Washington
Northern Division } ss.</p>
<p>Ellis DeBruler, being first duly sworn, upon his oath
deposes and says; that he is the party named in the foregoing
Answer; that he has read the same, knows the contents thereof,
and verily believes the smae to be true.</p>
<ab>Ellis DeBruler</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 20th dat of April, 1913.</p>
<ab>Eden Larken
Deputy Clerk, U.S. Dist. Court, Western Dist. of Washington</ab>
<fw>7</fw>
<pb/>
<ab>2x No. <gap reason="blank"></gap></ab>
<p>In the District Court
of the United States
for the
Western District of Washington</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Marie Miler for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>Answer and Return
to Writ and Petition Therefor.></p>
<p>Filed in teh
U.S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington,
Apr 21 1913
Frank L. Crosby, Clerk,
by EMS Deputy.</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>