<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0463.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John McKinnon vs. The United States. Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weekly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weekly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0463.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">John McKinnon vs. The United States. Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1897-01-04">January 4, 1897</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1897-01">January 1897</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>O'Keefe, Cornelius</term>
<term>Ellison, Price</term>
<term>Parke, Harold R.</term>
<term>Emerson, Charles</term>
<term>Culey</term>
<term>Birnie</term>
<term>Pete, Frank</term>
<term>Crowell</term>
<term>Tronson, Edward</term>
<term>Bell, Samuel</term>
<term>Falkener, Quin</term>
<term>Young, Frank</term>
<term>Murk, Henry</term>
<term>Heron, William</term>
<term>Ireland, C. W.</term>
<term>Hopkins, R. M.</term>
<term>Kenyon, Arthur H.</term>
<term>Farr, H. L.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Spokane County, Washington</term>
<term>British Columbia, Canada</term>
<term>Canada</term>
<term>Yale, British Columbia</term>
<term>Vernon, British Columbia</term>
<term>Okanogah, British Columbia</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McKinnon, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>The United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Griswold, Gorman C.</persName>
<persName>Cotty, James L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Brinker, William H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Circuit Court of the United States 9th Judicial Circuit</orgName>
<placeName>District of Washington, Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2021-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<ab>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES
9TH. JUDICIAL CIRCUIT, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTION, <add>Northern</add> <del>Western</del> DIVISION.</ab>

<ab>In the Matter of the Application 
of
John McKinnon for a Writ of Habeas 
Corpus.</ab>

<p>To the Honorable C. H. Hanford, Judge of the Circuit
Court of the United States, 9th Judicial Circuit, District of
Washington, Western Division.</p>

<p>The petition of John McKinnon respectfully shows to 
your Honor:</p>

<p>1st. That the said petitioner is now and was at all times hereinafter alleged a citizen of the United States.</p>

<p>2nd. That the said petitioner is now a prisoner imprisoned and 
confined in the custody of the United States Marshall in and for
the district of Washington in the County Jail of Spokane County,
State of Washington.</p>

<p>3rd. That the cause or pretense of the restraint of the said
petitioner according to the best of his knowledge and belief
is that on or about the 25th day of August, 1895 in the District 
and County of Yale in the Province of British Columbia, one, 
Cornelius O'Keefe filed his complaint with Price Ellison a Magistrate
in and for said district and county, charging that the said
petitioner did on the 18th day of August, 1895, at or near Vernon
in the County of Yale, Province of British Columbia, steal four
neat cattle, property of him, the said Cornelius O'Keefe, which
said complaint together with the depositions and evidence offered
upon the hearing of said charge with the warrant of arrest and warrant of commitment therein, marked Exhibits A. B. C. and D.
is as follows, and is hereby made a part of this petition.</p>

<pb/>

<ab>Indictable Offences.</ab>

<ab>(A) Vide ss. 1 and 9.</ab>

<ab>Information and Complaint for an Indictable Offence.
Canada.
Province of British Columbia.
District or County of Yale.</ab>

<ab>"Exhibit A"</ab>

<p>THE INFORMATION and complaint of Cornelius O'Keefe of 
Okanogan taken twenty fourth day of August in the year of our
Lord One Thousand Eight hundred and ninety five before the undersigned 
of her Majesty's Justice in and for the said District of
County of Yale. who saith that John McKinnon on or about the 18th
day of August instant at or near Vernon in the County aforesaid 
four neat cattle of the goods and chattles of the said Cornelisu
O'Keefe did unlawfully did steal.</p>

<ab>C. O'Keefe.</ab>

<p>SWORN before me the day and year first above mentioned.</p>

<ab>Price Ellison.</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Indictable Offences.</ab>

<ab>(S) Section 590.</ab>

<ab>Deposition of a witness.</ab>

<ab>Canada

Province of British Columbia. County of Yale.</ab>

<ab>"Exhibit B"</ab>

<p>The deposition of H. R. Parke of Vernon taken
before the undersigned P. M. for the siad County of Yale this
24th day if August in the year 1895 at Vernon in the presence and 
hearing of John McKinnon who stands charged that upon or about
the 18th day of August instant, at Vernon in the District of Yale
for neat cattle of the goods and chattels of C. O'Keefe unlawfully 
did steal.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Harold R. Parke, sworn, saith:</p>

<p>I am Provincial Constable residing at the City of 
Vernon.</p>

<p>I produce a Hide-- On the evening of the twenty-third
of August instant I s w a portion of a hide projecting from under
John McKinnon's stable, the accused. I told Charles Emerson of the
hide being there.</p>

<p>The following morning Charles Emerson brought me a 
piece of paper with a drawing of the brand which he said was on
the hide I had told him about. I thought that it was Mrs. O'Keefe's
brand and told him to take O'Keefe with him to see the hide. A 
short time afterwards he, Charles Emerson and O'Keefe returned
bringing the hide produced with them (Exhibit A). Mr. O'Keefe
identified the brand on the hide produced as his brand, Mr. O'Keefe
then laid an information against John McKinnon and I arrested the
accused on the twenty fourth of August instant. After the arrest
I searched under McKinnon's stables and found two more hides. The
hide about to be produced is a reddish colored hide -- he ear cut
off -- The hide produced ("Exhibit B") I took out from under the
accused stables on the afternoon of the 24th day of August instant-
this hide has an indistinct brand on the left ribs resempling Mr.
O'Keefe's brand -- after that, still on the 24th day of August
instant, I went to the slaughter house where McKinnon, the accused
keeps his hides, and found one black hide branded with a triangle
on the left hip high up near the back bone, the top of the left
ear was cut off. I also found a small roan hide in the same place
with no brand on it that I could see, I also found a large red
and white hide with the ears cut off and left leg cutt off. These
last mentioned hides are now in my possession. On the 24th of August I also found in a cutter in the shed of 
<unclear>McKinnon</unclear></p>

<pb/>

<p>McKinnons a black calf without brand and head cut off -- I could 
discover no brands on the hides mentioned with the leg cut off.</p>

<p>Cross examined by Mr. Culey.</p>

<p>The brand on ("Exhibit B") resemples <gap></gap> this is on
the left ribs -- I believe this is a brand. When I saw a hide projecting
from under the stable I was climbing over the fence and not
more than ten feet way-- the floor of the stable was about two
feet from the ground. That side was hence all open. </p>

<p>From what I knew of Charles Emerson's occupation I
told him of the hide being in the stables.</p>

<p>It was about six o'clock in the evening when I saw the
hide. -- about an hour or an hour and one-half afterwards I told
Emerson. Charles Emerson told me that he was a detective. He has no
done detective wrok for me before.</p>

<p>I have not got the paper emerson showed me. I never had
it in my possession. The hide (Exhibit A) when I saw it might have
been eight or ten days killed. The reason I told Emerson of the
projecting hide was that there was a reward of $500. offered for 
convictions of cattle stealing. I did not wish to work for a reward
as I am paid by the Government for my work.</p>

<p>I did not notice any other brands besides the one
mentioned, on the black hide found at the slaughter house. I think
I have seen Charles Emerson around here three or four months.</p>

<ab>By the Bench.</ab>

<p>The front of the stable is level with the ground and 
the side the manure heap fills up, the third side is blocked up
by a vehicle shed and the side where I saw the hide projecting is
about eighteen inches from the Govement fence.</p>

<p>The Government fence separates the building from the
Gaul and Government Building.</p>

<pb/>

<p>During the last week I have croseed the fence three times a day. I
always cross that way when I want to get meals for prisoners.</p>

<p>This place is in full view of any one crossing the fence 
but one cannot see anything under the stable without getting down
and looking.</p>

<p>Sometimes for months I never cross at all. The fence
is so close to the stables that anyone could see nothing under the 
stable without squeezing between the fence and building and getting
down to look.</p>

<p>When I first <del/> saw the hide the greater porion was
under the stable and the rest looked as if it had been pulled out
by a dog.</p>

<p>When I first spoke to Charles Emerson I intended to
continue the investifation myself. I used Emerson as a means.</p>

<p>I dont know of my own knowledge that the hide brought
by Mr? O'Keefe and Emerson on Saturday to me was the same hide
I saw on Friday morning.</p>

<p>I have seen Charles Emerson behind the Counter in
Shooke's fruit store apparently working. I dont know of any other
occupation.</p>

<ab>H.R.Parke.</ab>

<pb/>

<p>Charles Emerson, sworn saith: I am a Lathier.</p>

<p>Last Friday Mr. Parke informed me of a hide being under
McKinnon's stables he said I might look after it. I told him I 
would. About nine o'clock that night I went to McKinnons stable
I found the hide, (Exhibit A) there under the stable. The side of
the stable facing the fence is open from the ground. The fence is
about two feet from the stables. The fence is over four feet
high. The hide was under the stable all but one corner. I would
not have noticed it if I had not bee looking for it. I pulled the
hide out and started toward the sidewalk with it in my hand
In the morning of the 24th instant I examined the hide. after I
scraped off the hair I found a brand on it similar to the
There was an ear mark one ear was split. The other ear was not on
the hide. I left the hide in the brush behind the victoria stable
about five hours afterwards I took Mr. O'Keefe to see it. It was
in the same place where I had left it. I showed it to Mr. O'Keefe.
He said he would bring his rig and take the hide to the Jout House.
He did so. I saw the hide again on the 24th and again on the 25th.
I brought an hide into court this morning.</p>

<p>Const. Parke and myself found some more hides in a shed at 
McKinnons slaughter house between Vernon and Okanogah Lake. We fon
three hides. I found a brand on the Balck hide it was a triangle
The second hide was a roan hide. Could see not brand on it. The
third hide was a red and white. Could not see any brand or Marks
on it. These hides were sent to the Government house in an express
wagon. When I showed Mr. O'Keefe the hide exhibit A he said it was
his brand on it.</p>

<p>xd. When parke met me, he said good night. Then 
he said there was a hide under McKinnons stables. He said it might</p>

<pb/>

<p>pay me to look after it. I asked him whereabouts was under the
stable. He told me that it was near the southwest corner. It was
between half past six and seven or later. After I left Parke I
walked around town. I was in Hurks Barber shop part of the time. 
I did not say anything to Murk about what Parke had told me. I 
have been staying at Murks during the past week. I was also
in Davidsons fruit store and was about the street the rest of the
time until nine o'clock. It was dark at 9 o'clock just after
Parke informed me I walked past the place and saw that the hide
was there. When I went at nine o'clock for the hide I left it half 
way between the sidewalk and McKinnons shop. I wnet to the side-
walk as I saw a man there watching me. it was Mr. Birnie. He asked
me what I was doing there. I told him that I was taking a hide
out of there. I intended taking the hide to the brush. I was
scared the man on the sidewalk might say something about it. It 
was old Mr. Birnie-- after I spoke with Birnie I went back to the
hide and took it to the brush. I did not meet anyone else. I did
not tell anyone else that night what I had been doing. the hide
was not tied up. I saw Mr. Haron that night. he is night watchman. I
told him about the hide early Saturday morning. I told him about
taking the hide and asked him to come and see it after daylight. I
did not tell him what brand was on it as I had not seen it there. I 
told him I had not seen it there. I told him that I had left it
in the brush. Last a Wednesday night I slept either at Murks or
my own shack. I think I slept at Murks on Tuesday night. I remember
now I slept at Murks up to Friday night. I know a Half Breed named
Frank Pete. I saw him the say Smart was tried. in the afternoon.
it was nearly six. I saw him afterwards about eight o'clock, he
called me out of Davidsons. He was riding, he wanted me on business
he told me that there was counterfeit money among the six here.
He said he would be in Friday nights again. I saw him about four</p>

<pb/>

<p>o'clock on Friday. I am a detective. I have had experience on one
occasion. I have done detective work in the state before. I joined
the detective association. I have been in Vernon two years. I have
worked for Mr. Crowell. I have worked in Kelowna and Enderby.
I worked for Judge Spinks. I have had no permenent occupation
during the two years. there has not been enough lathing. I do not
know a siwash or half breed named Victor. I saw some siwashes on 
Friday night. The only one I saw at the Coral was Pete. There
were some whitemen strolling around. I took a walk with a white man
at the corral on Friday night. He left me with Pete, I saw Pete
twice that day. I did not say anything to Pete or Victor or any
siwash about the McKinnon business. </p>

<ab>C. EMERSON. </ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Edward Tronson sworn saith:</ab>

<p>I do not think I brought a calf to McKinnons shop.
I was in Vernon on Thursday last. Aleck an Indain boy was with
me we came in a wagon there was no calf in the wagon.</p>

<ab>Edward Tronson.</ab>

<p>Samuel Bell sworn saith: I am a Butcher I work for John McKinnon
I remember last thursday I received a small black calf from
Edward Trosson, the last witness on that night at McKinnons shop
I have once or twice helped him to kill. I have worked for him for
six months. I generally do the killing for McKinnon, Once or twice
I got Joe Mosgrove to help me, I find the cattle in the corral
at the slaughter house and I kill them. McKinnon generally puts
the cattle in the corral. I put the hides in the hide house and sat
them. I killed up to about a months or six weeks back. McKinnon has
done the killing since then. I have helped him once or twice.
Joe Mosgrove and Jerry Mosgrove have helped to kill. We have very
little veal in the shop. The last was on Thursday. There have been
several calves brought into McKinnons shop since I have worked there
McKinnon brought them in except one I got from Sluckey and one I 
got from Parrette. I do not know where McKinnon got them. I do not 
know exactly the number of cattle used by McKinnon since I have 
been with him. We got twenty four or twenty six from Frank Young
four from Quin Falkener and four or five from White valley?. These
are all the cattle that I know of being purchased. I commenced to
kill Frank Youngs cattle as soon as they were driven over here. I 
did not notice the brands of any cattle killed by me. I did not
bring any hides from the slaughter house up here. I never knew of
<unclear/></p>

<pb/>

<p>McKinnon's doing so. I received the calf from Edward Tronson at
the Butcher shop at 9 o'clock on Thursday night. he took it out of
the wagon. he did not say where he had got it. An Indian boy was 
with him. McKinnon always sent me down to kill the cattle were in
the corrals the corals are on Tronsons ranch. Nomone kills there
but McKinnon. He has the use of them. To my knowledge McKinnon puts
the cattle into the corral where when I kill, I kill what I think
is required for the shop. I leave what I do not want in the corral. McKinnon uses the hide house. It is used for putting the
hides in after they are killed. I killed with McKinnon on the 23rd inst. I helped McKinnon kill on the 14th inst. one Beef. It was a
red and white animal. I did not notice any brands. The animal was a heifer. I do not know where she came from. The skin was put in
the hide. It was a black animal killed on the 23rd it had a triangle 
brand near the rump bone. That skin was also put in the hide
house. I do not remember when we last killed before the 14th. We
never kill at the shop, never have any skins at the shop except the
veal skins. I have not noticed any hides about the premises. I did
not know of any hides being under the stables. I sleep in the
shop. McKinnon does not sleep in the shop.</p>

<p>xd. I am not familiar with brands, do not as a 
rule take notice of them. The hide house is not kept locked, anybody
can go in that likes, the stable is not fenced in, anyone can go
in there that likes. I could not say whether an average man could
go easily between the fence and stable. I never tried to get through
Anone passing the corral can see if there are cattle there.</p>

<ab>S. C. Bell.</ab> 

<pb/>

<p>Cornelius O'Keef sworn, saith: I am a framer and stock raiser. I 
live seven miles from Vernon. I saw the hides Exhibits A. and B.
has my brand on it in two places, on the ribw and on the hip. I 
have no other brand that s some cattle have it on once and some
of them twice. I have not disposed of any cattle for about two 
months I then sold four hundred head to Graves of Douglas Lake.
Theynwere delivered to him and taken away. they were not 
they were drivinm out at once. I did not sell any cattle to 
McKinnon. I have not been out amongst the cattle lately and cannot
tell if any are missing. I saw Emerson on Saturday mornng. He 
asked me if I ahd missed any cattle. I told him I did not know. He
took me to see a Hide in the brush below the Victoria Hotal and
tthe crack about half way down. The Hide I saw had my brand upon 
it. I first saw hide marked Exhibit b this morning in posessio
of the Govt. Agent. The Hides exhibits "A" and "B" are mine. The
reason that I have not missed any cattle is that I have not been to
round them up. I have not rounded any cattle up within the last six
months. Last Fall when Imrounded up I missed cattle and calves. 
When I rounded up before that I missed cattle. I dont know how 
many.</p>

<p>I cannot say whether the cattle I missed were stolen or 
not. The calves ought to be there. I knew the calves were there
when I branded them. I cannot account for their disappearance.</p>

<p>It would be a strange thing if the calves died. There
was no desease amonth them. From my knowledge on the range I cannot
say whether any were <del/> stolen or not. I cannot account for
their disappearance in any other way that their being stoloen; Why
I cannot swear that they were stolen is because I did not see any
one steal them.</p>

<pb/>

<p>xd. I think that I can safely swear that the
Exhibits "A" and "B" are not Graves hides, because Graves would
not allow the brand to be vented or the cattle rebranded as he
intended to market them at Victoria this summer. I do not know
whther he marketed them or not. Im delivered the cattle to Graves
at my corral I could not swear that he took them to Douglas Lake.
The last I saw of them they were about one mile from my Corral and 
going very well. I do not know whether Graves lost any I do not 
know if he sold any of them in this part of the country. I kill
what I require for my own use during the year. I have the hides
up at my own place. They are not kept under lock and key. I do not
know whether it is the custom to keep hide houses locked up. I hav
known the calf crop to come to my expectations. I do not knowthat
cayotes and wolves are hard on the calf crop in this country. I
do not know <del/> that I have lost cattle by poison during the
last two months. I lost some early in the Spring from that cause.
Sometimes a few of my cattle range as far as the mission. I lost 
eight or ten head in the spring from poison by wild parsnips.
A plant that killed some might have killed more if they would eat
it. I can only sweat to the two hides I have identified as bearing
my brand. Exhibit A I first saw in the brush below the Victoria
Hotel Exhibit B I first saw in the Government yard here -- I traced
one of the hides to McKinnon by Emerson from what he told me the
other, Exhibit B, by what Parke and Emerson told me.</p>

<p>Re. Exd. Several cattle are stolen from me each
year calves particularly. I suspected some one of stealing them.
I suspect some people more than others. The poisoner is among
those I suspect. The cattle only eat the wild parsnips just after
the snow goes off. In former years my cattle tan over the same 
range as they do now. I have noticed a marked decrease of the number

<pb/>

that should have come in during the past two years.</p>

<p>By McCayley, the number of people of people I suspect
is not large.</p>

<ab>C. O'Keefe.</ab>

<p>Henry Murk sworn, saith: I live in Vernon I am a Barber
I know Charles Emerson. I have heard that he gave evidence in this
case. He has lived at my place of an on for about three weeks. 
I do not know how he came there. I used to think jhe was one of the
unfortunates and could not get work, I never offered him work. My
brother offered him work in, my presence. He said he did not want
it. Emerson spoke to me two weeks ago last Monday night about making
$500. out of Jack McKinnon. I fix the date by a lecture I
attended with Emerson. I took a walk with him Monday before McKinnon
was arrested when we came to Jirouard's bridge we met a
half breed on horseback. The Indian made a sign and Emerson went
and spoke to him for a short time. I asked him what he was after.
We went to the coral. Emerson wanted to get his horse. He did not
get it. He went into the corral he did not meet any one there that
I am aware of. Last Monday week Emerson slept at my place. One
night, either Tuesday or Wednesday he did not sleep at my place. 
He did not sleep there on Thursday night. I told him to get other
quarters.</p>

<p>xd. I have known Emerson for three we weeks or a 
month.</p>

<ab>Henry Murk.</ab>

<p>William Nero n sworn saith: I am constable and night watchman in
Vernon, I met Emerson last Friday night about 11 o'clock P. M. he 
told me that he thought he had caught McKinnon. I asked him how
that was. He told me that he had found a hide under McKinnons'
stable; he said he had taken it over into the brush to inspect the

<pb/>

brand. He wished me to go with him to, see it. I told him I thought
it was a case for the Provincial Authorities to look after. I did
not wish to get mixed up with it. I saw him again about 5 o'clock
on Saturday morning. he was then going to where he had the hide. I 
have known Emerson by sight for over a year.</p>

<ab>William Heron.</ab>

<p>The above depositions of H. R. Parke, Charles Emerson, Edward
Tronson, S. C. Bell, C. O'Keefe, Henry Murke and William Heron on
the day and year first above mentioned at Vernon in the District
of Yale before me, C. W. Ireland, Police Magistrate for the City of 
Vernon aforesaid.</p>

<ab>(SEAL)</ab>

<ab>C. W. Ireland, P. M. (</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Indictable Offences.</ab>

<ab>(T) Section 591.</ab>

<ab>Statement of the Accused.

Canada.

Province of British Columbia.
County of Yale.</ab>

<p>John McKinnon stands charged before the under
signed a Stipindary Magistrate in and for the County aforesaid
this 24th day of August, in the year 1895 for that the said
John McKinnon on the 18th day of Aug, 1895 at Vernon in the County
of Yale four neat cattle of the goods and chattles of C. O'Keefe
unlawfully did steal. and the said charge being read, to the said
John McKinnon and the witnesses for the prosecution H. R. Parke,
C. O'Keefe and others being severally examined in his presence the 
said John McKinnon is now adressed by me as follows: - </p>

<p>Having heard the evidence do wyou wish to say anything
in answer to the charge: You are not obliged to say anything unless
you desire to do so; but whatever you say will be taken down in
writing, and any be given in evidence against you at your trial. 
You must clearly understand that you have nothing to hope from any
promise of favor, and nothing to fear from any threat which, may
have been helf out to induce you to make any admission or confession 
of guilt, but whatever you may now say may be given in evidence
against you upon your trial, notwithstanding such promise
or treat.</p>

<p>Whereupon the said John McKinnon says as follows --
I know nothing about the hides that were found under my
stable. They were not put there by me nor anybody that I know of. </p>

<ab>John McKinnon</ab>

<p>Taken before me at Vernon the day and year first above mentioned.</p>

<ab>C. W. Ireland, J. P.</ab>

<ab>(SEAL)</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Indictable Offences.</ab>

<ab>(T 1) Sec s. 56.</ab>

<ab>Warrant of Commitment.

Canada.

Province of British Columbia. 
District of County of Yale.</ab>

<ab>Exhibit C</ab>

<p>To all or any of the Constables, or other Peace Officers, 
in the District or County of Yale and to the Keeper of the
Common Gaol of the District or County of Yale at Kamloops in the
District or County of Yale.</p>

<p>WHEREAS John McKinnon was this day charged before
C. W. Ireland one of her majesty's Justices of the Peace in and for
the said District of County of Yale, on the oath of Cornelius O'
Keege and others, for that John McKinnon on or about the 18th day
of August 1895 at or near Vernon in the county aforesaid, four neat
cattle of the goods and chattels of Cornelius O'Keefe unlawfully
did steal.</p>

<p>These are therefore to command you, the said Constable
or Peace Officers, or any of you, to take the said John McKinnon,
and him safely convey to the Common Gaol at Kamlooks aforesaid and
there deliver him to the keeper thereof, together with this Precept
And I do hereby command you, the said Keeper of the Common Gaol, to
receive the said John McKinnon into your custody in the said
Common gaol, and there safely to keep him until he shall thence
be delievered by one course of law.</p>

<p>Given under my hand and Seal this thirteenth day of
August, in the year of our Lord One Thousand Eight Hundred and
ninety five, at Vernon, in the District or County aforesaid.</p>

<ab>C. W. Ireland, P. M.</ab>

<ab>(SEAL)</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>(F) Section 563.</ab>

<ab>Warrant in the First Instance to apprehend a person
charged with an Indictable Offence.</ab>

<ab>Canada.

Province of British Columbia.
County of Yale.</ab>

<ab>Exhibit D</ab>

<p>To all and any of the Constables and other Peace
Officers in the said County of Yale.</p>

<p>WHEREAS, John McKinnon of Vernon has this day been
charged, upon oath before me the undersigned Price <del/>
Ellison a stipindary Magistrate and for the said County of Yale
for that he on the 18th <del/> instant at Vernon in the County
aforesaid one cow of the goods and chattels of the said Cornelius
O'Keefe unlawfully did steal.</p>

<p>These are therefore to command you, in her Majesty's 
name forthwith to apprehend the said John McKinnon and to bring him
before one (or some other Justice of the Peace in and for the said
County of Yale) to answer unto the said charge, and to be further
dealt with according to law.</p>

<p>Given under my hand and seal this 24th day of August,
in the year one thousand eight hundred and ninety five at Vernon
in the County aforesaid.</p>

<ab>Price Ellison. S. M. (SEAL)</ab>

<pb/>

<p>4th. That on the 22nd day of December, 1896 one, E. C.
Simmons, made and filed with A. H. <del/> Kenyon, Commissioner
of the Circuit Court of the United States in the District of 
Washington, his complaint in writing, a copy of which said complaint 
is as follows and marked Exhibit E and made a part hereof: </p>


<pb/>

<ab>United States of America
District of Washington,
City of Spokane.</ab>

<ab>ss.</ab>

<ab>Exhibit E</ab>

<p>Before me,, A. H. Kenyon, a commissioner of the
Circuit Court of the United States for the District of Washington
personally appeared this day E. C. Simmons who being first duly
sworn on his oath deposes and says: that on or about the 18th day 
of August, 1895 near Vernon in the county of Yale, Province of
British Columbia in the Dominion of Canada, one, John McKinnon
did unlawfully commit the crime of larceny, by then and there
unlawfully, wilfully and feloniously stealing, taking and carrying
away four neat cattle of the value of Fifty Dollars the goods and
chattels of one Cornelius O'Keefe, contrary to the laws of said
Province of British Columbia.</p>

<p>And affiant prays that said John McKinnon be apprehended
and committed and that he be extradited to said Province of
British Columbia for trials as provided by laws and the convention
existing between the United States and Great Britain for the extra-
dition of person charged with crime. </p>

<ab>E. C. Simmons.</ab>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 22nd day of December, 1896.</p>

<ab>(SEAL).</ab>

<ab>A. H. Kenyon,
Commissioner of the Circuit Court 
of the United States for the 
District of Washington.</ab>

<pb/>

<p>And thereupon the said Arthur H. Kenyon as said commissioner
issued and delivered to the Marshal of the United States for
the district of Washington a warrant for the arrest and apprehension
of the said petitioner, which said warrant is as follows,
Marked Exhibit F. and made a part of this petition. </p>

<pb/>

<ab><unclear>Exhibit F</unclear></ab>

<ab>THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.</ab>

<ab>To the Marshall of the United States for the District
of Washington, and to his deputies, or any or either of them:</ab>

<p>WHEREAS, E. C. Simmons has made complaint in writing before,
the undersigned Commissioner of the Circuit Court of the United 
States for the District of Wash. charging that John McKinnon 
late of Yale County in the Province of British Columbia in the
minion of Canada did, on or about the 18th day of August A. D.
895 near Vernon in said County of Yale aforesaid in violation of
the laws of said Province, unlawfully, willfully and feloniously
commit the crime of larceny by then and there unlawfully, wilfully
and feloniously stealing, taking and carrying away four meat cattle
of the value of Fifty Dollars, the goods and chattels then and 
there of one, Cornelius O'Keefe, Contrary to the laws of said
rovince of B. C.</p>

<p>And affiant <del/> further prays that the said John Mcinon 
be apprehended and committed and that he be extradited to 
said Province of British Columbia for trial as provided by law
and the convention existing between the United States and Great
ritain for the extradition of persons charged with crime.</p>

<p>Now, therefore, you are hereby commanded, in the name
of the President of the United States of America, to apprehend the
said John McKinnon wherevore found in your District and bring his
ody forthwith before me or any other Commissioner having jursidiction 
of said matter, to answer said complaing, that he may then and
there be delt with according to law for said offense.</p>

<p>Given under my hand and seal this 22nd day of December, A..
1896.</p>

<ab>A.H. Kenyon (SEAL)</ab>

<ab>Commissioner of the Circuit Court
of the United States for the Distrt
of Wash.</ab>

<ab>Approved (SEAL)
United States Attorney. </ab>

<pb/>

<p>That on the 23rd day of December, 1896 the said petitioner
was by the United States Marshal brought before the said Arthur H.
Kenyon as said Commissioner, Whereupon the said petitioner appeared
in person and by his attorneys and the said petitioner by
his attorneys filed with the said Arthur H. Kenyon his demurer
and objections to the said affidavit and complaint of the said
E. C. Simmons, which said demurer and objections is as follows,
Marked Exhibit G. and made a part of this petition:</p>

<pb/>

<ab>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, EASTERN DIVISION,</ab>

<ab>before Arthur H. Kenyon, United States

Commissioner of the said Circuit Court.</ab>

<ab>The United States, Plaintiff,
-versus-
John McKinnon, Defendant. </ab>

<p>Comes now the above named defendant by his attorneys,
Corman L. Griswold and James E. Fenton and demurs to the affidavit
and complaing made by E. C. Simmons and filed with this Court on
December 22, 1896 and for grounds of said demurrer alleges:</p>

<p>1. If said affidavit and complaint does not charge the
said defendant with having committed within the jurisdiction of
the Province of British Columbia in the Dominion of Canada or
within the jurisdiction of Great Britain and crime provided for or
specified in the treaty between the United States and the Province
of British Columbia in the Dominion of Canada or Great Britain.</p>

<p>2. The said Arthur H. Kenyon as said United States Commisioner 
had no jurisdiction whatever to issue any warrant in this 
cause for the arrest of the said defendant and has no jurisdiction
whatever to hear or determine this cause in that, the <del/> crime alleged 
in the said affidavit is not one of the crimes mentioned in
the traeaty now existing between the United States and Great
ritain for the extradition of <add><unclear>fugitives</unclear> from</add> justice and is now an extraditable
offense. and in that said Dft is now in custody of the Chief of 
Police at <unclear>Spokane</unclear> Wash pending a <unclear>hearing</unclear> <unclear>why</unclear>
a writ of habeas corpus served and <unclear> why the</unclear> <unclear></unclear> Court
<unclear></unclear></p>

<p>3. That the said affidavit and complaint does not state
facts sufficient to constitute a crime against the laws of the
rovince of British Columbia in the Dominion of Canada or against
the laws of the State of Washington or of the United States and doe
not state facts sufficient to give <del/> the said commisioners court
urisdiction to issue a warrant herein or try and hear said cause
in that:</p>

<pb/>

<p>(a) it does not appear upon the face of the said affidavit or
complaing that the said E. C. Simmons who made and assigned the
said affidavit and complaint was or is an agent or representative 
of the Province of British Columbia, Dominion of Canada or of
reat Britain and in that:</p>

<p>(b) it does not appear upon the face of said complaint or
affidavit that the offense charged therein and a claim against
the laws of the Province of B. C. in the Dominion of Canada or
Great Britain and in that it does not appear upon the vace of the
said complaing and affidavit that the said Arthur H. Kenyon has
been authorized by any court of the United States to issue a 
warrant under the provisions of title 66 of the revised statues
of the United States of 1878, or that he <del/> the said Arthur H. Kenyon
has any authority to act in such proceedings and it <del/> us
does not appear upon the face of the warrant issued herein that the
said Arthur H. Kenyon has been authorized to act in this or similar
proceedings.</p>

<ab>James L. Cotty
Atty for Defendent

<del>Norman <unclear/></del>
and <del>James E Fenton</del>
Attorneys for Defendant. </ab>

<pb/>

<p>Whereupon the said Arthur H. Kenyon as said commissioner
overruled the said demurrer and the following proceedings were 
thereupon had before him, the said commissioner, a copy of
which said proceedings marked Exhibit H is as follows and made a 
part of this petition:</p>

<pb/>

<ab>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE <add>United</add> STATES <del>OF WASHINGTON.</del>
District of Washington</ab>

<ab>Before A. H Kenyon
Commissioner</ab>

<ab>United States, Plaintiff,
-vs-
John McKinnon, Defendant.</ab>

<p>Now at this time, December 23rd, 
1896, this cause coming on to be heard Arthur H. Kenyon, commissioner 
of the Circuit Court of the United States, District of
Washington, eastern division, and defendant herein having filed
a demurrer to the affidavit of plaintiff and the court having 
heard the <del/> the arguments and duly considered the same,
overrules said demurrer to which ruling of court duly accepted,
whereupon <del>the</del> E. C. Simmons <add>was</add> sworn to testify, whereupon the
defendant objected to any testimony being offered in this cause
on the gound that this court was no jurisdiction to hear or determine 
the same and on the further gorund that the offense charged
in the affidavit is not an extraditable offense in the treaty now
existing between the United States and Great Britain which objection 
is overruled; said E. C. Simmons testified the <del> position
to object and offered the objections thereto</del> 
as follows</p>

<p>Question. What Official position, if any, do you hold in the 
Province of British Columbia?</p>

<p>Answer. Provincial Constable of the Province of
British Columbia. </p>

<p>Question. Have you any special authority from the Government
of British Columbia to make <del>or testify in this</del> Complaint
case wherein John McKinnon is defendant?</p>

<p>Answer. I have the authority of my superior</p>

<p>Question. Who is he?</p>

<p>Answer. F. S. Huzzy</p>

<p>Question. What official position does he hold?</p>

<p>Answer. Suprentendant oof the Province of British
Columbia.
his duty the demand the</p>

<p>Question. Is it a duty or demand
<unclear></unclear>

<pb/>

surrender fugitives from Justice?</p>

<p>Answer. Yes Sir.</p>

<p>Question. What authority have you from British Columbia?</p>

<p>Answer. Authority by telegram.</p>

<p>Question. Authorized you to <add>do</add> what?</p>

<p>Answer. Authorized me to take necessary measures to
arrest John McKinnon.</p>

<p>Question. Do you know John McKinnon?</p>

<p>Answer. Yes Sir.</p>

<p>Question. How long?</p>

<p>Answer. Four years.</p>

<p>Answer. Do you know the John McKinnon who was tried before
Price Ellison, Stipendary Majestrate in the
District of Yale, Province of British Columbia</p>

<p>Answer. Yes, personally. Was well acquainted with him
for the last four years.</p>

<p>Look at those papers.</p>

<p>Questions. What papers are those?</p>

<p>Answer. No. one is the information and complaint for
the arrest of defendant.</p>

<p>Question. Made before whom?</p>

<p>Answer. Made before Price Ellison.</p>

<p>Question. On what day?</p>

<p>Answer. On the 18th day of August, instant.</p>

<p>Question. By whom was that complaint made?</p>

<p>Answer. Cornelius O'Keefe.</p>

<p>Question. Charged with what offense?</p>

<p>Answer. Charging the said John McKinnon with stealing cattle</p>

<p>Question. No two, what is that?</p>

<p>Answer. Deposition of a witness.</p>

<p>Question? What witness.?</p>

<p>Answer. H. L. Farr.</p>

<p>Question. Taken by this same Magistrate?</p>

<p>Answer. No, before C. W. Ireland.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Question. What is his position.</p>

<p>Answer. Police Magistrate.</p>

<p>Question. That is the original deposition, is it?</p>

<p>Answer. Yes Sir. </p>

<p>Question. And the next paper, what is that?</p>

<p>Answer. The deposition of Harold R. Parke.</p>

<p>Question Taken before whom?</p>

<p>Answer. C. W. Irelan, Police Magistrate.</p>

<p>Question. And the fourth paper, what is that?</p>

<p>Answer. The deposition of Charles Emerson.</p>

<p>Question. Taken before whom?</p>

<p>Answer. S. W. Arthur, Police Magistrate.</p>

<p>Question. And the fifth paper, what is that?</p>

<p>Answer. The deposition of Edward Tronson.</p>

<p>Question. Taken before whom?</p>

<p>Answer. C. W. Ireland, Police Magistrate.</p>

<p>Question. And Number Six?</p>

<p>Answer Deposition of Samuel Bell.</p>

<p>Question. Taken before whom?</p>

<p>Answer. Taken before C. W. Ireland, Police Magistrate</p>

<p>Question. No. Seven?</p>

<p>Answer. /Deposition of Cornelius O'Keefe.</p>

<p>Question. Taken before whom?</p>

<p>Answer. Taken before C. W. Ireland, Police Magistrate.</p>

<p>Question. No. Eight.</p>

<p>Answer. Deposition of Henry Mark.</p>

<p>Question. Taken before whom?</p>

<p>Answer. Taken before C. W. Ireland, Police Magistrate.</p>

<p>Question. No. Nine</p>

<p>Answer. The depostion of William Heron. </p>

<p>Answer. Taken before whom?</p>

<pb/>

<p><del/></p>

<p>Answer. Taken before C. W. Ireland.</p>

<p>Question. What is the next paper?</p>

<p>Answer. Statement of the accused.</p>

<p>Question. Taken before whom?</p>

<p>Answer. Taken before C. W. Ireland, Police Magistrate.</p>

<p>Question. And the 11th paper.?</p>

<p>Answer. Warrant of Commitment.</p>

<p>Question. Issued by whom?</p>

<p>Answer. C. W. Ireland, Police Magistrate.</p>

<p>Question. No. Twelve.</p>

<p>Answer. Warrant in the First Instance o apprehend a 
person charged with and Indictable Offence.</p>

<p>Question. Taken before whom?</p>

<p>Answer. Taken before C. W. Ireland, Police Magistrate
These papers will be marked Number 1, 2, 3 - - down to 12 and 
they will be offered in evidence of John McKinnon. These are the 
originals from the Stpindary Magistrates Court of the Province of 
British Columbia, District of Yale.</p>

<p>The defendant objects to the introduction of either of
the papers marked respectively i, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 
and 12 on the ground that neither of the said papers testifyied
to by the <del>warrants</del> witness are properly authenticated so as to be admitable
as evidence in any court in the Province of British Columbia and
on the furthe ground that neither of said papers are admissable
as evidence in any court of the United States and <del/></p>

<p>Question. Are these the original papers and records of tha
court in the trial of McKinnon for the charge of larceny.?</p>

<p>Answer. Yes Sir.</p>

<p>Question. Do you know whether or not that those papers, those

<pb/>

those originals, are admisable as evidence in the Courts of
ritish Columbia.</p>

<p>Answer. Certainly.</p>

<p>Question. Are they admissable?</p>

<p>Answer. Yes Sir.</p>

<p>The defendants <del/> renew the objections above
set out as to the admission of each aof the papers testified to 
and make the additional objection as appears upon the face of the
papers that the defendant, John McKinnon is charged with the
crime of cattle stealing and charged with a crime not
extraditable in the treaty between <del>with</del> this Country and <del/>
Great Britain.</p>

<p>The objections are overuled.</p>

<p>The defendant excepts to the filing of the court <del>that the papers are
extraditable</del> <add><unclear>admitted this and with permission</unclear></add> and the commissioner <del>of the office</del> to withdraw them
when the proper certified copies should have been taken.</p>

<p>Question. How do you know that those papers could be offered
as evidence in all criminal cases in British Columbia.</p>

<p>Answer. Because they are. The deposition taken in the
first instances are evidence. It is not necessary
to recall a witness. They do it, if near at hand 
but it is not necessary.</p>

<p>Question. Do you use a deposition as evidence when the defendant 
is away.</p>

<p>Answer. Sometimes, yes sir, But it is not necessary. </p>

<p>The defendant now moves that he be discharged from the
custody of the Marshal and this proceedings be dismissed against
him on the ground that the offence charged <add>in</add> said affidavit and the
<del/> <del>report of the</del> documental evidence shows <del>and</del> the crime of cattle
stealing and is not an offence or crime extraditable between the
United States and Great Britain and on the additional ground 
<del>that no authority hsa been shown <unclear/></del></p>

<pb/>

<p>That it does not appear that the person who made the 
affidavit is agent <del>or authority</del> or any agent 
or party authorized to make a complaint in extradition cases and in
that the defendant is now in custody of the Chief of Police of
Spokane awaiting the hearing of a writ of Habeas Corpus issued
out of the Superior Court of Spokane County, Washington and in
custody under the process of the court. The defendant offers 
evidence the petition ordered for a <del></del> return and
writ of Habeas Corpus filed and issued out of the Superior
Court of Spokane County, Washington, marked (Defendants Exhibit "A)
. C").</p>

<ab>Motion.</ab>

<p>The Motion is overuled and upon the ground of the
motion with reference to the writ of Habeas Corpus. The motion
is overuled upon that ground for the reason that the court is
informed by one of the Police Officers under the Chief of Police
refered to that said Chief of Police is now holding the said
prisoner at the instance of the Province of British Columbia and
is a fugative from Justice and that he makes no resistance to the
application for his discharge by a writ of "Habeas Corpus."</p>

<pb/>

<p>That the said John McKinnon is now restrained of his liberty
in the County Jail of Spokane County, Washington, illegally,
by the said United States Marshal and <del>is</del> his said imprisonment is
illegal in this: that the said affidavit and complaint herein,
Marked Exhibit E does not charge the said petitioner with having
committed within the jurisdiction if the Province of British
Columbia in the Dominion of Canada, ot within the jursidiction
of Great Britain any crime provided for or specified in the rtreaty
between the United States and the Province of British Columbia in
the Dominion of Canada, or of Great Britain, and in this that the
said Arthur H. Kenyon as said United States commissioner had no 
jurisdiction whatever to issue any warrant in this cause for
the arrest of the said petitioner and had no jurisdiction whatever
to hear or determine said cause, in that the crime alleged in the 
said affidavit, marked Exhibit E and the crime alleged in the
complaint made by the said Cornelis O'Keefe marked Exhibit A and
upon which the said petitioner was examined before the said Magistrate
in the said District of Yale, is not one of the crimes mentioned 
in the treaty now existing between the United States and
Great Britain for the extradition of fugitives from justice and
is not an extraditble offence; and in that neither the said complaint
of the said Cornelius O'Keefe, marked Exhibit A. nor the 
said affidavit of the said E. C. Simmons, marked Exhibit E states 
facts sufficient to constitute a crime against the laws in the 
Province of British Colubmia in the Domion of Canada or of the
laws of the States of Washington or of the United States, and
neither of the said complaints state facts sufficient to give the
said commissioners Court jurisdiction to issue a warrant therein
or to try and hear said cause, in that that it does not appear upon
the face of the said affidavit of the said E. C. Simmons, Marked,
Exhibit E that the said E. C. Simmons, who made and signed the 
said affidavit was or is an agent or representative of the Province
of British Columbia in the Dominion of Canada or of Great 
Britain: and in that it does not appear from the said complaint,
Marked Exhibit A. that the said Arthur H. Kenyon has been author-
ized by any court of the United States to issue a warrant under
the provisions of title 66 <del>in the</del> Revised Statues of the United
States, 1878 or that the said Arthur H. Kenyon had any authority
to act in such proceedings and the said petitioner alleges that the 
said Arthur H. Kenyon acted without any authority of jurisdiction
in said matter and that all the proceedings before him were and
are void: that the said petitioner is restrained and has been 
deprived of his liberty without due process of law and in violaiton 
of the Constiturtion of the United States and <add></add> Great Britain
for the extradition of fugitives from justice.</p>

<p>Wherefore your said petitioner prays that a writ of
Habeas Corpus may be granted to him directed to the United States
Marshal for the District of Washington, demanding him, the said
Marshal to have and produce the body of the said petitioner before 
this Honorable Court at a time and place in said writ specified,,
to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by your
Honor, concerning the said petition together with the time and
cause of detainment of the said petitioner and have then and there 
the said writ, and that your said petitioner may be restored to
his liberty and discharged from custody.</p>

<ab>James L Cotty
Atty for Petitioner</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Thae State of Washington,
County of Spokane.</ab>

<ab>ss.</ab>

<ab>I, John McKinnon, being duly sworn say that I 
<del>being duly sworn</del> am the petitioner above named: that I have
read the foregoing petition, know the contents thereof and the
allegations and statements therein contained, and the same are
true I verily believe.</ab>

<ab>John McKinnon</ab>

<ab>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 4th day of January, 1897.</ab>

<ab><unclear></unclear> N. Magnix</ab>

<ab>Notary Public in and for the State of
Washington, residing at Spokane,
Washington.</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>593. </ab>

<ab>Tx</ab>

<ab>No. 1062</ab>

<ab>In the United States
Circuit Court
FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</ab>

<ab>In the matter of the application
of John McKinnon
for 
a writ of Habeas Corpus</ab>

<ab>Petition for writ
of Habeas Corpus</ab>

<ab>Filed Jan. 14 1897
IN THE 
U.S. DISTRICT COURT.</ab>

<ab>R. M. Hopkins
CLERK.</ab>

<ab>By H M Walker.</ab>

<ab>Jas. L Cotty</ab>

<ab>Attorney for Petitioner</ab>

<ab>Filed Jan. 14 1897
IN THE
U.S. CIRCUIT COURT.
A. Reeves Ayres.
CLERK.</ab>

<ab>By H. M. Walther.
DEPUTY</ab>

<pb/>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>