<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Territory of Washington
County of Spokane}ss
To the honorable George 
Turner Judge of the Fourth Judicial
District of the Territory of Washington:
Your petitioner
William C. Swartz, would respectfully
represent to your honor that he is restrained 
of his liberty by E.F. Whittier the sheriff of
said county in the jail of said county
at the town of Cheney in the county and
Territory aforesaid.
That the cause or pretext of such restraint
is as follows to wit: On the 8th day of July
A.D. 1885, your petitioner was arrested under
a warrant issued by O.F. Wood Esq. one of
the Justices of the Peace in and for said
County of Spokane, on the complaint of
one A. Reading charging your
petitioner was thereafter brought before said
Justice of the Peace and an examination
into the guilt or innocence of your
petitioner of said charge, was had on the
9th day of July A.D. 1885, that on such
examination said Justice of the Peace
held your petitioner to bail in the sum
of five hundred dollars; that yor peti-
tioner was unable to give bail in said
amount, whereas upon he was committed
to the custody of said sheriff and in-
carcerated in said jail.
Your petitioner further represents that
there is not probable cause for charging your
petitioner with said offense, and that said
bail is excessive.
Wherefore your petitioner shows that said
restraint is illegal and prays your honor
to grant hi the writ of Habeas Corpus
without delay, directed to said sheriff
and commanding him that he being
your petitioner before your honor as a 
comment true and that the matter
and things aforesaid be examined into
and your petitioner discharged.
Sheriffs, Frank N Barnes
Attorneys for Petitioner
Territory of Washington
County of Spokane}ss
Frank N. Barnes, being 
first-duly sworn on his oath states that
he is one one the attorney of said petitioner
and makes this affidavit for and on his
behalf, that he has read the foregoing petition
&amp; knows the contents thereof and that the
matters an things therein stated are true
according to the best of his knowledge
and belief.
Frank N. Barnes
Subscribed and sworn to before
me this 11th day of August A.D> 1885
George Turner
Associate Justice J.P.

To the clerk of the District 
Court of the Fourth Judicial 
district of Washington Territory
See the writ of Habeas
Corpus issue as <unclear></unclear>
the petition whereas sign
before me at chambers in Spokane 
Falls at 10 o'clock a.m.
The subpoenas issue for the personality witnesses
August 14th 1885
George Turner
Associate Justice of
the Supreme Court W.T.</p>
