<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0117.008"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Lelah-Puc-ka-Chee and Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha v. W.G. Malin and G.N. Nellis. Defendants' Answer to Petition</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0117.008</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Lelah-Puc-ka-Chee and Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha v. W.G. Malin and G.N. Nellis. Defendants' Answer to Petition</title>
<date when="1899-12-21">December 21, 1899</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1899-12">December 1899</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Lelah-Puc-ka-Chee</term>
<term>Malin, W.G.</term>
<term>Nellis, G.N.</term>
<term>Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Kansas City</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Malin, W.G.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Nellis, G.N.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Shiras, O.P.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court in Northern District Iowa</orgName> 
<placeName>Toledo, Iowa</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="sab">transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0117.008"/> 

<p>Copied at the National Archives at Kansas City</p>

<p>insofar as possible secure the attendance at said school of all children between the age of five and eighteen years; that in pursuance of said Rules &amp; Regulations the said plaintiff Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee was induced to attend said school and is now attending said school; and so far as these defendants are able to discover is contented and happy and willing to continue in said school. Defendants deny that she is dissatisfied with her condition or,that she cannot eat or drink or that she is in any state of excitement or manifests any desire to return to her alleged husband or that she is suffering any injury either in body or mind on account of being a pupil in said school. On the contrary, defendants aver that said plaintiff is making progress in her education and is receiving much benefit in said school and that her attendance is necessary to,accomplish the education that is contemplated by Congress and the Indian Department in the established of the Indian school on said Reservation. Defendants further aver that they believe the fact to be that said plaintiff Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee has not been married to the plaintiff Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha as alleged in the petition of plaintiffs but that said marriage is fraudlent and void, if any there was, and the same was entered into by said Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee through fear and intimidation on her part and not of her own free will and accord. Defendants aver that Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha, and other Indians on said Reservation, are opposed to the Indian school thereon and use all their power and influence to prevent the Indian children from attending said school; and that Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha, and other Indians, have entered into a conspiracy to retard and interfere, in every way possible, with the progress of said school; and they refuse to recognize the authority of the Indian Agent W.G. Malin and the superintendent of said school G.N. Nellis. That through fear or misrepresentation of some one unknown to these defendants they induced said plaintiff Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee to depart with them from said Reservation to part unknown to these defendants and that upon their return they reported her marriage to the said Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha who was already man and whose <unclear>minfleis</unclear> still homing</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
