<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0241.015"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Summary of Case</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>

<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0241.015</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Summary of Case</title>
<date when="1885-07-20">July 20, 1885</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1885-07">July 1885</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Kelly, Jay U.</term>
<term>Walker</term>
<term>Willie</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term></term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Walker, M.A.</persName>
<persName>Walker, Charles</persName>
<persName>Walker, Helen</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Campbell, A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court For The Western District of Washington Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="#sab">transcribed, encoded</change> 
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0241.015"/>

<p>(3)</p>
<p>1601 1/2</p>

<p>if they came in the house he'd have to defend himself: Walker boys however didn't appear but I awaited for them 20 min or half an hour on the kitchen was in my underclothes at the time: he said that he was walking on the track with Mrs. Walker, when he seen the walker boys coming: Mrs W. then told (will) me to cut across toward home and that she would go on and ment her husband: he told me that he then saw the Walkers boys also cutting across to head him off but that he got away from time &amp; got home: he came into the room in great haste and was excited when he was asked for Mr revolver: know that Mrs. Walker has written him and given him presents, among which was a necktin upon etc. ring: I asked him next morning if he'd come down town and he said he would not as he didn't want to see walker until he'd heard what Mrs W. had told her husband so that this stories (Mrs W's this own) would 'jibe'. When he saw Walker next time W. told him (Wm) that it looked rathin suspicious swing him (Wm) with his (Ws) wife= but notwithstanding this he asked him (wm) up to his (Ws) house again Willie was never subject to fits or anything of that sort: our house was always unluckd:</p>
<p>Jay U. Kelly sometimes night watchman light and waterworks: did not know Wm Lockwood: saw him after he was dead upon the track: was at about 7.00 yesterday morning: <del>had</del> must have been run over by switch engine: heard engine stop: was in the building of light &amp; W. Works at the time. <del>about</del> between 20. or 40 rods from where found body: house is under trill from scene of accidents immediately upon hearing engine stop went up: was not over</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
