<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0365.013">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John Matthews v. Henry M. White. Type of Document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0365.013</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">John Matthews v. Henry M. White. Type of Document</title>
<date when="1921-08">August 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-08">August 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Kline, E.M.</term>
<term></term>
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Matthews, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>DIPLOMATIC REPRESENTATIVE OF GALICIA
(WEST UKRAINIAN REPUBLIC)
WASHINGTON, D.C.</p>

<p>File #107
August 26, 1921.</p>

<p>Hon. Alfred Hampton,
Assistant Commissioner General
Bureau of Immigration,
Washington D.C.</p>

<p>Dear Sir:</p>

<p>An application for passport for Yan Matveyeff
alias John Matthews, a native of East Galicia,
has been turned over to mt by the Ukrainian
Diplomatic Mission, together with other documents
bearing on his case.</p>

<p>A passport for the applicant and the documents
are herewith enclosed as requested.</p>

<p>Respectfully,
<unclear></unclear>
Diplomatic Representative of Galicia</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>US DEPARTMENT OF LABOR
IMMIGRATION SERVICE
DISTRICT NO.16</p>

<p>IN REPLYING REFER TO
NO. 37012/600</p>

<p>DISTRICT HEADQUARTERS
U.S. COMMISSIONER OF IMMIGRATION
SEATTLE, WASH.</p>

<p>Aug. 19,1921</p>

<p>Commissioner General of Immigration,
Washington, D.C.</p>

<p>Referring to Bureau file 54904/149, I have to advise
that JOHN MATTHEWS has made application for writ of habeas
corpus, and I have been instructed to show cause on September
6, 1921, why writ should not issue.</p>

<p>The application for the writ raods in part as follows,
"That ever since said date (the date of the
issuance of the warrant of deportation
February 19, 1921) your petitioner has been and
still is unlawfully and unreasonably restrained of
his liberty in the County Jail of King County by
Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration aforesaid,
under the pretended authority of said warrant or order
of deportation and that said restraint is unreasonable
and unlawful in this: that the government of the United
States, as your deponent is informed and believes, has
no diplomatic relations with the government of Ukranua
and is unable to execute its order or warrant of deportation
of aforesaid and is unable to deport your petitioner
to said Ukrania and is making no attempt to do so and
has no intention of so doing, and that unless the said
Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration aforesaid, is
prevented from so doing he will continue unlawfully and
unreasonably to restrain your petitioner of his liberty
and confine him as a prisoner in the County Jail of King
Couty aforesaid, all in violation of your petitioner's
right under the Constitution and alws of the United
States.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE your petitioner prays an order directing the 
Clerk of this Court to issue under its seal a writ of
habeas corpus directed at Henry M. White, Commissioner
of Immigration, requiring him to produce the body of
your petitioner in the above entitled court at such time
as the Court may fix and then and there show cause, if
any he has, why your petitioner should be further
restrained of his liberty.</p>

<p>(Signed) Jack Matthews, Petitioner
(Signed) Geo. H. Anderson, Attorney for Petitioner</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Commissioner General. August 19, 1921.</p>

<p>I request that the Bureau's file properly certified
for use in court be promptly forwarded, and taht I be advised
as to whether or not a passport has been secured, and if not
whether there is any likelihood that a passport will be
forthecoming in the near future.</p>

<p>I would also appreciate the receipt of any
suggestions which the Bureau may be able to make.</p>

<p>Henry M. White
Commissioner</p>

<p>TWL/R</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>54904/149           August 11, 1921.</p>

<p>Representative of Ukrainia in Ameries,
1901 Columbia Bond, N.W.
Washington, D.C.</p>

<p>Sir:</p>

<p>This letter will be presented by Mr. E M. Kline, a
representative of thie Bureau. It is desired to secure a
Ukrainian passport for the alien Yan Motveyeff, alias John
Matthews. This man on the advices of his attorney refuses
to sign the application herewith, and the Bureau will be
obliged to you if this passport could be issued without his
signature. Mr. Kline will present to you the hearing given
this man and also a copy of a letter received from the alien's
brother, which states that he was born in Kaminets, Podolska,
Ukrainia.</p>

<p>Respectfully</p>

<p>Assistant Commissioner General.</p>

<p>LBR;BC</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>COPY</p>

<pb></pb>
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>