<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0154.009"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0154.009</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">October 14, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date></term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Clifford, Peter A.
Long (Clifford, Williams), Grace E.
Clifford, Alice B.
Burt. J.  J.
White, W. H. 
DeLang, James
Hanford, C. H.
Ayres, A. Reeves
Matthew, H. M.
Herice, Deevnay 
Fuller, Melville W.  
Hopkins, C. B.
Stringer, John
Heade, Matthew H.
Tallman, Boyd J.
Humphreys, William P.
Allison, William B.
Norris, George E.
Huxston, R. I.
Koepfli, C. A.
Brewster, J. M.
Moor, A. N. 
Drake, James C.
Wright, B. O. 
</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Georgetown, King County, Washington
San Francisco, San Francisco County, California
Seattle, King County, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Clifford, Peter A.</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Long (Williams, Clifford), Grace E.
Williams, Herbert O.</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>White, W. H.
Burt, J. J. 
Steiner, G. E.
Sweeney
French
</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>
Humphreys, William P.</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.
Tallman, Boyd J.</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0154.001"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->

<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, NINTH JUDICIAL CIRCUIT,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs.
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.</p>

<p>No.
Motion to dismiss for want of 
Jurisdiction.</p>

<p>Come now the respondents Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams, by their attorneys Sweeney and Steiner, and moves the
court to stay proceedings herein, and dismiss the above entitled cause,
on the ground that the court has no jurisdiction in the premises.</p>

<p>Sweeney Steiner
Attorneys for respondents.</p>

<p>No. 1204.
CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs.
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.</p>

<p>Motion to dismiss for want of
jurisdiction.</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JUN 20 1904
A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk
HM Matthew Deputy</p>

<p>Sweeney and Steiner,
Attorneys for Respondents,
Heller Bldg. Seattle, Wash.</p>

<p>UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
Northern Division.</p>

<p>PETER A. CLIFFORD,
Petitioner,
v.
HERBERT O. WILLIAMS
and GRACE E. WILLIAMS,
Respondents.</p>

<p>No. 1204.
Filed June 28 
1904.</p>

<p>Petition for a writ of habeas corpus by a citizen of
California to obtain custody of his minor child. Heard on
motion to dismiss for want of jurisdicion. Motion granted.
W. H. White, and
J. J. Burt.</p>

<p>For the Petitioner.</p>

<p>Sweeney and Steiner, For the Respondents.</p>

<p>HANFORD, District Judge:-</p>

<p>This cause involves a controversy between divorced
parents for the custody of their child. The petitioner is
a citizen of California, in which state the parties were
domiciled when they were divourced. The divorce was granted
by a court of the state of California, and by its decree the 
custody of the child was awarded to the mother in accordance
with the laws of California, for the reason that being a lit-
tle girl of tender years it required the nuture of its
mother, although the divorce was granted to the father on ac-
count of her fault. The decree, however, recognized the
parental rights of the father by according to him the priv-
ilege of seeing the child periodically. The mother, after
being marriedd to her co-respondent, Herbert O. Williams, re-
moved from California to the state of Washington, bringing
the child with her, without obtaining leave of the court to
change the child's domicil, and the respondents are now cit-
izens of the state of Washington. The court which granted
the divorce subsequently made a new order, awarding the cus-
tody of the child to the father upon his application, of
which notice was served upon the attorney of reocrd for the 
mother. The respondents have by formal proceedings in a
court of the state of Washington attempted to acquire a le-
gal right to the custody of the child by adoption, which
proceedings are alleged in the petition to be invalid, for
the reasons that the petitioner did not consent to such adop-
tion of his child, and the court in which the proceedings
were had did not have jurisdiction. The respondents deny
the jurisdiction of this court to entertain the petition
for a writ of habeas corpus, and on that ground have moved
to dismiss the case.</p>

<p>I am impressed with the plausibility and force of the
arguments made in behalf of the petitioner, that it is de-
sirable that the national courts should have jurisdiction
of controversies involving conflicting orders and judgments
of courts of different states, but the court has no power to
invest itself with jurisdiction, and cannot assume it unless
jurisdictionn has been conferred by an act of Congress. The
Constitution of the United States establishes the range of
the judicial power of the national government, and ordains
that the judiial power shall be vested in a Supreme Court,
and such inferior courts which Congress is authorized to create. Con-
gress is entrusted with power to create tribunals inferior 
to the Supreme Court, and to define their jurisdiction so as
to make distribution of the limited powers which the judicial
branch of the national government may exercise. Therefore,
whenever one of the inferior courts contemplated by the con-
stitution is called upon to adjudicate a controversy, it
must appear that the jurisdiction invoked has been conferred
by an act of congress. These principles are fundamental,
and as incontrovertibly established by the often repeated
declarations of the courts, as the fact of the distribution
of the powers of the national government into three co-orfin-
ate branches. The jurisdiction of this court to adjudicate the
controversy between the parents of this child having been
challenged by the respondents' motion, the court cannot con-
sider any question touching the merits of the controversy,
until we find a particular statute which clearly confers
jurisdiction to adjudicate such a controversy.</p>

<p>Where is the statute? In the prosecution of this in-
quiry, it is logically necessary to first ascertain the na-
ture of the case, and its object. Originally, in England,
the great writ of Habeas Corpus ad subjiciendum was one of the
high prerogative writs by which courts acquired jurisdiction
of a person actually imprisoned or deprived of his liberty;
but in this case the writ was issued as a process of the court
to acquire temporary custody of a child which has not been
incarcerated in any prision, for the purpose of adjudicating
a controvery between its parents as to their respective
rights to its custody. The object sought by the litigation
is not to release the child from restraint but to determine
finally the legal rights of the parents. The case being a
civil action at law, and the jurisdictional process, being
the writ of habeas corpus, two theories of jurisdiction must
be canvassed, one requiring consideration of the general
statute defining the jurisdiction of the United States circuit
courts, and the other the statutory provisions relating par-
ticularly to writs of habeas corpus.</p>

<p>Looking, now, to the statutes, we find that congress,
by the general law defining the jurisdiction of United States
circuit courts has conferred upon them jurisdiction inclus-
ive of civil cases arising under the constitution or laws
of the United States, or treaties made under their authority,
and cases in which there shall be a controversy between cit-
izens of different states. If this grant of jurisdiction
were absolute and unlimited, there would be no difficulty
in resolving the question now under consideration n favor
of the court's jurisdiction, but the statute does not give
jurisdiction of all cases arising under the constitution,
laws or treaties of the United States, nor of all cases in-
volving controversies between citizens of different states,
but limits the jurisdiction of all such cases by a prescib-
ed amount of money or pecuniary value involved, and this cause
cannot be brought within the terms of that statute because
the right of a parent to have the custody of a minor child
is priceless, and the value of a person's liberty cannot be
estimated in money. Barry v. Mercein, 5 How. 110; Kurtz
v. Moffitt, 115 U. S. 487.</p>

<p>Under this general law, circuit courts have jurisdic-
tion of suits in which the lititgants claim lands under grants
from different states, and this case suggets the propriety
of conferring jurisdiction of suits in which the rights
claimed are based upon judgments or judicial orders of courts
of different states, without regard to property as the sub-
ject of litigation or the amount involved. This, however,
is a matter proper for congress to consider, and arguments
in favor of such enlargement of jurisdiction can have no
influence upon a court called upon to decide a question as
to its jurisdiction under existing laws.</p>

<p>The special grant of power to issue writs of habeas
corpus is contained in Chapter Thirteen of Title XIII., in-
cluding Secs. 751-766 U. S. R. S. As significance has been
ascribed to the arrangement into sections of the different
parts of the law, it is necessary for a correct analysis to
consider the several sections separately, and also to treat
the chapter in its entirety as one law. Sections 751 and
752 provide that, the supreme court, circuit courts and dis-
trict courts, and the justices and judges of said courts, 
within their respective jurisdictions, shall have power to
issue writs of habeas corpus for the prupose of inquiry into
the cause of restraint of liberty; section 761 provides for
a summary hearing, and authorities the court or jusrice or
judge to dispose of the party as law and justice require.
These sections seem to contain the entire grant of power,
and they do not contain any clause or sentence indicating
limitations of the power. It is unecessary to prove that
the power given by this law is not without any limitation, be-
cause unlimited power is not contended for in the argument in
behalf of the petitioner. The question is, whether the power
granted by these sections is co-extensive with the judicial
power of the national government, as defined by the constitu-
tion, so as to comprehend all cases within the jurisdictiom
conferrable upon the federal courts, or whether the power is to
be exercised only in cases within the limited jurisdiction
conferred upon the courts by other acts of congress. The
argument in favor of construing the law liberally, as a
grant of the whole power, permissible to be granted, with
respect to matters in which the writ of habeas corpus may
be approximately used as a process by which to acquire juris-
diction of a particular person, is supported in an able de-
cision of the Circuit Court of Appeals for the First Cir-
cuit, in the case of King v. McLean Asylum, 64 Fed. Rep. 331,
in which that court announced its conclusion:</p>

<p>"That the power granted by the judiciary act of 1789,
as remodeled by sections 751 and 752 of the Revised Statutes,
goes to the entire extent of the jurisdiction which congress
c ould, under the constution, vrst in the supreme court or
the circuit courts, except as expressly excluded by other
provisions of statute, and except as also necessarily ex-
cluded by the inherent nature of the courts themselves, and
of the machinery given them by law with which to work out
practical results."</p>

<p>I am unable, however, to follow that decision in this
case, for the reason that the facts of this cause do not af-
ford any safe ground upon which to base a distinction be-
tween this case and the Burrus case, 136 u. S. 586, in which
the supreme court was called upon to decide, and did decide,
a controverted question as to the jurisdiction, of a district
court of the United States in a habeas corpus case, to award
the custody of a child to its father, and denied the juris-
diction of the district court, on the ground that the writ
of habeas corpus cannot be used by courts of the United
States, except in cases where it is appropriate to their
jurisdiction, and in that connection the court said:
 </p>

<p>"Of course this does not mean that they have jurisdic-
tion in all cases to issue the writ of habeas corpus, but
that they have such jurisdiction when, by reason of some
other matter or thing in the case, the court has jurisdic-
tion which it can enforce by means of this writ."</p>

<p>This is a solemn declaration which cannot be brushed
aside as mere dicta, and this court is necessarly bound by
the determinations of the supreme court of questions af-
fecting the extent of its powers. The only material dif-
ferences between this case, and the Burrus case, are in the
facts that, the question involved in that case had reference
to the jurisdiction of a district court, and no conflicting
orders or judicial proceedings of courts of different
states were set up as the basis of rights claimed; whereas
this case is in a circuit court, and the petitioner claims
an absolute right to the custody of his child by virtue of
an order awarding the custody to him made by a court of the
state of California, and the petition attacks the validity
of proceedings of a court of the state of Washington giving
judicial sanction to the adoption of the child by the re-
spondents; but such differences do not justify the applica-
tion of any different principle or rule for contruing the
statute. Section 751 confers identically the same power to
issue writs of habeas corpus upon the district courts that
it confers upon the circuit courts, and no differences in
their capacity or functions, or the purposes for which they 
were established, distinguishing them from the circuit
courts, reclude the district courts from taking the power
granted by that section in all of its amplitude. Both are
inferior to the supreme court, and established by laws en-
acted by congress pursuant to authority given by the con-
stitution, and derive all of their powers and jurisdiction
from the same source, and they are equally well equipped
in their organization with all the means requisite for ex-
ercising the functions of a court in taking into custody a
person, and adjudicating all questions affecting that per-
son's liberty, and all questions affecting the authrity
and rights of others with respect to the custody and con-
trol of infants. The facts that, the litigants are citi-
zens of differnt states and that case involves a con-
troversey between citizens of different states, cannot be
treated as a feature affecting the question as to the rela-
tive powers of the circuit and district courts, without con-
ceding that the decision of the question must be controlled
by the general statues defining the jurisdiction of the
different courts. Congress has conferred jurisdiction of
civil actions at law and suits in equity arising under the
constitution, laws and treaties of the United States, and
of actions and suits of a civil nature presenting contro-
versies between citizens of different states upon the cir-
cuit courts, and has not authorized the district courts to
entertain jurisdiction upon those grounds, but it may do so,
and it is not unlikely that in the near future, agitation 
of the subject which has been going on for many years, will
result in constituting the district courts the sole repos-
itories of the original jurisdiction of the federal courts.
A concession that section 751 is to be construed, for the
purpose of determining the respective powers of the circuit
and district courts, with reference to the general statutes
defining their jurisdictions, is an abandonment of the en-
tire argument based upon the special grant of powers con-
tained in the habeas corpus law, because it takes us back to the
question whether under general law, the case is cognizable in the
circuit court, and leaves us there.
</p>

<p>Section 753 contains no grant of power, but is a re-
striction upon the power of the federal courts, prohibiting
the issuance of the writ of habeas corpus in behalf of a
prisoner in jail except under the prescribed ocnditions
enumerated in that section. To meet the conditions exist-
ing at the time of South Carolina's attempt to nullify the
laws of the United States, and deal with officers of the
 national government under its criminal laws for acts done
in the performance of official duties, congress enacted:</p>

<p>"That either of the justices of the supreme court
or a judge of any district court of the United States, in
addition to the authority already conferred by law, shall
have power to grant writs of habeas corpus in all cases of
a prisoner, or prisoners in jail, or confinement, where he
or they shall be committed or confined on, or by any author-
ity or law, for any act done, or omitted to be done, in pur-
suance of a law of the United States, x x x x ." 4 U. S. Stats.
p. 634, Sec. 7.</p>

<p>This law has been recast in the revised statues, and
the body of it with changed phraselogy now constitutes sec-
tion 753, and as already indicated, there is in it no grant
of powerm so that it must now be construed with reference
to its position following sections 751 and 752 in order to
give it any definite and clear meaning, unless we assume that,
by implication, it confers power to grant writs of habeas 
corpus in the excepted cases enumerated. Thus construedm
the section, by implication, would confer jurisdiction upon
the federal courts generally, without discriminating between
circuit and district courts, to issue writs of habeas corpus
in behalf of the persons held in custody in violation of the
constitution of the United States. It is the main conten-
tion of the petitioner in this case that as the respondents
have refused to surrender the child in compliance with the
order of a court of the state of California they have failed
to give full faith and credit, in the state of Washington,
to a judgment of a court of the state of California, and
that such refusal constitutes detention of the child in cus-
today in violation of section 1 of Art. IV. of the constitu-
tion, and that the habeas corpus law does exporessly or by
implication confer jurisdiction upon this court as a citcuit
court of the United States to grant the relief which he seeks
by the writ of habeas corpus. If the law by necessaryim-
plication does confer jurisdiction upon the federal courts
to grant writs of habeas corpus in the particular cases enum-
erated in section 753, such implied jurisdiction is necessaar-
ily limited by the conditions to which the law is applicable,
and does not include this case, for the reason that the child
is not imprisoned in jail, and imprisonment in jail appears
to be the first condition recited in that section, and is the
controlling condition governing all of the cases which by
reason of the exceptions the federal courts are permitted to
take cognizance of.  </p>

<p>There is another fatal objection to the petitioner's
contention. That objection is grounded upon the difficulty
of bringing the case within the purview of the full faith and
credit clause of the constitution. That section of the
constitution prives that congress may by general laws pre-
scribe the manner in which the public acts, records, and ju-
dicial proceedings of every state "shall be proved, and the
effect thereof," and pursuant to that authority congress has
by section 905 U. S. R. D. prescribed the manner in which
public acts, records and proceedings shall be proved, and the
effect thereof, as follows:</p>

<p>Sec. 905, x x x The records, and judicial proceedings
of the courts of any state of territory, or of any such coun-
try, shall be proved or admitted in any other court within
the United States, by the attestation of the clerk and te
seal of the court annexed, if there be a seal, together with
a certificate of the judge, chief justice, or presiding magis-
trate, that the said attestation is in due form. And said
records and judicial proceedings so authenticated, shall have
such faith and credit given to them in every other court with-
in the United States as they have by law or usage in the court
of the state from which they are taken."</p>

<p>Under this law a judgment of a court of a state can on-
ly be made effective elsewhere within the United States, through
the instrumentality of a court having local jurisdiction. Sec-
tion 905, and the provisions of constitution upon which
it is based, establish a rule of evidence rather than a 
ground of jurisdiction. Wisconsin v. Pelican Insurance Co.,
127 U. S. 265-300. See, especially, pages 291-2-3.</p>

<p>Applying this rule to the case in hand, a duly authen-
ticated transcript of the judgment awarding to the petitioner
custody of his child, is competent avidence in this state,
and when so proved in a court of this statem the judgment it-
self will have the same validity, force and virture in this
state that it has by law or usage in the state of California,
unless it can be impeached for fraud or lack of jurisdiction
in the court which rendered it, the parties and the court
will be bound by it, so far that the controvery which it
determined cannot be again litigated in this state. But
until a court other than a court of the state of California
refuses to give such faith and credit to that judgment, the
refusal of the respondents to surrender the child will not
constitutte a violation of the constitution. In this con-
nection, it should be noted that the petition does not al-
lege that in the proceedings for legal adoption of the child
 by the respondents, the Washington court failed to give full
faith and credit to the order of the California court, award-
ing custody of the child to the petitioner, or acted with 
knowledge thereof. The duty of the respondents to obey the
command which the judgment contains is not more imperative
by reason of their presence in this state, than if they had
remained in California, and their custody of the child in
this state is not in violation of the constitution. It is 
not, because, according to the act of congress the judgment
awarding the legal custidy to the petitioner, can have no
other force or effect in this state than it has in California,
and until equal faith and credit has been refused, by a court,
there can be no ground for complaining of any violation of
the constitution, and no cause of action which will entitle
the petitioner to invoke the jurisdiction of a national
court, for the preservation of a constitutional right.</p>

<p>U regard chaoter thirteen of Title XIII. U. S. R. S.
as one law, intended to govern the practice of the federal
courts in habeas corpus cases, the several sections thereof
having relation to each other to constitute a complete har-
monious system. In general terms, it authorizes the courts,
and the justices and judges thereof, to issue writs of habeas
corpus, and dispose of persons restrained of liberty, as law
and justice require, prohibiting, however, the use of the
writ in behalf of prisoners in jail except in the enumerated
cases, in which the national government, acting within its
sphere, may properly interfere. And I am constrained by the
decision of the supreme court, in the case of Burrus, 136
U. S. 586, to hold that the authority which the law gives
does not enlarge the jurisdiction of this court, to embrace
this case. Motion to dismiss grated.</p>

<p>C. H. Hanford
Judge</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>