<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0159.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>In Re: Application of N. T. B. Pentreath for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Yu, Jingming" xml:id="jy">Jingming Yu</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0159.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">In Re: Application of N. T. B. Pentreath for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</title>
<date when="2022-06-16">June 16, 2022</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington.</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western Disctrict of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Unlawful Arrest</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1905-03">March 1905</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#jy">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0159.007"/>

<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, NINTH JUDICIAL CIRCUIT, WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF N. T. B. PENTREATH ON HABEAS CORPUS</p>
<p>No. 1274.</p>
<p>RETURN.</p>

<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, STATE OF WASHINGTON, COUNTY OF KING.</p>

<p>To the Hon. C. H. HANFORD, Judge of the above entitled Court:</p>
<p>Comes D. F. Willard, acting Chief of Police of the City of Seattle, Washington, appearing as respondent herein for the cause and reason taht Thomas Delaney, Chief of Police of the City of Seattle, Washington, he being the person to whom said writ of Habeas Corpus was and is directed, is now, and at the time of the service of the said Writ herein, absent from the said City of Seattle, and your respondent for and during such absence is the acting Chief of Police of said City.</p>
<p>Your respondent respectfully above to this Honorable Court that it is true that one N. T. B. Pentreath eptitioner herein is now and was at the time of the service of said Writ in custody of your responent, and was at the time of said service of said Writ confined and imprisoned in the City jail of the said City of Seattle, and was restrained of his liberty thereby, but your respondent respectfully shows that such restraint, confinement and imprisonment was and is lawful, which is the cause, and only cause of his said imprisonment and restraint. That said imprisonment and restraint is lawful as and your respondent shows this Honorable Court in this:</p>
<p>That the said Thomas Delaney, Chief of Police of the City of aforesaid, and your respondent acting in his stead was advised by telegraph and telephonic message from diverse peace officers fo the City of Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, that the petitioner herein had in said Province theretofore committeed crime against the laws of said Province, and that said officers believed and had reason to believe that the said petitioner herein had fled from the justice of the City of Vancouver, Province aforesaid, and was then, and could be found within the United States of America, and at or in the vicinity of the said City of Seattle. That your respondent acting in teh public service and not otherwise, directed diverse police officers of the City of Seattle to apprehend the petitioner herein. That upon such information and in the service aforesaid search was made and the petitioner herein was found in the City of Seattle, County of King, Washington, and said officers acting under said information arrested and took into custody the petitioner herein produced him before your respondent who placed him in confinement and imprisonment in the City jail of the said City of Seattle, until suitable, proper and diligent official action could be taken in the premises by proper public officials of the said Province of British Columbia; that the petitioner herein was so taken into custody in the said City of Seattle on the 27th Day of March, 1905, and that immediately upon this petitioner being taken into custody aforesaid, your respondent cause information to be communicated by telegraph and telephone to the proper peace officers and public officials of said City of Vancouver that this petitioner was then so in custody; that thereafter and on the same day and date one David Scott a peace officer of said City of Vancouver, British Columbia arrived in teh City of Seattle armed with and then and there had in his possession a warrant for the arrest of the petitioner herein, issued by one Thomas Crawford one of His Majesty's Justice of the peace, in and for said City of Vancouver, which said warrant was issued in due form of law in conformity to and suitable to the criminal procedure of said Province, and was based upon proper complaint and information theretofore filed in the office of the said Justice of the Peace at Vancouver aforesaid.</p>
<p>Your respondent furthe rshows this Honorable Court, that for a period of several days thereafter, the petitioner herein made diverse and many promises to our respondent and his subordinate police officers of the said City of Seattle, that he, th epetitioner herein would freely and of his own accord return with the said Scott to the said City of Vancouver, waiving the formality and legality of any extradition proceedings, but that the petitioner in each instance refused to freely and voluntarily return to said Vancouver.</p>
<p>Your respondent further shows this Honorable Court, that as soon thereafter as proper and diligent official action could be taken, a copy of the complaint or information so filed before said Justice of the peace at Vancouver and upon which said warrant was issued was forwarded to your respondent, and that thereafter on the 30th day of March, 1905, a complaint in due form of law was file din the Justice Court, in and for Seattle Precinct, King County, Washington, beofre P. V. Davis, Esq., Justice of the Peace, whereby and wherein, this petitioner is charged with being a figitive from the justice of the City of Vancouver, Province of British Columbia, Canada, wherte he is charged with having heretofore committed the crime of unlawfully and fraudulently uttering a forged document, as if it were genuine, knowing it was forged and with intent to defraud, and thereafter and upon said date a warrant for arrest in due form of law was issued by said Justice of the Peace,<add>that <unclear/> was made upon petitioner</add> and the petitioner herein is now held in custody by your respondent by virtue of the same.</p>
<p>Your rspondent further shows this Honorable Court, that the said crime so charged against the petitioner herein in the said City of Vancouver is an extraditable offence under the existing laws and treaties between the Dominion of Canada and the United States of America, and that your respondent is informed and verily believes that application will be made by the proper public officials of said Province upon the proper public officials of the </p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>