<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0272.012.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Columbia George v. Charles B. Hopkins. Petitioner Exhibit B.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Czapla, Ethan P" xml:id="epc">Ethan Czapla</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0272.012</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Columbia George v. Charles B. Hopkins. Petitioner Exhibit B.</title>
<date when="1901-11-21">November 21, 1901</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno>1390ColumbiaGeorgeIndian</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1901-11">November 1901</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Raley, J.H.</term>
<term>Parsons, Wm.</term>
<term>McElroy, B.F.</term>
<term>Hall, John H.</term>
<term>Edna, Anna</term>
<term>Craig, Joseph</term>
<term>Fleming, M.A.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Pendleton, Oregon</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>George, Columbia</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Hopkins, Charles B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Slater, R.J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Frye, Jesse A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C.H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#epc">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the Circuit Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington.

In the matter of the application of Columbia George for a writ of Habeas Corpus.

Transcript of said <unclear>writ for corpus</unclear>U.S. Circuit Court</p>

<pb/>

<p>In the Circuit Court of the United States For the District of Oregon</p>

<p>United States of America
       vs.
       Columbia George and Toy Toy</p>

<p>John H. Hall, United States District Attorney,
       for the Government,
       R. J. Slater, J. H. Raley and Wm. Parsons for Defendants.</p>

<p>B. F. McElroy. 
       A witness called on behalf of the Government, testified, among other things, 
       as follows, after being first duly sworn. Direct examination.</p>

<p>Questions by Mr. Hall:
       Your name is B. F. McElroy?</p>

<p>A. Yes, sir. 
       Q. Where do you reside, Mr. McElroy?
       A. I am living on the reservation, Umatilla Reservation, about four miles east of Pendleton.
       Q. How long have you resided there?
       A. Six years past.
       Q. How do you happen to be living upon the Umatilla Indian Reservation?
       A. I have some land leased there.
       Q. Of whom?
       A. The Indians
       Q. Did you knwo Anna Edna in her lifetime?
       A. Yes, sir.
       Q. Who was Anna Edna?
       McElroy - direct - 1</p>

<pb/>

<p>A. She was a lady, an Indian woman, about 50 years old - 51 or 2 perhaps.
       Q. Was she residing upon the Umatilla Indian Reservation?
       A. Yes, sir. 
       Q. Where did she reside with reference to where you live?
       A. Well, she lived aobut - I built her a cabin on the line that I live on, about 15 rods from my house, where I live.
       Q. Was her cabin upon the Umatilla Indian Reservation?
       A. Yes, sir.
       Q. About 15 rods from your house?
       A. Yes, sir.
       Q. Can you describe to the jury, Mr. McElroy, about the relations where your house was to her house, and your buildings,
       etc., around there, so that they will understad the premises?
       A. Yes, sir. 
       Q. Will you do so, please?
       A. Well, my house is about - we will say this table is a 40 of land - my house is about 30 rods from the line running north and south,
       over this way, and about 20 rods from the line running east and west, right up here. My house is right up here. And her house was about
       15 rods right down that way.
       Q. What direction - northwest?
       A. No, sir, southeast; right off that way; no, northeast - right down this way. My house is up on quite an elevated piece of ground.
       Q. Where is Anna Edna now?
       A. She is dead and buried.
       Q. When did she die?
       A. She died on the evening of the 24th of August
       Q. What year?
       A. 1900
       Q. Where did she die?
       McElroy - direct - 2</p>

<pb/>

<p>A. She died about four or five rods from her own cabin, right across in some folks' tent that was camped there. I had a man and his son working for me,
       and he had been moving, and he had a tent along, and had a cover on his wagon-box, and he took his wagon-box off, and they slept in that, and then
       they cooked in the tent. And the woman staid there all the time while we was harvesting. She died right at the door of the tent.
       Q. On the Umatilla Indian Reservation?
       A. Yes, sir, within a few rods of her own house.
       A. I went over there to the tent. The woman was laying down right at the door of the tent.
       Q. Whose tent?
       A. Old man La Mar's.
       Q. How far was that form Anna Edna's cabin?
       A. It is about four rods.
       Q. Upon whose land do you reside?
       A. Tatzhammer's
       Q. An Indian?
       A. Yes, sir.
       Q. Indian Allotment?
       A. Yes, Sir.</p>

<p>Cross Examination

       Questions by Mr. Raley:

       Q. Was that house of Anna Edna's located on her own land?
       A. No, sir.
       Q. Whose land is it on?
       A. Tatzhammer's

McElroy - cross- 3</p>

<pb/>

<p>Joseph Craig. A witness called on behalf of the Government, being first duly sworn, testified, among other things, as follows. Direct Examination.</p>

<p>Questions by Mr. Hall:

Q. Did you ever have any conversation with Columbia George with reference to the death of Anna Edna, in Pendleton?
A. Yes, sir.
Q. Where was that conversation had?
A. In the County jail there, where he was.
Q. You may state to the jury waht the conversation was.

A. I went to see Columbia George about some money that he was owing me - went to see him about that.
Q. Did you talk with him about your Indian affairs?
A. Yes, sir.
Q. Well, then, how did you come to have any conversation about the death of Anna Edna?
A. Why, after I got through with him about my own business, I started to walk off, and he called me back, after I had took about two or three steps he called me back, and then he wanted to tell me about the affair about this woman.
Q. What did he say?
A. First he told me to step up close ot the bar, and then he said he wanted to tell me about it, and I told him that I didn't want to hear about it; but he insisted, and went on telling me.
Q. What did he tell you?
A. In the first place, he said that "It wasn't my fault. I am very sorry for what we have done. I never thought of ever killing or hurting anybody. I drank, but I never wanted to hurt or kill anybody; but it was Toy Toy's fault altogether. He had arranged

Craig Direct - 1</p>

<pb/>

<p>the plans to kill Anna Edna."

Q. Well, what else did he say?
A. He said that he met Toy Toy, or was with Toy Toy in Pendleton, and as they came around near Damon's saloon Toy Toy said "Let's go in the saloon, the back part of the saloon, and have something to drink.""So we went in, and Toy Toy asked for order for a bottle of whisky. He got it and we drank it. After we took a few drinks, why, he commenced telling me about what we should do. He says "Let's kill that old woman. She is an Indian doctor. She killed my father, and you came very near dying on account of her, and let's us kill her."
Q. Meant that Columbia George came very near dying?
A. Yes, sir. And then he said that "I was afraid; didn't want to do it. After drinking some more, kept on talking about it, and then I consented, and aked him, 'Well, how are we going to do it?' He says, 'We will go over here to the drug store and get some poison' He said he told Toy Toy "How will I tell them" Toy Toy says 'We will go in there, and you tell him taht coyotes are killing off our chickens, giving us trouble, and we want to get some poison, some medicine, to kill them, kill the coyotes off. And I told his that I didn't have the money to buy it with. We went into the drug store. He said that he had the money; that he would give me the money. And we went off and went into the drug store, and he gave me a quarter to buy the poison with, and I went in, while Toy Toy stood at the door, the front door,"looking that nobody would see them, watch them there. "And I went in there and asked the man to give me medicine to kill coyotes. He gave me a small bottle." Paid two bites for it, and they got a bottle. GOt of bottle of alcohol in the drug store; paid 50 cents for it.

Jos. Craig - Direct - 2</p>

<pb/>

<p>They went out. "Then Toy Toy says, 'Let's go up - let's go up the river and look for Anna Edna, and we will fixt it. We will mix it up there. After we get up on the road, we will mixt it, and have it all ready. So we went up. When we got to this place, a little bridge above Pendleton about a mile and a half, we got off our horses, and then we had an empty bottle, small flask, about a two-bit size - half pint flask. And Toy Toy filled this bottle with water about half full, and filled the rest of it with water, filled it up, and then put some of this poison in it."

Q. Filled it up with water or alcohol?
A. The alcohol was poured into the half pint bottle, and then the water, and then it was mixed with strychnine. He said that Toy Toy done all this, and that he had it in his hands shaking it a long time. After shaking it, Toy Toy says, "Let's go back to town. I don't think Anna Edna has come out yet. I believe she is in town. Let's go back there and find her.""Then when we went back, we went on, before we got to town, he told me that I must go up and give it to her. After we found out that she wasn't in town,"-
Q. Did he speak about meeting anybody?
A. No, I don't recollect that he did; I don't believe he did. Then he said that Toy Toy told him to go up and find this old woman, and get her to drink it. "I went back up; got up to her house. She was there. I had the bottle in my pocket, and I took it out and offered it to her, and she took a drink; and then I took the bottle and I left the house. Then I went back towards town."</p>

<pb/>

<p>I hereby certify that the foregoing is a true and correct copy of a part of the testimony of the witnesses B.F. McElroy and Joesph Craig, given on the trial of the case of the United States of America vs. Columbia George and Toy Toy, which case was tried on the 21st, 22nd, and 23rd days of November, 1901.

M.A. Flemming
Official Stenographer United States Circuit Court, District of Oregon</p>

<pb/>






</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>