<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0406.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Samuel Gowen and Donald Webster v. JH McGraw. Applicantion for Writ.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace" xml:id="GT">Grace Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0406.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Samuel Gowen and Donald Webster v. JH McGraw. Application for Writ.</title>
<date when="1883-02-24">Feburary 24, 1883</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives</repository>
<collection>King Frontier Justice</collection>
<idno>Case 3181</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1883-02">Feburary 1883</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>James Ludlow
James Seavey
JH McGraw
Thomas Newland
C.F. Hess
</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle
Whatcom</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Donald Webster</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Samuel Gowen</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>JH McGraw</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>JM Hall
Wood</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Samuel Greene</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Third Judicial District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington Territory</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-06" who="#GT">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<ab>Territory of Washington
Third Judicial District
ss.</ab>
<ab>In the district court holding terms at Seattle in the county of King.</ab>
<ab>In the Matter of the Application
of Samuel Gowen and Donald Webster for
A Writ of Habeas Corpus
Application for a Writ
of Habeas Corpus</ab>
<ab>To the Hon. Roger S. Greene, Judge of the District Court of the
Third Judicial District of Washington Territory.</ab>
<p>The petition of Samuel Gowen and Donald Webster 
respectfully shows: that the said Samuel Gowen and Donald Websterand
each of them is unlawfully imprisoned, detained, confined and 
restrained of his liberty by J.H. McGraw, the Sheriff of King County in
Washington Territory, at the said imprisionment, dention, confinement and constraint
are illegal and that the illegality thereof consists in this:
to wit: -- --</p>
<p>The cause or pretence of the said imprisonment, dentention, confinement
and restraint is a certain commitment dated -- Jan 17th, 1883, issued 
by one, Thomas L. Newland, who is or pretends to be a justice of the 
peace in whatcom county, Territory of Washington, which commitment is 
in the words and figures following, to wit"</p>
<p>"Territory of Washington
"Whatcom County
SS.
"To any constable and the keeper of the jail of said county: 
" Whereas Samuel Gowen and Donald Webster ahve been brought 
"this day before the undersigned one of the Justices of the Peace
"In and ForSaid County, charged on hte oath of Charles F. Hesswith having
"on th 15th day of January, 1883, in said county commited the offense
"of sault on the person of Mrs. C.F. Hessand made improper roposals 
"to Mrs. C.F. Hess destroyed saloon bar fixtures,
liquors and breaking windows belonging to C.F. Hess. Keeping saloon
at Sterling in said county anf territory and in the progress of
the trial of said charges it appearing to the said Justice that the
said Samuel Gowen and Donald Websterhave been guilty of the offense
of sault on the person of Mrs. C.F. Hessand made improper proposals to 
the said Mrs. C.F. Hessthe wife of Charles F. Hess, destroyed Daloon Bar
Fixture, liquors and Breaking windows. The property belonging to
16th day of January, 1883, commited at the time and placs aforesaid: and
whereas the said <del>Donald Webster and Samuel Gowen</del> Samuel Gowen and Donald
Websterhave failed to give bail in the sum of two hundred dollars each for their appearance
to answer at the next term of the district
court, as required by me therefore on the name of the United States
you are commanded to recieve the said Samuel Gowan and Donald Webster
into your custody and into the said jail nad they there safely keep until they
be discharged by due course of law, given under my hand ths
this 17th day of January, 1883.</p>
<ab>|Signed|Thomas S. Newland."
<pb></pb>
Justice of the Peace of Mount Vernon, in and for Whatcom Co. Wash.
"Ter</ab>
<ab>Which commitment and all the proceedings thereunder are void
and illegal for the following reasons, to wit:</ab>
<p>First.
Because the facts in the case and the testimony givenon the trial
and examination of these applicatsdo not show any probable cause or 
ground whatsoeverto charge them with any charge crime or misdemeanor
whatsoeverthere being an entire absence and want of such probable
causethere being no testimony whatsoever - tending to charge there
applicants with assualt or any other crime or misdemeanor whatsoever.</p>
<p>Second.
Becayse the complaintmade against these aplicants and all the testimonyon 
the examination and trial do not showor pretend that any offense
was commitedove which thesaid Justice did not have jurisdiction
to thy determine and punish, and which would not have been sufficiently
punishedby a fine not exceeding 100 dollars and costs.</p>
<p>Third.
Because these applicants are and were not guilty of the misdemeanorcharged
against them nor of any other crime or misdemeanor
whatsoever. The said act of the said justice in comitting these
applicantsas aforesaid being arbitrary and unjust and holly unwarrantted by the law or the facts.</p>
<p>Fourth.
Because the complaint made and the prosecuting witness himself
did not say nor pretend to say that any offense was committed which was
beyond the jurisidiction of ofsaid Justice of the Peace to try, determine, 
sentence and punish which would n ot have been sufficiently punished
a fine not exceeding 100 dollars with costs.</p>
<p>Wherefore your petitioners and applicants pray that
a Writ of Habeas Corpus may be granteddirected to the said J.H. McGraw
Sheriff aforesaid commanding him to have the bodies of the aforesaid 
Samuel Gowen and Donald Webster, before your honor at a time and place
therein to be specified to do and recieve what shall then and there be
considered by your honor concerning saidSamuel Gowen and Donald Webster
together with the time and cause of his detentio n, and said writ and 
thatsaid Samuel Gowen and Donald Webster may be restored to their liberty.</p>
<ab>dated -- Seattle Feby 24th, 1883
Donald Webster
Samuel Gowen</ab>
<ab>Territory of Washington, County of King |SS.</ab>
<p>Samuel Gowen and Donald Websterbeing duly sworn on oath,
each for himself says: that he has heard read the foregoing application
and that he knows the contents ther of and believes the same to be true.</p>
<ab>Subscribed and Sworn to before me
this 24th day of Feburary, 1883.</ab>
<ab>J. Wood, Notarypublic in and  for King County, Washington Territory.</ab>
<pb></pb>
<ab>No. 3181
In Re
Samuel Gowen and
Donald Webster
Habeas Corpus
Application for Writ
Filed Feburary 24 188
James Seavey, Clerk.
By James P Ludlow
Deputy Clerk.
Hall + Wood 
for applicants</ab>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>