<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the United States District Court, In and For the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Chin Hing, for a Writ of Habeas 
Corpus. } No. 2857
Assignment of Errors</p>
<p>Comes now John J. Sullivan, and as Attorney for the Petitioner
and appellant in the above entitled cause, says: That in the record
and procceding in this case, and in the Order and Judgement
entered on the twenty-ninth day of May, 1915, there is manifest error 
in this, to-wit:</p>
<p>I. 
That the Court erred in refusing to grant the Writ of Habeas
Corpus, and discharge the petitioner.</p>
<p>II.
That the Court erred in admitted as evidence the so-called
record marked "Exhibit A" without further proof than the cerificate 
thereunto appended.</p>
<p>III.
That the Court erred in ruling that the so-called record
marked "Exhibit A" was to the effect that Chin Hing had been granted
a full and fair hearing on his application to land in the United States.</p>
<p>IV.
That the Court erred in ruling that the so-called record
marked "Exhibit A" proved that the petitioner had been accorded the
right to appeal from the excluding decision, and that said appeal 
had been heard and decided in a fair and legal manner, in accordance
with the rules and regulations governing the admissiion of Chinese
into the United States.</p>
<p>V.
That the Court erred in overruling counsel for petitioner
<fw>1.</fw>
<pb/>
that inasmuch as said so-called "Exhibit A" contained no written
decision or order signed by the Secretary of Commerce and Labor,
it did not appear therefrom that the appeal had been duly acted
upon by the United States.</p>
<p>VI.
That the Court erred in ruling that the so-called "Exhibit A"
proved that a proper record on appeal had been submitted to, and
acted upon by the officers authorized by law to act, under and by
virtue of the rules and regulations governing admission of Chinese
into the United States, and the right to appeal from an adverse decision
by the Commissioners at the Port of Entry.</p>
<p>VII.
That the Court erred in refusing to rule as requested by 
counsel for petitioner, that the memorandum for the Acting Secretary,
included in said record, was an irregular, improper, and illegal
addition to the record made by the Commissiioner-General of Immigration,
or under his authority, and was not evidence, was not given
under oath as shown by the record, and should not have been made a
part of the record, or admissible.</p>
<p>VIII.
That the Court erred in ruling that the so-called record
marked "Exhibit A", conclusively proved that the petitioner had been
accorded a fair hearing, both at the port of entry and on appeal,
in accordance with the law and treaty between the United States and
China, and rules and regulations governing the admission of Chinese,
and that there was evidence to substantiate the findings of the
Department.</p>
<p>IX.
That the Court erred in refusing to rule that no one but the
Secretary of Commerce and Labor has a right to affirm an excluding
decision.</p>
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
<p>X.
That the Court erred in refusing to rule that there was
nothing in the record to show that the Acting Secretary had been
authorized to act.</p>
<p>XI. 
That the Court erred in refusing to rule that the record
showed such unfairness and illegality as to warrant the Court to
investigate the status, or discpose of the case as law and justice
required, omitting therefrom such evidence as should not ahve been
admissible.</p>
<p>XII.
That the Court erred in not finding that the petitioner
was the son of a merchant of New York City.</p>
<p>XIII.
That the Court erred in granting the Petition of the Government
to withdraw commission to take interrogatories of Louis F.
Post, Assistant Secretary, heretofore granted by the Court.</p>
<p>XIV.
That the Court erred in granting the Petition of the Government
to withdraw commission to take interrogatories, after the same
had been stipulated, and upon refusal of said Louis F. Post to answer
and rule to show cause had been issued by Justice Gould, an Order
was entered by said Justice Gould commanding said Louis F. Post to
answer same, and upon said answer to said interrogatories depended
the determination as to whether the petitioner had been ordered
deported without authority, and the Court should have allowed said
matter to be determined as the issue had been made up.</p>
<p>XV.
That the Court erred in allowing a copy of said record taken
at said hearing before the Immigration Department to be termed the
"original record" in this case, as shown by the first return.</p>
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
<p>XVI.
That the Court erred in allowing a further return on the
day of hearing by the Government, showing that the Secretary had
examined the orginal record, when by the first return, the orginial 
record was alleged to be before the Court, and no Order had been
issued by this Court allowing same to be taken from the files of the
Court.</p>
<p>XVII.
That the Court erred in withdrawing the commission to take
interrogatories and allow an alleged finding of the Secretary of 
Commerce and Labor to be offered in evidence, after the said cause
between the petitioner and the Government was at issue.</p>
<p>XVIII.
That the Court erred in not holding that <add>by</add> the record in the
cause, the burden of proof was upon the Government to show that
J.B. Densmore acted without authority.</p>
<p>XIX.
That the Court erred in not finding that the petitioner
should have had notice that the appeal would be heard by the Secretary
of Commerce and Labor, after this case was before the Court,
and that <add>permission</add> should be given counsel to present a brief, or oral
argument, or both before said Secretary; and that said alleged
hearing under said circumstances without Order of the Court when
this case was before this Court and issue made up, was irregular,
illegal, and unfair, and the Court should not have admitted the
finding and return as made on the day of hearing as shown by the
record.</p>
<p>XX.
That the Court erred in rendering a Decree and Judgment,
discharging the Writ of Habeas Corpus, and remanding the petitioner
to the custody of the officers of the United States, and depriving
him of his liberty.</p>
<fw>-4-</fw>
<pb/>
<p>XXI.
That said Order entered on the twenty-ninth day of May,
1915, is not warranted by, nor supported by the facts of the law
in the premises, but is contrary thereto,</p>
<p>Wherefore, said Chin Hing, the petitioner and appellant
herein, by and through his Attorney, John J. Sullivan, prays that
his Assignment of Errors be entered upon the record in this case,
and that upon the hearing of this appeal it may be adjudged by the
United States Circuit Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, and
that the Order and Judgement on the twenty-ninth day of May, 1915
made and entered, be in all things reversed, set aside and held for
naught, and that it be adjudged and decreed that the petitioner
and appellant have an adjudication in his favor, as prayed for in
said amended petition.</p>
<ab>Chin Hing
Petitioner</ab>
<ab>By and Through John H Sullivan
His Attorney and
Solicitor.</ab>
<pb/>
<p>No. 2857
Original</p>
<p>In the
Superior Court
State of Washington
King County</p>
<p>In the Matter of the
Application of Chin Hing
for a Writ of Habeas
Corpus.</p>
<p>Assignment of Errors</p>
<p>Filed in the
U.S. District Court
Western Dist. of Washington,
Northern Division
JUN 10 1915
Frank L. Crosby, Clerk,
By EM Lakin Deputy
2x</p>
<p>Beeler &amp; Sullivan
Lawyers
510-11 White Building
Seattle, Wash.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>