<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0471.010">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Salfest S. Sylvester v. Stener S. Wenaas. Return to Writ</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0471.010</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Salfest S. Sylvester v. Stener S. Wenaas. Return to Writ</title>
<date when="1899-06-29">June 29, 1899</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1899-06">June 1899</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Hopkins, R. M.</term>
<term>Ayres, A. Reeves</term>
<term>Ander, J.</term>
<term>Gordon, C. J.</term>
<term>Fullerton, J.</term>
<term>Dunbar, J.</term>
<term>Reavis, J.</term>
<term>Rogers, John R.</term>
<term>Devine, Joseph M.</term>
<term>Alling, H.</term>
<term>Jenkins, Will D.</term>
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>North Dakota</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-09" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<ab>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</ab>

<ab>In the matter of the application of
Salfest S. Sylvester for a Writ of
Habeas Corpus.</ab>

<ab>Return to Writ.</ab>

<p>Comes now the Respondent, Stener S. Wenaas, and for return to
the Writ of habeas corpus issued herein states, that he admits that the
said petitioner is now in his custody and control, but denies that the
said petitioner is now in his custody and control, but denies that the
custody and control of said Petitioner by this respondent is in any
manner illegal and unlawful, but alleges the fact to be that his custody
abd control is in accordance with the laws of the State of Washington,
and of the United States. </p>

<p>Respondent further states that during the summer and fall of 1898
the petitioner was in the employ as the agent of the Equitable Life
Assurance Society, which is a corporation, and as the agent of said
Company <add>While said Petitioner <unclear>who in trail Court</unclear>, until Dakota</add> received into his possession certain money and property of
said Company amounting to several hundred dollars, which sums he <del>then and there</del> unlawfully
and feloniously embezzled and converted to his own use.</p>

<p>Respondent further shows that thereafter the said petitioner in
order to avoid the laws of the State of North Dakota fled therefrom and
became a fugitive from justice of said state and thereafter took refuge
in the State of Washington.</p>

<p>Respondent further showeth that subsequent thereto the Governor
of the State of North Dakota made due demand on the Governor of the
State of Washington, which demand was accompanied by a requisition and
other papers pursuant to law, demanding that the Governor of the State
of Washingtion deliver over to the authorities of the State of North
Dakota the said Petitioner as a fugitive from justice of the State of
North Dakota as aforesaid; that the Governor of the State of North
Dakota duly appointed this respondent, Stener S. Wenaas, as the agent</p>

<pb/>

<p>of said state to receive said petitioner on said requisition proceedings.</p>

<p>Respondent further showeth that said requisition as issued by the
Governor of the state of North Dakota, together with the various and
diverse papers thereunto attached was by this respondent delivered to
the Governor of the State of Washington on or about the 26th day of
December, A. D. 1898; That pursuant to the laws of the United States
and of the State of Washington, and by virtue of the requisiton and
demand as made upon him by His Excellency the Governor of the State of
North Dakota, His Excellency, the Governor of the State of Washington,
did on the 26th day of December, A. D. 1898 under his hand and the
Seal of the State issue his certain Governor's warrant directing this
respondent as the agent of the State of North Dakota to arrest said
petitioner and convey him from this state to said State of North
Dakota. That this respondent holds custody of the said petitioner
under and by virtue of said warrant as aforesaid, a copy of which is
hereto attached marked Exhibit A. and made a part hereof.</p>

<p>Respondent further shows that he denies each and every allegation
contained in the petition of petitioner herein, except such as may he
herein admitted, which are inconsistent with or in opposition to the
statements and allegations in this return made.</p>

<p>Respondent further shows that heretofore and on or about the 28th
day of December, A. D. 1898, the said petitioner appealed to the
Superior Court of King County for a Writ of Habeas Corpus alleging that
his distraints of liberty was at that time unlawful and that he was then
unlawfully in the custody of this respondent; that to said proceedings
this respondent made due and regular return; that the Superior Court
on the trial and hearing of said matter coming up on the appliation
of defendant, the present petitioner, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus and
on respondent's return thereto, <add>a <unclear>open </unclear> that the</add> said respondend having said petitioner
in his custody under and by virtue of the Governor's warrant, a copy of
which is hereto attached marked Exhibit A., was in all things lawful
and correct and in conformity to the laws of the State of Washington
and of the United States.</p>

<ab>-2-</ab>
<pb/>

<p>That thereafter the said Petitioner in the Superior Court of
King County appealed from said determination of the Superior Court to
the Supreme Court of the State of Washington, and such proceedings were 
thereafter hadin the Supreme Court of the State of Washington in said
cause that said last named court did on June 20th, 1899, render its
judgment and opinion that the custody of the said petitioner was lawful,
and affirmed the judgment of the Superior Court of King County to that
effect directing that said petitioner be at once delivered to this
respondent in conformity with the extradition proceedings and the
warrant of the Governor of the State of Washington.</p>

<p>That thereafter the Remittitur from the Supreme Court of this
state, together with the opinion of said court, was duly filed in the
Clerk's office of King County, the original remittitur and the certified
copy of the opinion of the Supreme Court of the State of Washington
is now and here produced and exhibited in court. A copy of the opinion
of he Supreme Court herein <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear> tx. B" 
<unclear></unclear> a <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear></p>

<ab>Stener S. Wenaas</ab>

<ab>Jas F McElroy
Attorney for Respondent.</ab>

<ab>STATE OF WASHINGTON
County of King.</ab>

<ab>ss</ab>

<p>Stener S. Wenaas being first duly sworn, upon oath
deposes and says: I am one of the respondents in the above entitled
matter; as such I make the foregoing return and that the facts and statements
set forth in the foregoing returns are true.</p>

<ab>Stener S Wenaas</ab>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 29th day of June, 1899.</p>

<ab><unclear>Na</unclear> D. Futton
Notary Public in and for the State of
Washington, residing at Seattle.</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.</ab>

<ab>STATE OF WASHINGTON.</ab>

<ab>EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENT.</ab>

<ab>TO ALL TO WHOM THESE PRESENTS SHALL COME, GREETING:</ab>

<p>WHEREAS, It has been represented to me by His Excellency
JOSEPH M. DEVINE, Governor of the State of No.Dakota that Solvest
A. Sylvester stands charged in said State with the crime of EMBEZZLEMENT
committed in the County of Traill in said State and is a fugitive
from the justice of said State and has taken refuge in the State of 
Washington;</p>

<p>AND WHEREAS, the said Governor of the State of North Dakota has
pursuant to the constitution and laws of the United States demanded of
me that I cause the said Solfest A. Sylvester to be arrested and delivered 
to Stener S. Wenaas, agents authorized to receive him into their custody
and convey him back to said State of North Dakota.</p>

<p>AND WHEREAS, said representation and demand are accompanied by
affidavits, complaint, information, indictment and warrant whereby the
said Solfest A. Sylvester is charged with the said crime and being a
fugitive from the justice of said State and having taken refuge in the
State of Washington, which are certified by said Governor of North
Dakota to be duly authenticated.</p>

<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I , J.R. ROGERS, Governor of the State of Washington,
do hereby authorize and empower Stener S. Wenaas, the agent named in
said demand, to take the said Solfest A. Sylvester wherever he may be 
found in this State, and transfer him to the line thereof at the expense
of the State of North Dakota. </p>

<p>And I hereby command all civil officers within the said State of 
Washington to afford all needful assistance for the execution of this 
warrant.</p>

<p>IN TESTIMONY WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand and caused the seal of
the said State be affixed at Olympia, this twenty-sixth day of
December, A. D. 1899.</p>

<p>(Seal of the State of Washington.)</p>

<ab>J. R. ROGERS.</ab>

<ab>BY THE GOVERNOR</ab>

<ab>WILL D. JENKINS, Secretary of State.
By H. Alling, Chief Clerk.</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>In re SALFEST A. SYLVESTER.</ab>

<ab>No. 3252</ab>
<ab>Filed June 20th, 1899.</ab>

<p>The appellant, Salfest A. Sylvester, sued out a writ of habeas
corpus in the superior court of King County, whereby he sought to be
discharged from the custody of Stener A. Wenaas. The cause and
pretense of his arrest and detention he alleged to be a warrant issued
by His Excellency, John R. Rogers, governor of the State of Washington,
without first having the Givernor of North Dakota certify that an
affidavit, if one has been made, stated a crime and was correct under
the laws of said state, and that no indictment or affidavit required
by law has been found or made in North Dakota. He further alleged that
his imprisonment and restraint were illegal because, first, the governor 
of North Dakota has not certified that a crime is charged second, that
no crime has been or is now charged or evidenced as is by law required,
and, third, that the governor's warrant does not state facts sufficient
to warrant petitioner's arrest and detention. The writ was duly served
the respondent who thereupon made return thereto that he was the duly
accredited agent of the State of North Dakota; that he denied that said
petitioner was or is unlawfully restrained of his liberty; admits that
the said petitioner is in the custody and control of the respondent;
that said custody is in all things legal and in accordance with the
constitution and laws of the United States, the states of North 
Dakota and Washington; that the respondent, as agent of the state
of North Dakota, holds the said petitioner is his custody under and by
virtue of a warrant for the arrest and extradition of said petitioner,
issued by His Excellency J. R. Rogers, governor of the state of Washington,
a copy of said warrant being hereto attached and made a part
of this return, the original neverthless being now and here produced in
court, upon the filing of this return the said petitioner moved the
court to require the respondent to incorporate into and make a part of 
his return the representation and demand of the executibe of North</p>

<pb/>

<p>Dakota alleged in the warrant as accompanied by affidavits, complaint, 
information, warrant and indictment, so that said return should set forth
the facts presented to the governor of the State of Washington upon
which he issued his warrant. This motion was denied by the court and the
appellant duly excepted to the ruling. Thereupon the appellant interposed
a demurrer to the return on the ground that the same did not
state facts sufficient to warrant a lawful imprisonment and detention
of the petitioner. The demurrer was overruled by the court, and an
exception taken; and the court thereupon dismissed the writ and entered 
an order fixing th bail of appellant in the sum of $500, and remanding
him to the custody of the sheriff of King County until said bail be
given, to be held by said sheriff at the expense of the state of North 
Dakota. From the judgment and orders of the court the petitioner
appeals.</p>

<p>The respondent moves to dismiss the appeal upon the following
grounds: I() a failure to serve and file briefs within the statutory
time; (2) a lack of diligence in the prosecution of the appeal, and (3)
that the order appealed from us not an appealable order and that the
court has no jursidiction to entertain the appeal. Under the circumstances
of this case we think there is no substantial merit in the first two
grounds of the motion, and in regard to the point that the order
remanding the appellant into custody is not appealable or subject to
review by this court, <del>and</del> the case of In re Foye and that of In re
Baker not yet reported establish the law of this state adversely to the
contention of the respondent. For the reasons given more at large
in those cases, the motion to dismiss is denied. </p>

<p>Following the rule laid down in the two cases above mentioned,
we next proceed to determine the merits of this case, or, in other 
words, to ascertain whether, in fact, the appellant is and was illegally
restrained of his liberty as alleged in his petition for the
writ of habeas corpus. In this instance, it will be borne in mind,
the papers accompanying the requisition of the governor of North
Dakota were not produced at the hearing before the superior court,</p>

<pb/>

<p>and we are therefore necessarily limited to a consideration of the 
return of the respondent to the writ; and the question is, does the
return, which is admitted to be true by appellant's demurrer, show
facts sufficient to autorize the arrest and extradition of the appellant
under article 4, section 2 of the constitution of the United 
States, and <unclear>symbol</unclear>5278 of the Revised Statutes of the United States, which
provisions constitute the law governing the subject of interstate
extradition. It seems to be the established law in this country that
the executive authority of a state upon whom a demand has been made by
the executive authority of another state for the rendition of a fugitive
from justice, cannot be coerced by the courts to produce or
exhibit the papers accompanying the requisition of the governor of the
demanding state.</p>

<ab>Church on Habeas Corpus, <unclear>symbol</unclear> 480;
People v. Donohue, 84 N.Y.438.</ab>

<p>And that being true, it would seem logically to follow that one
having the custody of an alleged fugitive from justice should not be
obliged, on a hearing upon habeas Corpus, to produce such papers. In
fact, this point was directly raised and passed upon adverse;y to the
contention of the appellant in the Matter of Leary, 10 Benedict, 197;
6 Abbott's New Cases, 44. See also People v<unclear></unclear> Donohue, 84 N.Y.438. The
executive warrant in this case recities:</p>

<p>"Whereas it has been represented to me by His Excellency, Joseph
M. Devine, Governor of the State of North Dakota, that Salfest A.
Sylvester stands charged in said state with the crime of embezzlement
committed in the county of Traill in said state, and is a fugitive
from the justice of said state and has taken refuge in the State of 
Washington;</p>

<p>And whereas, the said Governor of the State of North Dakota has,
pursuant to the constitution and laws of the United States demanded of
me that I cause the said Salfest A. Sylvester to be arrested and delivered
to Stener S. Wenaas, agents authorized to receive him into their
custody and convey him back to said state of North Dakota</p>

<p>And wgereasm said representation and demand are acomoanied by
affidavits, complain, information, indictment and warrant whereby
the said Salfest A. Sylvester is charged with the said crime and being
a fugitive from the justice of said state and having taken refuge in
the State of Washinton, which are certified by said Governor of
North Dakota to be duly authenticated.</p>

<p>Now, therefore, I, J. R. Rogers, Governor ofnthe State of Washington,
do hereby authorize and empower Stener S. Wenaasm the agent named
in said demand, to take the said Salfest A. Sylvester wherever he may
be found in this state, and transfer him to the line thereof at the
expense of the State of North Dakota.</p>

<p>And I hereby command all civil officers within said state of </p>

<pb/>

<p>Washington to afford all needful assistance for the execution of this 
warrant. * * *</p>

<p>This warrant, as we have before observed, was made a part of the
respondent's return to the writ, and appellant's demurrer admits the
truth of all of its material allegations, and, if it states all of the 
facts required by the constitution and laws of the United States to
authorize the arrest of a fugitive from justice, then the a rest and
detention complained os is not ellegal and appellant ought to be - 
remanded to the custody of the respondent to be transported to the
state of North Dakota to answer to the charge there preferred against 
him. An examination of this warrant will show a compliance with all the
conditions prescribed by <unclear>symbol</unclear> 5278 of the Revised Statutes of the United
States. It clearly recites a demand by the governor of the State of
North Dakota for the rendition of appellant as a fugitive from justice
from that state; that the demand was accompanied by the papers therein
specified; that it appears therefrom that appellant is charged in that
state with the crime of embezzlement and that the papers accompanying
the requisition were duly authenticated by the governor of the said
state of North Dakota. None of the recitals are controverted by the
appellant, and we think the warrant constitutes a sufficient authority
for the arrest and extradition of the appellant</p>

<ab>People vs. Donohue, supra
People v. Pinkerton, 77 N.Y.245
Ex Parte Regal, 114 U.S. 642
Roberts vs. Reilly, 116 U.S. 80
Church on Habeas Corpus (2nd Ed.) <unclear></unclear>480
Matter of Clerk, 9 We nd.212</ab>

<p>The judgment and order of the lower court remanding the appellant
was, in our opinion, correct and proper, and it is therefore affirmed;
and it is ordered that the appellant be delivered to the respondent as
the agent of North Dakota when he shall appear, and that in the mean
time he be kept in the custody of the Sheriff of King County at the
expense of said state.</p>

<ab>Anders, J.</ab>

<ab>We concur:
Gordon, C. J.
Fullerton, J.
Dunbar, J.
Reavis, J.</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Tx</ab>

<ab>776</ab>

<ab>10d
pd</ab>

<ab>In Re Habeas Corpus
of
S. S. Sylvester
Return to Writ</ab>

<ab>FILED IN THE 
U. S. CIRCUIT COURT, 
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.</ab>

<ab>JUN 29 1899
A. REEVES AYRES, CLERK</ab>

<ab>R M Hopkins Dep.</ab>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>