<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0272.016.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Columbia George v. Charles B. Hopkins. Assignments of Error on Appeal</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Czapla, Ethan P" xml:id="epc">Ethan Czapla</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0272.016</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Columbia George v. Charles B. Hopkins. Assignments of Error On Appeal</title>
<date when="1906-04-27">April 27, 1906</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno>1390ColumbiaGeorgeIndian</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1906-04">April 1906</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the United States Circuit Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>In the matter of the Application of Columbia George, for a writ of Habeas Corpus. No. 1390</p>

<p>ASSIGNMENTS OF ERROR ON APPEAL</p>

<p>Come now the petitioner above named and files the following assignment
 of errors upon which he will rely on his appeal from the order of this 
Honorable Court made on the 27th day of April 1906, in the above-entitled matter.</p>

<p>I. The court erred, in denying the petition of sad petitioner for a writ of Habeas Corpus, and
in dismissing said petition.</p>

<p>2. The court erred in quashing the rule or order to Charles B. Hopkins, United States Marshal for the
Western District of Washington ordering him to appear before said court on the 26th day of February 1906
and show cause, if any, why the writ of Habeas Corpus should not be issued as prayed for in said petitions.</p>
<p>3. The court erred in sustaining the objections of the United States District Attorney to the evidence
offered by the petitioner to-wit a patent of the United States issued to the said Columbia George for certain
lands scheudled ot the said Columbia George as his allotment, upon the Umatilla Indian Reservation in the
State of Oregon which is refered to in the record and marked "Exhibit A."</p>

<p>4th</p>

<p>5.</p>

<p>The cout erred in sustaining the objection of the United States District Attorney to the evidence offered
by said petitioner to-wit a certified copy of a portion of the testimony of witness B.F. McElroy and witness
Joseph Craig which is refered to in the record and marked Exhibit B.</p>

<p>6.</p>

<p>The court erred in holding and deciding at the hearing of said petition that the court could not receive
evidence outside of the record for the purpose of showing that the Circuit Court Of The United States for the
District of Oregon had no jurisdiction to indict, try or convict the petitioner in that certain criminal
action wherein and wereby the said petitioner was tried, convicted and sentenced to life imprisonment.</p>

<p>7.</p>

<p>The court erred in not holding and deciding that the evidence offered by the petitioner showed conclusively
that at the time he was tried and convicted in said United States Circuit Court for the District of Oregon, he
was a full blood Indian and an allotte upon the Umatilla Indian Reservation in the State of Oregon and as such
was at said time a citezen of the United States and of the state of Oregon both civil and criminal and that
the said United States Circuit Court for the District of Oregon had no jurisdiction in said cause.</p>

<p>8/</p>

<p>The court erred in not sustaining the petition and issuing the writ of Habeas Corpus as prayed for.</p>

<p>R.J. Slater
   Attorney for petitioner and appellant</p>







</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>