<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<note>906 906</note>

<p>Territory of Washington</p>
<p>County of Pierce</p>

<p>Territory of Washington agt James Riley} Criminal Action</p>

<p>Return Comenced before A B Rabbesen J P on the 1st day of March A.D. 1861</p>

<p>This day comes now Mow Jette Lo Who make Oath in writing 
and say that on the night of the 28th of February 1861 James Riley did 
in a rude and insolent manner unlawfully Strike and beat one 
A. Loe and likewise on same night he Jame Riley did make an 
assault upon an Indian woman named Emma with intent to 
commit a rape, and further says on Same Evening he said Riley did 
in a rude and unlawfull manner did touch and push deponant 
and further more that he the said Riley did in a rude and 
threatening Manner is in Crowd of two or more persons Exhibit a 
pistol and bower knife, and at Same time he Riley did feloniously 
take steal and carry away on Silver Watch from the Hotel Kept 
by this deponant and that the value of said watch is fifteen dollars 
and that the same was the property of A. Loe and demand that said 
Riley be dealt with according to law. Whereupon was Issued a 
writ for the arrest of Said Riley and the Same placed in hands of Sheriff 
Tucker for Service. Same day Comes Sheriff and makes return of writ 
by bringing prisoner into Court and he the said Riley being arrained 
and charge read to him pleads not guilty and say that he is ready 
for trial but the Court being of the Opinion that he the said Riley 
was not in a condition to proceed with the examination ordered 
that the Case he continued until next day in being the 2nd day of 
March at 11 oclock A.M. and he the said Riley gave bonds in the 
sum of One Hundred dollars for his appearance at Court at Said time 
with James Hughes as Said and the Same was approved and a subpoena 
was filed at the request of defendant for nine persons</p>

<p>March 2nd 1861 12 oclock in Case Called and defendant asks to have 
the Case Continued as the principal Witness on the part of defendant is 
absent on account of Sickness in the family and it is not <unclear>porabe</unclear> for 
him said Witness James Hughes to attend and it was Ordered by the Court 
that the case be continued until Tuesday March 5th 1861 10 oclock PM</p>

<p> March 5th 1861 11 Oclock AM case called and defendant appears and 
by his attorney Geo Gallagher waves the examination and files with the 
Court a bond in the sum of two hundred dollars for his appearance

<note>over</note>

<pb...></pb...>

at the next setting of the District Court to answer with James Hughes 
and P. J Moores as <unclear>further</unclear> and the same was approved</p>

<p>A.B. Rabbesen J.P.</p>


<p>This certifies that the foregoing is a true Copy of the proceeding in the 
above entitled Cause as appears on the Docket in my Office</p>

<p>A.B. Rabbesen J.P.</p>

<p>Fee Bill</p>

<p>Justice Fees</p>

<p>Complaint 50</p>
<p>Affidavit 50</p>
<p>Writ 75</p>
<p>Subpoena 9 persons 2.00</p>
<p>Writing Bond 2.00</p>
<p>Approving bail 75</p>
<p>Adjornment by request of Deft 75</p>
<p>Approving bail 75</p>
<p>Transcript of proceeding sto D.C. 1.00</p>
<p>$7.00</p>

<p>Sheriff Fees</p>

<p>Service of writ and bringing deft into Court 1.75</p>
<p>Subpoena 7 persons 5.25</p>
<p>One days Attendance on Court March 2nd 2.00</p>
<p>" " " " " " 5th 2.00</p>
<p>$5.25</p>

<p>Witness Fees</p>
<p>D.b. Waldrors two days attendance 2.00</p>

<p>I certify that the above is correct</p>

<p>A.B. Rabbesen J.P.</p>

<p><gap>Territory</gap> of Washington agt James Riley</p>

<p>Transcript of proceedings before Justice Court</p>