<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0215.042">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chung Him and Seid Yam v. Henry M. White. Bond for Chung Him</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0215.042</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Chung Him and Seid Yam v. Henry M. White. Bond for Chung Him</title>
<date when="1920-07-14">July 14, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-07">July 1920</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Smiser, James A.</term>
<term>Collins, H. B</term>
<term>Mahony, H. B.</term>
<term>Heneghan, M. J.</term>
<term>Fedderson, H. L.</term>
<term>Winston, Wills. T</term>
<term>Strench, W. G.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Ketchikan, Alaska</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Him, Chung</persName>
<persName>Yam, Seid</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Corrigan, John L.</persName>
<persName>Winston, Will H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>U.S. Department of Labor</p>
<p>Bureau of Immigration</p>
<p>Washington</p>

<p>54321/147</p>

<p>August 28, 1920.</p>

<p>Inspector in Charge, Immigration Service, Ketchikan, Alaska.</p>

<p>The Bureau refers to your letter of July 23, No. 528/146. and advises that the bond(s) in the sum of 1,000.00 executed in behalf of the alien(s) named below has been approved by the Department.</p>

<p>Chung Him</p>

<p>Exact Copy as Signed by <supplied>Alfred Hampton</supplied></p>

<p>Mailed Aug 30 1920 by <unclear></unclear></p>

<p>Assistant Commissioner General.</p>

<pb/>

<p>54821/147</p>

<p>Bond</p>

<p>That the alien, Chung Him a native of China, who arrived at the port of Unknown, will be delivered for hearing or deportation.</p>

<p>Dated July 14, 1920</p>

<p>Amount, $1,000.00</p>

<p>Department of Justice</p>
<p>Office of</p>
<p>United States District Attorney</p>

<p>Juneau, <unclear>Alas</unclear> . July 19, 1920</p>

<p>Examined and approved as to form and execution.</p>
<p>James A <unclear>Smiser</unclear></p>
<p>U.S. Attorney.</p>

<p>By Jos. Y. Backston</p>
<p>Asst. U.S. Atty</p>

<p>U.S. Department of Labor</p>
<p>Bureau of Immigration</p>

<p>Aug 5 1920, 19</p>

<p>Respectfully referred, by direction of the Secretary, to the Solicitor for the U.S. Department of Labor for examination as to form and execution.</p>

<p>(Signed) Alfred Hampton</p>
<p>Assistant Commissioner General.</p>

<p>Solicitor Aug 6 1920</p>
<p>1-16124</p>

<p>Department of Justice</p>
<p>Office of the</p>
<p>Solicitor for the U.S. Department of Labor</p>

<p>Aug 9 - 1920, 19</p>

<p>Examined and approved as to form and execution.</p>

<p>H.B. Collins</p>

<p>Acting Solicitor</p>
<p>BWM</p>

<p>U.S. Department of Labor</p>
<p>Office of the Secretary</p>

<p>Aug 9 - 1920, 19</p>

<p>Correspondence</p>
<p>1920</p>
<p>11</p>
<p>Aug</p>
<p>Immigration</p>

<p>H.B. Mahony</p>
<p>Acting Secretary</p>

<p>Approved: Indexed</p>

<pb/>

<p>U.S. Department of Labor</p>
<p>Immigration Service</p>

<p>Bond Conditioned for the Delivery of an Alien</p>

<p>The Following Rules Must be Particularly Observed and Complied With:</p>

<p>1. This bond should be made and executed in duplicate.</p>

<p>2. The full name and the residence of each party to the bond should be stated in the body of the instrument, and the signatures, which should conform thereto, should be witnessed by two other persons, who should sign their names as witnesses and state their places of residence.</p>

<p>3. A wax or wafer seal must be affixed to signature of each party to the bond.</p>

<p>4. A married women will not be accepted on the bond.</p>

<p>5. All erasures and interlineations must be noted, word for word, immediately above the signatures of the witnesses, as having been made before execution of the bond. The general statement that "erasures and interlineations were made before execution" is insufficient.</p>

<p>6. The signers of the bond must justify in double the amount of the bond in the form for that purpose accompanying the bond.</p>

<p>7. The affidavits of the signers of the bond must be taken and subscribed before an officer authorized to administer oaths generally, who must certify that he administered the oath and affix his official seal. In case such officer is not provided with a seal, his authority to administer oaths and his official character must be duly certified.</p>

<p>8. A commissioner of immigration or an immigrant officer in charge must certify that the signers of the bond are good and sufficient and fully responsible to insure the payment of the entire amount of the bond. In the absence of officials designated on page 3 of this instrument.</p>

<p>9. On and after December 1, 1917, there should be attached to the original copy of each bond the documentary stamp required by the War Revenue Act of October 3, 1917.</p>

<p>Where a premium is charged for the execution of the bond the stamp should be in a sum amounting to 1 cent for each dollar or fractional part thereof of the bond a stamp in the sum of 50 cents is required. These stamps should be canceled when the bond is executed.</p>

<p>Where a premium is charged a notation should be made on the instrument stating the amount of such premium.</p>

<p>Know all Men by these Presents:</p>

<p>That we, M.J. Meneghan residing at Ketchikan, Alaska and H.L. Fedderson residing at Ketchikan, Alaska are held and firmly bound unto the United States of America, in the full and just sum of One thousand dollars ($1,000.00) to be paid to the United States, for which payment well and truly to be made, we, and each of us, do bind ourselves, our heirs, executors, administrators, successors, and assigns, jointly and severally, firmly by these presents.</p>

<p>Sealed with our seals and dated this 14th day of July, 1920</p>

<p>Whereas, Chung Him, an alien, aged 65 years, a native of China, who arrived at the port of unknown per S.S. unknown on the 15th day of June, 1916, has under the provisions of section 19 of the immigration act of February 5, 1917, been placed under arrest on warrant of the Secretary of Labor, issued on the 3rd day of June, 1920, on the charge that he is unlawfully within the United States:</p>

<p>And whereas, pending the final disposal of his case the said alien desires to avail him self of the privilege of being released from custody accorded by section 20 of the said Act of Congress, and has applied to the immigration official by whome said warrant has been served for his release upon giving a proper bond or undertaking that he will deliver himself into the custody of the said immigration official or other proper immigration official representing the United States Government for hearing or hearings and for deportation in case he is found to be unlawfully within the United States:</p>

<p>Now, therefore, the condition of this obligation is such that if the above-bounden obligors, or either of them, shall, in case said alien is released from custody, cause the said alien to be delivered over to the said immigration official or other proper immigration official representing the United States Government for hearing or hearings in regard to the charge upon which, as above set forth he has been taken into custody, and if, in case the said alien, upon such hearing or hearings, is found to be unlawfully within the United States, and is for any reason released from custody pending issuance of a warrant of deportation or after said warrant has been issued and pending final</p>

<pb/>

<p>deportation, they or either of them at any time upon request, cause the said alien to be delivered into the custody of the said immigration official for deportation under the aforesaid warrant, delivery either for hearing or hearings or for deportation to be made upon request of the proper immigration official, and to be complete only upon acceptance of said alien by said immigration official, then this obligation to be void; otherwise to remain in full force and virtue.</p>

<p>Signed and sealed in the presence of-</p>

<p><unclear></unclear> R <unclear>Nickey</unclear></p>
<p><unclear>Wills</unclear> T. Winston</p>
<p><unclear>W.M</unclear>R Nickey</p>
<p><unclear>Wills</unclear> T. Winston</p>

<p>H L Fedderson</p>
<p>M J Heneghan<unclear></unclear></p>

<p>Oath of Signer of Bond</p>

<p><del>State</del> Territory of Alaska</p>
<p><del>Country</del> City of Ketchikan</p>

<p>ss:</p>

<p>M. J. Heneghan, being duly sworn, deposes and says that he is one of the signers of the foregoing bond in the case of the alien, Chung Him; that he resides at No. <gap></gap> street, in the City of Ketchikan, in the Territory of Alaska, and that the value of his property over and above all debts and liabilities incurred by him and exclusive of property exempt from levy and sale upon execution, is over $2,000.00 to wit, real estate situated at Lot Seven (7) in Block Twenty (20) present fair marked value of deponent's interest in which $10,000.00 and personal property consisting of goods and fixtures; that he is now liable upon no other bond, obligation, or recognizance, either as principal or surety, except as hereinafter stated: Immigration bond, $1,000, in the case of Somenuseke Saito.</p>

<p>Deponent further says that he is of full age and under no legal disability to execute the foregoing bond; and that he is not employed in the service of the United States Government in any capacity whatsoever.</p>

<p>M J Heneghan</p>
<p>Signature of Deponent</p>

<p>Sworn to and subscribed this 14th day of July, 1920, before me.</p>

<p><unclear>Wills</unclear> T. Winston</p>
<p>Notary Public</p>

<p>Notary Public for Alaska</p>
<p>My Commission Expires June 12, 1921.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Oath of Signer of Bond</p>

<p>Territory</p>
<p><del>State</del> of Alaska</p>
<p><del>Country</del> City of Ketchikan</p>

<p>ss:</p>

<p>H.L. Fedderson, being duly sworn, deposes and says that he is one of the signers of the foregoing bond in the case of the alien, Chung Him; that he resides at No. <gap></gap> street, in the City of Ketchikan, in the Territory of Alaska, and that the value of his property over and above all debts and liabilities incurred by him, and exclusive of property exempt from levy and sale upon execution, is over $2,000.00, to wit, real estate situated at Lot Six (6) in Block Twenty-One (21) present fair market value of deponent's interest in which is $3000.00; and personal property consisting of furniture &amp; fixtures; that he is now liable upon no other bond, obligation, or recognizance, either as principal or surety, except as hereinafter stated:</p>

<p>Deponent further says that he is of full age and under no legal disability to execute the foregoing bond; and that he is not employed in the service of the United States Government in any capacity whatsoever.</p>

<p>H L Fedderson</p>
<p>(Signature of Deponent)</p>

<p>Sworn to and subscribed this 14th day of July, 1920, before me.</p>

<p><unclear>Wills</unclear> T. Winston</p>
<p>Notary Public.</p>

<p>Notary Public for Alaska</p>
<p>My Commission Expires June 12, 1921.</p>

<p>Certificate of Solvency</p>

<p>I certify that I have made due and diligent personal inquiry as to the financial responsibility the signers of the foregoing bond and am satisfied that their representations as to their financial resources are true in every respect, and that they are good and sufficient and fully responsible to insure the payment of the entire amount named in the bond.</p>

<p>Witness my hand and seal this 14th day of July, 1920.</p>

<p>W G Strench [L.S.]</p>
<p>Signature of Certifying Official</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>