<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Territory of Washington
County of Spokane} 
In the District Court of the
4th Judicial district
holding terms at county
seat of Spokane County
Territory of Washington
vs.
Ray Raymond Defendant
Territory of Washington
County of Spokane W.T. Ray Raymond being first fuly
sworn on my oath state: I am defendant above
named and I am not guilty of the crime with which
I am charged in this indictment nor of any offense
therein contained against the laws of Washington
Territory. I believe I cannot have a fair trial of this
cause in the county of Spokane on account of and
owing to the prejudice and excitement against
me in and among the inhabitants of said County, and
I ask to be tried by disconnected triers. That
among the facts upon which such belief is 
founded I state the following:
I have a number of bitter personal enemies
in the city of Spokane Falls in said County, whom
am informed and believe, and upon such information 
and belief allege have ever since I was
accused of this crime busied themselves
industriously circulating false statements
purporting to be the facts retolding to this case
and also in circulating rumor and false
to the effect that I am a dangerous and quarrelsome
attention and given to the wonton and reckless
use of firearms, and so persistently has this
statement been made that many give people of the
county have come to believe it and to repeat it
as true; that many false and, malicious statement
and charges against this defendant have been
circulated among the inhabitant of said
county among which I am informed
and believe, and upon that information 
and belief alleges that since I was at
land of the crime it has been circulated 
among and is generally believed by
the people of the county, that I had therefore
murdered my husband and had
killed two men &amp; oen woman in
matters are of which are wholly false
but have tended greatly to excite any
prejudice the people of the court, against
and that many false and exagerated
and highly covered and prejudicial
account, purporting to be the facts
in this case have been invented
among the people of the court among
other false and untrue statements
purporting to be the facts in this case
circulated since I was accused of
this crime <del>was</del> is the following
I am informed and believe, and upon
such information and belief allege that
me George Turner, who appearing no
a special provention against me
at the hearing of the habeas corpus
application to admit me to bail
heard before this court affront the
thing of such having stated
That the prosecution
had witnesses to prove that at the
time of the killing with which I am
charged the deceased was in the hallway of the
"Bay Window" house and mar the door and that
two men had hold of him putting him
wit and had bereve him to his knees
and had hold of him and that this
applicant came out of her room with
a loaded and locked revolver and
said derive him did fix him
and thrusting the revolver in his
throat fixed the shot that killed him
applicant here states politely that such
statement of the facts in this and is
wholly untrue and alleges upon her information 
and belief that the prosecution never
at any time had any person who
cover &amp; swear his wavy part of it
many thing assembling it applicant 
is further informed and believes that this story was commendated
among the people of this county until
many good people came to believe it
to be the true statement of facts in
the case, and am greatly purporting against
defendant by name thereof that whether
or not said special prosecutor was 
employed against defendant volunteered
to prosecute for applicant does not know
but applicant has been informed and believes that
citizens of Spokane Falls attempted
to employ special council to be aid in
her prosecution.
Applicant further statesthat during the time of the
preliminary hearing of this case before justices
Peel and Booge she heard many expressions
of bitter prejudice against her from
among the crowd of people in attendance
and heard the crowd stomp their feet
in approval of the final determination 
of such <del>hearing</del> justices in holding
defendant for murder in the first degree 
without bail and during said
hearing refused many strong
manifestations of prejudice and
excitement against her and
was became alarmed for her own
safety, applicant has heard and the affidavit
of her attorney Thomas C. Griffitts heaving and
knows many of the facts therin stated concerning
the recurances at the preliminary hearing
before said Justices of her own knowledge,
and concerning the publications in
the newspaper therin referred to
and knows such statement to be true
and she reported said affidavit and
to the affidavit of her other comments
herein filed and to the other affidavit
filed in support of this justice force
were specific statement of the
facts and circumstances upon which she
bases her belief in the prejudice of the people
I have stated the facts and titleing my defenses
herin truly <del>and</del> fully to my council in this
cause and am among by there that I have a
good defense and me that can be made available
herein if I can have a fair trial; that this application 
is not made for delay but
in good faith and that Justice may be
one. Ray Raymond
Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 2nd day of Dec. 1886
J. Kennedy Stout
Notary Public
Wash. Terr.</p>
