<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0473.002"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla" xml:id="mg">Mikayla Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0473.002</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">September 2, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date>29 July 1899</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Denning, J. Henry</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>State of Washington</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Nordstom, Charles W.</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>Miller, John F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jacobs, Orange</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court Northern Division</orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.473.002"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p> IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE DISTRICT </p>
<p>OF WASHINGTON, Northern Division</p>

<p>In the matter of the Application of
Charles W. Nordstrom, for the Writ of
Habeas Corpus, Appearing by his next
friend, J. Henry Denning</p>

<p>PETITION FOR WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS</p>
<p>To the Honorable Judge of the Circuit Court of the United States
for the District of Washington, Northern Division:-</p>
<p>Your petitioner for relief by habeas corpus and for writ
therein most respectfully to the court, that,</p>
<p>I</p>
<p>Your petitioner J. Henry Denning avers that he is the friend of 
the said Charles W Nordstrom in whose behafl he petitions for relief
in habeas Corpus and for a writ of habeas corpus herein.</p>
<p>II</p>
<p>That the said Charles W. Nordstrom is a citizen of the United
States and a resident of the State of Washington, and is at present
confined in the county jail of King County, State of Washington, under
an alleged conviction of muder had in the Superior Court of the
State of Washington for King County, on April 2, 1892, and thereafter
various proceedings were had and judgement and final sentence of
death taken had against said Charles W. Nordstrom by the said 
Superior Court of the State of Washington.</p>
<p>III</p>
<p>And that they said Nordstrom was sentenced to death and to be
excecuted by the sheriff of said King County, and that subsequently
to-wit, on the day of 189, the said Charles W.
Nordstrom sued out a writ of habeas corpus before the Circuit Court
of the United States for the District of Washington, Northern Division,
claiming relief thereunder; saild reflief being denied by the said
Circuit Court, whereupon and thereafter said petitioner appealed said
Habeas Corpus proceeding to the Supreme Court of the United States;
said Sureme Court of the United States did on the day of 
189, dismiss the petition upon the ground that the matter was not
complete enough in the details of the pleading, in failing to set out with
proper certainty and preciseness the exact grounds upon which the
petitioner rested his contentions embracing the attempt to deprive
petitioner of his life without due process of law, particularly, in that
he failed to annex a copy of the indictment or information and to set
out the verdct in the case, both of which were subjects of complaint;
that thereafter the said court duly dismissed said petition and con-
firmed the order of the Circuit Court of the United States for the
State of Washington, and sent down to said Circuit Court of the
United States for the State of Washington its mandate on or about the 
8th day of March, 1899.</p>
<p>IV</p>
<p> That said mandate of the Supreme Court of the United States
specifically provided that the said cause of said petitioner was
returned to the said Circuit Court of the United States for further
proceedings therein to be had, to-wit, to be had in the Circuit Court
of the United States for the State of Washington according to the 
laws of the United States and according to justice on the permises. </p>
<p>V</p>
<p>That thereafter, to-wit, on the 15th day of May, 1899, the said
Superior Court of the State of Washington for King County assumed to
take jurisdiction of the petitioner befire any final judgment had been
made by the said Circuit Court of the United States for the State of 
Washington upon said petition and in accordance with the mandate of 
the Supreme Court of the United States, and without any order having
been made by said Circuit Court of the United States, or by any proper
order whatsoever in the premises either transferrng the said cause to 
the said Superior Court of the State of Washington, or releasing and
relieving itself of jurisdiction of said peitioner Charles W. Nordstrom
</p>
<p>VI</p>
<p>That the said petitioner Charles W. Nordstrom by his friend duly 
made objection to the Superior Court of the State of Washington for
King COunty, to-wit, the Hon. Orange Jacobs, Judge, taking jurisdic-
tion therein in anywise whatsoever, for that, to-wit, the said petition-
er had the right to proceed n the said United States Circuit by appro-
priate amendment amendng his petition to conform to the opinion of the
Supreme Court of the United States, in the cause given and rendered in 
that certain case, entitled, Charles W. Nordstrom v. The State of
Washington, based upon the opinion and reasons of that other certain
case of Carner v. State of Washington, both petitions being similar
in letter, words, paragraph and subject matter.</p>
<p>VII</p>
<p>That said Superior Court of the State of Washington for King County 
assumed to take jurisdiction over the objections of said petitioner,
and did proceed, notwithstanding, to exercise said jurisdiction to the 
exlusion of the said Circuit Court of the United States against the
objection and protest of said petitioner and his friend, to which due
exception was taken, which exception was allowed and preserved in the
record of said cause.</p>
<p>VIII</p>
<p>The petitioner informed the court by affidavit and by due presen-
tation of the record that sad question of said petitioner's federal
rights in the Federal Court was still undisposed of, which said 
affidavit was duly filed and duly presented before the said Hon. Orange
Jacobs, Judge of the said Superior Court of the State of Washington for
King County, and the said federal question was therein fully stated,
wholly and completely, as more fully appears by reference to the
record on file in the Superior Court of the State of Washington for 
King County, which said objection to the said jurisdiction to said
jurisdiction were in the words as appears in exhibit "a" to this 
peition, which exhibit is made a part of this petition for reference.</p>
<p>IX</p>
<p>Your petitioner further alleges that notwithstanding said objec-
tion and said question being raised, that said Superior Court of the 
State of Washington for King County proceeded to take jurisdiction of
the person of petutuiner and sentence him to death, to-wit, to die on
the 11th day of August 1899, to be hanged by the sheriff of said King
County; that from said conduct and action of said Judge of the 
Superior Court of the State of Washington for King County said
petitioner did duly appeal to the Supreme Court of the State of Washing-
ton claiming relief and exemption upon his said ground of his federal
rights and previleges as therein set fort; that the Supreme Court of 
the State of Washington did on the 24th day of July, 1899, deny to the
said petitioner relief, and did decide the said federal question and
conention against the interests of said pettioner and adverse to his 
contention, and did refuse the relief prayed for, and did affirm the
condcut and action of the said Superior Court, to-wit, the judgement of
the said Hon. Orange Jacobs in overrulung the obections of said
petitioner to the jurisdiction of his court, and did overrule and deny
petitioner's petition for relief upon the ground that under the 
federak kaw and the Consitution of the united States that said Auperior
Court had no jurisdiction of the cause and of the petitioner, for that, 
to-wit, the said Circuit Court of the United States for the State of
Washington alone and only held and had jurisdiction of the Retitioner
in anywise whatsoever y any proceeding whatsoever authoriaing the 
State court to take jurisdiction of the person of the said Charles W.
Nordstrom in anywise whatsoever.</p>
<p>X</p>
<p>The the said Supreme Court of the State of Washington in so de-
ciding against the contention and claim of right of said petitioner
denied him his rights under the Constituion and laws of the United 
States, and decided contrary to petitioner's rights under the con-
stitution of the United States, and against the laws of the United
States, and in violation of the laws of the United States and to the
detriment of petitioner's interests and against the life of petitioner
and contrary to the Constitution of the United Stat es and the laws thereunder.</p>
<p>XI</p>
<p>Your petitioner further showeth that previous to the 15th day of
May, 1899, to-wit, on March the 18th, 1899, prior to and previous to 
the Superior Court taking jurisdiction of said Charles W. Nordstrom,
Your petitioner J. Henry Denning as the friend of the said Charles W.
Nordstrom did duly by affidavit make known to the court a fact which 
has ever since remained, and is now a factm that the said Charles W.
Nordstrom gas subce tge verdict and judgmebt against him, become insane,
that he was of unsound mind, that he was demented and crazy, that he
was unable to present to the court in his own behalf any fact or factsw
which might go to the amelioration of his sentence or the avoidance
of the execution thereupon. That he was in such condiction of mind as
to be unable to prepare himself for the event of death, and was in
such a state of mind as to make the act inhuman that would take his 
life by process of law or otherwise, that the said Chares W. Nordstro m
was wholly irrespnsible in mind, and for a long time prior thereto
has been and was then a subject for the insane asylum, being crazy
and insane.</p>
<p>XII</p>
<p>That the petitioner did ask that a hearig be had for the said
Charles W. Nordstrom, that said hearing be judicial, that said hearing
be legal, that petitioner did pettion that all proceedings against the
said Charles W. Nordstrom be stayed until such legal hearing could be
had, that said Charles W. Nordstrom be permitted such a hearing, and 
particularly, for such a hearing as would enable him to produce witness-
es and those acquainted with his condition by whom it could be demon-
strated annd established that he was of such unsound mind as to exempt 
him from furtherprocess of the law, and to exept him from any other or
further process of the courts looking to his inoaroeration as criminal and of taking his life as such.</p>
<p>XIII</p>
<p>That said court delined and refused to grant to the said Nordstrom
a legal hearing either by jury or by legal comission in open court
whereat and at which time the said Nordstrom would have the opportunity 
through his friend to establish his mental condition. That said peti-
tion was sustained by affidavit and by evidence tendered to the court
from impartial, reliable, trustworthy, and wholly creditable sources
who has knowledge and information absolute as to the condition of the
mind of the said Nordstrom, yet, nevertheless and notwithstanding,
the said court refused to grant the said Nordstrom an opportunity of
presenting witnesses in his behafl through his friend or in anywise
in order to establish at a legal hearing in open court or to a jury
or before the court upon a trial his real mental condition or to
establish his said insanity. </p>
<p>XIV</p>
<p>That subsequently the said court nevertheless proceeded upon the 
statement that the said court was satisfied and did proceed notwith-
standing theinformation of the affidavid informing the said courtof
the insanity of the said Nordstrom; and your petitioner durther showeth 
that said affidavid was in nowise denied denied by the said court or
the Prosecuting Attorney of King County or by any person whomsoever by
any written form of denial from any sourse whatsoever that the said
Nordstrom was insane as claimed by oru pettioner in behalf of the 
said Nordstrom.</p>
<p>XV</p>
<p>The the said Hon. Orange, Jacobs, Judge of the Superior Court of
the State of Washington for King County did insist upon naming a day 
for the execution of the said Nordstrom, and did, notwithstanding the h 
showing and representations, name the 11th day of August, 1899, as 
the time for taking the life of the said Nordstrom by the 
sheriff of King County, Washington.</p>
<p>XVI</p>
<p>There is no statute in the State of Washington prescribing
offence of murder in the first degree and murder in the second degree.
That the verdict returned against your petitioner is in words follow-
ing, to-wit:
</p>
<p>State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintiff,</p>
<p> -vs-</p>
<p>Charles W. Nordstrom,</p>
<p>Defendant.</p>
<p> "We </p>
<fw type="footer"> &amp;</fw>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>