<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0215.023">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chung Him and Seid Yam v. Henry M. White. Bond for the Release of Jung Him</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0215.023</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Chung Him and Seid Yam v. Henry M. White. Bond for the Release of Jung Him</title>
<date when="1922-06-24">June 24, 1922</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1922-06">June 1922</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Williams, A.V</term>
<term>Williams, Lillian</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Him, Chung</persName>
<persName>Yam, Seid</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Corrigan, John L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>

<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-03" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>No. <supplied>5630</supplied></p>

<p>In the District Court of the United States</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Jun 24 1922</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<p>B and S 2-P.71</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 5630</p>

<p>Bond For the Release of Jung Him</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Jung Him et al for a writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>KNOW ALL MEN BY THESE PRESENTS, that we Jung Him, as principal, and A.V. Williams and Lillian Williams, of Seattle, Washington, as sureties, jointly and severally acknowledge ourselves to be indebted to the United States of America, in the sum of one thousand dollars ($1,000.00), lawful money of the United States, to be levied of our goods and chattels, lands and tenements, upon this condition;</p>

<p>Whereas, on the 6th day of December, 1920, the said Jung Him was by the judgment and decree of this court ordered released and discharged from the custody of the United States Commissioner of Immigration, Luther Weedin; and whereas, the said Luther Weedin (but by his predecessor in office, Henry M. White), has appealed from said judgment and decree to the Circuit Court of Appeals, and by an order of this court, dated December 6, 1920, it was provided and directed that said Jung Him be released from custody upon the furnishing of a good and sufficient bond in the sum of $1,000.00, to be approved by the United States District Attorney;</p>

<p>NOW, THEREFORE, if the said Jung Him shall submit himself to the custody of the said Luther Weedin, as Commissioner of Immigration, whenever he shall be directed so to do by the Circuit Court of Appeals, and shall abide by and perform any order, judgment or decree that may be made by said Circuit Court of Appeals from time to time, then this recognizance to be void; otherwise to remain in full force and effect.</p>

<p>A V Williams</p>

<p>Lillian Williams</p>

<pb/>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 24 day of June, 1922.</p>

<p>Gordon Mifflin</p>

<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle</p>

<p>United States of America, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</p>

<p>ss</p>

<p>A.V. WILLIAMS and LILLIAN WILLIAMS, being first duly sworn, according to law, on their oaths, respectively, do say, each for himself and herself, that he is one of the sureties who signed and sealed the within bond; that he is above the age of twenty-one years; that he is a bona fide resident of the State of Washington, and property holder therein; that he is neither a counselor nor attorney at law, Sheriff of a County, Clerk of Superior Court, nor other officer whatever of any court whatsoever; and that he <add>each</add> is worth the full sum of $3000.00, over and above all his debts and liabilities whatsoever, exclusive of property exempt from execution.</p>

<p>A V Williams</p>

<p>Lillian Williams</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 24 day of June, 1922.</p>

<p>Gordon Mifflin</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle</p>

<p>The foregoing bond approved this 24 day of June, 1922.</p>

<p><unclear></unclear><unclear></unclear></p>
<p>Assistant United States Attorney</p>

<p>The foregoing bond approved this 24 day of June, 1922.</p>

<p>Neterer</p>
<p>Judge.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>