<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0221.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chin Quock Wah vs. Henry M. White.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0221.005</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-03">March 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Beeler, Adam</term>
<term>Boyle, John M.</term>    
<term>Chin, Quock Wah</term>
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Cushman, Edward E.</term>    
<term>Lakin, Edward M.</term>
<term>Sargent, John H.</term>
<term>Sullivan, John J.</term>    
<term>Wainwright, Morton D.</term>
<term>White, Henry M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Chin Quock Wah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Adam Beeler</persName>
<persName>Sullivan, John J.</persName>    
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Edward E. Cushman</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-03" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE WESTERN 
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of 
Application of Chin Quock
Wah, for a Writ of Habeas
Corpus )
No. 2971
ORDER TO SHOW CAUSE.</p>

<p>The above named Petitioner having made application
to this Court for Writ of Habeas Corpus, by and through Adam 
Beeler, of the Law Firm of Beeler &amp; Sullivan, attorneys and 
counsellors for the said Petitioner, address to the United 
States Commissioner of Immigration, Henry M. White and to 
such other person or persons, agent or agents, acting by, 
through or under him, or in behalf of the United States Government, 
in whose custody the Petitioner is shown by his petition
to be confined and restrained of his liberty and to be ordered 
deported, as alleged in his petition illegally and unwarranted
and without power and not under virtue of or by authority of
the Statutes of the United States, and the Court being fully
advised by Beeler &amp; Sullivan, counsel for the said Petitioner.</p>
<p>IT IS NOW THEREFORE ORDERED, that the United States
Commissioner of Immigration, Henry M. White, in and for the 
District of Washington in charge of the Immigration Station 
and Detention House at Seattle, S tate of Washington, and such 
person or persons acting under or through the said Henry M. 
White, said Commissioner of Immigration and in behalf of the
United States Government, having the custody of the said 
Petitioner Chin Quock Wah show cause before this Court at the
Courtroom at the Federal Building in the City of Seattle on the
15 day of March, 1915, at 10 - o'clock in
the AM. why said application should not be granted, and in
the meantime, the United States Commissioner of Immigration
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
Henry M. White in and for the District of Washington in 
charge of the Immigration and Detention Station at Seattle, 
Washington, as well as such other person or persons who 
are acting under and through you, refrain and desist from 
deporting or placing, and removing said Petitioner Ching 
Quock Wah, from the said District of Washington, or carrying
into effect any warrant or order for his deportation which 
may be held by you or either of you.</p>
<p>IT IS FURTHER ORDERED that said Chin Quock Wah
either by himself or through his attorney Adam Beeler, 
of the Law Firm of Beeler &amp; Sullivan, within five days give 
over to the United States Commissioner of Immigration, Henry 
M. White, in charge of the Immigration Station at Seattle, 
Washington, such amount as he may demand as a fund for the
keeping of said Chin Quock Wah until said action of this Court
in hearing said petition or until such further action of the
Government in relation to his case is considered, which sum
shall not exceed the sum of $100.00.</p>
<p>IT IS FURTHER ORDERED that a certified copy of 
this order shall be served upon the Honorable United States
Commissioner of Immigration, Henry M. White, or such person
or persons acting by or through him or in behalf of the United 
S tates in connection with the Immigration Station at Seattle, 
Washington, or any such Government official in charge of said
Chin Quock Wah, Petitioner, on or before the hour of 10
o'clock aM, of this 4 day of March, 1915, 1915.</p>
<p>Done this 4th day of March, 1915.</p>
<ab>Edward E. Cushman
JUDGE</ab>

<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
<p>FORM No. 282.</p>
<p>RETURN ON SERVICE OF WRIT.</p>
<p>United States of America,
Western, District of Washington, } ss:</p>
<p>I hereby certify and return that I served the annexed Habeas Corpus, 
<gap/> on the therein-named Henry M White, 
United States Commissioner of Immigration,
<gap/>
by handing to and leaving a true and correct copy thereof with John H. Sargent,
<gap/> personally
at Seattle Washington, in said District on the 4th, day of 
March, , A.D. 1915.</p>
<ab>John M Boyle.
U.S. Marshal
By Morton D. Wainwright
Deputy</ab>
<p>Marshals Fees $2.30
7―279</p>

<p><add>Original</add>
<del>COPY</del>
No. 2971</p>
<p>GOB-5-853</p>
<p>IN THE 
<del>SUPERIOR</del> <add>UNITED STATED DISTRICT</add> COURT
<del>STATE OF WASHINGTON</del> <add>WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</add>
<del>KING COUNTY</del>
<add>NORTHERN DIVISION</add></p>

<p>UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT 
    OF AMERICA. 
Plaintiff
vs.
CHIN
QUOCK WAH
Defendant</p>

<p>ORDER TO SHOW CAUSE</p>

<p>BEELER &amp; SULLIVAN
Attorneys for Defendant. 
510-11 WHITE BUILDING
SEATTLE, WASH.</p>

<p>2X
FILED IN THE
U. S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington,
NORTHERN DIVISION
MAR5-1915</p>
<ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk,
By EML Deputy</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>