<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0187.025">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.187.025</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1914">1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-05">May 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Buntline, Ned</term>
<term>Gaboriau, Emile</term>
<term>Grayson, Marie Robina</term>
<term>Kock, Paul</term>
<term>Turner, Charles A.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Everett, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Marie Robina Grayson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Noah Shakespeare</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
    <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>Attorney and Counsellor at Law</p>
<p>Everett, Wash., May 21, 1914.</p>
<p>n.g.</p>
<p>Chas. A. Turner, Esq., 
U. S. Immigration Inspector, 
Everett, Washington.</p>

<p>Dear Sir:</p>
<p>I have to acknowledge receipt of record in re Marie Robina, 
alian Lena Mitchell, deportation proceedings, which since I last saw 
it has had attached certain communications from Immigrant Inspectors 
Barbur, Barker, and Fisher which I have read. Such communications are 
attached I presume for the purpose of giving information to the Department
which will affect its action in the matter of its decision in this 
deportation case.</p>
<p>It is probably true that in matters of this kind the same rules 
of evidence do not apply as in Common Law Courts, but as far as my 
knowledge goes I have never known that all rules of evidence had been 
abolished in proceedings of this kind, and that the impressions, surmises, 
guesses and dreams of Inspectors at divers places would have conferred 
upon them the dignity of evidence.</p>
<p>The sole and only issue in this case is whether or not Marie 
Robina was a citizen of the United States at the time of her arrest 
January 24th, 1914.</p>
<p>The communications from the different Immigration Inspectors 
might make an interesting chapter in a work of the character of Gaboriau 
of Paul Kock, or possibly the world renowned series of Ned Buntline's 
Five Cent Detective series, but when any higher degree of literary merit 
is claimed for them it undoubtedly appears that the party so claiming 
is in gross error.</p>
<p>The Department of course will bear in mind that these various 
effusions result apparently of div rs brai n s torms in these officials
while they assert no fact positively, do state a number of conjectures,
surmises and guesses, and that the party most affected by these various 
lucubrations has had no opportunity to meet them.</p>
<p>It is supposed that the Department will brush aside as mere 
teeming fancies the matters which are beside the real question, and will 
not allow such things to affect its determination in any regard whatever, 
where the civil rights of the party are determined under the Constitution 
and the Laws enacted in pursuance thereof.</p>
<p>Respectfully submitted,</p>
<ab>(Signed) Noah Shakespeare, Attorney for Respondent, Marie Robina</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>