<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0117.017"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Lelah-Puc-ka-Chee and Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha v. W.G. Malin and G.N. Nellis. Brief and Argument of Petitioners</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0117.017</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Lelah-Puc-ka-Chee and Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha v. W.G. Malin and G.N. Nellis. Brief and Argument of Petitioners</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1899-12">December 1899</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>James, W.A.</term>
<term>Lamb, Jacob W.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Kansas City</term>
<term>Toledo, Iowa</term>
<term>United States</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Malin, W.G.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Nellis, G.N.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Lamb, Jacob W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Shiras, O.P.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court in Northern District Iowa</orgName> 
<placeName>Toledo, Iowa</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="sab">transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0117.017"/> 

<p>are promptly carried out. That is they shall promptly place such children in the Government Boarding Schools and carefully provide for <del/> them suitable boarding, lodging clothing, books and teachers,&amp;,&amp;,</p>

<p>But the law is that just as soon as these refuse to keep their children in these Schools or just as soon as the parent withdraws consent just so soon, the General Government looses the power to compel the children of such Indians to return and remain in such Schools, and the defendants herein, servants of the General Government can have no greatre powers, I am quite anxious to see the distric attorney,s
 brief in support of and to sustain his idea or argument" That the defendants have almost unlimited power, that is to seize by force and hold and educate and in short do that which the General Government itself cannot do. The facts in this case are that the conduct of the defendants toward these Indians and force and compulsion used in getting and holding them in this Indian School. In which they are encouraged, crowded, madly farward by an ungovernable local prejudice is not only illegal in itself, but is also seriously retarding rather than aiding the policy of the General Government in following the way and the only way opened to even attempt to educate and civilize the Indians.</p>
<p>The General Government does not and never has asserted any authority over the Indians Except as founded upon their consent,
U,S, VS Imoda 4Mont- 38</p>
<p>WA James Comissioner report of 1898 <unclear>Grages</unclear> 175&amp;180</p>
<p>All of the cases and statutes above cited fully support the three principal complaints therein made, and further fully show the policy of the Federal Government has ever been consistent and in harmony therewith, and furthermore no instructions have ever been sent to any Indian agent or U,S, Indian School Superintendent but what have been carefully drawn and given in harmony therewith.</p>
<p>There are several cases reported wherein Indian Agents and U,S, Indian School-Superintendents, neglecting to read these laws and instructions, they have ignored and disregarded the objections of Tribal Indians to send their Tribal children as well as the refusal of the parents or next of kin thereof to give their consent to send such children to these Government School and have attempted by proceedings in courts such as Habeas-Corpus proceedings to get possession of such children thereunder and compel their attendance in this legal and the only proper way to try and test same and have failed in the courts.</p>
<p>But these defendants, failing perhaps to read these laws and above Statutes and their instructions as they first should have done, and perhapse encouraged and flattered by an unreliable and dangerous local prejudice, have rashly pushed out into the field of imaginary powers vested in them much further than any thing yet recorded in the law-books and much further than the Federal Government, itself, has ever ventured.</p>
<p>That is these defendants have for months had gathered around them a gang of scrub-Indian-Police created by themselves, for the express purpose of forcibly taking holding and confining a small minority of these Indian children in this Toledo Indian school against the determined will and consent of such Indians and their <sic>patents</sic> and next of kin, aided at times by threats of imprisoning those parents for simply hanging on to their children while being torne from them, and at other times revolvers have been drawn to aid and intimidate such parents into an involintary consent. And when in some cases parents have fled with their children from their reservation to avoid capture these same Scrub-police have followed captured and forcibly locked them in this School.</p>

<p>JW Lamb atty for Petitioners</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
