<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0471.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Salfest A. Sylvester v. Stener S. Wennaas. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>


<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Salfest A. Sylvester v. Stener S. Wennaas. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1899-06-26">June 26, 1899</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1899-06">June 1899</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Davine, Joseph M.</term>
<term>Rogers, J. R.</term>
<term>Jenkins, Will D.</term>
<term>Alling, H.</term>
<term>Moyer, William H.</term>
<term>Vandeventer, A. T.</term>
<term>Murphey, James B.</term>
<term>Matthew, H. M. </term>
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Traill County,North Dakota</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sylvester, Salfest A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Wenaas, Stener S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Albertson, R. B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>McElroy, James F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Circuit Court of the United States for the District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>District of Washington, Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-09" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<ab>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, Northern Division.</ab>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of 
Salfest A. Sylvester for a Writ of
Habeas Corpus.</p>

<ab>No.
PETITION FOR WRIT OF HABEAS
CORPUS.</ab>

<p>To the Honorable C. H. Hanford, Judge of the above entitled Court:</p>

<p>Comes now the petitioner, Salfest A. Sylvester, a citizen of the
United States and a resident of the State of Washington, and respectfully 
represents to the court as follows:</p>

<p>That he is now confined as a prisoner in the county jail of King
County, State of Washington, and that to the best of his knowledge he
is not committed or detained by virtue of any process of law known to
the courts of the United States, or of the several States, but that
he is so detaied and restrained of his liberty in violation of the
Constitution and of the laws of said government, and in violation of
the Constitution and laws of the State of Washington, and that he is
not held in confinement by virtue of any final judgment or decree of
any competent court or tribunal or constituted authority, or by virtue
of any process issued upon any valid judgment, decree or warrant, and
that he is so held without due process of law.</p>

<p>That the facts concerning his detention as aforesaid and the
claim of authority by virtue of which he is so restrained of his liberty
are, to the best of his knowledge and belief, as follows:</p>

<p>That on or about the 26th day of December, 1898, your petitioner
was taken in custody by one Stener S. Wennaas, claiming to be an
agent appointed by the Governor of the State of North Dakota for the
purpose of siizing your petitioner as a fugitive from the justice of
said State of North Dakota under a demand made, as he alleges, by the
Governor of the State of North Dakota upon the Governor of the State
of Washington for the extradition of your petitioner from his said</p>

<p>-1-</p>

<pb/>

<p>present place of residence to said State of North Dakota, that said
Stener S. Wennass further claimed at that time, and still claims, to be
entitled to the custody of your petitioner for the purpose of extraditing 
him as aforesaid under and by virtue of a pretended warrant
issued by the Governor of the State of Washington, <del>of which the following
is a copy:</del> of which the following is <unclear></unclear></p>

<ab>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.
STATE OF WASHINGTON.
EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENT.</ab>

<p>To all to whom these presents shall come, greeting:</p>

<p>WHEREAS, it has been represented to the by His Excellency
Joseph M. Davine, Governor of the State of North
Dakota, the Salfest A. Sylvester stands charged in said State
with the crime of embezzlement committed in the County of
Traill in said State, and is a fugitive from the justice of said
State, and has taken refuge in the State of Washington;</p>

<p>AND WHEREAS, the said Governor of the State of North
Dakota has pursuant to the Constitution and laws of the
United States demanded of me that I cause the said Salfest
A. Sylvester to be arrested and delivered to Stener S. 
Wenass, agents authorized to receive him into their custody
and convey him back to said State of North Dakota;</p>

<p>AND WHEREAS, said representation and demand are accompanied
by affidavits, complaint, informatin, indictment
and warrant whereby the said Salfest A. Sylvester is charged
with the said crime, and being a fugitive from the justice of 
the said State and having taken refuge in the State of
Washington, which are certified by said Governor of North
Dakota to be duly authenticated.</p>

<p>NOW THEREFORE, I J. R. Rogers, Governor of the State of
Washington, do hereby authorize and empower Stener S.
Wenaas, the agent named in said demand, to take the said
Salfest A. Sylvester wherever he may be found in this State,
and transfer him to the line thereof at the expense of the
State of North Dakota.</p>

<p>And I hereby command all civil officers within said State
of Washington to afford all needful assistance for the execution
of this warrant.</p>

<p>IN TESTIMONY WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand
and caused the seal of the said State of Washington to be
fixed at Olympia, this twenty-sixth day of December, A.D.
1898.</p>

<ab>J. R. ROGERS.</ab>

<ab>By the Governor,
WILL D. JENKINS,
Secretary of State.</ab>

<ab>By H. ALLING,
Chief Clerk</ab>

<p>That acting under said pretended warrant and in his capacity as
such pretended agent, the said Stener S. Wannaas, placed your petitioner
in the county jail of said King County, Washington, in the temporary
custody of the sheriff of said county, who was then one William
H. Moyer, pending the proposed removal of your petitioner to the said
State of North Dakota.</p>

<ab>-3-</ab>

<pb/>

<p>That the said Sterner S. Wennaas is now in the City of Seattle,
in said King County, State of Washington for the purpose of forceably
removing your petitioner against his will from the State of Washington
to the State of North Dakota, and that he will do so forthwith unless
restrained by the order of this court, and that your petitioner is
now being held by A. T. Vandeventer, who is now the sheriff of said
King County, State of Washington, in response to the demand of said
pretended agent, <del>who is agent of the said Sterner S. Wennaas.</del>
and who is the agent of said Sterner S. Wennaas</p>

<p>That your petitioner has never had a valid determination of his
rights in said matter by the courts of the State of Washington.</p>

<p>That your petitioner is so held in custody in violation of the
Constitution and laws of the United States and without legal process,
for the reason that he is held under a claim arising out of the Constitution
of the United States and th extradition laws thereof, and
that the provisions of said Constitution and laws have been violated
and disregarded in the following respects:</p>

<p>1. Because the Governor of the State of North Dakota in his
alleged demand upon the Governor of the State of Washington did not
accompany the same with documents suc as required by the extradition
laws of the United States, and because it does not appear from said
demand and the documents accompanying the same that your petitioner
stands charged before any court of the State of North Dakota with the 
commission of any crime against the laws of said State, and because it
does not appear therefrom that your petitioner is a fugitive from the
justice of said State.</p>

<p>2. Because your petitioner is not a fugitive from the justice of
said State, and because he is not guilty of any crime against said law</p>

<p>3. Because the said extradition warrant to issued by the Governor
of the State of Washington does not state facts sufficient to warrant
the arrest and detention of your petitioner.</p>

<ab>-3-</ab>

<pb/>

<p>4. Because said warrant is void on its face for the following
reasons:</p>

<p>(a) It does not appear therefrom that your petitioner was
actually present in the State of North Dakota when the alleged embezzlement 
referred to in said warrant was committed.</p>

<p>(b) Because it does not appear from said warrant that your petitioner
stands charged with treason, felony, or any other crime, in
that, it does not appear from said warrant that there is any statute
in the State of North Dakota defining embezzlement and making it a
criminal offense, and because no proof was submitted to the Governor of
the State of Washington of the existence of any such law.</p>

<p>(c) Because said warrant does not state facts sufficient to
constitute any act of embezzelment or any other crime, <del><unclear>either</unclear></del> under
the laws of the State of Washington, or the State of North Dakota.</p>

<p>(d) Because said warrant recits that the representations and 
demand of the Governor of the STate of North Dakota were accompanied by
"affidavits, complaint, information and indictment," and it does not
appear therefrom what was the particular form of accusation upon
which the Governor of the State of Washington issued his warrant, and
because it does not appear therefrom that said Governor issued his
warrant upon affidavit, complaint or information made before a magistrate
of the State of North Dakota.</p>

<p>5. That your petitioner is not guilty of the alleged offense of
embezzelment.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, to be relieved of said unlawful detention and
imprisonment, your petitioner prays that a Writ of Habeas Corpus issue
directed to the said Sterner S. Wennaas and A. T. Van devanter, may
issue in this behalf, so that your petitioner may be forthwith brought
before this court to do, submit to and receive waht the law may require.</p>

<ab>S A Sylvester
PETITIONER.</ab>

<ab>R B Albertson
Atty for Petitioner</ab>

<ab>-4-</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>United States of America,
State of Washington,
County of King.</ab>

<ab>ss.</ab>

<p>Salfest A. Sylvester, being first duly sworn, on his oath
deposes and says: That he is the petitioner named in the above and
foregoing petition; that he has read the same, knows the contents
thereof, and that the statements therein made are true, as he verily
believes.</p>

<ab>S A Sylvester</ab>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 26th day of June, A. D. 1899.</p>

<ab>James B Murphey</ab>
<ab>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle. </ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Tx</ab>

<ab>No. 776</ab>

<ab>In the Circuit Court
OF THE 
UNITED STATES
District of Washingtion, Northern Division</ab>

<ab>In the Matter of the
Application of Salfest A. Sylvester for a 
writ of habeas corpus</ab>

<ab>Petition for H C Writ
<del>Order to Show Cause</del></ab>

<ab>Filed this 26th day
of June 1899

A. Reeves Ayres Clerk.
By HM Matthew Deputy</ab>

<ab><del>Jas. Hamilton Lewis,</del>R B Albertson
Attorney for Petitioner</ab>

<ab>Office-FIFTH FLOOR, PIONEER BLOCK
Corner First Act. and James St. SEATTLE, WASH.</ab>



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>