<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States, for the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division</p>
<p>In the matter of the Petition of
Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo
Sugiura, alias B.K. Sugiura,
aliens, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus | #2628
Petitioners' reply brief</p>
<p>Argument</p>
<p>We shall take but little issue with counsel for the Government,
upon the "RULE" and the "REASONS FOR THE RULE", bu which the
Court is limited in this sort of proceeding, to the one question of
whether or not the petitioners had a fair and legal hearing; and if
so, whether there is, in the record, any evidence to sustain the
charge.</p>
<p>While such hearing need not be in accordance with every 
rule of criminal proceedure, yet there are a few fundamental rules,
which a sense of propriety and common justice would dictate as necessary;</p>
<p>(a) There must be some definite and specific offense charged, 
bringing the alien within the excluded class, in order that he may
have an opportunity to meet it upon the Government warrant to show
cause why he should not be deported;</p>
<p>(b) There must be a hearing on that specific charge:</p>
<p>(c) There must be some evidence adduced which amounts to legal
evidence, tending to prove this specific charge;</p>
<p>(d) There must be a finding by the proper authorities, which
finding, in order to be legitimate and sufficient, must be based on
and fairly deducible from this evidence. A finding which is clearly
arbitrary, that is not fairly deducible from such evidence, that is
based, rather, upon the opinion of some Inspector or other official, 
<fw>1</fw>
<pb/>
to the exclusion or in disregard of the evidence or one which is 
arrived at by reason of extraneous circumstances arising subsequent
to such hearing, or upon findings based upon some alleged offense
other than the one charged in the orginial Warrant, cannot be sustained
as a fair and legal hearing; and if such is the case here, it
is the duty of the Court to sustain the Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>Our contention here is that the petitioners did not have a 
fair and legal hearing for the following reasons:</p>
<p>1. The Warrant of Arrest, which reads as follows:
"Warrant - Arrest of Aliens
That the said aliens are unlawfully within the
United States in that they have been found assisting,
protecting, or promising to protect from arrest, a
prostitute or prostitutes."
does not definitely charge them with any specific act amount to a
violation of the Immigration Act.</p>
<p>2. The Warrant for Deportation, which reads as follows:
"Warrant - Deportation of Alien
That the said aliens are unlawfully within the
United States, in that they have been found assisting
a prostitute and protecting or promising to protect
from arrest, a prostitute, and may be deported
in accordance therewith."
does not find them guilty of any specific act amounting to a violation
of the Act.</p>
<p>3. There was and if absolutely no evidence in the record what-ever,
which can be regarded as legal evidence, tending to prove them
guilty of the violation attempted to be charged.</p>
<p>4. The postion now taken by counsel for the Government in
his Brief, and which was announced by him for the first time at the
hearing on this Habeas Corpus, and which is evidently based upon the
letter of opinion of Mr. J.B. Denamore, Solicitor, appended to and
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
as a part of his Brief, not only takes us by surprise, but is clearly
a subsequent idea, and is an adroit and desperate effort, after failing
on the first, to convict petitioners in some other offense than 
that in the original Warrant, upon which the hearing was had.</p>
<p>In United States v. Sibray, 178 Fed. pp. 148 and 149,l the 
Court says:</p>
<p>"I am constrained to hold that the charge is not sufficiently
specific. It is not required that the warrant of
arrest should have the formality and particularity of an
indictment, but it should give to the alien sufficient information
of the specific act or acts which bring him within
the excluded classes, so that he can offer testimony in refutation
of the charge at the hearing directed to be had by 
the warrant of arrest in pursuance of the act of Congress
and the rules of the department. What woman is he charged
with importing and for what immoral purpose? Was he convicted
of or did he admit the commission of a crime? Was
it a felony or other crime or misdemeanor involving moral
turpitude? If either, which was it? By paragraph "b",
Rule 35, as has been seen, a fully statement of the facts
must be the basis of the warrant. It is contemplated therefore,
that facts, and not conclusions, must be set forth in
the warrant.</p>
<p>The hearing provided for should be according to established
precedent, because that is contemplated by the act
and regualtions.</p>
<p>There is no finding that any particular felony, crime, 
or misdemanor prior to entry was admitted.</p>
<p>I have gone over the testimony taken by the inspector,
and do not find any evidence that the relator was convicted
of or admits the commission of any offense which can be
embraced within the general language of the warrants."</p>
<p>Then can be no doubt, from an inspection of the record,
that the said hearing on the Warrant of Arrest was solely and only
upon the theory that petitioners had rendered assistance and protection
to some prostitute in avoiding arrest. There never was any other
idea or charge, either inferentially or otherwise, and no other evidence
adduced, than on this one ground. The very letter of information 
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
of Thos. M. Fisher, Inspector (see record) recommending this
arrest clearly shows this one idea and intention; he says:</p>
<p>"In the view of the facts above mentioned, it would seem to
me that noth of these parties are subject to deportation,
on the ground that they assisted a prostitute and promised
to protect her from arrest."</p>
<p>The charge in the Warrant of Arrest and in the Warrant of Deportation
and all the evidence adduced thereon, clearly indicate this one
charge of assisting a prostitute from arrest (see also,k letter of 
Ellis de Bruler, Commissioner of Immigration, to the Commissioner
General, dated November 11, 1913, on thee lower third of page 2 thereof),
which reads as follows:</p>
<p>He thus refers to the evidence of Ito and Umeda on this point only.</p>
<p>The announcement of counsel for the Government at the hearing
of the Habeas Corpus, coming, as it did, frankly and voluntarily,
that he had carefully searched through the record in the Immigration
proceeding in this case, and failed to find an evidence upon which
the Warrant for Deportation could properly be based upon said ground 
of assisting from arrest, was not a surprise to us, because, we likewise,
were unable to find any such evidence. But the subsequent announcement
of councel, raising for the first time in this Habeas Corpus
proceeding, the question of construction or meaning of the words,
"who in any way assists", as used in the Immigration Act and Warrant
of Arrest and for Deportation, claiming that said words were not to
be construed with the rest of the setence in which they are used,
but that Congress really meant and intended to carve out another offense,
and provide against the same, than that of assisting from
arrest, came as a complete surprise to us, and is clearly an effort
<fw>4</fw>
<pb/>
now to bolster up a failing cause, and catch the aliens upon some
other charge still more indefinite than the first, and upon which
they have not had a hearing.</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>