<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0162.120">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ray Raymond v. Territory of Washington.  Gillespie Testimony</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
<name n="Hidalgo, Emily" xml:id="eh ">Emily Hidalgo</name>
<name n="Ham, Bethany" xml:id="brh">Bethany Ham</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0162.120</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ray Raymond v. Territory of Washington. Gillespie Testimony</title>
<date when="1886-06-29">June 29, 1886</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term>June 1886</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Raymond, Ray</term>
<term>Gillespie, W. D.</term>
<term>Lynch</term>
<term>Stanley, Ruby</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Spokane County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Raymond, Ray</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Peel, J. J. L.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Fourth Judicial District</orgName>
<placeName>Spokane County, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#lkw">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2021-07" who="#eh">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">
        
<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0162.120"/>
<p>
Territoru of Washington
County of Spokane}ss.
</p>

<p>
Territory of Washington
    vs
Ray Raymond
</p>

<p>
W. D. Gillespie sworn
I hold the office of Policeman in Spokane
Falls I know the Defendant Ray Raymond
and where she lives, have been a
Policeman two months and a half
I was at her residence on the
Morning of the 26th of June and saw
the dead body of a man and heard a
a pistol prior to that.
</p>
<p>
    On the morning of the shooting
I was at the California house and
heard the shot Have found the
First shot <unclear>Bark</unclear> I see the door
of the slut house open and looked
to me like a man laying in the
hallway and some one being
over him    I ran down to the slut
house found a man lying 
there in the door I asked what
the trouble was, of the defendant she
stated she had shot at the man and
said she didn't <unclear>shoot</unclear> him I
went to work to see if he was <unclear>there</unclear>
pulled down his shirt in front and
told her she had shot him sh
said O My God have I shot
him; at the time I got there she
</p>
<pb/>
<p>
was asking some one to bring water
</p>
<p>After I told her that the man was
shot she told me that they were in the
middle parlor taking a drink and
that one of the Girls got up and went
to the door and say who is in
the hall of said door and looking
and in the hall says O Ray there
is a man in the hall and Ray got
up and went out into the hall and 
asked the man what he was doing there
and ordered him to leave, he said
he would not, and struck at her and
tried to close the door she stepped
into her room and took a pistol
out of the drawer came back and
asked the man if he would go now
said he would not and struck at
her, and she pulled up the gun
and fired, </p>
<p>
<del></del> Witness requested
to make a diagram of the Hall + rooms
in the building where the homicide
<unclear></unclear> and gave a verbal discription
of the premises    The man was laying
in the North hall with his <add>head</add> lying near
the out door part of his body in the
in the entrance way one leg - the
hall inside the inner door   the door
on the right is where she says the weak
light was burning in the Hall
</p>
<pb/>
<p>
As a general thing you could see
one through the slut   The slut
was skinny
</p>

<p>
I did not pay particular
attention <add>when the man was shot</add> but as near as I can recall of
right side of the neck near the coller bone
the man was alive after I got there
but did not seem concerning I
was in the middle parlor of the house
at the time of his death
</p>
<p>
I arrested the defendant and took
the pistol from her witness exhibit pistol
three loaded chambers now and two empty
4 shells is one shell empty <add>the pistol now is in <unclear>stact mailier</unclear>in which I recind it</add>
</p>
<p>

The man had large features
large nose about 38 years old
possible 40 he had a a dark
checkered coat no rest a can wool
or collar shirt blue Overalls Boots
wone for wear - left Boot hole = top
where big toe would come his
nose prick marks at large  Color of hair
Brown</p>

<p>
Cross Ex
</p>

<p>
Had a very long moustache
between sandy &amp; dark gray tanery drooping
no hat on, coat on. as stated before
dark checkered gray collar or the
shirt lucid = front blue overalls
one leg rolled up whith left leg
<del>shoulder</del> not say if any are donee
anything with the chlothes or not
overalls seemed soiled
</p>

<pb/>

<p>
Had no beard other than moustache
</p>
<p>
A man should Judge would
weigh 150 to 155 medium height
a man about as tall as Judge Peel
little taller <del>larger</del> man then the Hart Lad
a very large nose and prick marked
His coat was new did not
notice any dirt on it
</p>

<p>
I was in the Bar room the
California I House <unclear>still doing</unclear>
close to the side door a the
west when I heard the shot
</p>

<p>
Then I ran <unclear>downhill</unclear> across
the street and was with 20
feet when I saw the light in
the slut building  I spoke to
some one in the California house
as I ran out    when I saw
the light in the slut building and
not see any one coming seem
to me I did see some one on
the street but do not know who it
was   saw no one ahead of seen
some one behind me   Door
was entirely ajar when I saw the
light in the slut building the door
of the <add>body</add> <del>man</del> was entirely ajar the Mans
Body would prevent it from doing
</p>

<p>When I first saw the door ajar
saw the same person was leaning
over him as when I arrived at</p>

<pb/>

<p>
at the door    It was the defendant
something less than a minute <unclear>spared</unclear>
after I heard the shot until I got there
The deft was asking some one to
bring watter or why the did not bring
water   She seemedin the act of
trying to give relief to the man
she was excited and was <unclear>laughing</unclear>
her head and asked me of he was
hurt and said she had shot at him
but did not think she had hurt him
</p>

<p>
She adressed me first and asked
him of towards a couple of minutes
afterwords when I told hershe had
shot him she told me she did not
instead to shoot him she was trying
get some one to give him some whiskey
so as to revive him  Shortly after
I got there I think one of the Girls
from the House brought some water the
first thing after I got there I asked
her what was the trouble and she
replied that she shot at him or the
man <unclear>I seen not shot what the she said</unclear>
him or the man - His head laying the
only N. E. corner, on his back with his
face up his ehad pressed forward <unclear></unclear>
the wall one of his legs one way &amp; one angled
up - Bunam Set
</p>

<p>
She said after stated her she had
shot the man O. My God have I
shot him  She showed considerable
feeling
</p>

<pb/>

<p>
threw up her hands and began
crying going from one room to
the other - all she had to do was
to go from <del>one room</del> <add>the hall</add> to the <del>other</del> <add>adjourning room</add> to get
whiskey   I followed near all the
time she did not by to get any
she was very much excided and saying
did not make any effort to except
was about 2 10 4 minutes - before I
got <del>to do</del> the Revolver The First thing
I and been <del>to do</del> <add>look</add> to see if the man
was hurt when I got up from the man
I asked for the Revolver   She was
standing just on the inside of the door
in the middle Parlor I asked  her for
the Revolver she says here it is and
took it from somewhere in her dress
</p>

<p>
I was on the left side of the body
when I got up to get the Revolver- she
could see me in an a the body of the
man  This occupied only a few
minutes   She told me this a few
minutes after, she told me she asked
him to get out he replied he would
not go out, did not at that or
any other time <add>before the coroner <unclear></unclear> </add> tell me that he said 
he be <unclear>dead</unclear> if he would go out
</p>
<p>
I did not swear before the coroner
Jury that she told me that she had
told him to go out and he said he be <unclear>dead</unclear>
if he would go out  I am trying
</p>

<pb/>
<p>
to give her exact words <del>and there if</del>
I told him to go out were all their
words I referred it was the outside
door that was referred to <add>that she was inside the door </add> She has said
he struck at her from what I
understood he only struck at her
 and before she got the revolver, she
said she got the revolver from
a drawer in her <add>Burnam in her</add> hand she said
she came back and ordered him out
again he then struck at her and
she then raised the revolver and
fired did not say he struck her
 on the right shoulder did not swear
so before coroner jury
</p>

<pb/>

<p>
No one arrested 
at the scene with me <unclear>until</unclear> one
Came in about a minute- I think her
Lynch helped me to open his shirt
and examine the wound and was
inside the vest in le with- me Lynch
a small man with dark moustache
I <unclear>meant</unclear> to keep people out I did
not close the outer door, after the
door was closed I tried to keep
People out say <unclear>50 less</unclear> minutes-
When I got there I saw no one but
Ray in the Hall saw one of the
Girls think it was Ruby Stanley
in the middle parlor door.
</p>

<pb/>

<p>
had seen the man that was killed
before about Mr Burnes place at the door going in or in about
Lelf over before Burnes place is a saloon at that time I was
<del>going into B</del> coming out of Banres
he was going in I noticed he 
was a stranger in the place paid
no particular attention to him
</p>

<p>
He was not drinking when I
saw him but had the appearance
of having been drinking acted
as though he had a little aboard
</p>

<p>
I saw him on the street just before
dark was in a crowd same three or <unclear></unclear>
did not know them, know Johnny
May <unclear>be 188</unclear> by sight do not know
whether he had been with the man
before he was murdered <unclear></unclear>heard
he was  I <unclear>subpoenaed</unclear> him 
to appear at this examination on the
part of the Territory the same
</p>

<p>
I have told all as far as I <unclear>remember</unclear>
about the case
</p>

<p>
ReDirect
</p>

<p>
The mans coat was new the front clean
did not see the back    should Judge the overalls
&amp; shirt had been worn same time and
were soiled   I was the first man that
 mached the house after I heard the shot
I saw at the house Defedant and
</p>

<pb/>

<p>
Ruby Stanley 
and herself said 
in the middle parlor
</p>

<p>Defendant mentioned the Girl
there were two Gentlemen
drinking together
Pub hall <add>about</add> 4 feet Deft</p>

<p>
Body extended nearly to the outer door
for towards door body nearly in hall
When I first got there she was
<del></del>swinging her hands over him after
I told her the man was shot she <unclear>may felt</unclear>
considerable feeling  Her demeanor
was after the manner of one very much
excited She related circumstances four
times   I stated an first examination twice
vaired such time added to each
time she told is    I believe that the
last couple of times she told <add>it</add> she was more case about did not any cannot retell
what new facts she told except it
was little different than before    Hall
was lighted when I looked down after the 
shot    Believe the south <add>hall</add> is the customary
entrance but they use both
</p>

<p>ReCross</p>
<p>
I know the character of the House
House is a house of public character
one that gentlemen frequent at all
times of the night      Suppose they ask
for permission to enter if door is
closed they cannot enter without asking
when I go I ring the bell each time
she told a little more <add>that is added a little more to the story</add> she surround
that night, third &amp; fourth <unclear>malt</unclear> after
serving     after I got there saw
</p>

<pb/>

<p>
Ruby Stanley &amp; Ray only
    I told her where the man was 
dead these accounts were told by
her before I told her man was dead
</p>

<p>ReDirect</p>

<p>
She was sooning about three minutes
she threw up her hands <unclear>gan way</unclear>
and did not seem to have conciousness
when she came to she came to she went from room
to room     She swooned after stated
her <unclear>must</unclear> arrest her same 5 minutes
she swooned on the Road to Mr Gilespies
<del>and</del>
</p>

<p>ReCross</p>

<p>
<del>I dont know</del> Dont know the
immediate cause of swooning, and
was given her to <unclear></unclear> from a room
by putting water in her face
</p>

<p>ReDirect</p>

<p>
Saw the body of the man after he
was dead and know he was dead
Transactions I have described took
place -   Spokane Falls, <add>Spokane County</add>Wash TY
</p>

<p>
I and a say <unclear>to</unclear> man
when I saw him before this occurance
was under the influence of liquor
seemed to be very quiet and peacable
</p>

<p>
Think there is a Bell on the door at the
North Hall
</p>

<p>ReCross</p>

<p>
No one called my attention to
the man in the afternoon
W. D. Gillespie
</p>

<pb/>

<p>
Subscribed and sworn to before me on this June
29th 1886
J.J.L. Peel
Justice of the Peace
</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>