<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0183.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Gwoo Shee Ah Look v. United States. Judge's Statment.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0183.004</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Gwoo Shee Ah Look v. United States. Stipulation.</title>
<date when="1914-04-29">April 29, 1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2647GwooSheeAhLook</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-04">April 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Gen, Chin You</term>
<term>Chuck, Lim</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Look, Gwoo Shee Ah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Frye, Jesse A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wilbur</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Spencer</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, George P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Bean, R. S.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>


</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States
for the District of Oregon.</p>
<p>In re Chin You Gen, Petitioner.
Portland, Oregon, Monday, April 20, 1914.</p>
<p>R.S. Bean, District Judge. (Oral):</p>
<p>The Petitioner is a Chinese woman, married to and
the wife of one Lim Chuck. She was ordered deported by the
government authorities on the ground that she was engaged in
prostitution, and she brings this proceeding to obtain her discharge,
asserting that she was not accorded a full and fair
hearing by the Immigration authorities.</p>
<p>It appears that she and her husband were apprehended
by the police officers in this city in a raid made by them November
4, 1913. The Inspector of the Immigration service at Portland was
notified of the arrest, and on the day named visited the City Hall,
took a statement from the Petitioner and from her husband, neither 
being present when the statement of the other was made, and then
Petitioner was thereupon, by the Immigration Commissioner, ordered
confined in the City Jail where she was kept in close confinement,
denied the right to interview her friends or her attorney, or to
communicate with any one except by authority of the Commissioner
until the 10th of November, although the Commissioner was notified
that she had an attorney who desired to communicate with her.</p>
<p>On November 10th, some six days after her arrest, she 
was again taken before the Commissioner, notified that she would
have a hearing and that she was entitled to an attorney if she
desired one. Her statement was again taken by the Commissioner and
<pb/>
reduced to writing. She cannot speak English and all her statements
were made through an interpreter employed by the Immigration
service. After this statement was taken on the 10th of November,
her attorney was allowed to consult with her, but on the 17th of
November, seven days later and after she had been accorded the
service of an attorney, the Inspector took the testimony of the
two police officers who made the arrest, and the vital testimony
upon which the order of deportation was based, without her presence
or the presence of her attorney, and denied the right of her counsel
to be present at the hearing or to cross examine the witnesses. Her
counsel thereupon requested the privilege of producing witnesses to
testify before the Commissioner on her behalf and this was denied,
but he was advised that he might submit affidavits from these
witnesses or parties whom he desired to call, and the Commissioner would
then determine whether or not in his judgment the testimony was material
and should be made a part of the record.</p>
<p>The record as thus made up, without the Petitioner being
present at any of the examinations and being represented either in
person or by counsel, was transmitted to Washington, and based upon
that the order of deportation was issued.</p>
<p>Now, the enforcement of the Immigration Laws is vested by
Congress in an Executive Department and the action of that Department
is not reviewable by the courts unless it is made to appear that
the proceedings is maufestly unfair and the action of the officers
such as to prevent a fair investigation, or that there was a manifest
abuse of the discretaion committed to them by the Statute. In
all other cases the courts have held that the order of the Executive
Officers within the authority of the Statute is final and that the
<pb/>
courts cannot review their findings nor disturb their proceedings.</p>
<p>Now, the rules of the Department have provided that upon
the receipt of the warrant of arrest an alien shall be taken before
the person or persons therein described and granted a hearing to 
enable him to show cause, if any, why he should not be deported,
and during the course of the hearing the alien shall be entitled to
inpect the warrant of arrest and all the evidence on which it is
issued, not at such stage thereof as the Immigration Officers may
deem proper, shall be permitted the advice and assistance of course
and if counsel is seelected, the rules provide that he shall be
allowed to present during the further conduct of the hearing, to
inpsect the record, make copy of the minutes of the hearings so fasr
as they may have been presented, and to offer evidence to meet any
evidence theretofore at thereafter presented by the government.</p>
<p>The only question in this case is whether the Petitioner was
accorded such a hearing and in my judgment she was not. The Immigration
Authorities under the decisions of the court and the rules
of the Department, any conduct such preliminary investigation as they
may deem wise or proper, may take such statements of parties prior to
the formal hearing as they may deem expedient without the presence
of the alien and without the alien being represented by counsel, but
at some stage of the proceedings, before the warrant of deportation
issues, the rules prescribe and common consideration for the rights
of an individual demand that the alien shall have an opportunity to
present such evidence as he may have to show that he is not within
the meaning of the law and should not be deported, and that the right
was denied the Petitioner in this case. After she had been accorded
by the Commissioner the right and privilege of counsel, her counsel
<pb/>
was denied the right to be present at any of the hearings, to 
cross examine any of the witnesses, or to produce anty witnesses on
behalf of the Petitioner, except that he was permitted to submit
such affidavitss as he could procure, and these affidavits were
transmitted as part of the record.</p>
<p>Now, in the United States vs Sibray, 178 Fed. 144, it was
held that the hearing provided for by the rules contemplated a
hearing at which an alien is allowed to be present, to confronted 
with the witnesses against him and to have full opportunity to cross
examine, and such was the decision in Hanges vs. Whitfield, 209 Fed.
and is the effect of Roux vs. Commissioner, 203 Fed. The doctine
seems to be that no person can be deprived of his liberty and deported
without an opportunity to show his right to remain and to
present such evidence to the officers whose duty it is to pass upon 
this evidence.</p>
<p>"Now, the warrant of deportation was issued by the authorities
at Washington based upon the record as made up before the Commissioner
and it seems to me that under all the authorities and under all the
rules of procedure the Petitioner in this case should have been allowed
to have appeared wither in person or by counsel, at the proceedings
which took place after she had been accorded counsel, and that was on
the 10th of November, but notwithstanding that the Commissioner took
the testimony of the two material witnesses without the presence of
the Petitioner and denied the right of ehr counsel to be present at
that hearing, and that, it seems to me, was a violatic of the rules
prescribed by the Department."</p>
<p>The Petitioner is entitled to her discharge.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>