<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0208.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ichitara v. Henry M. White. Discharge of Order</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0208.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ichitara v. Henry M. White. Discharge of Order</title>
<date when="1919-12-18">December 18, 1919</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1919-12">December 1919</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Yow, Chin</term>
<term>Toy, Ju</term>
<term>Singh, Moola</term>
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Tia Juana, Mexico</term>
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Matsutsuyo, Ichitara</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wardell, Ray M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Moore, Ben L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-01" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>No. <supplied>4918</supplied></p>

<p>In the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Dec 18 1919</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Lietch Deputy</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 4918</p>

<p>Filed Dec. 18, 1918.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Ichitara Matsutsuyu to be Released on Habeas Corpus:</p>

<p>Robt. C. Saunders, U.S. Attorney,</p>
<p>Ben L. Moore, Ass.U.S. Attorney,</p>
<p>For Government.</p>

<p>Ray M. Wardall, Attorney for Ichitara Matsutsuyu.</p>

<p>NETERER, District Judge,</p>

<p>The petitioner was arrested pursuant to a warrant of the Secretary of Labor, charged with being an alien found in the United States in viiolation of the Immigration Act, in that he was likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry. A hearing followed. At the hearing, the petitioner was represented by counsel. He was further charged with having been convicted of a crime involving moral turpitude subsequent to the Act of February 5, 1917. No formal objection was made against the consideration of this charge, and time was given to present such testimony as was desired.</p>

<p>It appears that the petitioner entered the United States through the Port of San Francisco in 1906. On June 1, 1917, he went to Tia Juana, Mexico, where he was for a short time, and reentered the United States. On June 9th following, he was arrested, charged with smuggling Japanese boys into the United States from Mexico. He was tried, convicted, and sentenced to the penitentiary for two years. He was ordered deported upon both charges preferred.</p>

<p>The petitioner seeks release on the ground that he has been a resident of the United States for thirteen years; that at the time of his arrest, he was engaged in a profitable business in the United States; and that the second charge was preferred without authority or warrant of law, and that he was denied a fair hearing. The court's jurisdiction is to determine whether a fair hearing was accorded. If so, the petition must be dismissed. Chin Yow v. U.S., 208 U.S. 8: U.S. v. Ju toy, 198 .S. 253; Ex parte Moola Singh, 207 Fed. 780.</p>

<p>Did the re-entering into the United States constitute an entry within the purview of the Immigration Act? The solution depends upon the legislative intent of the Congress. The power of Congress over the alien is unlimited. It may admit without limitation, or exclude without reason; or prescribe rules for admission, or rules of conduct after admission.</p>

<p>The decision of the Federal Courts are not in harmony. The trend of the decisions, however, hold<del>s</del> that a re-entering after a temporary absence, is within the purview of the Act. While not deciding, the Supreme Court in Lapina v. Williams, 232 U.S. 78, I think, supports that view. The Circuit Court of the 6th Circuit, in Frick v. Lewis, 195 Fed. 693, discusses the issue, and holds a re-entry after a temporary absence of one hour to be a re-entry under the Act. In that case, the petitioner had been a resident of the United States for some time; had declared his intention to become a citizen; went into Canada for an hour, and returned, and was, thereafter, ordered deported. The court declined to release him. The same issue was presented to the same court in Sinincalchi v. Thomas, 195 Fed. 701, where it adhered to this view. In the Frick v. Lewis case, the petitioner was charged with crime, but the indictment returned was not res adjuticata on the deportation proceedings. In the instant case, the petitioner was returning into the United States not from a lawful errand in Mexico, but in the consummation of acts offensive to the Immigration Act.</p>

<p>On the question of the additional charge, it is sufficient to say that under Subdivision 4, Rule 23 of the Immigration Rules, (b), it is provided that:</p>

<p>"If during the hearing it shall appear to the examining inspector that there exists a reason, in addition to those stated in the warrant of arrest, why the alien is in the country in violation of law, the alien's attention shall be directed to the facts which constitute such reason, and he shall be given opportunity to show cause why he shall not be deported therefor."</p>

<p>There was, therefore, no irregularity in the preferring of the second charge, and all the time required was given for the presenting of testimony. A fair hearing was given.</p>

<p>The order to show caue is discharged.</p>

<p>Jeremiah Neterer</p>
<p>Judge</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>