<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0268.015">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ernest Hutchinson v. City of Seattle. Brief. </title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Tecca, Lauryn" xml:id="lnt">Lauryn Tecca</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0268.015</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ernest Hutchinson v. City of Seattle. Brief.</title>
<date when="1904">1904</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1904">1904</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hutchinson, Ernest</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>City of Seattle</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#lnt">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT OF THE NINTH
CIRCUIT, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.</p>

<p>In the matter of the petition of
ERNEST HUTCHINSON
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>No. 1183
Brief of Petitioner</p>

<p>Our first proposition is that a license means a permission
to do something certain in the way of a permission to do
a thing that otherwise would not be lawful, Therefor a license 
is that which circumscribes, regulates, restrains and gives the
right to control and prohibit. The poliy therefore of license is
to have under control and to that extent duress: to prohibit that
which might otherwise be a public nuisance or a public evil. Outside
of that the police power has no right to go. When it goes
beyond regulating, controlling or prohibiting that which is <del>not</del> a
nuisance or a public evil or which threatens to become a public 
wrong, the authority that grants the license exceeds its constitutional
power.</p>

<p>Therefore we have endeavored to present succinctly to Your
Honor the reasoning of the Courts along the lines here propounded
and as we believe <del></del> the constitutional lines upon which the question
of the constitutionality of the ordinance presented in this 
cause must be decided.</p>

<p>We first cite Your Honor to the following sections and
marginal headings.</p>

<p>Freund Police Power which is an entirely new work on this 
subject. We first the cite section 38:</p>

<p>S38. LICENSE AS A POLICE MEASURE. The license as a police
measure is properly only an incident to restraint or regulation
and should, therefore, not be upheld where there is no power to
restrain. Upon this principle an ordinance imposing a license fee</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>upon the owners of bicycles was declared illegal in Illinois, the
Court holding that the use of streets for private vehicles is as
much of a matter of common right as their use for walking on foot,
and that the charter power to regulate the use of streets cannot 
be made the foundation for a restraint upon the exercise of common 
rights except for specific purposes of order or safety. The ordinary
use of the wheel was held to justify no restraint upon this 
principle, and upon this theory the decision seems sound; for it
would not be maintained that a license might be required for walking
on the streets. Discriminative licenses may be justified by
the conditions of a business; thus it had been held that a municipal
corporation may impose license fees on meat shops kept outside
of the public market, since they require special supervision;
and licenses may be graded according to the amount of business done.</p>

<p>We next cite section 93.</p>

<p>S 93. RESTRAINTS UPON BUSINESS AND UPON PARTICULAR DEALINGS.
Certain classes of business may be placed under special control
because they furnish facilities for the commission of crimes or for
their concealment. Crimes may to some extent be prevented by properly
restricting the sale of weapons, poisons or explosives; and
their detection may be facilitated by a strict supervision of these
trades. The law, may, therefore, forbid the sale of poisons except
upon responsible prescriptions; and it may require the keeping
of registers showing every sale of weapons, with the name of the
purchaser. As stolen goods usually find their way into the hands
of pawnbrokers or dealers in second-hand goods, these trades may 
be kept under control by the requirement of a license by demanding
reports and authorising inspection. </p>

<p>Again we cite section 494.</p>

<p>S 494. LEGITIMATE GROUNDS OF RESTRAINT AND PROTECTION FROM
COMPETITION.   In <del></del> an earlier portion of this treatise the attempt
has been made to assign the various restrictions to the several 
heads of the police power, and it had been shown that they may be</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>reduced to the following classification: prevention of crime or
of its concealment (pawnbrokers, junk dealers), protection of
morals and order (liquor selling, public amusements), prevention
of fraud (peddlers, auctioneers, employment offices, insurance,
warehousing), and protection of health and safety (the great mass
of other restrictions.</p>

<p>It may be said that where none of these public interests comes
into play, there is no warrant for the exercise of the police power
but it must be asked whether this limitation gives adequate protection
to the principle of liberty. There are few trades that
cannot be exercised as to endanger in a remote degree health
and safety, or so as to expose the public to fraud. There are very 
few cases indeed in which restrictions will be avowedly based upon
the desirability of restraining competition on the part of free citizens
(the competition of convicts and of foreigners is met by legislation)
is no legitimate ground of state interference, for the greatest and 
most successful exertion of industry and genius by legitimate
methods cannot be regarded as detrimental of the public welfare.
Thus not attempt at legislation against department stores has been
successful. To prevent an abuse of the police power for the alleged
<del></del> protection of health or saefty or the alleged 
prevention of fraud, the courts must be allowed to judge whether
restrictive measures have really these ends in view. A remote abd
slight danger should not be <del></del> recognized as a sufficient ground
of restriction, and the provisions of the law should be scrutinized
in order to see whether they in reality tend to effectuate their 
object. By general consent the police power at present does not
interfere for these purposes. Even for the prevention of fraud only
these forms of business are restrained which present exceptional
facilities for imposition upon the public, or which invite the 
public confidence in an extraordinary degree. So for the protection</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>of morals as a rule only those pursuitsare controlled which have 
a notorious connection with vice or disorder.</p>

<p>This last citation states the law of the case and is a 
summary of the jurisprudence covering the matter of police power
in the administration of justice in the United States.</p>

<p>Here ia a harmless business; a harmless contract; a lawful
way of doing your business; and the general plan of trading
amongst business men. What is injurious; what is immoral; what 
tends to a nuisance; what in connection with the trade stamp business
tends to evil or crime; what is the thing that justifies 
restraint? Nothing. The business is lawful; the contract is lawful.
There is nothing in the contract or trade agreed to by the 
parties that justifies control or that tends to evil, immorality
or a public nuisance. There is nohing that endangers the public. </p>

<p>The Grocers' Association undertakes to control the business
of Seattle. It undertakes to say how you will carry on your 
business and if you do not fix the prices according to their schedule
you will be boycotted. Here is a more dangeroud association 
than anything in the trading stamp business as illustrated in this 
cause or in any cause that the courts have passed upon</p>

<p>It was for this association that the ordinance was passed.
To protect this association from the liberal use of printers' ink
and the right of contracting or advertising this ordinance was
passed. It was conceived in inquity and is kept on the statute
books for the purpose of doing wrong. In other words here are 
men engaged in conspiracy to keep up the prices of the commodities 
and get the council to pass an ordinance protecting them.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Thus the combine would prohibit the legislation competition
and to that extent so far as they could protect themselves by 
legislation - <del></del> prevent the engagement of others in business that would
interfere with their methods of trade.</p>

<p>This ordinance requires that $600.00 shall be paid by 
the man who comes in here to start up a business in trading stamps
as set forth in the petitioner's appeal for justice. From the 
man who enters into business with him is exacted $100.00. This 
he is restrained and prohibited from engaging in a legitimate enterprise
and lawful business as a competitor against the man in business who under
the rules of his association <del></del> fix and maintain prices or goods 
in this market.</p>

<p>With this we ask Your Honor to consider the following
authorities which we believe are decisive in this case.</p>

<p>We say that the matter presented to your Honor here
was not presented to the Supreme Court and if it had been presented
we believe that the decision would be different.</p>

<p>We also say to Your Honor that you are not bound by that
decision and upon this point we ask the consideration of the 
authorities submitted.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>UNITED STATES COURTS.</p>

<p>Comity between U.S. and State Courts</p>

<p>Exception as to General or Co mmerical Law.</p>

<p>This court will not follow State decisions which do not 
present a clear case of construction of a State statute, but
assert general principles. Venice v. Murdock, 92 U.S. 494, 23: 583.
Genoa v. Woodruff, Id. 502,23:586.</p>

<p>Where private rights are to be determined by the application
of common-law rules alone, this court does not feel bound 
by State decisions. Chicago v. Robbins, 2 Black, 418, 17:298.</p>

<p>Decisions of State courts are not binding upon questions
concerning contracts of insurance, those being questions of general 
commercial law. Carpenter v. Providence Washington Ins. Co. 16
Pet. 495. 10: 1044.</p>

<p>The courts of the United States are not controlled by the 
decisions of State courts in questions of general Commerical Law.
Brooklyn City, etc. R.R. Co. V. Nat.. Bank of Republic, 102 U.S.
14, 26:61</p>

<p>Boyce v. Tabb, 18 Wall. 546, 21:757.</p>

<p>Delmas v. Merchants Mat. Ins. Co. 14 Wall 661, 20:757.</p>

<p>The construction placed upon a State statute by the highest
court of that State, in a case where the decision did not necessarily 
involve the construction of the construction of the statute, is not binding
on this court. Carroll v. Carroll, 16 How. 275, 14: 936.</p>

<p>In deciding whether a State statute is uncontitutional as violating
a contract by the state, if the decision of the existence 
of an alleged contract requires a construction of the State Constitution
and laws, this court is not necessarily governed by previous 
decisions of the State Courts, except where they have been so firmly
established as to constitute a rule of property. Louisville
&amp; N.R.R.Co. v. Palmes, 109 U.S. 244, 27:922.</p>

<p>The decision of the State court, constructing a statute which
is claimed to constitute a contract, is not conclusive on the Supreme
Court of the United States, where there is a claim that it 
was a contract the obligation of which had been impaired. Wright
v. Nagle, 101 U.S. 791, 25:921. Jefferson Branch Bank v.
Skelly, 1 Black, 436. 17:173.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court will put an independent construction on the 
validity of a municipal ordinance, where the question involves its 
repugnance to the Constitution of the United States. Yick Wo v.
Hopkins, 118 U.S. 356, 30:220.</p>

<p>The nature of Taxation generally, what uses are public and
what are private, and the extent of unrestricted legislative power
are matter which, like questions of commerical law, no state can 
conclusively determine for this court. Olcott v. Fond du Lac County,
16 Wall. 678, 21:382.</p>

<p>Index for <unclear></unclear> (Laws, Ed.) vol. 1 - P.532-535
<unclear></unclear> 293. 492-494</p>

<pb></pb>

<p><del>In the matter of the application of Ernst Hutchinson for Writ 
of Habeas Corpus</del></p>

<p>Is ordinance No. 6036 of the City of Seattle void?
<note>City Code 423</note></p>

<p>Ordinance No. 6036</p>

<p>"An ordinance to license and regulate certain trades and occupations
in the City of Seattle, providing penalties for violation thereof
and repealing all ordinances inconsistent therewith."</p>

<p>"To license and regulate certain trades and occupations."</p>

<p>What are "trades and occupations"?
Wesbter says:</p>

<p>"Trade, n. 1. A track; a trail; a way; a path; also, passage; travel; resort.
2. Course; custom; practice; occupation; employment.
3. Business of any kind; matter of mutual consideration; affair; dealing
4. Specifically; the act of business of exchanging commodities by
barter or by buying and selling for money; commerce; traffic; barter.
5. The business which a person has learned, and which he engages in,
for procuring subsistence or for profit; occupation; especially,
mechanical employment as distinguished from the liberal arts, the
learned professions, and agriculture; as, we speak of the trade of a 
smith, of a carpenter, or mason, but not now of the trade of a farmer,
or a lawyer, or a physician.
6. Instruments of any occupation.
7. A company of men engaged in the same occupation; thus, booksellers 
and publishers speak of the customs of the trade, and are collectively 
designated as the trade.
8. pl. The trade winds.
9. Refuse or rubbish from a mine.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Syn. -Profession; occupation; office; calling; avocation; employment;
commerce; dealing; traffic.</p>

<p>Trade, v. i. 1. To barter, or to buy and sell; to be engaged in the
exchange, purchase, or sale of ggods, wares, merchandise, or anything
else; to traffic; to bargain; to carry on commerce as a business.
2. To buy and sell or exchange property in a single instance.
<del></del>
Trade, v.t. To sell or exchange in commerce; to barter."</p>

<p>What is occupation?</p>

<p>Webster answering this says:</p>

<p>"Occupier, n. 2. One who follows an employment; hence a tradesman.
Occupy, v.2. 1. To take or hold possession of; to hold or keep for
use; to possess.
2. To hold, or fill, the dimensions of; to take up the room or space
of; to cover, or fill; as, the camp occupies five acres of ground. 
3. To possess or use the time or capacity of; to engage the service
of; to employ; to busy.
4. To do business in; to busy ones self with."</p>

<p>Bouvier defines trade thus:</p>

<p>"Trade. In its most extensive signification this word includes
 all sorts of dealing by way of sale or exchange. In a more limited
sense it signifies the dealings of a particular business, as the 
India trade; by trade is also understoof the business of particular
mechnaic, hence boys are said to be put apprentices to learn a trade
as the trade of a carpenter, shoemaker and the like. Trade differs 
from art.</p>

<p>2. It is the policy of the law to encourage trade, and therefore
all contracts which restrain the exercise of a man's talents in trade 
are detrimental to the commonwealth, and therefore void; though he
may bind himself not to exercise a trade in a particular place, for,
in this last case, he may pursue it in another place, the commonwealth
has the benefit of it."</p>

<p>Let us now look into the constitutional phase of the case.
We will first examine its relation to the Constitution of the
State, and for aid in this examination we will cite such parts of the
State Constitution and of the State Law as we believe have any bearing
on the question before the court.</p>

<p>Here then we will first call attention to the provisions of the 
State Constitution.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Art I.</p>

<p>Declaration of Rights</p>

<p>S1. All political power is inherent in the people, and governments
derive their just powers from the consent of the governed, and are
established to protect and maintain individual rights.</p>

<p>S3. No person shall be deprived of life, liberty, or property without
due process of law.</p>

<p>S8. No granting irrevocably an privilege, franchise, or immunity 
shall be passed by the legislature.</p>

<p>S12. No law shall be passed granting to any citizen, class of citizens
or corporation other than municipal, privileges or immunities which 
upon the same terms shall not equally belong to all citizens
or corporations.</p>

<p>S29. The provisions of this constitution are mandatory, unless by
express words they are declared to be otherwise.</p>

<p>S30. The enumeration in this constitution of certain rights shall
not be constued to deny others retained by the people.</p>

<p>S32. A frequent recurrence to fundamental principles is essential
to the security of individual right and the perpetuity of free government.</p>

<p>Art. VII.</p>

<p>Revenue and Taxation</p>

<p>S1. All property in the state, not exempt under the laws of the
United States, or under this constitution shall be taxed in proportion
to its value, to be ascertained as provided by law. The legislature
shall provide by law for an annual tax sufficient, with other
sources of revenue, to defray the estimated ordinary expenses of the
state for each fiscal year. And for the purpose of paying the state 
debt, if there be any, the legislature shall provide for levying a 
tax annually, sufficient to pay the annual interest and principal
of such debt within twenty years from the final passage of the law
creating the debt.</p>

<p>S2. The legislature shall provide by law a uniform equal rate</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>of assessment and taxation on all property in the state, according
to its value in money, and shall prescribe such regulations by general
law as shall secure a just valuation for taxation of all property,
so that every person and corporation shall pay a tax in proportion
to the value of his, her, or its property; Provided, That a deduction
of debts from credits may be authorized; Provided further, That 
the property of the United States. and of the state, counties, school
districts, and other municipal corporations, and such other property
as the legislature may by general laws provide, shall be exempt from
taxation; And provided further, That the legislature shall have
power, by appopriate legislation, to exempt personal property to the
amount fo three hundred ($300.00) dollars for each head of a family 
liable to assessment and taxation under the provisions of the laws 
of this state of which the individual is the actual and bona fide owner.</p>

<p>S5. No tax shall be levied except in pursuance of law; and every
law imposing a tax shall state distinctly the object of the same to
which only it shall be applied.</p>

<p>S9. The legislature may vest the corporate authorities of cities, o
towns and villages with power to make local improvements by special
assessment or by special taxation of property benefited. For all 
corporate purposes, all municipal corporations may be vested with 
authority to assess and collect taxes, and such taxes shall be uniform
in respect to persons and property within the jurisdiction of the body 
levying the same.</p>

<p>Art. XI.</p>

<p>County, City and Township Organization.</p>

<p>S10. Corporations for municipal purposes shall not be created by
special laws; but the legislature, by general laws, shall provide for 
the incorporation, organziation and classification in proportion to 
population, of cities and towns, which laws may be altered, amended
or repealed. Cities and towns heretofore organized or incorporated
may become organized under such general laws whenever a majority of</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>the electors voting at a general election shall so determine, and
shall organize in conformity therewith; all cities or towns heretofore
or hereafter organized, and all charters thereof framed or adopted 
by authority of the constitution shall be subject to, and controlled
by general laws. Any city containing a population of twenty thousand
inhabitants, or more, shall be permitted to frame a charter for
its own government, consistent with and subject to the constitution
and laws of this state, and for such purpose the legislative authority
of such city may cause an election to be had, at which election there
shall be chosen by the qulified electors of said city fifteen freeholders
thereof, who shall have been residents of said city for a period 
of at least two years preceding their election and qualified electors,
who duty it shall be to convene within ten days after their election
and prepare and propose a charter for such city. Such proposed charter 
shall be sbmitted to the qualified electors of said city, and if a 
majority of such qualified electors voting thereon ratify the same,
it shall become the charter of said city, and shall become the organic
law thereof, and supersede and existing charter, including amendments
thereto, and all special laws inconsistent with such charter. Said
proposed charter shall be published in two daily newspapers published
in said city for at least thirty days prior to the day of submitting
the same to the electors for their approval, as above provided. All
elections in this ection authorized shall only be upon notice, which
notice shall specify the object of calling such election and shall
be given for at least tne days before the day of election, in all
election districts of said city. Said elections may be general or
special elections, and, <del></del> except as herein provided, shall be governed
by the law regulating and controlling general or special election 
in said city. Such charter may be amended by proposals therefor submitted
by the legislative authority of such city to the electors thereof 
at any general election after notice of said submission, published 
as above specified, and ratified by a majority of the qualified electors
voting thereon. In submitting any such charter, or amendment
thereto, any alternate article or proposition may be presented for the 
choice of the voters, and may be coted on separately without prejudice
to others.</p>

<p>S11. Any county, city, town or township may make and enforce within
its limits all such local police, sanitary and other regulations as
are not in conflict with general laws.</p>

<p>S12. The legislature shall have no power to impose taxes upon counties 
cities, towns or other municipal corporations, or upon the inhabitants 
or property thereof, for county, city, town, or other municipal purposes, 
but may, by general laws, vest in the corporate authroities
thereof the power to assess and collect taxes for such purposes.</p>

<p>S13. Private property shall not be taken or sold for the payment of
the corporate debt of any public or municipal corporation, except in
the mode provided by law for the levy and collection of taxes.</p>

<p>Municipal Corporations of the First Class.</p>

<p>Laws of 1890, Page 215.</p>

<p>S1. Any city now having, or which may hereafter have, a population
of twenty thousand or more inhabitants, may frame a charter for its 
own government.</p>

<p>S5. Any such city shall have power:</p>

<p>Second, to provide for levying and collecting taxes on real and
personal property, for its corporate uses and purposes, and to provide
for the payment of the debts and expenses of the corporation;</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Twenty-second, to direct the location and construction of all buildings
in which any trade or occupation offensive to the senses or deleterious
to public health or safety shall be carried on, and to regulate
the management thereof; and to prohibit the erection or maintenance 
of such buildings or structures, nor the carrying on of such trade
or occupation within the limits of such corporation, or within the 
distance of two miles beyond the boundaries thereof;</p>

<p>Thirty-first, to declare what shall be a nuisance and to abate the
same, and to impose fines upon parties who may create, continue, or suffer
nuisances to exist;</p>

<p>Thirty-second, to regulate the selling or giving away of intoxicating,
malt, vinous, mixed or fermented liquors: Provided, That no
license shall be granted to any person or persons who shall not first
comply with the general laws of the state in force at the time the
same is granted;</p>

<p>Thirty-third, to grant licenses for any lawful purpose, and to fix
by ordinance the amount to be paid therefor, and to provide for revoking 
the same: Provided, That no license shall be granted to continue 
for longer than one year from the date thereof;</p>

<p>Thirty-four, to regulate the carrying on within its corporate limits 
of all occupations which are of such a nature as to affect the public
health or the good order of said city, or to disturd the public peace,
and which are not prohibited by law, and to provide for the punishment
of all persons violating such regulations, and of all persons who 
knowingly permit the same to be violated in any building or upon any 
premises owned or controlled by them.</p>

<p>Taxation.</p>

<p>Laws of 1897, Page 136.</p>

<p>S1. That all real and personal property now existing, or that shall
be hereafyer created or brought into this state, shall be subject to
assessment and taxation for the support of the state government, and
for county, school, municipal, or such other purposes as shall be 
designated by law, upon equalized valuations thereod, fixed with reference
thereto on the first day of March at 12 o'clock meridian, in 
each and every year in whcih the same shall be listed, except such 
property as shall be expressly exempt therefrom by the provisions of
law. </p>

<p>Assessment Lists</p>

<p>S6. All real property in this state subject to taxation shall be
listed and assessed under the provisions of this act in the year 1900
and biennially thereafter on every even numbered year, with reference
to its value on the first day of March preceding the assessment. All
personal property in this state subject to taxation shall be listed and 
assessed every year with reference to its value on the first day of
March preceding the assessment: Provided, That the assessed value of
all real property in this state as fixed by the assessment of 1897b
shall be assessed value until the year 1900: Provided, further
That real estate becoming subject to taxation since the last assessment
be assessed and included in the assessment list and tax roll in every
odd numbered year: And provided further, That the destruction or removal 
of improvements since the last preceding assessment shall be
duly noted by the county assessor and the assessment and tax rolls
herein provided made to conform to such changes: Provided further,
That all real estate subject to taxation shall be listed by the assessor
each year in the detailed and assessment list, and in each odd numbered 
year the valuation of each tract for taxation shall be the
same as the valuation thereof as equalized by the county board of
equalization in the preceding year. </p>

<pb></pb>

<p>S1. It  shall be the duty of the county assessor in each county in
which there is a city of the first class, as soon as the county and state
boards of equalization have finally fixed the valuation of the property
in such county for state and county taxation in each year, to
certify to the city comptroller or each city of the first class in
such county a summary of the valuation of all real estate and personal
property in such city, or subject to taxation therein, as shown by
the assessment roll of each county, as finally fixed by the said boards
and also a list of all residents of such city liable to pay a poll tax
It shall be the duty of the county assessor in making up his assessment
roll for the county to place the property within the limits of
any such city subject to taxation therein in as compact a form as
practicable on said roll, so that the city taxes may be extended in
the same manner as state and county taxes are extended, and that portion
of said assessment roll embracing persons and property subject
to taxation in such city shall constitute also the assessment roll
of such city of the first class for the levy and collection of the
taxes thereof. When by reason of a change in the boundaries of any
such city or otherwise, the rate of taxation is required to differ in
different districts thereof, the real and personal property in each
district shall be properly segregated for that purpose, and such segregation
shall duly appear in the summary certified as aforesaid.
</p>

<p>County Treasurer shall Collect</p>

<p>Laws of 1895, Page 407.</p>

<p>The county treasurer of each county in which there is or shall
be a city of the first class is hereby constituted ex officio collector
of city taxes of such city, and before entering upon the duties of
his office he shall execute in favor of such city and file with the
clerk thereof a good and sufficient bond, the penal sum to be fixed
by the city council, such bond to be approved by the mayor of such
city or other authority thereof by whom the bond of the city treasurer
is required to be approved. All special assessments and special taxation
for local improvements assessed on property benefited shall be
collected by the city treasurer except as otherwise provided by this
act.</p>

<p>Collections paid over</p>

<p>S8717. All such city taxes collected shall belong to such city, and 
the county treasurer shall turn over all such taxes so collected to
the city treasurer on Monday in each week and take a receipt therefor
in duplicate, and at the same time he shall certify to the city comptroller
the amounts of taxes so collected and turn over and deliver
with such certificate one copy of the receipt of the city treasurer
therefor. The county treasurer shall also render to the city comptroller
on each Monday between the first day of January and the first 
day of May a statement of all taxes collected for such city during the
preceding week. </p>

<p>Delinquent taxes.</p>

<p>S8718. All taxes of any such city assess under the provisions 
of this act becoming delinquent shall be collected and enforced by the 
same officers and in the same manner as delinquent county and state
taxes now are or may hereafter be collected and enforced. Any real
property sold to the county for state, county and city taxes shall 
be held by the county for the common benefit of the county and city
in proportion to the equitable interest of each in the taxes, costs 
and expenses for which the same were sold. All provisions of law 
relating to discount on state and county taxes and penalties, interest
and costs thereon and the times when the same become due, payable
or delinquent shall apply to city taxes levied under authority of this
act. </p>

<pb></pb>

<p>But one roll-local assessments.</p>

<p>S8720. The assessment roll of the county made as herein provided
shall be deemed and held to be also the assessment roll of any city
of the first class therein, and in cases where the charter of any such
city requires delinquent assessments for local improvements, or any
 special taxes or assessments whatever to be entered on the annual tax
roll of such city, the city treasurer shall from time to time certify
the same, together with the accumulated penalties and interest there
on, to the county treasurer, who shall enter the same on the general
county assessment roll against the property so taxed or assessed in a
separate column head, "Delinquent local assessments, city of .......,"
in the manner directed by such charter, and the same shall be a part
of the tax due on such property and with interest shall be collected
as other taxes, separate account being kept thereof, and if not paid
within the time fixed for the payment of other taxes, shall be collected
as other taxes are collected, together with the additional charges
penalties and interests authorized to be charged and collected on
other delinquent taxes; and all other proceedings shall be taken thereon
as if the same were originally a part of the general tax assessed
against such property.</p>

<p>This act supersedes..........</p>

<p>S8721. <del></del>Thsi act shall supersede all conflicting
provisions of law or charters of cities of the first class relating
to the assessment, equalization and collection of general taxes for
municipal purposes: Provided, That in counties having cities of the
first class the city council thereof shall select a committee of three
members of such council to act with the board of county commissioners
as a board of equalization, and shall have the powers and perform
the duties concerning the equalization of assessments in their respective
cities that are given to the county boards of equalization by the
general revenue laws of the state. The city council may provide for 
the compensation of the members of the committee for the time they 
are actually engaged as members of the board of equalization.</p>

<p>See laws of 1890, Page 215.</p>

<p>U.S. Constitution</p>

<p>Preamble 1-</p>

<p>We the people of the United States, in order to form a more perfect 
union, establish justice, insure domestic tranquility, provide for the
common defense, promote the general welfare, and secure the blessings 
of liberty to ourselves and our posterity, do ordain and establish
this Constitution for the United States of America.</p>

<p>Art. I</p>

<p>Powers of Congress. Sec. 8.</p>

<p><del></del> To regulate commerce. 
Powers prohibited to States. Sec. 10.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Art. III.</p>

<p>Extent of Judicial Power. Sec. 2.</p>

<p>Art. IV</p>

<p>Privileges of Citizens. Sec. 2.</p>

<p>Amendments to the United States Constitution.</p>

<p>Art. V.</p>

<p>Rights of persons.</p>

<p>Arts. IX.-X.</p>

<p>Rights reserved by the people.</p>

<p>Art. XIV</p>

<p>Sec. 1. Citizenship shall not abrudge ETC. Life - liberty -
property - due process of law.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Liberty-Defined</p>

<p>Cooley's Constitutional Limitations; 6th edition, page 359 and 364.
P. 412.... in organized society, liberty is the creature of law, and
every man will possess it in proportion as the laws, while imposing
no unnecessary restraints, surround him and every other citizen with 
protection against the lawless acts of others.</p>

<p>P. 412 Note 2. "Liberty," says Mr. Wesbter, "is the creature of law,
essentially different from that authorized licentiousness that trespasses
on right. It is a legal and refined idea, the offspring of
high civilization, which the savage never understood, and never can
understand."</p>

<p>P. 413/ Note 1.</p>

<p>P. 416.</p>

<p>P. 484... To forbid to an individual or a class the right to acquisition
or enjoyment of property in such a manner as should be permitted
to the community at large, would be to deprive them of liberty
in particulars of primary importance to their "pursuit and happiness;"</p>

<p>P. 484, Note 2.</p>

<p>P. 485 .. Equality of rights, privileges, and capacities unquestionably
should be the aim of the law; and if special privileges are granted,
or special burdens or restrictions imposed in any case, it must be
presumed that the legislature designed to depart as little as possible
from this fundamental maxim of government.</p>

<p>P. 485, Notes 1.
Private righst not to be construed away by legislation. P. 54. N.
Municipal control, 288
See Ordronaux's Constitutional Legislation: pp. 22, 36, 37, 38,
168, 169.</p>

<p>Cooley's Principles of Constitutional Law: pp. 246, 247. see
chap. 16, Sec. II; pp. 328, 345,346.</p>

<note><unclear></unclear> is property
p. 388 police <unclear>driver</unclear>
pp 256 - Sec 2+3 </note>

<p>License id., 255, 258</p>

<p>Equal protection of the laws guaranteed by the
XIV Amendment</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Cooley's Constitutional Limitations, pp. 11; 13, sec. 17; 14, Notes 2.</p>

<p>P. 11.... The general purpose of the Constitution of the United States
is declared by its founders to be "to form a more perfect union,
establish justice, insure domestic tranquility, provide for the common 
defense, promote the general welfare, and secure the blessings 
of liberty to ourselves and our posterity.</p>

<p>P. 11, Notes 2.</p>

<p>13.... The fourteenth amendment has several objects. 1. It declares
all persons born or naturalized in the United States, and subject
to the jurisdiction thereof, to be citizens of the United States and
of the State wherein they reside; and it forbids any State to make
or enforce any law which shall abridge the privileges or immunities
of citizens of the United States, or to deprive any person of life,
liberty, or property, without due process of law, or to deny to any
person within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws.</p>

<p>PP. 484, 485, 486.</p>

<p>P. 489 ... The Constitution of the United States contains provisions
which are important in this connection. One of these is, that the
citizens of each state Shall be entitled to all the privileges and
immunities of citizens of the several States. </p>

<p>P. 489, Note 3.</p>

<p>State v. Mitchell, 53 Atl. 887</p>

<p>1. The federal constitution, in amendment 14, the last clause of the
first section, and the constitution of this state, in section 1 of article 
1, affirmatively guaranty to all persons an equality of right
to pursue any lawful occupation under equal regulation and protection
by law, whatever the difference in their personal powers, attributes,
conditions, or possessions.</p>

<p>2. While these constitutional provisions do not prohibit the state 
diversifying its legislation to meet and equalize diversities in
different kinds of occupations, such as diversities must really exist 
inherent in the subject-matter legislated upon, to justify any legislative
disrimination. A merely arbitrary classification, not based 
on actual differences in kind, is forbidden by the constitution.</p>

<p>Legislative Interference.
Validity of the Ordinance Number 6036.</p>

<p>City of Springfield v. Jacobs, 73 S.W. Rep. 1097.
1. An ordinance imposing a license tax of $50 per day on the business
of conducting "a transient, or traveling, clothing, dry goods, jewelry
or other kind of store," and defining such stores as stores commonly 
dsignated as fire-sale or bankrupt-sale stores, etc., operates unreasonably
and oppressively, and is void.</p>

<p>Gast v. Buckley, 64 S.W. Rep. 632.
1. A city ordinance requiring the payment of  a license tax for the 
privilege of buying claims is void to the extent that it requires a 
person to pay such tax for the privilege of buying claims for himself
and not as a broker, though that may be his business.</p>

<p>2. A person who buys claims for himself that is not a broker.</p>

<p>Thurlow Medical Company v. City of Salem, N.J., 50 Atl. 475.</p>

<p>State (Margalies prosecutor) v. City of Atlantic City, N.J.
50 Atl. 367.</p>

<p>Restraining and licensing auctioneers, unreasonable, etc</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>People v. Gillson, 109 N.Y. 390</p>

<p>17 N.E. 343.... Police power - premium giving by food sellers.
Acts N.Y. 1887, c. 691, amendatory of Pen. Code S335a, making it
a misdemeanor for any person who sells food to give away therewith
as a part of the transaction of sale, any other thing as a premium,
gift, etc., is in violation of the constitutional provision which 
secures to each person his liberty and property; and is not within
the proper exercise of the police power of the state, either to protect
the public health and safety or to prohibit lotteries, or to 
regulate trade; nor is it a valid exercise of the legislative power
to enact what shall amount to a crime.</p>

<p>In re Jacobs 98N. Y. 98</p>

<p>Commonwealth v Emerson, 165 Mass. 146. Common v. Sisson, 60 NE 385</p>

<p>City of Chicago v. Netcher, 183 Ill. 104; 48 L.R.A. 261; 5 N.E. 707</p>

<p>State of Missouri ex rel. Wyatt v. Ashbrook, 48 L.R.A. 265.....
1. An exercise of the power of taxation for the sole purpose of
revenue or undue restraint or prohibition of a business will not be
saved from the constitutional restrictions that apply to it as the 
imposition of a tax, by its designation in the statute as a "license
fee."</p>

<p>2. A statute which nowhere attempts to protect any public interest,
or defend against any public wrong, which shows upon its face that 
regulation is not its purpose, but that revenue or undue restriction
of a business in the interest of others is the aim in view, cannot
be sustained as an exercise of the police power, although it purports
to be "An Act to regulate business and trade."</p>

<p>3. To sustain a statute as an exercise of the police power, the
courts must be able to see that its object to some degree tends toward
the prevention of some offense or manifest evil, or that it has
for its aim the preservation of the public health, morals, safety, or
welfare.</p>

<p>State of Rhode Island v. Dalton, 48 L.R.A. 775</p>

<p>A statute which prohibits a person who sells and article from giving
to the purchaser as part of the same transaction a stamp, coupon, or 
other device which will entitle him to receive from a third person 
some other well-defined article in addition to the one sold is an 
unwarrantable interference with individual liberty guaranteed by Const.
art. 1, S10, and U.S.Const. 14the Amend. S1.</p>

<p>Long v. State of Maryland, 12 L.R.A. 425.</p>

<p>A gift enterprise which does not involve the element of chance
cannot be prohibited by the legislature even though it is carried on
by a merchant to induce customers to buy his goods.</p>

<p>Stockton Laundry Case; In re Tie Loy (C.C. Cal.) 26 Fed. Rep. 611</p>

<p>1. Constitutional Law - fourteenth amendment - city ordinance - due
process of law - privileges and immunities of citizens of United 
States - equal protection of laws.</p>

<p>A city ordinance that makes it an offense for any person to carry
on a laundry where clothes are washed for pay, within the habitable
portion of the city, is unconstitutional.</p>

<p>2. Habeas Corpus - Violation fo unconstitutional city ordinance - 
Rev. St. U.S. S753</p>

<p>A party who is held in custody for the violation of a city ordiancne 
that is in conflict with the fourteenth amendment to the United States 
constitution is entitled to be discharged on habeas corpus.</p>

<p>In re Sam Kee, 31 Fed. 680; in re Hong Wah, 82 Fed. 523.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>People v. Gillson, 109 N.Y. 390</p>

<p>Harding v. People, 160 Ill. 459; 43 N.E. 624</p>

<p>Eden v. People, 160 Ill. 296; <del></del> L.R.A. 659; 43N.E. 1108.</p>

<p>Bailey v. People 109 Ill. 28; 54 L.R.A. 838; 60 N.E. 98</p>

<p>Constitutional law - due process - discrimination.
A statute regulating the number of people a lodging house keeper
may permit to sleep in one room contravenes Const. 1870, art. 2 S2,
guarantying that no person shall be deprived of property without die
process of law, being discriminatory against lodging house keepers
as a class, and exempting keepers of other houses of public entertainment,
such as inns, hotels, and boarding houses.</p>

<p>Railroad Company v. Husen., 95 U.S. 465 ....</p>

<p>1. The statute of Missouri which prohibits driving or conveying any 
Texas, Mexican, or Indian cattle into the State, between the first
day of March and the first day of November in each year, is in conflict
with the clause of the Constitution that ordains "Congress shall
have power to regulate commerce with foreign nations, and among the 
several states, and with the Indian tribes.</p>

<p>2. Such a statute is more than a quarantine regulation, and not a
legitimate exercise of the police power of the State.</p>

<p>St. Louis Ry. Co. v. Gill, 156 U.S. 649; Book 39 L.R.A. 567.....</p>

<p>2. A state law which established a tariff of rates so unreasonable 
as to destroy the value of the property of a railroad company, may
be held to be unconstitutional, as taking the property without due 
process of law.</p>

<p>People ex rel. Madden v. Dycker, 76 N.Y. Supp't 111 .....</p>

<p>1. Constitutional law - police power - prohibition of use of trading
stamps - unlawful deprivation of liberty and property.</p>

<p>Laws 1900, c.768, S384p/, forbidding the issue and distribution of trading
stamps to be redeemed by any person other than the merchant who
sells the goods with which such stamps are given, is not a lawful
exercise of the police power, and is unconstitutional, as being an
unlawful deprivation of liberty and property.</p>

<p>Ruhstrat v. People, 185 Ill. 133; 49 L.R.A. 181; 57 N.E. 41 ....</p>

<p>1. The constitutional right of evert citizen to choose his occupation
includes the right to advertise it in a legitimate way, and
Act April 22, 1899, prohibiting the use of the national flag for such 
purpose, unduly interferes with personal liberty, unless thereby the
public health, safety, welfare, or comfort <del></del> is conserved.</p>

<p>Ex-parte McKenna, 126 Cal. 429; 58 Pac. Rep. 916.</p>

<p>City of Tacoma v. Krech, 15 W. 296.......</p>

<p>A legislature having no authority under the constitution to pass
laws partaking of the character of special legislation, it cannot
delegate such power to a city council.</p>

<p>An ordinance of a city prohibiting barbers from pursuing their
calling on Sunday for compensation, is void as an act of special legislation
as it singles out one class of people and imposes restrictions
upon them which are not imposed on other citizens alike.</p>

<p>Covington &amp; L. Turnpike Road Co. v. Sandford, 164 U.S. 578;
Book 41 L.C.P.Co. 560.......</p>

<p>4. A statute reducing the tolls that may be charged by a turnpike
company, and requiring it to conform to a tariff of rates that is 
unjust and unreasonable, which prevents it, out of its receipts, from
keeping its road in proper condition for public use or from earning
any dividends whatever for stockholders, is unconstitutional as a 
deprivation of property without due process of law.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Bessette v. People, (Ill.) 62 N.E. 215 ......</p>

<p>5. Act June 11, 1897 (Laws 1897, p.233), regulating horseshoeing by
section 15 providing that the provisions thereof shall apply to cities
of over 50,000 inhabitants, but that cities of over 10,000 inhabitants,
may adopt its provisions, thus excluding towns of under 10,000 inhabitants,
is an arbitrary and unreasonable discrimination between
persons engaged in the same occupation, and repugnant to Const. Ill.
1870, art. 2, SS1, 2, guarantying liberty and the pursuit of happiness,
and prohibiting deprivation of life, liberty, or property without
due process of law, and also violates article 4, S22, which provides 
that the general assembly shall not pass local or special laws 
granting to any corporation or individual any special or exclusive
privilege or immunity.</p>

<p>Millet v. People, 117 Ill. 294; 7 N.E. 631.
Act compelling measurement of coal by weight as basis of wages.
Unconstitutional.</p>

<p>Munn v. Illinois, 94 U.S. 113, warehouse case - fixing charges.
8. The court does not hold that a case may not arise in which it
may be found that a State has, under the form of regulating her own
affairs encroached upon the exclusive domain of Congress in respect to
interstate commerce.</p>

<note>See dissent p. 136. <unclear></unclear>938</note>

<p>Shaver v. Pennsylvania Co. 71 Fed. 931 ........</p>

<p>2. Constitutional Law - liberty of contract - class legislation.
A statute of Ohio (87 Ohio Laws, p. 149) provides that no railroad 
company, insurance company, or association of other persons shall
require any agreement or stipulation with any other person, in or
about to enter the employment of a railroad company, whereby such person
agrees to waive any right to damages from such railroad company
 for personal injuries, or any other right whatever, and all scuh agreements 
and stipulations shall be void. Held that such statutexx violates 
the fourteenth amendment of the Constitution of the United 
States, by depriving persons affected by it of their liberty of
contract, without due process of law, and also violates article 2,
S26, of the constitution of Ohio, providing that all laws of a general 
nature shall have uniform operation throughout the state; since
such statute is class legislation, affecting only railroad employees,
and accordingly that such statute is void. </p>

<p>In re Wilshire, 103 Fed. 620; 623........</p>

<p>The courts are not bound by mere forms, nor are they to be misled
by mere pretenses. They are at liberty - indeed, are under a solemn 
duty - to look at the substance of things, whenever they enter upon 
the inquiry whether the legislature has transcended the limits of its
authority. If, therefore, the statute purporting to have been enacted
to protect the public health, the public morals, or the public safety
has no real or substantial relation to those objects, or is a palpable
invasio of rights secured by the fundamental law, it is the duty
of the courts to so adjudge, and thereby give effect to the constitution.</p>

<p>Mugler v. Kansas, 123 U.S. 661. <note></note></p>

<p>A law is not general beacuse it operates upon all within a class
unless there is a substantial reason why it is made to operate upon
that <del></del> class only and not generally 
upon all.</p>

<p>Ex parte Leo Jentzsch, 32 L.R.A. 664.</p>

<p>It is a judicial question whether a trade or calling is of such
a nature as to justify police regulation.</p>

<pb></pb>


<p>When the police power is exerted for the purpose of regulating
 a useful business or occupation and the mode in which that business 
May be carried on or advertised, the legislature is not the exclusive
judge as to what is a reasonable restraint upon the constitutional
right of the citizen to pursue his calling or exercise his own
judgment as to the manner of conducting it.</p>

<p>Eden v. People, 161 Ill. 296; 32 L.R.A. 659; 43 N.E. 1108.</p>

<p>Ex parte Frank, 52 Cal. (606, (28 Am. Rep)
<note><unclear></unclear></note></p>

<p>Cooley Constitutional Limitation, 390</p>

<p>Huzo v. San Francisco, 33 Cal. 143; Argenti v. San Francsico
16 Cal. 282, Wallace v. San Jose, 29 Cal. 180; Dillon on Mun. Corp.
sec. 55, et seq.</p>

<p>Legislature prescribes extent of powers.
Cooley's Con. Lim., 6th ed. p. 227-231, 232, 281, 203, N.</p>

<p>License of occupations in general.
Id. 743</p>

<p>When are taxes Id. 243, N., 609, N.
Limited generally to expenses etc., Id. 243, N.</p>

<p>Trades.
By-Laws in restraint of,  void.
Dillon, Mun. Corp. 4th ed. sec. 319 N. (on p. 398), 321., 323, 324,
393.</p>
<note>sec 322</note>
<p>May be regulated, 323-326.
Power to be license and tax trades. Id. 357, 361, 362, 366 N/, 785,791,
793.</p>

<p>Nature and extent of License Power. Id. 357-362.</p>

<p>Dinstinction between power to license and tax.
Id. 115, 357-361, 748,750 N., 764, 768.</p>

<p>See Tiedman's Limitations of Police power, sec. 101 to and including 105.</p>

<p>pp - 171 A. 327 - 171 - 172-3-4-5
176-7-8-9-180-1-3-5-6-7
and sec 102 p. 289 293-296</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>We now call attention to the case of Fleetwood v. Read, 21 Washington,
p. 547.</p>

<p>The State relies upon this case as <del>the</del> an entire defense against 
the attack we are making on the Ordinance No. 6036. We have no scruples
in saying that that case in no way is decisive of this case. We
present different facts; we present different questions of law. The
opinion of the court in that case is based upon paragraph or subdivision
33 of the laws of 1890, page 215, found in Pierce's Code in
section 3732, page 596. That law says that the city has power to grant 
licenses for all lawful purposes and we maintain that the provision is
meaningless and adds nothing to the power given to the city under
Art. 11, section 11 of the State Constitution. <del></del></p>

<p>Section 11 says: Any county, city, town or twonship may make
and enforce within its limits all such local police, sanitary and other
regulations as are not in conflict with general laws.</p>

<p>Section 12 of the same article of the constitution refers to
the imposition of taxes. The collection and levy of taxes as we have 
shown is provided for under the laws of 1897 page 136 and will be 
found at section 8713, which we have referred heretofore in this 
brief and cited the law in full. We have shown that the city has 
no power to lecy taxes as a revenue by means of issuing licenses in 
regulation of its police power and therefor the ordinance No. 6036
is ultra viris.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court, on page 552 of the opinion referred to in the
21 Wash., says that there is no police power exercised by authority 
of this ordinance; then we say <del>and we have argued</del> if it is not a police
power <del><unclear></unclear></del> it cannot exercise any other power in the way of issuing
licenses, and again we say that sub. 33 cited by the court
has no meaning when taken in connection with what the supreme court says;
that there is no police power exercised in the ordinance</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Again we say; Sub. 33 says that the city may grant licenses for 
all lawful purposes, but the lawful purpose must be such as the
city has pwer to regulate by <del></del> authority of its police power to
protect the municipality from that which may become a detriment to
its peace, happiness and propseprity. If it doesn't mean this then 
as we have stated it is meaningless and can grant no other <del></del> or
greater power than that conferred upon it by the constitution, and, as
we have shown,, the constitution has restricted it to local, police, 
sanitary and other regulations not in conflict with general laws.</p>

<p>Now as to revenue imposition we have shown that it is in conflict
with the general revenue law, and as a police regulation it
is no basis for the regulation or control: in other words there is
no foundation on which to build the exercise of police power and 
sanitary regulations of the city</p>

<p>Again we say that section 13, Art. 11 of the State Constitution 
controls the imposition of this license.</p>

<p>It is an interference with private property; it is an imposition 
on private property; it is an interference with the liberty of the 
individual: if the ordinance means anything it places the individual and his property under the direct
supervision and control of the police <del>power</del> of the city.</p>

<p>Now there must be some real cause for the exercise of the police
power over the business that the city seeks to control. The cause, 
however, is not apparent on the face of the record as made. Probably
it would have been better to have taken some evidence in this case
or to have submitted it upon statement of facts. With thsi purpose
in view we have <del></del> prepared a statement of facts and herewith
submit them with the brief and the legal questions therein discussed.</p>

<p>Respectfully submitted.</p>

<p>Carroll &amp; Carroll</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>STATEMENT OF FACTS</p>

<p>The defendant, Ernest Hutchinson, is a member of the firm of 
Hutchinson &amp; Hutchinson of Battle Creek Michigan, doing business
throughout the United States as the "National Stamp Company."</p>

<p>Their method of doin business is known as commission advertising.
The company contracts with retail dealers in all lines of merchandise.
The contract in substance is that defendant sells to the retail
dealer the buyer's or trading stamps at the rate of fifty cents per
hundred. The dealer gives to each cash purchaser one stamp for each
ten cents represented in the purchase. The purchaser is then and there
informed that the stamps will be redeemed in goods, wares or merchandise
at the store of the company issuing them. The holder of the 
stamp need only call at the company's store or place of business,
where the goods, wares and merchandise are exposed, with the prices 
in stamps marked thereon. The holder of the stamps can choose from 
the stock any article or articles he wishes in redemption of the 
stamps delivered to the company.</p>

<p>The defendant contracts with the retailers for one year, during
which time his company agrees to supply the retailers with stamps,
and publish their names and business and address in the company's
subscribers book; and deliver said book to the people in the vicinity
and advertise the subscribers' business in the newspapers and also 
in such advertisement to notify the public that all stamps secured in
trade at the places named will be redeemed in merchandise at the
company's store.</p>

<p>No. 1183</p>

<p>In the United
States Circuit
Court of the
Ninth Circuit
District of
Washington</p>

<p>In the matter of 
the petition of 
Ernest Hutchinson
for Writ of Habeas 
Corpus</p>

<p>Brief of Petitioner</p>

<p>Carroll &amp; Carroll
Attorneys for Petitioner</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>