<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0364.030">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Tsunetaro Machida v. Luther Wedin. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0364.030</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Tsunetaro Machida v. Luther Wedin. Petition</title>
<date when="1921-07-28">July 28, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-07">July 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Holland, P. O.</term>
<term>Crosby Jr, F. L.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Machida, Tsunetaro</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Wedin, Luther</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Horner, Thomas R.</persName>
<persName>Judd, Edward</persName>
<persName>Lonergan, Pierce</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington. Northern Division.</p>

<p>Petition</p>

<p>No. 6190</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of TSUNETARO MACHIDA for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>State of Washington, County of King,</p>

<p>ss:</p>

<p>To the Honorable Judges of said Court:</p>

<p>TSUNETARO MACHIDA, being first duly sworn, on his oath represents to the court that he is at present time being unlawfully and illegally imprisoned, detained, confined and restrained of his liberty by Henry M. White, commissioner of immigration of the United States at Seattle, King county, Washington, and that the place of his unlawful detention and imprisonment is the United States Immigration Station, Seattle, King county, State of Washington, in said district.</p>

<p>That the said imprisonment, detention, confinement and restraint are illegal; and that the illegality thereof consists in this, to-wit:</p>

<p>That petitioner, Tsunetaro Machida, is being held for deportation to Japan, of which country petitioner was formerly a resident, and that the pretended cause on which he is detained, and for which he will be deported unless the court grants him the prayer of this petition, is insufficient in law to hold him, and insufficient in law to deport him. That said charge upon which he was arrested and is now being held, is as follows, to-wit:</p>

<p>That petitioner, Tsunetaro Machida, is being held for deportation to Japan, of which country petitioner was formerly a resident, and that the pretended cause on which he is detained, and for which he will be deported unless the court grants him the prayer of this petition, is insufficient in law to hold him, and insufficient in law to deport him. That said charge upon which he was arrested and is now being held, is as follows, to-wit</p>

<p>"That Tsunetaro Machida, who landed at Calexico, California, on March 26th, 1919, has been found in the United States in violation of the Immigration Act of February 5, 1917, to wit: That he has become a public charge within five years after his entry into the United States from causes not affirmatively shown to have arisen subsequent thereto; and that he was a person likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry into the United States."</p>

<pb/>

<p>(2)</p>

<p>That the foregoing charge, and the whole thereof, and each and every part thereof, save that as to <add>the time of</add> his entry, is wholly untrue and incorrect; that the contrary is the fact; that he is not now, and never has been, likely to become a public charge; that to the contrary he is thrifty, industrious and earns, and is capable of earning, good salary and good wages at his business of fishing, butlering, laboring, canneryman, and various other employments in which he <add>has been</add> <del>is</del> engaged and in which he has made a success; that there has not been, and petitioner believes that can not be, a single fact adduced to establish the said charge that he is or is likely to become a public charge; that affiant is about 32 years of age, in excellent health, and has always been hard-working and frugal.</p>

<p>That petitioner first came to the United States from Japan in May, 1910, on the Japanese steamer, Kamakura Maru; that shortly thereafter he worked for the Barniston Lumber Company, near Cedar Falls, Washington, about 25 miles from Seattle; that in May, 1912, he went from Seattle to Juneau, Alaska, where he remained until November, 1915; that while in Alaska affiant worked as janitor for the Elk's Club; also for the First National Bank as porter; also as porter and houseman for Harry Mayo; that while in Alaska he had no trouble and deserved and held an excellent reputation; that he has earned and deserved such a reputation at every place he has worked and lived.</p>

<p>That leaving Juneau, he worked until November, 1915, at the Port Moreland Cannery, Alaska, under Tikutake, Japanese labor contractor, of Seattle. In November of that year he left Alaska for California, stopping about 15 days in Seattle, and going from there by rail to California. He stopped one day in San Francisco, and then went to San Pedro, remaining there until June and supportingmyself by janitoring and general labor. In June, 1916, he went to Long Beach, California, and fished until the fall of 1917, operating a </p>

<pb/>

<p>(3)</p>

<p>boat named the "Wakamura," and owned by one Hoffhill, as I recall.</p>

<p>He then contracted with a Mr. Stevens, a fisherman from Van Camp, California, and he aided me financially in buying "The Sunshine," for which I paid between $700.00 and $800.00.</p>

<p>In November, 1918, he went to Mexicali, Mexico, in<del>e</del>terested in mullet fishing, a jumping cod much prized. He went to the Japanese Association there where he met other Japanese and friends.</p>

<p>We lunched together, and talked generally about the unfortunate condition of the world, and how fortunate was America in its security and prosperity, and of America's superior opportunities for the laboring man and the common people. He praised America warmly. Before leaving America he was requested by a Mr. Samajima to extend greeting to his brother in Mexicali. About 8 P.M. of that day two Japanese were arrested trying to cross the border, and among these were the one to whom petitioner had that day lunched and a brother of Samajimi. Petitioner returned to California, was regularly <add>and legally</add>, admitted at the border. He went to Brawley, <add>California,</add> and inquired to see a Mr. Yamamoto there; and hearing of the arrest of the two Japanese petitioner became frightened and got on the train at Brawley, California, and while<del>m</del>on the train bound for Los Angeles, was arrested at Nyland, California, in March, 1919. He wished to go to Los Angeles because he had friends there.</p>

<p>He was subsequently indicated for aiding alien laborers to get into the United States; and <add>paid</add> <del>put up</del> over $400.00 <add>to</add> <del>with</del> a lawyer named Monroe to defend him. When trial came Monroe was in court in an intoxicated condition, as petitioner believes, for he smelt liquor on his breath, and insisted that he plead guilty as the easiest way out, as it would only mean 30 days in jail at the outside. Petitioner understands Emglish very indifferently, and yielded to the advice of the lawyer. Upon pleading guilty he was given two years at McNeil's Island, and upon his release was re-arrested and held for deportation.</p>

<pb/>

<p>(4)</p>

<p>Petitioner avers that <add>he</add> was and is innocent of the charge to which he was thus improperly led to plead guilty; that he never advised or assisted any aliens of any one else to enter the United States; that such a thought never occurred to him. That he plead guilty under the advice of the lawyer to whom was paid over $400.00, and under the representation that it would be a trifling matter.</p>

<p>Petitioner avers, under advice of counsel, and here pleads, that the offens of which he stands convicted, on the record, is not sufficient to warrant his deportation to Japan; that it is not such an offense, under that statutes and laws in such cases made and provided, as will justify deportation.</p>

<p>As to being a public charge petitioner <add>further avers</add> <del>aevrs</del> that since being in America he has earned on an average of $1600.00 a year as nearly as he can estimate it; that since his release on bonds in this deportation proceedings he returned to California and earned $410.00 in forty days packing canteloupes for Horibe, a Japanese of the Imperial Valley, California, and that he has paid for and <del></del> now owns the $1000.00 in Liberty bonds deposited for his appearance with the Immigration officers before his surrender of himself to them prior to the verification of this petition. That he has money and is much sought as a worker in the various works in which he has been engaged. He asks that the testimonials filed in his behalf with the Immigration officials and all the records be read in connection with this proceeding.</p>

<p>That the charge that he is likely to become a public charge is entirely untrue; that to the contrary he is thrifty, industrious, and is capable of earning more than the average workingman earns; that he is thirty two years of age and in excellent health.</p>

<p>That the offense of which he was convicted is insufficient under the law to warrant his deportation, and that it is not allege in the proceedings against him.</p>

<pb/>

<p>(5)</p>

<p>That the said Act of Congress of February 5, 1917, and no act or law, rule or regulation, under the facts of this case, warrants or permits the legal deportation of petitioner.</p>

<p>That petitioner expects to make the United States his permanent residence.</p>

<p>That petitioner is not held by said Immigration Commissioner upon any final process issued by a court of common jurisdiction, nor is he held upon any process, or order for contempt of any court, officer or body having authority to commit him or hold him; nor upon any warrant issued by any court in the State of Washington; nor upon any indictment or information in or of this state; nor is there any legal or valid reason for the detention of petitioner.</p>

<p>That petitioner is held upon the pretended and fictitious grounds hereinbefore set forth, namely, that he has become a public charge within five years after his entry into the United States from causes not affirmatively shown to have arisen subsequently thereto; and that he was a person likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry into the United States. That such charges are utterly without proof, fact or evidence to substantiate them, and that the truth and fact is the contrary as hereinbefore set forth; that he is thrifty, healthy, provident and above the average in earning capacity.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner prays:</p>

<p>First: That a writ of habeas corpus issue out of this court directed to Henry M. White, the said Immigration Commissioner in whose custody your petitioner now is, commanding and requiring said commissioner to have the body of your petitioner before this court on some special and convenient day to be determined by the court, and then and there to show cause why this petitioner is detained of his liberty, and why he should not be forthwith and immediately discharged from said custody, and be restored to his liberty without day; and to assure their appearance the return day</p>

<pb/>

<p>(6)</p>

<p>be made definite and specific.</p>

<p>Second: That your petitioner be discharged from said custody; and that he have such other and further relief, both special and general, as to the court seems just and right in the premises.</p>

<p>Tsunetaro Machida</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 28th day of July, A.D. 1921.</p>

<p>P. O. Holland</p>

<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

<p>Thos. R. Horner</p>
<p>Counsel for Petitioner.</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 6190</p>

<p>In the <gap></gap> Court of the United States for the District of Washington</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Jul 28 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By F. L. Crosby Jr Deputy</p>

<p>Service of papers in this case may be made upon <gap></gap> Attorney for <gap></gap> at No. <gap></gap> Street Room <gap></gap> Block</p>
<p>Washington</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>