<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0492.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Pizzi, Annabella D." xml:id="adp">Annabella D. Pizzi</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>NSF</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0492.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant.</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-06-11">June 11, 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Medcraf, Francis Medcraf</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>The State of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Emery, Geo D.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Lundin, Alfred H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Helsell, Frank P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="justice_of_the_peace">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
                  
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#adp">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT FOR THE
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE PETITION
OF FRANCIS STEPHEB Medcraf
FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.} No. 3038
Petition.</p>
<p>TO THE HONORABLE JEREMIAH NETERER, JUDGE OF SAID COURT;
The petition of Francis Stephen Medcraf respectfully
shows;</p>
<p>That he is forty- (40) years of age and has declared 
his intention to become a citizen of the United States.</p>
<p>That your petitioner is unlawfully imprisoned, detained,
confined and restrained of his liberty by ROBERT T. HODGE, who is
the Sheriff of and for ---------, King County, Washington, at
Seattle in said state in this district.</p>
<p>That the said imprisonment, detention, confinement and
restraint are illegal and that the illegality thereof consists in 
this, to- wit:</p>
<p>That on the 18th day of May A.D. 1915, one H.F.
Conover did make and file in writing, under oath, a complaint before
Justice Reah M. Whitehead who was then and still is a Justice of
the Peace in the State of Washington in and for Seattle Precinct in
the County of King, which said complaint charged this petitioner
with having on the third day of May 1915 committed the crime of "practicing
dentistry without a certificate as followsL:</p>
<p>He, said John Doe Medcraf" (meaning this petitioner)
"in the county of King, state of Washington, on the 3rd day of May,
1915, did then and there willfully and unlawfully practice dentistry
and did then and there treat diseases and lesions of the human teeth
and jaws of said H.F. Conover, H.F. Conover then and there
being a human being, and did then and there receive from H.F.
Conover, in payment therefor, the sum of two dollars ($2), without
<pb/>
having first filed for record and having recorded in the office of 
the Auditor of the county wherein he then and there practiced, to wit,
in the office of the Auditor of King County, State of Washington, a
certificate from the Board of Dental Examiners of the State of Washington,
authorizing him to so practice provided by law,
contrary to the form of the stature in such case made and provided,
and against the peace and dignity of the State of Washington.
(Signed) H. F. Conover
Subscribed and sworn to before me this 18th day of May 1915
(Signed) Reah M. Whitehead
Justice of the Peace, Seattle Precinct,
King County, Washington."</p>
<p>That thereupon the 21st day of May the said Reah M.
Whitehead as such Justice of the Peace, issued a warrant in the name
of the State of Washington in words and figures as follows:-
"WARRANT OF ARREST"</p>
<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON
COUNTY OF KING} SS
 IN JUSTICE COURT, SEATTLE PRECINCT</p>
<p>To the Sheriff or Any Constable of Said County:</p>
<p>Whereas H. F. Conover has this day complained in writing,
under oath, to the undersigned one of the Justices of the Peace in
and for said County, that on the 3rd day of May 1915 in said County
and State, John Doe Medcraf did commit the crime of Practicing dentistry
without a certificate.</p>
<p>Therefore, in the name of the State of Washington, you are
commanded forthwith to apprehend the said John Doe Medraf and bring
him before me to be dealt with according to law.</p>
<p>Given under my hand this 21st day of May 1915.
(Signed) Reah M. Whitehead
Justice of the Peace."</p>
<pb/>
<p>And thereupon on that day your petitioner was arested by authority
of said warrant, by Edward Shrewsbury, a constable, and taken before
said Justice of the Peace who thereupon required him to give bail for
his appearance to answer to said charge on the 3rd day of June 1915
at 1-30 o'clock P?M. and to stand committed to the county jail in
default of such bail. That petitioner ghave such bail and on said date
his trial wasn't continued until June 9th 1915 at 1-30 o'clock P.M. at
which time he duly appeared before said Justice and moved to quash said
writ and discharge petitioner upon the grounds and all thereof hereinafter
stated;- towit, the unconstitutionality of the statutes of
the State of Washington hereinafter set forth as hereinafter specificied.
Said motions being denied, the Court holding said laws to be 
valid and constitutional, received evidence and all the facts hereinafter
recited were fully shown. Thereupon the said court found petitioner
guilty as charged and adjudged him to pay a fine of $
and to stand committed until such fine be paid, to the County Jail
of King County <add>not exceeding 20 days</add> and thereupon issued the warrant of commitment in
pursuance of said judgement and your petitioner is now in custody 
thereunder and is so detained by the Sheriff of King County, Washington
in the said jail, in virtue of said commitment. </p>
<p>Petitioner further shows that siad charge is based upon the facts
recited in said warrant and complaint hereinbefore set forth and upon
the Statutes of the State of Washington, viz; sections 8412 to 8425
respectively inclusive of Remington &amp; Ballingers Cosed and Statutes
of Washington (Annotated) whish are as follows;</p>
<p>"8416. (3025*) Examinations- Certificate.
Any person or persons seeking to practice dentistry
in the state of Washington, or to (own), operate or cause to be operated,
(or to run or manage) a dental office or place for the practice 
of dentistry in the state of Washington after the passage of this
act shall file his or her name, together with an application for examination, 
with the secretary of the state board of dental examiners,
and at the time of making such application shall pay to the secretary 
of the board as a fee of twenty- five dollars. and to present him
or herself at the first regular meeting thereafter of said board to
undergo examination before that body. No person shall be eligible
for such an exmaination unless he or she shall be of good moral
character and shall present to said board his or her diploma from
some dental college in good standing and shall give satisfactory
evidence of his or her rightful possession of the same: Provided,
 this section shall not apply to persons engaged in the practice of 
dentistry at the same time of the passage of this act who are bona fide
citizens of the state of Washington. All persons successfully passing 
such examination shall be reigstered as licensed dentists in the
board register as hereinafter provided, and also receive a certificate,
said certificate to be signed by the president and secretary
of said board and in <unclear></unclear> the following <unclear></unclear> to- wit</p>
<p>This is yo certify that ______ is hereby licensed to practice
dentistry in the state of Washington. This certificate must be
filed for record in the office of the auditor of any county in
which the party holding such certificate desires to practice, and
it is unlawful for him (or her) to practice dentistry in any county
in which said certificate is not filed for record.</p>
<p>Dated at ______this______day of ______, A.D. 190_.</p>
<p>__________
(President of said board of examiners.)
(Secretary of said board.)</p>
<pb/>
<p>"8417. (3026) Certificate to be Recorded.
The certificates in this chapter provided for shall entitle
the holder thereof to practice dentistry in any county in the state
of Washington: Provided, such certificate shall first be filed for
record in the office of the auditor of the county in which such
holder desires to practice, and nothing herein contained shall be
construed to permit any holder of any certificate to practice in any
county in this state unless such certificate shall have been first
recorded in the office of the auditor of such county as herein provided:
Provided further, that any such holder of a certificate may
practice in more than one or any number of counties in this state
on having such certificate recorded in each of such counties in
which such holder desires to so practice. Said board of dental examiners
shall, upon satisfactory proof of the loss of any certificate
issued under the provisions of this chapter, issue a new certificate
in place thereof. Any person failing to pass the first examination
successfully may demand a second examination at the subsequent meeting
of a said board, and no fee shall be charged to (for) said examination:
Provided, that the second examination is taken before the expiration
of one year. (L. '93, p.91, Section 5.)"</p>
<p>"8420. (3028) Auditor's Record.
The county auditor of each county is required to record, in
a special book to be kept by him for that purpose, all certificates
issued under the provision of this chapter which may be presented to
him for that purpose. After the record of any such certificate, such
auditor shall return to the same with a certificate of its record to the 
party entitled to the same. Said auditor shall receive for such filing
and record a fee of one dollar. (L. '93, p.92, Section 7.)"</p>
<p>"8421. (3029*) Penalty.
Any person who, as principal, agent, employer, employee or
assistant, who in any manner whatsoever shall practice dentistry or
who shall (own, run,) operate or cause to be operated, (or manage)
a dental office or headquarters in the state of Washington without
having first filed for record and has recorded in the office of the 
auditor of the county wherein he shall so practice or do such act,
a certificate from said board of dental examiners as herein provided,
shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction shall 
be fined in any sum not less than fifty dollars, nor more than two
hundred dollars, or be confined for any period not exceeding six
months in the county jail for each and every offense; Provided, the
foregoing provisions of this section shall not, prior to the tenth 
day of July, 1901, aplly to any person who shall be practicing
dentistry in this state at the time of the passage of this act and
whose name shall be registered under the provisions of this act in
the records of said board. After said tenth day of July, 1901, all 
the provisions of this section shall apply to all persons whomsoever.
All fine recovered under this act shall be paid into the common
school fund of the county in which the conviction is had."</p>
<p>"8424. (3032*) Practicing Dentistry Defined.
All person shall be said to be practicing dentistry within
the meaning of this chapter who shall contrary to this act for a
fee or salary or other reward paid either to himself or to another
person for operations or parts of operations of any kind, treat diseases 
or lesions of the human teeth or of jaws or correct malpositions
<pb/>
thereof, (or who shall own, run or manage a dental office or department)
in the state of Washington, without registering and procuring
the license as herein provided."</p>
<p>Petitioner further says that said law, and in particular
the sections quoted, aforesaid, are void and of no effect, and
contravene the provisions of Section 1, Article 14 of the amendments
to said constitution, in that they deprive your petitioner of his
liberty and property without due process of law, and deny to your 
petitioner the equal protection of the laws.</p>
<p>Petitioner says further that the said law is in contravention
of the provisions of Article 5 of the amendments of the constitution
of the United States, in that it deprives your petitioner
of his liberty and property without due process of law.</p>
<p>Petitioner further sayd that the said law is in contravention 
of the constitution of the state of Washington, to-wit:
Section 12 of Article 1 thereof because the same grants privileges
and immunities to certain citizens and classes of citizens, which
upon the same terms shall not equally belong to all citizens.</p>
<p>Petitioner further shows that the same is in contravention 
of Section 7, Article 1 of the constitution of the state of
Washington in that the same distrubs petitioner in his private affairs
without authorit of law, and that the same is in contravention
of Section 3 of Article 1 of the constitution of the state of Washington
in that it deprives the petitioner of his liberty and property 
without due process of law. </p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that at the age of thirteen
years, being then a resident of London, England, he was regularly
apprenticed to Wm. Lombardi, L.D.S, a practicing dentist, member of
Royal College of Dental Surgeons of England, at 17 Grand Marlborough
Street, London, W.C., England. That he entered such apprenticeship
<pb/>
on the 6th of August 1888 and thereafter continued to act and
serve said master as apprentice in his said business of dentistry
and dental surgery for five years, being the full term of his apprenticeship.</p>
<p>That on September 8, 1893, after serving such apprenticeship, 
petitioner removed to Athens, Greece where he worked as dental
assistant to Mr. Coracatsanis, Surgeon Dentist, who was the leading
dentist of Athens, and continued so to work for two years as dental
mechanic in the regular study and practice of that profession. </p>
<p>That in the fall of 1895 petitioner returned to London and
entered again the office of Wm. Lombardi, aforesaid, for further
study and there prosecuted such study in dental surgery for six
months under said dentist.</p>
<p>That in 1896 petitioner was engaged in the office of Dr.
Waldo Royce, dentist at Tunbridge Wells, England, said Dr. Royce
being a graduate of Harvard University, U.S.A., where petitioners
remained and practiced for eight months as general dental assistant.</p>
<p>In December 1896 petitioner moved to Cannes, France where
he was emploted by Mr. Jas. Shillcock, L.D.S., Member Royal College
of Dental Surgeons, and was employed in charge of the office of said
dentist for five months.</p>
<p>In June 1897 petitioner returned to the office of Wm. Lombardi
where he studied and practiced dental surgery for five months.</p>
<p>In December 1897 petitioner was employed by Dr. Edwin 
Shillcock, L.D.S., at Nice, France, as general assistant and continued 
in that practice for a term of six months.</p>
<p>In July 1898 petitioner was employed in a dental office at
Mile End Road, London, England for four months as dental mechanic.</p>
<p>In November 1898 petitioner returned to Mr. Edwin Shillcock,
L.D.S., at Nice, France and was by him employed for seven months in
<pb/>
the practice of general detnal work.</p>
<p>In June 1899 petitioner was employed in the office of Dr.
Isador Clifford in London, England and continued there for a period
of four months as chief dental mechanic. Said Dr. Clifford had a 
very large practice in dentistry and treated as dentist, the then 
Prince of Wales, who is now the King of England.</p>
<p>That in December 1900 petitioner aggain was employed by Mr. 
Edwin Shillcock at Nice, France, as operating assistant and continued 
there as such for seven months.</p>
<p>In July 1901 petitioner returned to London and opened an
office for himself as dentist on High Street, Plumstead, London, S.E.
where he continued the practice of dentistry for two years.</p>
<p>In April 1903 an account of ill health petitioner removed
to Canada and made his home at Lethbridge, Alberta for five years
where he continued to practice his profession as dentist.</p>
<p>That in Febrauary 1908 petitioner  moved to Seattle, Washington
and declaring his intention to become a citizen of the United States 
he opened an office as dentist at East 72d Street, Greenlake, Seattle
where he has continued the practice od dentistry undisturbed until
the issue of the warrant of arrest herein complained of.</p>
<p>That immediately upon opening his said office and before beginning
the practice of dentistry at Seattle, aforesaid, your petitioner
duly applied to the State Board of Dentistry of the state of Washington
for license to practice dentistry, tendered the legal fee and 
offered himself for examination, pursuant to law, and in all things
complied with the requirements of the statutes in such case made and
provided, save only, that he did not present any diploma from any 
college of dentistry whatever for the reason that he did not possess
one and does not now possess any, having obtained his possession,
learning and skill at the places, by the practice and study and in 
<pb/>
the matter hereinbefore set forth.</p>
<p>That for the reason that he did not and could not present
any such diploma the said State Board of Dentistry Examiners refused
to receive the application of petitioner of a license, refused to
examine him as to his qualifications to practice dentistry and refused
to grant him any license therefor. </p>
<p>Petitioner further shows that he is and at all times has 
been ready and willing to submit to examination by any duly constituted 
authority as to his qualifications to practice dentistry and is
willing to pay the fees provided by law and otherwise comply with
all the provisions of law and with all reasonable requirements, save
the presetnation of a diploma aforesaid. </p>
<p>That in order to obtain such diploma it would be 
necessary that petitioner attend some dental college for at least three years;
that no such college exists in the state of Washington, or ever has
existed in this state, and that your petitioner is unable for want
of financial means to sustain himself and his family during the time
that would be required to go to some other state and attend such
college and obtain such diploma, and that were he to take that course
he would learn nothing more than he alread knows, would acquire no
other or further skill than he already possess and would be no
better qualified in point of fact to practice his profession than he
now is.</p>
<p>Petitioner further says that he is fully qualified by experience,
study and practice to perform all the operations incident to
his profession with skill and according to the best standards to
practice in that profession. That he always has and still does read
and study arduously in all the matters and things pertaining to his
profession and keeps himself fully up to the best and most modern
standards in the practice of dentistry and dental surgery. That he
<pb/>
maintains and has ever maintained in Seattle during his practice 
there, one of the best equipped dental offices in the city and has
a large clientele of patients and customers, not one of whom has
ever complained of any inattention, want of skill or otherwise in 
the course of his practice here.</p>
<p>That your petitioner possesses and will present to your
Honor the highest recommendations as to moral character and professional 
skill from those with whom he has been employed. That your
petitioner is a man of family and of good character and in every way
qualified to practice the profession of dentistry aforesaid.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that H. F. Conover the complainant
who caused his arrest, was employed by the State Dental Board to
obtain information and to solicit and induce your petitioner to perform
upon him an operation in dental surgery, to- wit: the removing
of two decayed teeth, for the express purpose of causing petitioner's
arrest therefor, and not for any honest purpose in promoting the
public health, morals or safety.</p>
<p>Petitioner further shows that there are many dentists now
practicing as such in the state of Washingon who were so practicing
and were residents of the state in the year <unclear>1901</unclear>, at the time of
the passage of the law above quoted, who never have been examined
by the state board nor possessed any diploma from any dental college.</p>
<p>Petitioner further shows that the Supreme Court of the state
of Washington has declared the said law herein quoted to be not
violative of the state or federal constitution in the particulars
herein set forth, and that unless this honorable court defends and 
preserves the rights of your petitioner under the constitution of
the United States and of the state of Washington, petitioner will
be further restrained of his liberty and deprived of his property
pursuant to said void unconstitutional law and in violation
of the constitution of the United States in the particulars as
<pb/>
aforesaid.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE your petitioner prays that a Writ of Habeas Corpus
be granted, directed to the said Robert Hodge as Sheriff of King Cou
County, Washington, commanding him to have the body of your petitioner
Francis Stephen Medcraf before Your Honor at the time and place
therein to be specified, to do and receive what shall then and there
be determined and considered by Your Honor concerning him, together
with the time and cause of petitioner's detention and said Writ;
and that petitioner may be restored to his liberty.
Dated June 11th, 1915.
Francis Stephen Medcraf.</p>
<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON
SS
COUNTY OF KING</p>
<p>FRANCIS STEPHEN MEDCRAF being first duly sworn,
and oath says; that he is the petitioner named in the foregoing petition;
that he has carefully read the same and knows the contents
thereof and that the same is true of his own knowledge save as to 
the matters therein stated on information and belief and as to such
matters he believes it to be true.
Francis Stephen Medcraf.</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 11th day of June A.D. 1915.
Geo D. Emery
Notary Public for Washington
Residing at Seattle.</p>
<figure></figure>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>