<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0180.011.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Reply Brief.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0180.011</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Reply Brief.</title>
<date when="1914-02-05">Feburary 5, 1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2628AlbertYoung&amp;KamasaburoSugiura</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-02">Feburary 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Dodge</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Brewer</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Young, Albert H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sugiuro, Kamasaburo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Myers, H. A. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>McClellan, R. W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Johnstone, Walter L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, G. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington district Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States, For the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division</p>
<p>In the matter of the Petition of
Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo 
Sugiura, alias B.K. Sugiura,
aliens, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus | #2628
Petitioners' reply to the
Government's Additional
Authorities</p>
<p>The most striking distinction in the case of Sinis Calchi v.
Thomas, 195 Fed. <del>710</del> <add>701</add>, cited by counsel as additional authority, which
indeed is applicable to all the other cases cited, and especially to
all the cases city by Judge Dodge in the California case of Jen Yuen
v. United States, 186 Fed. 350, is that in them all the aliens had
either been convicted, or had plead guilty, or had declined to answer
in charges of <del>claim</del> <add>crimes</add> amounting to moral turpitude. Of course, in
such cases, it was not necessary for the Government to go further in
evidence. But that is not the case now before the Court. The petitioners
herein not only have strongly denied, and still deny their
guilt as charged, but have twice been tried and acquitted. Hence, we
urge that under these circumstances, it is necesary for the Government
to submit some proof upon which to base a Warrant for Deportation.</p>
<p>Judge Dodge, in the case above cited says:
"The aliens' opportunity to be head need not be on any
regular set occasion, nor according to the forms of judicial
procedure; it may be such as will secure the prompt, vigorous
action contemplated by Congress, and appropriate to the nature
of the case."</p>
<p>This decision of Judge Dodge is perhaps the strongest and
most sweeping of them all, and yet, he holds that it is necessary to
have some sort of hearing upon the charge.</p>
<fw>1</fw>
<pb/>
<p>In the Sinis Calchi case above cited, the Court refers to
the Japanese case in 189 U.S. page 87, in reference to the charges
upon which the aliens were tried, and says:
"It was in effected treated as immaterial, because
appellant had notice of the purpose of the investigation."</p>
<p>Our contention in the case at bar is that the aliens did
not have notice of the charge that they had assisted a prostitute
in any other manner than to avoid arrest. We contend that this
point was never raised until after the hearing, and for the first time
in the hearing on Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>With respect to the aliens' constitutional and common-ordinary
rights for a hearing, we would especially commend to the 
Court the powerful argument of Judge Brewer in his dissenting opinion
in the case of Fou Yue Tin vs. United States, 149 U.S. 698; 13 Sup.
Ct. 1016; 37 L. Ed. 905. The aliens in that case had live long in
the United States, had established residence and acquired property,
and were being deported in much the same arbittrary manner as in this
case.</p>
<p>We also commend to the Court the argument in the case of
Yamataya vs. Fisher, 189 U.S. 86 (47 Law Ed. 721) in which the
Court says:
"This court has never heeld, nor must we now be understood
as holding that executive officers, when executing the
provisions of a statute involving the liberty of persons may
disregard the fundamental priniciples that inhere in due
process of law .... It is not competent for ..... any
executive office .... arbitrarily to cause an alien to be
deported without giving him all opportunity to be heard upon
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
the questions involving his right to be and remain in the
United States. No such arbitrary power can exist where
the principles involved in due process of law are recognized."</p>
<ab>Respectfull submitted,
R.W. McClelland
Myers &amp; Johnstone
Attorneys for Petitioners</ab>
<p>True copies of the opening and
closing brief of the Government
in the above submitted cause is
hereby acknowledge on this Feb 5/14</p>
<ab>RW McClelland
and Myers &amp;Johnstone
Attys for Petitioners</ab>
<p>Same acknowledgement is hereby made as to
petitioners 2 give for
G.P. Fishburne
Assistant Dist atty</p>
<fw>3</fw>
<p>No 2628</p>
<p>In the 
District Court
of the United States
for the Western District
of Washington
Northern Division</p>
<p>In the matter of the Petition
of Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo
Sugiura, alias B.K.
Sugiura, aliens, for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Petitioners' reply to 
Government's Additional 
Authorities</p>
<p>R.W. McClellan, H.A.P.
Myers
W. L. Johnstone
Attorney for Petitioners
1158 Empire Building</p>
<p>J.L. MacDonald Company No. 183</p>
<pb/>
<p>Service of within reply brief
and receipt of copy admitted this 
5th day of
Feb. 1914
Attorney for U.S.</p>



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>