<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
Northern Division

In re George Hawkins
Application for Writ of Habeas 
Corpus.

NO. 1047. ORDER.

And now on this 7th day of November, 1902, Charles B. Hopkins,
United States Marshal for the District of Washington, having
in obedience to the Writ of Habeas Corpus heretofore granted produced
in open court the said George Hawkins, and endorsed upon said
writ his return, and the said Hawkins being personally present, and
also represented by his counsel, James E. Fenton, and John B. Allen,
and Melvin Grigsby, United States District Attorney for the Second
Division of the District of Alaska, appearing specially in behalf
of the government of the United States, and the court having heard
and considered the petition, the return thereto, the arguments of
counsel, and being now sufficiently advised in the premises, doth
now decide, order and adjudge as follows:

THE COURT:

This petitioner is actually within the territorial limits
of the jurisdiction of this court, for he is actually within the
boundaries of the District of Washington. He is, therefore, under
the protection of the Constitution of the United States, which declares
that no person shall be deprived of his liberty without due
process of law, and this court is charged with the responsibility
of protecting him in that right. There is no question in my mind
but what the court has jursidiction to act upon this petition. I

<pb/>

<p>do not think I should have any delicacy in doing what seems to be 
right in the matter out of regard for the order which Judge Moore
has made. As Judge of that court he made a ruling in accordance 
with the provisions of the local law of Alaska, but it is a fact
nevertheless that the court in Alaska did not have jurisdiction of
the person of the defendant; that is, actual physical jurisdiction.
Its jurisdiction was only theortecial, by reason of his having been
in that jurisdiction and having been the subject of judicial proceedings.
Now, the inquiry to be made is whether this petitioner
is being restrained of his liberty without due process of law He
is restrained of his liberty. By what lawful authority? What is the
process? Where is the writ? It is not permissible for the Warden
of the Penitentiary on McNeil's Island to detain and incarcerate
within the walls of that insitution any person without judicial 
process, he must have a judicial writ. According to the petition 
and the return, there is no writ except the warrant of commitment,
which is in legal effect annulled by the decision of the Circuit
Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit reversing the judgment of
conviction. If there is anything else which takes the place of
the writ and has the force of a writ, it must be the mandate of the
Circuit Court of Appeals. If that does not take hold of the person
of the petitioner and commit him for trial at Nome, Alaska, then
there is nothing. Now, assuming that there may be such a thing as
a legal commitment without an actual writ of mandate of the appellate
court, there has been a failure on the part of the government,
to do its duty in taking the petitioner out of the Penitentiary in 
which he was being held to the place of trial, during the season of
1902, when navigation was open, and when it might have been done.
There was time between the date of the decision at San Francisco
and the closing of navigation for the government to have done that.
If the mandate of that court affects the petitioner at all, it affects
a man in custody and powerless to remove himself to Alaska.</p>

<pb/>

<p>It is to be regarded as a command to a ministerial officer charged
with the execution of its process to take him out of the Penitentiary
and back to Alaska. That has not been done, and that places
the matter before the court in this light, that this petitioner is
being unlawfully deprived of his liberty in violation of the Constitution
of the United States, because it is without judicial process.
Now what should be done with him? The District Attorney denies the
authority of thsi court to admit the prisoner to bail. But if this
court has no right to hold him to bail and release him upon his
giving bail, the duty of the court would be to give him his liberty
absolutely. I am inclined, however, to risk any question there may
be of assuming authority, to admit him to bail.</p>

<p>It is the order of this court that the application of the
petitioner for a writ of habeas corpus be and it is hereby granted,
and it is further ordered upon the petition, that the petitioner be
admitted to bail in the sum of $3,000.00, conditioned for his appearance
at Nome, Alaska, at the date set for his trial, there to 
remain, and not depart without leave, until the termination of the
prosecution against him under the indictment which ahs been found
against him. And upon his showing of the peculiar circumstances of
his case it is further ordered by this court that he be admitted to
bail in the amount specified upon his own personal recognizance.</p>

<p>ALLEN:-

If it please the court, I would like to make an inquiry.
I want to know whether he could not go and surrender himself back
to the place--because he is poor, and might possibly have some
trouble in paying his fare up there,-- if it would not be satisfactory,
if in ample time, whether he could surrender himself and notify
the authorities so that he could be taken back up there, if he
should happen to be in a position where he could not pay his fare
back.</p>

<pb/>

<p>DISTRICT ATTY:

I will arrange that the defendant may be taken to Nome
at such time as may be required.

PRISONER called to the bar.</p>

<p>THE COURT:

You, George Hawkins, acknowledge yourself to be indebted 
and owe the United States of America the sum of $3000.00, the same
to be collected by levy upon your goods, chattels, lands and tenements,
wheresoever situated, conditioned, nevertheless, that if you
shall appear at Nome, in the Second Judicial District of Alaska, for
trial upon the indictment there pending against you on the day fixed
by the order of that court for trial and from day to day thereafter
and from term to term of the court, and not depart without leave,
<del>the</del> this obligation is to be void, otherwise to be in full force
and virtue. Do you so acknowledge?</p>

<p>PRISONER: Yes, sir.</p>

<p>THE COURT: 
The prisoner is now released from custody.</p>

<ab>C. H. Hanford
Judge</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>TX</ab>

<ab>No. 1047.</ab>

<ab>Form No. 599.</ab>

<ab>G.O.B. 7-385</ab>

<ab>IN THE Circuit COURT
OF THE UNITED STATES
FOR THE
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.</ab>

<ab>In re 
George Hawkins.
Application for Writ
of Habeas Corpus.</ab>

<ab>ORDER.</ab>

Filed Jan 2, 1903
A Reeves Ayres, Clerk,

By A. N. Moore, Deputy.


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>