<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-04" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE
APPLICATION OF NG KWACK KANG
FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS</p>
<p>No. 3157.
Filed January 14, 1916.</p>
<p>Beeler and Sullivan,         For Petitioner</p>
<p>Clay Allen, U.S. Attorney    For Government
Albert Moodie, Asst. U.S. Atty.</p>
<p>NETERER, District Judge:</p>
<p>The petitioner applied for admission to the United States as the son of an American born
Chinaman. His application was denied by the Commissioner of Immigration, an appeal was prosecuted to
the Secretary of Labor, the Commissioner affirmed, and a warrant of deportation issued. Petition for
writ of habeas corpus was made, in which he charges, First, That he was not accorded a fair hearing,
in that he was denied the right of counsel, and the evidence adduced at the preliminary examination
was wrongfully and unlawfully used against him at the hearing after arrest; Second, That there is no
evidence in the record to support the findings of the Immigration officers, and that the decision of
the Department of Labor is arbitrary and should be set aside, and Third, That the applicant is
entitled to have his appeal heard and determined by the Secretary of Labor, and that the record
discloses that it was heard and determined solely by one Alfred Hampton, and approved by Louis F.
Post, Assistant Secretary of Labor.</p>
<p>An examination of the entired record shows that the petitioner was accorded a fair  trial. While
an alien cannot claim the constitutional rights guaranteed to a citizen, he has rights which, under
treaty stipulations and the law, must be respected. None of the treaty rights nor provisions of the
law applicable to this case appear to have been violated. The examination of an alien for admission
is necessarily summary and informal. The record shows
<pb></pb>
that no opportunity was denied the applicant to produce testimony and all witnesses sought were
examined. There is nothing in the record to show that the right of counsel was denied. The fact that
counsel was not present or was not given opportunity to cross-examine the witnesses did not deprive
him of a right, Ex parte Chin Quack Wa, 22 Fed. 138; U.S. v. Williams, 190 Fed. 898.</p>
<p>"If the petitioner was not denied a fair opportunity to produce the evidence that he esires or a
fair, though summary, hearing, the case can proceed no further."</p>
<p>Chin Yow v. U.S., 208 U.S., at page 11.</p>
<p>Courts ahve such jurisdiction only as is conferrred by Congress. No discretion is vested, and
Congress has the right to prescribe rules, fix limitations, and confer authority where it deems
wise. By provision of Section 25 of teh Chinese Exclusion Act of February 20, 1907, 34 Stat. at
Large, page 906, it is provided:
"*******That in every case where an alien is excluded from admission into the United States, under
any law or treaty now existing or hereafter made, the decision of the appropriate immigration
officers, if adverse to the admission of such alien, shall be final, unless reversed on appeal to
the Secretary of Commerce and Labor *******".</p>
<p>The supreme authority is conferred upon the immigration officers, and when it appears that
petitioner was given a fair hearing, Moola Singh et al, 207 Fed. 780, the writ must be denied. Even
though the court might arrive at a different conclusion or decision, Chin Yow v. U.S. supra, such
fact would not give the court the right to review, when there is any evidence upon which to
predicate the finding. There is nothing in the record to show that the appeal to the Secretary fo
Labor was not determined by the proper official, and in the absence of a showing to the contrary,
the memorandum decision will be held to be the decision of the Secretary of Labor within the
provisions of the act, In Re Jem Yuen, 188 Fed. 350, Keyser v. Hitz, 133 U.S. 138.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>The writ is discharged and the petitioner remanded to the Department of Immigration.</p>
<p>Jeremiah Neterer
JUDGE.</p>

<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>