<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0373.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Alfonso Gagliardi v. T.W. Lynch. Decision</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0373.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Alfonso Gagliardi v. T.W. Lynch. Decision</title>
<date when="1921-12-30">December 30, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-12">December 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Gagliardi, Alfonso</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Lynch, T.W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Allen, Clay</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Frater, John A.</persName>
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-08" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the United States District Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>No. 6443.</p>

<p>Decision.</p>

<p>Filed Dec.30,1921.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Alfonso Gagliardi for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>The alien entered the United States August 4, 1915, departed November 4, 1920, reentered February 13, 1921, being passed by the Immigration Inspectors at Blaine, a preliminary examination having been made at St. Johns, New Brunswick, <del>by United States Inspector</del> About June, 1921, some inquiry was made of the alien about his passport, and information thereto was given and he was directed to return to his place of abode and employment. October following he was arrested and brought before the Board of Inquiry, and was thereafter ordered deported for the reason "that he was a person likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry, and that he entered without inspection by means of false and misleading statements." The testimony shows conclusively that during the five years residence of the alien in the United States  he was employed in profitable vocations as a farm laborer. He is physically strong and able bodied and during the year 1920 prior to his departure was engaged with his two brothers in truck farming, and is now interested in a lease upon forty-three acres of agricultural land, all of which is fit for cultivation, and from which he made during the year prior to his departure, $2,000.00; that he invested a great portion of this in this land in further prepapration for cropping. The alien registered under the draft law and did not claim exemption, but was willing to serve under our flag.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Allen, Martin &amp; Wardell, Attorneys for Petitioner.</p>
<p>Thomas P. Revelle, U.S. Atty, and John A. Frater, Asst.</p>
<p>U.S. Atty, Attorneys for United States.</p>

<p>NETERER, District Judge, - - - -</p>

<p>The testimony is conclusive that the alien was not likely to become a public charge. The record is likewise conclusive that there was no competent testimony presented that any fraud was practiced by the alien on entering. On the contrary the record does show that passport was obtained from a source believed to be legitimate and upon arriving at Havre, France, a delay of eight days was occasioned so that the passports might be forwarded to the Italian Consul for inspection, and that they were returned approved. There is nothing in the examination of the alien or any competent testimony presented that the visa is spurious and there certainly is nothing to indicate that the alien is chargeable with any irregular conduct with relation to it. The only matter in the record on which fraud is predicted is a statement in a letter not introduced in evidence that a bureau file will show that the State Department determined that the visa, stamps etc. are fraudulent. This is not evidence. This court held In Re Plastino, 236 Fed. 295, that an alien has a right to have the issue determined in accordance with established, recognized rules of procedure, and to determine such an issue in the absence of any proof is not in harmony with the traditions and principles of this government in the administration of law where fundamental rights of men are involved. Mr. Justice Clark in Kwock Jan Fat vs. White, 253 U.S. 454, at page 464, says:</p>

<p>"The acts of Congress give great power to the Secretary of Labor over**** immigrants****. It is a power to be administered, not arbitrarily and secretly, but fairly and openly, under the restraints of the tradition and principles of free government applicable where the fundamental rights of men are involved, regardless of their original or race. It is the province of the</p>

<p>-2-</p>

<p>courts, in proceedings for review, within the limits amply defined in the cases cited, to prevent abuse of this extraordinary power****."</p>

<p>The writ is granted.</p>

<p>Neterer</p>
<p>Judge.</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Dec 30 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger Clerk</p>

<p>S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>