<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0088.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0088.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Type of document</title>
<date when="1887">1887</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1887">1887</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McKay, Alice</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, Della</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020-05" who="#lkw">encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#nl">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>ELWOOD EVANS, a witness called on behalf of the Petitioner, after being duly sworn, testified as follows.</p>

<p>Q. [Ronald] You live in Tacoma A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. How long have you lived there? A. Since 1879.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know Mrs. McKay? Petitioner in this case? A. I do sir.</p>

<p>Q. Have you seen much of her since she and her husband separated? A. A few years ago she used to annoy me a great deal. I saw her a great deal more than I wanted to..</p>

<p>Q. Do you know anything of her reputation as an honest law abiding virtuous woman?</p>

<p>A. Well, there were quite a number of years there that between her disposition to save her husband from trouble, she would bear the trouble herself and paid the money to make herself poor to help him out of all his trouble, and that was the great criticism that we made about her conduct at that time. That was her great difficulty.</p>

<p>Q. Since they have separated how has she been getting along? A. I have seen her in the street probably as often as once a week for perhaps the last year or eighteen months, and she has been to my house with the chidlren often when her husband was here and I have yet to see her the first time under the influence of liquor. I do not think there is any time since 1869---I did business in 1869 when she owned considerab,e property in the old town, it was frittered away. I know of a case connected with the McKay's as early as 1869. Nearly every difficulty she has had arose out of her attempts to help McKay, paying costs from his trouble. That is what lead to her <sic>pecuniar</sic> troubles.</p>

<p>Q. From what you know of her and see of her, do you consider that woman is fit and proper and competent person to have the custody and care and management of this child? A. If I knew her to be a bad woman, but her ardent temperament and affectionate disposition and affection toward her children I believe makes her the best <sic>gurdian</sic>. I think she is a devoted mother, too affectionate wife for her own good. I think that she has been her real difficulty.</p>

<p>Q. You have frequently talked with her about these childrenhave you? A. Yes, she has been to me probably talking about getting her child back perhaps 25 or 30 times in the past two or three years. I have done so much charity business in that direction that I am ashamed to say that I declined to come to Seattle. But it has been her intense and ardent hope all the time when she comes in my office--</p>

<p>The COURT. Is she Scotch or Irish? A. I think she is Irish. I believe her

<fw>[Evans, D-EX.<gap></gap> 76--227.</fw>

<p>19</p>

<pb...></pb...>

husband is <del></del> Scotch. He is a bully-ragging sailor, <sic>becat</sic> her, knocked her teeth out. When I first knew her she was a very handsome woman.</p>

<p>Q. How does she use her children, dress them and take care of them? A. I think she is as good a mother as you can find any where. I never heard a single compaint of neglect under any circumstances.</p>

<p>Q. Do you think that woman is competent to educate that child? and have the custody</p>

<p>A. I think she would put her where she would be educated if she could not do it herself. I will risk her for doing the best for the child.</p>

<p>Q. You think she has got the grit to do it and ability? A. Too much grit.</p>

<p>Q. From what you know of her do you believe she would be guilty of committing adultery? A. I dont know anything, I never heard anything about the adultery part. I know nothing about her residence, never have been inside of her house since she occupied that old brewery over in the old town. She has been to my house probably twenty ties since then, and to my office probaably fifty or a hundred and generally has had these children with her.</p>

<p>Q. What is she doing now, working for a living or keeping a saloon? A. I never heard of her keeping a saloon. I do know of her workingg out, washing and ironing She has not done this for me but I speak of her reputation.</p>

<p>Q. She has a good reputation for being an industrious wand honest woman? A. I think she has. Very industrious woman. So far as business matter if that is any criterion of honesty, she is very honest. She does what she promises. If she comes to an attorney and says she cant pay him she keeps her word.</p>

<p>Q. When she promises to pay she keeps her word? A. I guess so. I have not had any of that kind of promises. I dont know.</p>

<p>CROSS-EXAMINATION.</p>

<p>Q. [Gilman] You have never been out <sic>whre</sic> she lives? A. Not laterly, not perhaps within two or three years.</p>

<p>Q. You dont know who lives with her? - Well I do pretty near, as near as a man can know without seeing actually in the house.</p>

<p>Q. A man might live there and you not know it? A. Yes, that is true.</p>

<p>Q. She might be intoxicated frequently and you not know? it? A. She might do it, anybody else might.</p>

<p>Q. Is she generally regarded in that community as a respectable woman? A. I have heard nothing said against her within the last two or three years.</p>

<fw>[Evans, C-EX.<gap></gap> 76--234.</fw>

<p>20</p>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>Q. There was a good deal said before? A. Anterior to that time she was considerably in court. Anybody who had such a husband would be very likely to be talked about.</p>

<p>Q. Has her reputation improved any more than to this extent, than that she is doing a little better? A. I can find gentlement in old Tacoma who have known her and known her through her troubles that consider her a respectable and reputable and would do anything to <sic>helf</sic> her in reason.</p>

<p>Q. Is she generally spoken of and regarded as a respectable woman? A. Among my acquaintances we do not talk about women. I have not heard her character discussed.</p>