<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States, in and for the
Western District of Washinton, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of Marie Miler
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. } No. 2457</p>
<p>Petitioner's Brief.</p>
<p>The petitioner in this case, Marie Miler, was on or
about the 7th day of January,m 1913, arrested under and by virtue
of a warrant issued by the Secretary of Commerce and Labor on
ground that she was a member of one of the classes of aliens
required to be deported under the laws of the United States, to-
wit: That the alien was connected with a house of prostitution
and practiced prostitiution and derived benefits therefrom after
she had entered the United States, such conduct being in violence
of the Act of Congress of Feburary 20th, '07, and amended by the
Act apporved March 26th, 1910. That thereafter said Marie Miler,
on or about January 13th, was givenn a purported
hearing before Thomas M. Fisher, Inspector of Immigration, stationed
at Seattle, Washington. That at said hearing the said
Marie Miler was not represented by counsel, although she had
employed one Roger Marchetti to represent her at that hearing,
and also had paid him a reasonable fee for his services in that
matter, and relying upon his assurance she presumed that all
the proceedings is reference to her examination were regular
and that her rights would be protected by the said Roger
Marchetti.</p>
<p>It appears from the return of the Honorable Ellis 
DeBruller, respondent in this action, that the said Roger Marchetti
did not at said hearing on January 13th, 1913, or at any other
hearing or hearings subsquent thereto appear in behalf of the
said Marie Miler, nor inform her of the fact that he would not
appear, notwithstanding she had paid the said Roger Marchetti
a reasonable fee for his services and had relied upon him to
<pb/>
defend her in said deportation proceeding.</p>
<p>By reason of the foreging this Honorable Court can
readily see that it was utterly impossible for the said
Marie Miler to controvert any of the evidence produced by the Immmigration
officers, upon which they based their findings, as a ground
for ordering her deportation to Austria.</p>
<p>Marie Miler insists, as alleged in her petition, that
the affidavit of Angelo Bassani, I. G. Polet and Vincent
Patrosini are absolutely falso in every particular, and that if
she had had an opportunity of producing evidence to controvert
the said affidavits, it<del><unclear/></del> would have been possible for her to
establish the falsity of each of the said affidavits in their 
entirety, but owing to the fact that the said Roger Marchetti
failed to properly conduct her defense in this case, as aforesaid,
it was impossible for her in said proceeding before Immigration
officers to do so.</p>
<p>It appears from the record that the Immigration officers
did notify Roger Marchetti of the hearing and the record
also discloses his assurances and attitude in reference thereto,
but the record does not show that his failure to appear and his
promises in reference thereto were ever communicated to Marie
Miler, and as a matter of fact they never were, and for that
reason the Immigration officers were at fault and mislead the
said Marie Miler in reference to her rights. The least that 
they could havee done would have been to notify her that her attorney
was not exerting himself in her behalf so that she might
have been enabled to have procured other counsel and this
establish the falsity of the purported affidavits as above stated,
and also introduced evidence which would have proven her innocence
beyond question.</p>
<p>It was not until the 13th of April, 1913, that the
said Marie Miler was informed of the exact status of the proceedings
against her and until after she had employed additional
counsel to sue out the writ of Habeas Corpus in this section, and
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
at which time <add>the</add> order of deportation had already been issued with
directions to the respondent in this case to send her to Ellis
Island, New York, tehre to await her deportation to Austria.</p>
<p>The Court can readily see that owing to this fact it 
was impossible for the petitioner, Marie Miler, to make application
to teh Secretary of Commerce and Labor to permit her to
submit additional evidence or permit her to appeal from the decision
of the respondent in this case to his superior, as, in
the meantime, she would have already been sent on her way to
Ellis Island.</p>
<p>On the question of the inability or the prevention of
the alien immigrant from appealing the case,
In re Morrow, 86 Federal, 117,
and also the cause of
Lavin vs. LaFevre, 125 Federal, 693,
are in point. from a careful reading of these cases it would
appear that the statutees regarding immigration and deportation
evidently contemplates to appeal from the subordinate officers to
the Secretary of the proper department, and where she is prevented
from presenting her case to that tribunal <add>of</add> review it does
not seem to be within the intent of Congress that the decision
of the subordinate officers shall be final.</p>
<p>In regard to Agelo Bassani's affidavit, and in fact
the affidavits of all the Italians, Polet, and Petrosini, we think
it no more than a fair statement that this Honorable Court should
carefully consider their contents. The affects of these affidavits 
are unqualifedly denied by Marie Miler throughout her
entire testimony before the Inspectors, and wihtout the assistance
and advice of counsel it would seem that the story, as told by 
Marie Miler and also her husband on their examination, was entirely
trustworthy and entitled to a great deal of weight.</p>
<p>The attention of this Court is especially called to
the affidavit of Angelo Bassani wherein he states that is was
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
not until in May, 1912, that he first met Marie Miler, record
page 32. It appears from the testimony of Marie Miler herself
that affiant had met the said Marie Miler and her husband in Butte
Montana, serval month previous and had advised them at that 
time to come to Seattle, but that they had disregarded his advice and had gone to the State of California instead.</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>