<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0147.012">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Gladys Fredrika Fuson v. Territory of Washington. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Hidalgo, Emily" xml:id="eh ">Emily Hidalgo</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0147.012</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Gladys Fredrika Fuson v. Territory of Washington. Petition</title>
<date when="1916">October 26, 1916</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fuson, Gladys Fredrika</term>
<term>McMasters, Lona</term>
<term>Mason,Blanche H.</term>
<term>Fuson, Harold W.</term>
<term>Merrill, Lilburn</term>
<term>Williams, Edward</term>
<term>Laxew, Edin</term>
<term>Sheldon, M.E.</term>
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Laxew, Edin</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Fuson, Gladys Fredrika</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Dykeman, King</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0147.012"/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATE SISTRICT, WESERN DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION 
OF MRS. GLADYS FREDRIKA FUSON,
FOR WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.} 
NO.3451
PETITION.</p>

<p>Come now Mrs. Gladys Fredrika Fuson, by her next frind-
Lona McMasters, and petition this Honoable Court for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus herin, and alleges as follors:</p>

<p>That heretofore, on Friday, October 20th, 1916, the said
Mrs. Gladys Fredrika Fuson, was a resident of Port Townsend
and arrested the above named Mrs. Gladys Fredrika Fuson and trasported 
her to Seattle against her will and withough her consent,
alleging as cause therfor that one King Dykeman had verbally instructed 
her so to do.</p>

<p>That the said King Dykeman and Blanche H. Mason and Harold 
W. Fuson and Doctor Lilburn Merrill have confined the said Mrs. 
Glays Fredrika Fuson in a prison or jail at Broadway and Spruce
Streets, in the City of Seattele.</p>

<p>That said arrest, imprisonment and restrained were and are 
illegal and contrary to the course of common law and of the guarantees
of the Constitution of the United States concerning life,
libery and the persuit of happiness.</p>

<p>That it was not alleged that the said Mrs. Gladys Fredrika 
Fuson had committment any offense against the laws at any time or any 
place.</p>

<p>That no warrant or information was issued</p>

<p>That, as affiant belives, that said Mrs. GLadys Fredrika 
Fuson is not being held by any sentence of any competent court.</p>

<pb/>

<p>That she has not been served with any kind of process and
that when affiant asked for the reasons she could obtain no satisfaction
from the said persons, or any of them.</p>

<p>Affiant further says that the said Mrs. Gladys Fredrika
Fuson is married woman who has been abandoned by her husband, the 
above named Harold W. Fuson; and that the said Harold W. Fuson has 
commenced suit for divorce against the said Mrs. Gladys Fredrik
Fuson, to which she has filed an answer and cross complaint in the 
Superior Court of King County, Washington.</p>

<p>That affiant belives that said proceeding was begun for 
the express purpose of preventing said Mrs. Gladys Fredrika Fuson
from making her defense to said action and for the purpose of holding 
her incoluntary imprisonment for the advantage of the said
Harold W. Fuson in said action; and affiant belives and states the
fact to be that the said Dykeman, Fuson, Mason and Merill have 
illegally conspired to deprive the said Mrs. Gladys Fredrika Fuson
of her rights of libert guaranteed to all citizens of the United
States. Affiant further says that the said Mrs. Gladys Fredrika 
Fuson is a native bor citizen of the United States and entitles to
all of the privileges and immunities of such,</p>

<p>Tha the affiant and the said Mrs. Gladys freiks Fuson 
are both poor persons, and ask to be permitted to prosecute this 
action as such.</p>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON
COUNTY OF KING, } SS:</p>

<p>LONA Mc MASTERS, being first fully sworn, deposes and
says: that she is the person named in the foregoing Petition as the 
next friend of the ssaid Mrs. Gladys Fredika Fuson; that she has 
read the forgong Petition for Habeas Corpus, knows the contents
therof and that the same is true; that the reason that affidavits
of verification is made by addiant and not by the said Mrs. Gladys
Fredirka Fuson is that the said Mrs. Gladys Fredrika Fuson is in 

<pb/>

duress and unale to sign the same,</p>

<p>Mrs. Lona Mc Masters</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 25th day of October 
1916.</p>

<p>M E Sheldon 
Notarary Public in and for the State 
of Washington, residing at Seattle</p>

<figure></figure>

<pb/>

<p>No.3451</p>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT
COURT, WESTERN DISTRICT OF 
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION 
OF MRS. GLADYS FREDRIKA FUSON,
FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS</p>

<p>PETITION</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U.S. Distict Court, 
Western Dist. of Washington,
NORTHERN DIVISION
OCT 26 1916
FRANK L CROSBY CLERK
Edin Laxew Deputy</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>