<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0224.004">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Lewis Johnson v. Defendant. Rex v. Lewis Johnson Case Transcription, Witness Transcription,John Pritchard.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0224.004</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">John Lewis v. Defendant. Rex v. Lewis Johnson.</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-06">June 15, 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>H.C. Shaw</term>
<term>Lewis Johnson</term> 
<term>E.E. Robinson</term> 
<term>John Pritchard</term> 
<term>J.K. Kennedy</term> 
<term>L.H. Heaney</term> 
<term>John Pritchard</term> 
<term>McGill</term> 
<term>Shayer</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Vancouver, British Colombia, Canada</term> 
<term>Olalla, British Colombia</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>John Lewis</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-02" who="#AS">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p><unclear></unclear></p>
<p>POLICE COURT</p> 
<p>(Before H.C. Shaw, Esq., P.M.)</p> 
<p>June 19th, 1915. Vancouver, B.C.</p> 
<p>REX vs LEWIS JOHNSTON</p>
<pb></pb> 
<p>POLICE COURT</p> 
<p>(Before H.C. Shaw Esq., P.M.)</p> 
<p>Vancouver, B.C. June 15th, 1915. </p>
<p>Canada
Province of British Columbia
County of Vancouver
City of Vancouver</p> 
<p>REX vs LEWIS JOHNSTON</p> 
<p>LEWIS JOHNSTON charged on the infromation of E.E. Robinson
of the city of Vancouver on the 15th day of June, 1915, for 
that at the said City of Vancouver on the 4th day of June, A.D.
1915, he did unlawfully steal the sum of $1800:00 the pro-
perty of John Pritchard.</p>  
<p>Contrary to the form of the Statute in such case made and
provided.</p> 
<p>J.K. KENNEDY, ESQ. Counsel for Prosecution</p>
<p>L.H. HEANEY, sworn as stenographer</p>
<p>JOHN PRITCHARD,
Hotel Main.
called as witness, as being first
sworn, testified as follows:</p> 
<p>QUESTIONS by MR KENNEDY:</p> 
<p>1 Q. What is your occupation, Mr Pritchard? A. Wel I have
not been doing anything for about three years. I ran a store
at Ollala, in a mining camp at Ollala B.C. That was the last
business I was in.</p> 
<p>2 Q. When did you come to Vancouver last? A. I think about the
13th of February I came here. That would be about four months
ago.</p> 
<p>3 Q. Now on the 4th of June, Mr Pritchard, will you tell us in
your own words what occurred in connection with this charge?
A. Well I had a deal on for some land, and I went to the Bank
and withdrew eighteen hundred dollars from the Canadian Bank of
Commerce, Hastings Street; and my lawyer went over to West-
minster to search the title for me that day, and I was waiting
for him to come back, and he didn't get back till about 5:30</p>
<p>4 Q. We can shorten that a great deal. You had the eighteen
hundred dollars in your pocket at what time of night? A. Well
I had it when I was up
<pb></pb>
in the lawyer's office. That would 
be about six o'clock.</p> 
<p>5 Q. Well what next? A. My lawyer and -r Shayer- that is the
party I am buying the land from - we left the office and
alked over to the Commercial Hotel and had a drink; and my
lawyer, Mr. McGill he went away home, and we walked down as 
far as the Woods Hotel and got another drink; and that is the
last I recollect.</p> 
<p>6 Q. Who were with you when you had the drink at the Woods
Hotel? A. Mr. Shayer</p> 
<p>7 Q. And anybodyelse? A.No.</p> 
<p>8 Q. And when you had a drink at the first Hotel? A. That was
just after we left the office.</p> 
<p>9 Q. Who was with you then? A. Mr. McGill, my lawyer, and Mr Shay
er and myself.</p> 
<p>10 Q. Are you a drinking man? A. Yes I have been drinking all my
life, but not much.</p> 
<p>11 Q. Have you ever had it happen recently that two drinks would
put you clean out A. No</p> 
<p>12 Q. What were you drinking? A. Seagrams Rye whiskey</p>
<p>13 Q. And that is the last you recollect till when? A. Till
next morning at seven o'clock</p> 
<p>14 Q. Where did you find yourself then? A. In the Hotel Main
lying on the bed with my clothes on.</p> 
<p>15 Q. Where is that with reference to the Woods Hotel? A. Why
the Woods is on Hastings street and the Main is on. . . .</p> 
<p>16 Q. How far away, how many blocks? A. About four blocks, five
blocks, I guess</p> 
<p>17 Q. Were you staying up at the Main Hotel at all? A. Yes I have
been staying there all along since I have been in town.</p> 
<p>18 Q. Did you find yourself in your own room then? A. Yes</p> 
<p>19 Q. What about the money? A. When I woke up, the first thing I 
thought of was the money when I found what shape I was in
lying on the bed, and I found it was gone.</p> 
<p>20 Q. Were you dressed? A. I was lying on the bed with my
<pb></pb>
clothes on.</p> 
<p>21 Q. When was the last time you that you remeber, that you saw you 
had the money? A. I don't know. I don't recollect
any particular time that I had it.</p> 
<p>22 Q. You say you had it when you were at the lawyer's office
A. Yes and I am sure I had it when I was at the Woods. I am 
confident I had it at the Woods, although I don't recollect
putting my hand on it.</p> 
<p>23 Q. How were you carrying it? A. In a pocket-book in my left 
hand hip pocket?</p> 
<p>24 Q. Had you shown the money to anybody at either of the Hotels
that you recollect? A. No not at that time.</p> 
<p>25 Q. Do you remember seeing at either Hotel any colored man
A. No I don't</p> 
<p>26 Q. What was the denominations of the money? A. There were
seventeen hundred dollar bills and two fifties that I took out
of the Bank, and then I'had some ten dollar bills in my pocket
-- I think about ninety dollars in ten dollar bills in my 
pocket-book.</p> 
<p>27 Q. In the same book? A.Yes in the same pocket-book, in the same
pocket</p> 
<p>28 Q. And the whole pocket-book was gone, A. Yes</p> 
<p>29 Q. In all you lost how much? A. I think $180</p>
<p>30 Q. $180? A. $1880, I should say because I had change for a
ten dollar bill in my pocket the next morning, and I think 
I must have changed a ten dollar bill some place. So I 
think I may say $1880.</p>
<p>31 Q. In the vicinity anyway? A. Yes</p> 
<p>32 Q. I asked you a moment ago whether you are a drinking man;
are you man who is in the habit of getting drunk? A. No
not in the habit; once in a while I get off but I don't make
a practice of it.</p> 
<p>33 Q. Have you been on any spree recently> A. No.</p> 
<p>34 Q. Had you gone out with the intention of a spree on this
occasion at all? A. No certainly not.</p> 
<p>35 Q. You say "certainly not" because you had so much money with
you? A. Yes</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>