<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0117.015"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Lelah-Puc-ka-Chee and Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha v. W.G. Malin and G.N. Nellis. Brief and Argument of Petitioners</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0117.015</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Lelah-Puc-ka-Chee and Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha v. W.G. Malin and G.N. Nellis. Brief and Argument of Petitioners</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1899-12">December 1899</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Bridleman</term>
<term>Campbell</term>
<term>Kagma</term>
<term>Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee</term>
<term>Malin, W.G.</term>
<term>McMillun</term>
<term>Nellis, G.N.</term>
<term>Steward, J.O.</term>
<term>Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Iowa</term>
<term>Kansas City</term>
<term>United States</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Malin, W.G.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Nellis, G.N.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Lamb, Jacob W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Shiras, O.P.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court in Northern District Iowa</orgName> 
<placeName>Toledo, Iowa</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="sab">transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0117.015"/> 

<!-- <p>Copied at the National Archives at Kansas City</p> -->

<p>KAGAMA VS Jackson Iron CO, 43 N,W Rep 602 to 606 same in 76 Mich 498</p>

<p>The above cases not only hold that Tribal Indian marriages are valid but also hold that Tribal Indians are not subject to State Courts and <del/> that Tribal Indians were placed beyond our jurisdiction by the U,S Constitution and that we have no more right to control their domestic relations, usages and laws than those of India or Turkey. In this connection I call attention to the last clause of part 9 of Chap- 188 on page 428 of Vol- 2 (no,s 1 to 5 passed in 1895 in supplement to U,S, Revised Statutes. Which reads, "And it shall be unlawful for an <sic>Indean</sic> agent or other employee of the Government to induce or seek to induce, by withholiding rations or by other improper means, the parents or next of kin of any Indian to consent to the removal of any Indian Child beyond the limits off the reservation. Your Honor will reccollect this Toledo School is of the Reservation, Now the sole purpose for which the above act was passed, was, to put a stop to agents and Superintendents of the General Government overleaping the law and policy of the General Government in their unlawful attempts to enforce compulsory education. In deidance of all the above authorities and well defined laws, these defendants, Fresh from the Rural districts, have out-striped any thing yet on record in the books (So far as petitioner,s atty is able to find in all the numerous cases read) in the way of a vigerous enforcement of compulsory Indian education, with a numerous police force they have gathered in the boys and girls, and now have commenced the novel work of forcibly gathering in the married Squaws. (That too while their husbands are still living and hanging to them) Then comes in support of this before unheard of conduct, The novel argument of the District attorney " That if the this agent and Superintendent are not allowed to thus go on in using such force and compulsion in getting these Indians into this school, The Government may as well close its doors and tear it down. Such argument, if it can be called such, sounds more like information borrowed from the numerous decisions and recorded policies of the Federal Government concerning its powers and jurisdictions over these T Tribal Indians. In a defferent form expressed the District attorney 
in behalf of these defendants, and in defense of their illegal acts and
doing and in his attempt to justify the same claims in behalf of the  F
Federal Government almost unlimitted power in the United States and its
Agents over these Indians Or in orther words the district attorney
claims these defendant-agents of the Federal Government have the unlimited
power to do what the Federal Government
 cannot itself do and what the Federal-constitution forbids it doing, Such is by no means the law on the contrary the well defined law and policy of the Federal Government is to civilize and educate these Tribal Indians only by and through two fixed rules and conditions. - FIRST Just as fast and rapidly as such Tribal Indians by promise, treaty or consent will send their children into these Government Schools and permit them to so remain. SECOND Providing further that the parents or next of kin of such Tribal Indian children, Individually give their consent to send the them into these schools and so long as they permit them to remain in such schools In other words the Indians on their part both as a Tribe and as Individual parents must first contract promise and agree and consent, then and not until then have these defendants any power to act or do. When such parental consent and promises are yielded by the Indians and so long as such Indians are willing to keep them in effect and their children accordingly in these Government Schools then and not until then it is made the duty of the Government Indian agents and Superintendents of the Government School to see that such agreements and consent and willingness</p>
<p>see other side of this sheet</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
