<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0187.013">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
    <title>Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0187.013</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
    <title level="m" type="main">Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1914">1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-06">June 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>


</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Everett, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Marie Robina Grayson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Noah Shakespeare</persName>
<persName>Louis A. Merrick</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Clay Allen</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA. DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON.</p>

<p>In re Marie Robina Grayson,
alias Marie Robina. 
ORDER.</p>
<p>2780</p>

<p>The petiton of Marie Robina Grayson, alias Marie Robina, having
been to day presented to the Court, in open Court, praying that a 
writ of habeas corpus issue to Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration 
directed, and alleging that the said Henry M. White, unlawfully 
detains the said Marie Robina Grayson, and deprives her of her liberty, 
within the District and Division afroresaid, and the Court having duly 
examined such petition, it is now, after full consideration,</p>
<p>ORDERED that a writ of habeas corpus in due form of law 
do forthwith issue out of and under the seal of this Court, to Henry
M. White, Commissioner of Immigration, directed, commanding and 
requiring the said Henry M. White, to produce before this Court, at a 
regular session thereof, appointed to be holden at the Federal Building, 
in the City of Seattle, in said District on the 3rd day of July, 
1914, at the opening of said Court on said day, the body of said Marie
Robina Grayson, alias Marie Robina, and to then and there return
said writ, with a full cause of the detention of the said Marie Robina
Grayson, fully set forth.</p>
<p>IT IS FURTHER ORDERED that at the same time and place the said 
Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration, do certify to this Court
all the proceedings had before Charles A. Turner as <del>County</del> Immigration
Inspector, and before the said Henry M. White, or any other 
official of the Immigration service in such District, subsequent to 
the 1st day of January, 1914, respcting the deportation of the said 
Marie Robina Grayson, alias Marie Robina, to the end that such record
having been inspected such order may be made therein as of right and 
justice ought to be made.</p>
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
    <p>6/27/14
    S. E. L.</p>
<p>IT IS FURTHER ORDERED that the said writ of habeas corpus contain
a clause directing that the said Marie Robina Grayson, be enlarged
and released from custody of the said Henry M. White, upon the filing 
in the office of the Clerk of this Court, <add>in the sum of two thousand dollars</add> a bond, conditioned for the 
obedience to any orders of this Court, in said matter made,by the said
Marie Robina Grayson, and in case of the discharge of said writ of 
habeas corpus by this Court rendition by the said Marie Robina Grayson, 
of her said body into the custody of the said Henry M. White, such bond
to be in a form to be approved by the United States District Attorney, 
for this District, and with sureties satisfactory to said District 
Attorney, and upon the filing of such bond, so approved, let the 
said Marie Robina Grayson, alias Marie Robina be discharged from 
custody pending the further order of this Court, in this proceeding.</p>
<p>Done in open Court this 27th day of June, 1914.</p>
<p>By the Court</p>
<ab>Jeremiah Neterer <lb/>
Judge.</ab>

<ab>Ok.
Allen <lb/>
U.S. Atty.</ab>

<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
    <p>g O B - 5- 20 S X</p>
<p>UNITED STATES OF 
AMERICA
DISTRICT COURT
FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF 
WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>In Re. 
Marie Robina Grayson
alias Marie Robina
Bankrupt</p>

<p>Order</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. District Court
Western Dist. of Washington.
JUN 27, 1914</p>
<ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk,
By EML Deputy</ab>

<p><add>Noah Shakespeare
and</add> Louis A. Merrick
Attorney for Marie Robina
Everett, Washington</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>