<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0124.014">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Territory of Washington V. David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford. Criminal</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0124.014</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Territory of Washington V. David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford. Criminal</title>
<date when="1891">1884</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">September 1884</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>David Aimesworth</term>
<term>J.S. Danford</term>
<term>M.H. Whitney</term>
<term>H.J. Whitney</term>
<term>S.C. Whitney</term>
<term>F.A. Bettes Deputy</term>
<term>Dr. J.W. Johnson</term>
<term>Helen Varker</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Cheney, Washington</term>
<term>Spokane County, Washington</term>
<term>Adams County, Washington</term>
<term>New York</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-09" who="#lkw">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>The Territory of Washington
vs.
David Aimesworth
J.S. Danford } District Court for
the first Judicial 
District of Washington
Territory, holding terms 
at Cheney in Spokane County

David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford are
accused by the grand juries of the counties of 
Spokane and Adams, &amp; of the Crime &amp; obtaining
<del></del> property by false pretenses comes
written as follows: The said David Aimesworth 
and J.S. Danford on the Sixth day of September
A.D. 1884 in the county of Spokane in the District
and Territory aforesaid unlawfully knowingly
designedly, and with intent to defraud one
M.H. Whitney, did falsely pretend that a
certain paper writing produced by the said 
David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford to the said
M.H. Whitney and purporting to be a bill of 
exchange drawn by the Spokane County
Bank and signed by the said David Aimesworth
as Cashier thereof, under and by the name 
of D. Aimesworth Cas which said Spokane
County Bank was then and there an <unclear></unclear>
of persons consisting of the David Aimesworth
and J.S. Danford and purporting then and 
to do a general banking business at the Town of
Cheney in the County, District and Territory of 
upon the Seaboard Bank New York for the payment
to the order of H.J. Whitney of the sum of One 
Hundred Dollars was then and there a good,
genuine and available order for payment of the 
sum of One Hundred Dollars, and was then and
there of the value of One Hundred Dollars which
said paper writing was of the ten or following then
is to say:
"No. 4065," "Cheney W.T. Sept. 6th 1884"
"Spokane County Clerk"
Pay to the order of H.J. Whitney One Hundred
Dollars,
To Seaboard Bank
#100, New York, } D. Aimesworth, Cas.
and the said David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford
did then and there unlawfully knowingly designed
and with intent to defraud the said M.H. Whitney to
pretend to the said M.H. Whitney that a certain paper
writing then and there produced by the said 
David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford to the said M.H.
Whitney and purporting to be a bill of exchange
drawn by the Spokane County Bank as aforesaid
and signed by the said David Aimesworth as cashier
under and by the name of D. Aimesworth Cas.
upon the Seaboard Bank drew forth for the 
payment to the order of H.J. Whitney of of the
sum of Two Hundred &amp; fifty Dollars, was
then and there a good, genuine and available
order for the payment of the sum of Two Hundred
and fifty dollars and was then and there of the 
value of two hundred and fifty dollars
which said paper writing was of the ten or 
following that is to say.
No. 4066     Cheney W.T. Sept. 6th 1884,
Spokane County Bank,
Pay to the order of H.J. Whitney Two Hundred
and fifty dollars.
D. Aimesworth Cas.
To Seaboard Bank
4200. New York
And the said David Aimesworth and
J.S. Danford did then and there unlawfully, 
knowingly, designedly and with intent to defraud
the said M.H. Whitney falsely pretend to the said
M.H. Whitney that a certain paper writing then 
and there produced by the said David Aimesworth
and J.S. Danford to the said M.H. Whitney and
purporting to be a bill of exchange drawn
by the Spokane County Bank as aforesaid and
signed by the said David Aimesworth as cashier
of said bank under and by the name of
D. Aimesworth Cas upon the Seaboard Bank New
York for the payment to the order of M.H. Whitney
of the sum of Five Hundred Dollars was then
and there a good genuine and available
order for the payment of the sum of five
hundred dollars and was then and 
there of the value of five hundred dollars 
which said paper writing was of the tenor
following that is to say:
No. 4067.  Cheney W.T. Sept. 6 1884
Spokane County Bank
Pay to the order of H.J. Whitney Five
Hundred Dollars.
D.Aimesworth Cas.
To Seaboard Bank
4500# New York}
And the said David Aimesworth and
J.S. Danford did then and there unlawfully
knowingly, designedly and with the intent 
to defraud the said M.H. Whitney, falsely pretend
to the said M.H. Whitney that a certain paper
writing then and there produced by the said
David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford to the said
M.H. Whitney and purporting to be a bill of 
exchange drawn by the Spokane County Bank
as aforesaid and signed by the said David
Aimesworth as cashier of said bank under
and by the name of D. Aimesworth upon
the Seaboard Bank of New York for payment
to the order of H.J. Whitney of the sum of
Five Hundred Dollars was then and there
a good genuine and available order for
the payment of the sum of Five Hundred
Dollars and was then and there of the value 
of five hundred dollars which said paper
writing is of the ten or
following that is to say:
No. 6067 Cheney W.T. Sept. 6, 1884
Spokane County Bank,
Pay to the order of M.H. Whitney Five
Hundred Dollars,
D. Aimesworth Cas.
To Seaboard Bank
4500# New York}
And the said David Aimesworth and
J.S. Danford did then and there unlawfully
knowingly, designedly and with the intent
to defraud the said M.H. Whitney falsely pretend
to the said M.H. Whitney that a certain paper
writing then and there produced by the said 
M.H. Whitney and purporting to be a bill of
exchange drawn by the Spokane County Bank
as aforesaid and signed by the said David
Aimesworth as cashier of said Bank under
and by the name of D. Aimesworth upon 
the Seaboard Bank of New york for payment
to the order of H.J. Whitney of the sum of
Five Hundred Dollars was then and there
a good genuine and available order for 
the payment of the sum of Five Hundred
Dollars and was then and there of the value
of Five Hundred Dollars which said paper
writing is of the tenor following that is to say:
No. 4068,  Cheney W.T. Sept. 6, 1884
Spokane County Bank
Pay to the order of M.J. Whitney Five Hundred
Dollars
To Seaboard Bank
43004 New York}  D. Aimesworth Cas.
And the said David Aimesworth and J.S.
Danford did then and there unlawfully, knowingly
designedly and with intent to defraud the said
M.H. Whitney falsely pretend to the said M.H. 
Whitney that a certain paper writing then and
there produced by the said David Aimesworth
and J.S. Danford to the said M.H. Whitney
and purporting to be a bill of exchange drawn
by the Spokane County Bank as aforesaid
and signed by the said David Aimesworth
as cashier of said bank under and by the 
name of D. Aimesworth Cas, upon the Seaboard 
Bank of New York for the payment to the
order of H.J. Whitney of the sum of Five 
Hundred dollars was then and there a 
good, genuine and available order for the 
payment of the sum of five hundred dollars
and was then and there of the value of five
hundred dollars, which said paper 
writing is of the tenor following that is to say:
No. 4069 Cheney W.T. Sept. 6th, 1884
Spokane County Bank
pay to the order of H.J. Whitney Five Hundred
Dollars D. Aimesworth Cas.
Seaboard Bank,
#500# New York
And the said David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford
did then and there unlawfully,
knowingly, designedly and with intent to defraud the 
said M.H. Whitney, falsely pretend to the said
M.H. Whitney that a certain paper writing then 
and there produced by the said David Aimesworth
and J.S. Danford to the said M.H. Whitney and 
purporting to be a bill of exchange drawn 
by the Spokane County Bank as aforesaid and
signed by the said David Aimesworth as cashier
of said bank, under and by the name of
D. Aimesworth Cas. upon the Seaboard Bank of New York
for the payment to the order of M.H. Whitney of
the sum of five hundred dollars was then
and there a good, genuine and available 
order for the payment of the sum of five 
hundred dollars and was then and 
there of the value of five hundred dollars 
which said paper writing was of the tenor
following that is to say:
No. 4070 Cheney W.T. Sept. 6th 1884
Spokane County Bank
Pay to the order of H.J. Whitney Five
Hundred Dollars
To Seaboard Bank. D.Aimesworth Cas.
$500 New York
And the said David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford
did then and there unlawfully, knowingly, designedly
and with the intent to defraud the said M.H. Whitney
falsely pretend to the said M.H. Whitney that the said
Spokane County bank as aforesaid kept an 
with the said Seaboard bank of New 
York for the payment of the said bill of exchange
and each and every of them, and that the said
Spokane County Bank had full power, right, 
and authority to draw bills of exchange upon the
said Seaboard Bank of New York, by means of
which said false pretenses so as aforesaid, there
said David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford did
then and there unlawfully, knowingly, designedly
and with the intent to defraud the said M.H. Whitney
obtain from the said M.H. Whitney a negotiable
promisary now signed by the said M.H. Whitney
together with H.J. Whitney and S.C. Whitney for the sum
of Five Hundred and eleven dollars and sixty seven cents
which said promisary note was dated the said 6th 
day of September A.D. 1884, and repayable to the <unclear></unclear>
of said David Aimesworth as cashier of said 
Spokane County Bank, under and by the name
of D. Aimesworth Cashier, in seventy days of 
the date thereof, which said promisary note
was then and there of the value of Five Hundred
and eleven dollars and sixty seven cents, and which
said promisary note was then and there of the goods
chattel and property of said M.H. Whitney: and 
one good genuine and available bill of 
exchange bill of exchange for the sum of
two hundred and eighty eight dollars, which 
said bill of exchange was endorsed and payable
to the order of said M.H. Whitney which said
bill of exchange was then and there of the value
of two hundred and eighty eight dollars, and was
of the goods, chattel and property of said M.H.
Whitney, a one particular deception of which
said bill of exchange the grand jury are valuable
to give, and then tenor afterwhich is to the 
grand jury unknown: and one certain 
check upon the Spokane County Bank 
signed by the said M.H. Whitney, for the amount
of ninetwwn hundred dollars, dated the sixth
day of September 1884 and payable to the said
David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford under
and by the name of D. Aimesworth Cas, she
the said M.H. Whitney then and there having money
in the hands of the said Spokane County Bank for the
payment thereof, which said check was then and
there of the value of nineteen hundred dollars, and
was of the goods, chattel, and property of said M.H. 
Whitney: Which said goods, chattel and property
were by the said David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford
deceptedly obtained as aforesaid from the said M.H. 
Whitney with the intent to cheat and defraud the said
M.H. Whitney out of the same: Whereas in truth
and in fact the said paper writings were with
then and there, nor was any of them a good, genuine
and available order for the payment of the sum of
sum of money therein pursed, or for the payment
of any sum of money whatever, nor were
the said paper writings, or either, or any or all of them of the
value by the said David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford
then and there pretended or of any value whatsoever but
each and every of said paper writings was then and 
there wholly worthy and of a value. And whereas
in truth and in fact the said Spokane County Bank
did not keep any account with the said Seaboard
Bank; and whereas in truth and in fact the said
Spokane County Bank had not any money in the
hands of the said Seaboard Bank for the payment
of the said bills of exchange, ot either or any of them
and whereas in truth and in fact the said Spokane
County Bank had not any power, right or authority
to draw bills of exchange upon the said Seaboard
Bank, as the said David Aimesworth and 
J.S. Danford then and there will know; contrary 
to the form of the statute in such case
made and provided. Dated at Cheney in the District
aforesaid the ninth day of October A.D. 1884  S.C. Hyde
District Attorney
By F.A. Bettes Deputy
Names of the witnesses named before
the Grand Jury
Mrs. M.H. Whitney  Dr. J.W. Johnson
Mrs. Helen Varker
Found at the existance of Mrs. M.H. Whitney</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
