<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0241.040"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Continuation of Application for M.A. Walker</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>

<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0241.040</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Continuation of Application for M.A. Walker</title>
<date when="1885-08-25">August 25, 1885</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1885-07">July 1885</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Byrd, Lewis</term>
<term>Campbell, Alex</term>
<term>Hoyt, John P.</term>
<term>Walker, M.A.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Tacoma, Pierce County, Washington Territory</term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Walker, M.A.</persName>
<persName>Walker, Charles</persName>
<persName>Walker, Helen</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Campbell, A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court For The Western District of Washington Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="#sab">transcribed, encoded</change> 
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0241.040"/>

<p>1601 1/2</p>

<p>In the District of the Second Judicial District of Washington Territory, holding terms at Tacoma, in and for Pierce County, Wash. Terry.</p>

<p>xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx
In the matter of application of x
                                x
M.A. WALKER,                    x     Habeas Corpus
                                x
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus     x
xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx</p>

<p>To the Honorable John, P. Hoyt, Judge of the Second Judicial District of Washington Territory, holding terms at Tacoma, in and for Pierce County, Washington Territory.</p>
<p>The petition of M. A. Walker, respectfully shows: ---</p>
<p>I.</p>

<p>That he, the said petitioner, is unlawfully imprisoned, contained, confined and restrained of his liberty by Lewis Byrd, Sheriff of said Pierce County, Washington Territory, 
and that he</p>

<!-- note over the typed text -->
<p>III</p>

<p>That the said imprisonment, detention, confinement and restraint are illegal, and that the illegality thereof consists in this, to wit:---</p>
<p>That there was no evidence or testimony taken or presented before or to said A. Campbell, justice of the peace, to show that said William Lockwood met his death, or was killed, or attempted to be killed, or was struck, stabbed, shot, or otherwise hurt or assaulted, or was in any wise injured or attempted to be injured by any person or persons, criminally, or otherwise; or that he met his death or was killed by any person or persons; but the evidence only tended to show that he was killed on the track of said railroad by an engine and car, and by accident.</p>
<p>That there was no evidence or testimony taken or presented before said justice of the peace that said William Lockwood was killed, or attempted to be killed, or was s truck, stabbed, shot or otherwise hurt or assaulted, or was in anywise injured or attempted to be injured by this petitioner, or by or through his assistance, knowledge or connivance; or that he met his death or was killed by this petitioner, or that this petitioner was in anywise accessory thereto; but said evidence only tended to show that said deceased was killed on said railroad track by being struck and run over by an engine and car on said track, and by accident,</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
