<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the United States District Court, In and For the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Chin Hing, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. } No. 2857
Bail Bond</p>
<p>Whereas, Chin Hing, by and through his Attorney, John J.
Sullivan, filed an application in the above entitled Court for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus, which said Writ was after <add>hearing</add> discharged by
the Honorable Heremiah Neterer, Judge in and for theWestern District
of Washington, Northern Divison, and said petitioner remanded 
to the custody of the United States Commissioner of Immigration;
and</p>
<p>Whereas, the said petitioner, Chin Hing, by and through his
Attorney, John J. Sullivan, has appealed from said Order and Judgment
entered on the 29th day of May, 1915, to the Circuit
Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit; and</p>
<p>Whereas, pending said appeal the above entitled Court
has required the said petitioner, Chin Hing to be enlarged upon 
furnishing a Bail Bond in the sum of ONe Thousand Five Hundred
($1500.00) Dollars, with sufficient sureties for the appearance of
said Chin Hing in the above entitled court, in case said Decree and
Order and Judgment be affirmed.</p>
<p>Now, therefore, know all men by these presents: that we, 
Chin Hing, as principal, by and through his Attorney, John J.
Sullivan, and National Surety Company, a corportation,
as sureties, are held and firmly bound unto the United States in
the penal sum of One Thousand Five Hundred ($1500.00) Dollars,
for the payment of which <del><unclear/></del> well and truly to be made they bind
<fw>1.</fw>
<pb/>
themselves, their heirs executors, administrators and assigns,
jointly and serverally, by these presents,</p>
<p>Sealed with their seals and dated this 1 day of
June, 1915.</p>
<p>The condition of the above obligation is such that if the 
above mentioned Chin Hing shall at all times render himself amenable
to the orders and processes of the above entitled court, in
case said Decree of the above entitled court be affirmed by the
Circuit Court of Appeals of the Ninth Circuit, and will appear for
judgment in case it be ultimately determined that the said petitioner
is not entitled to a Writ of Habeas Corpus, and is remanded
to the custody of the Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle,
Washington, then this obligation to be void; otherwise to remain 
in full force and effect.</p>
<figure/>
<ab>Chin Hing</ab>
<ab>By John J Sullivan
Attorney for Petitioner
Chin Hing</ab>
<p>National Surety Company
By J Sullivan
Attorney-in-fact</p>
<p>C.K.Allen
US Atty</p>
<p>State of Washington
County of King } ss</p>
<p>Appointed 
Jeremiah Neterer
Judge</p>
<p>being first duly sworn, each for himself deposes and says:That 
he is one of the parties who executed the foregoing bail bond as
surety; that he is worth the sum of Three Thousant ($3,000.00)
Dollars over and above all his just debts and liabilities in statutory,
separate property siutated in King County, State of Washington,
not by law exempt from sale on execution; that he is not an
attorney or counselor at law, Clerk of the Superior Court, County
Clerk, or other City, County or State official.</p>
<fw>2.</fw>
<pb/>
<p><gap reason="blank"/></p>
<fw>3.</fw>
<pb/>
<p>No. 2875
Original</p>
<p>In the U.S.
<del>Superior</del><add>District</add> Court</p>
<p>In and For the Western
District of Washington,
Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the
Application of Chin Hing,
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Bail Bond</p>
<p>Filed in the
U.S. District Court
Western Dist of Washington
Northern Division
JUN % 1915
Frank L. Crosby
By EML Deputy
2x</p>
<p>Beeler &amp; Sullivan
Lawyers
510-11 White Building
Seattle, Wash.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>