<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0177.003.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">February 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Bajlo, Ivanica</term>
<term>Bajlo, Jack</term>
<term>Bilin, Paska</term>
<term>Bajlo, Tonka</term>
<term>Bolancia, Jerry</term>
<term>Bryan, Fenley</term>
<term>Cushman, Edward E.</term>
<term>DeBruler, Ellis</term>
<term>Ennis, Charles H.</term>
<term>Fisher, Thomas M.</term>
<term>Jurin, Joe</term>
<term>Madison, Fany</term>
<term>Majewski, Detective</term>
<term>Millowan, Frank</term>
<term>Radovich, Nick</term>
<term>Rasho, L. G.</term>
<term>Skorish, Ivan</term>
<term>Wilson, W. B.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Tonka Bajlo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Chas. H. Ennis</persName>
<persName>Fenley Bryan</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON 
NORTHERN DIVISION</p>
    
<p>In the Matter of the Application 
of Tonka Bajlo for the Writ of 
Habeas Corpus )</p>
<p>2459
no. 1328
BRIEF SUBMITTED IN SUBSTITUTION
OF ARGUMENT IN ANSWER TO WRIT</p>

<p>BRIEF SUBMITTED BY RELATOR IN REPLY TO ANSWER OF
COMMISSIONER OF IMMIGRATION, ELLIS DeBRULER, and 
the SECRETARY OF THE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR in re
DEPORTATION OF TONKA BAJLO.</p>

<p>Pursuant to agreement entered into between Mr. Brockway,
Assitant United States District Attorney, and Chas. H.Ennis, 
attorney for Tonka Bajlo, and with the consent of Edward E.Cushman,
Judge of the United States District Court for Western District
of Washington, the following brief is submitted in substitution 
of oral argument:</p>
<p>STATEMENT OF CASE</p>
<p>Tonka Bajlo is a native and subject of Austria about 
30 years of age, the wife of Jack Bajlo, who landed in this
country at the port of New York on the S.S. "OCEANIC" on March
9, 1911, accompanied by her husband. She immediately after their 
arrival in company with her husband went to Pittsburg, Pennsylvania,
where they resided for a period of one year living together as man
and wife, and after she resided a year in Pittsburg living with 
her husband, then she came to the city of Seattle where she has
lived during the past year.</p>
<p>The reason for her leaving her husband was because of 
his continuous, inhuman and bestial cruelties. Upon her arrival 
in Seattle she obtained employment as housekeeper and cook
at 917 Addition Street for a man by the name of Paska Bilin,
at which place were some five or six Austrians who were employed
as laborers by the various contractors in the city of Seattle.
She remained in the employ of Bilin for some 9 or 10 months,
after which she obtained employment with Ivan Skorish and Paska
Bilin, at 815 Charles Street, as cook and housekeeper, at which
place she remained for about two months cooking for four Austrian
<pb/>
<fw></fw>
laborers, when she was arrested on April 7, 1913, by Thomas M.
Fisher, Inspector of Immigration, at the port of Seattle, upon
a telegraphic warrant issued by Hon. W.B.Wilson, Secretary of 
Labor, upon the charge of being found an alien practising prostitution
after entry in this country, and on said day a hearing
was had by Thomas M.Fisher, Inspector of Immigration at the 
Detention Station of the port of Seattle.</p>
<p>At such hearing Tonka Bajlo was the first witness to be
called, without the presence of an attorney. At the conclusion 
of her testimony on direct examination Inspector Fisher informed
her in the following language of her right to have an attorney:</p>
<p>Q. "You have a right to be represented by counsel if you
desire." A. "I have no money to hire an attorney."</p>
<p>Q. "Do you waive your right to be represented by counsel
at this or any future hearing of the case?" A. "Yes."</p>
<p>At this hearing teh testimony of Jack Bajlo, her 
husband, Ivan Skoric(or Skorich,) and Paska Bilin were taken,and the 
testimony of these witnesses is herewith submitted as part of 
the Government's case, and referred to by this relator as part
of this reply brief to the answer of the Commissioner of Immigration,
Ellis DeBruler, to the petition for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.
Upon the testimony, <add>statements and affidavits</add> herewith submitted. Inspector Thomas M.Fisher
made the finding that he had talked to her and that she told him
she had been living with John or Joe Jurin as his wife since
coming to Seattle, and that she had been intimate with a number 
of men in the house where she was living; that she was living in
a house of the Austrian quarter, she being the only woman there
and that there were from 4 to 5 to a dozen Austrians living there 
from time to time; that from the condition of her room he had no
question in his own mind but that she was practicing prostitution,
and that in view of these facts he finds that Tonka Bajlo is a 
citizen of Austria, and that she entered this country March 9, 
1911, at the port of New York, and that she had been found
practicing prostitution since her entry into the United States, 
and recommended that she be deported to the country from whence
<pb/>
<fw>-2-</fw>
she came.</p>
<p>On April 9, 1913, in a letter to the Commissioner 
General of Immigration, Ellis DeBruler, Commissioner of Immigration
at the port of Seattle, upon the findings made by inspector Thomas
M.Fisher, recommended the deportation of Tonka Bajlo in the following
language to-wit:</p>
<p>"From the evidence adduced it appears that this woman
was of the excluded classes at the time of entry, i.e. a 
person who admits having committed an offense involving
moral turpitude, and a person likely to become a public 
charge, and she has been found practicing prostitution.
I therefore recommend that she be found to be in the 
United States in violation of law, and ordered deported
to the country from whence she came at the expense of 
the importing vessel, etc."</p>
<p>On April 7, 1913, a warrant was issued by the Secretary 
of Labor ordering the arrest of Tonka Bajlo, from which the following
excerpts are quoted:</p>
<p>"Whereas, from evidence submitted to me it appears 
that the alien Tonka Bajlo who landed at the port of
New York ex SS. "OCEANIC" on or about the 15th day of 
March, 1911, has been found in the United States in 
violation of the Act of Congress approved February
20, 1907, amended by the Act approved March 25, 1910,
for the following among other reasons: That the said 
alien is a prostitute and has been found practicing
prostitution subsequent to her entry into the United 
States.</p>
<p>I, W.B.Wilson, Secretary of Labor, by virtue of
the power and authority vested in me by the laws of teh
United States, do hereby command you to take into custody
the said alien, and grant her a hearign to enable her to
show cause why she should not be deported in conformity
with the law. For so doing this shall
be your sufficient warrant. W.B.Wilson, Secretary of 
Labor."</p>
<p>On April 15, 1913, the Secretary of Labor ordered the 
deportation of Tonka Bajlo to Austria, the country from whence
she came, upon the finding made by Ellis DeBruler, Commissioner
of Immigration at the port of Seattle, and Inspector Thomas M.
Fisher, upon the testimony adduced at the hearing held by Thomas
M.Fisher on April 7, 1913.</p>
<p>On April 16, 1913, an order to show cause why a Writ
of Habeas Corpus should not be issued was signed by Hon. Edward
E.Cushman, Judge of the United States District Court for the 
Western District of Washington,in response to the petition of
relator, said order being returnable on April 21, 1914, and in
<pb/>
<fw>-3-</fw>
answer to said order, the commissioner of Immigration, Ellis 
DeBruler, through the United States District Attorney's Office
filed the records in case in this court, and denied the
jurisdiction of this <add>honorable</add> court to intervene, claiming that the action
of the immigration officers upon its approval by the Secretary 
of Labor is final and not reviewable in a court of law.</p>
<p>The grounds upon which the relator seeks the issuance
of the Writ of Habeas Corpus are:-</p>
<p>1. That she did not have a fair and legal hearing as prescribed
by law, and that no sufficient opportunity was allowed
to present counter-evidence to show cause whay she should not be
deported upon the warrant charging her with the offense of "being
an alien practicing prostitution in this country after entry," in 
this, that she did not understand the proceedings which were
conducted against her at the time of the hearing and that she
was without the assistance of counsel, and when informed what the 
result of the hearing was, she demanded a rehearing and services
of counsel, and the rehearing was denied.</p>
<p>2. That there was absolutely no evidence to support the 
charge made against her in the warrant of arrest issued by the 
Secretary of Labor.</p>
<p>3. That the statements alleged to have been made by her 
in the testimony as translated into English, are in some instances
absolutely false and have been misinterpreted by the interpreter.</p>
<p>4. That the interpreter, who was hired especially for this
hearing, refused and decline to translate the statements made by 
her in which she charged her husband as being irresponsible mentally 
and acting through malice.</p>
<p>5. That the affidavit made by Jack Bajlo, her husband,
which is part of the Government's answer to the relator's petition 
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, was made by said Baljo with the purpose
in view of wreaking vengeance upon his wife, because she
declined to live with him by reason of his extreme cruelty and 
inhuman treatment, and said Baljo has since the hearing admitted
such to be the fact, as evidenced by affidavits marked Exhibits
B and C.</p>
<pb/>
<fw>-4-</fw>
<p>In connection with statement 5 we especially draw the 
attention of the court to the affidavits of Nick Radovich, <add>and</add> L. G.
Rasho and marked Exhibits B. and C.</p>
<p>Previous to applying for an order to show cause why
a Writ of Habeas Corpus should not be issued discharging Tonka
Bajlo from the custody of the immigration officials, said Tonka
Bajlo applied to Ellis DeBruler, Commissioner of Immigration 
at the port of Seattle, for a rehearsing which was denied by Ellis
DeBruler as Commissioner on the ground that she had been ordered
deported by the Secretary of Labor upon the testimony submitted 
at the only hearing had and which is hereto referred to and
made a part of the Government's answer to the return of this 
application for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, and in this connection 
we submit the affidavits of Ivan Scorich, Fany Madison, Frank
Millowan and Jerry Bolancia, which affidavits were submitted to
the Hon. Commissioner of Immigration at the port of Seattle in 
support of the application for a rehearing in this cause before
the immigration officials. Said affidavits are marked Exhibits
D., E., F., and G.</p>
<p>We desire especially to call the attention of the court 
to the affidavit of Tonka Bajlo and marked Exhibit A, which recites
a tale of cruelties equal to any of those practiced in the Dark 
Ages, and her statements as to cruelties and as to her virtuous
conduct are borne out by the affidavits of Nick Radovich, L.G.
Rasho, Fany Madison, Jerry Bolancia and Frank Millwan.</p>
<pb/>
<fw>-4-</fw>
<p>ARGUMENT</p>
<p>It will be admitted:</p>
<p>1st. That the United States Government acting through
Congress, has the power to exclude all aliens.</p>
<p>2nd. That it has, in the same way, power to deport any 
alien found in this country.</p>
<p>3rd. That it has the power also to provide by law for the 
admission or deportation of any class or classes of aliens and
prescribe the terms and conditions upon which they may be admitted,
may remain, or be excluded or deported.</p>
<p>These rules are well established. On the other hand it
is equally true and well established:-</p>
<p>1st. That such powers are vested exclusively in Congress.</p>
<p>That Congress can act in the matter only through laws
duly enacted.</p>
<p>3rd. That in the absence of such laws all aliens can enter
and remain here.</p>
<p>4th. No officer or tribunal can exclude or deport them
except by virtue of such laws and in the manner prescribed by 
law.</p>
<p>It follows that an alien cannot be ordered deported
by the immigration officers unless it appears that they are 
acting:-</p>
<p>a. Within the terms of the law.</p>
<p>b. In the manner prescribed by law.</p>
<p>If they undertake to do so a question of law is raised
and the courts have jurisdiction to hear and determine the matter.
The courts cannot review the findings and orders of the immigration
officials when they act within the terms of the law and in the
manner prescribed thereby, just because the court may have a 
different opinion as to the weight of the evidence.</p>
<p>But whether or not there is any law authorizing deportation
in a specific case is for the courts to determine.</p>
<p>Whether or not the officials followed the law in the
proceedings is for the court to determine. Whether or not the 
alien had such a fair hearing as the law accords her is for
<pb/>
<fw>-5-</fw>
the courts to determine. Whether or not there was any evidence
to support the findings is for the court to determine.</p>
<p>The foregoing propositions are fully supported by
the following authorities:-</p>
<p>Chin Yow vs. United States. 208 p.8.</p>
<p>Davis vs. Manolis. 179 Federal 818.</p>
<p>United States ex rel. Bosny et al. vs. Williams. 185
Federal, 598.</p>
<p>Ex parte Koerner. 176 Federal, 478.</p>
<p>United States ex rel Nicola vs. Williams, 173 Federal,
626.</p>
<p>Zakonaite vs. Wolf. 33 Supreme Court Reporter, Vol. 33, 
p. 31.</p>
<p>We submit that it is quite clear from this record that
the petitioner did not have such a fair, legal hearing as the
law contemplates in the following respects:-</p>
<p>1st. The warrant under which she was taken into custody
charges her with one offense to-wit: that of practicing prostitution
after entering the united States, while the evidence
taken and the findings and order of deportation cover two other
charges not included in the warrant.</p>
<p>2nd. That there was absolutely no evidence establishing 
or tending to establish the charge made in the warrant.</p>
<p>3rd. That the finding of the Inspector on the charge made
in this warrant,(pp. 22 and 23), show, on its face that it was
not based on evidence taken at the hearing, but upon alleged
admissions which he claims to have obtained from her at the 
time of her arrest.</p>
<p>4th. That she is a woman with little education, not able to 
speak the language, and was not able under the circumstances to
make a proper showing.</p>
<p>5th. That the record of the evidence as returned is incorrect,
<add>and</add>misleading, in that she and otehr witnesses are reported
to have made statements which in fact they did not make.</p>
<pb/>
<fw>-6-</fw>
<p>6th. That even if the local officers had the right to take
evidence and make findings upon charges not embodied in the
warant, that evidence does not show that she was guilty before
entering the country of an offense which brings her within the
prohibited class, nor does it show that she is likely to become
a public charge.</p>
<p>We do not here refer to the weight to be given the
evidence <add>but claim that</add> even if true as a matter of law it does not show that
she is within the prohibited class.</p>
<p>This is a patition for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, not
a hearing under the writ, and consequently it does not devolve 
upon us at this time to show to the court that the alien has a 
right to remain in this country, but only to show that she has
not had such a hearing to determine that questino as under the
law she is entitled to. If she has not had such a hearing then
the Writ of Habeas Corpus must issue, and the court,upon the
return of the writ, will examine into the question of her right
to remain,and render judgement accordingly.</p>
<p>In order words an alien when arrested under a charge
for deportation has the right, primarily, to a full and fair 
hearing by the tribunal prescribed by the statute, and in the 
manner therein provided. If it appears on hearing of the petition
for the writ that nto such hearing has been accorded him,
then the writ will be issued, and the court upon the return of the
writ will give him such hearing, and enter its decree.</p>
<p>In a recent case decided by the united States Supreme 
Court, 208 U.S. p. 8, this docrine was announced:</p>
<p>The law fixing the procedure under which the immigration
officials must act under which the attempted to deport they 
petitioner is found in sections 20 and 21 of the Act of February
20th, 1907.</p>
<p>Federal Statutes Annotated, p. 103, Section 20, provides
that "upon the warrant of the Secretary of Commerce and Labor
the alien shall be taken into custody and deported, and further 
that such alien after being so taken into custody may give bonds
<pb/>
<fw>-7-</fw>
and be released upon condition that he will appear "for teh
hearing or hearings in regard to the charge upon which he
has been taken into custody."</p>
<p>This section clearly contemplates that the hearing shall
be had only upon the charge made in this warrant.</p>
<p>To take one into custody under a warrant charging a 
particular offense, then hold a tral set for hearing under that
warrant, and at such trial take evidence, make findings and enter
judgement on an entirely different charge is a procedure so repugnant
to the American idea of justice and fair dealing, that
we apprehend a court will not tolerate it, unless the statute so
clearly permits it that no other construction of the statute is 
possible. Conceding for the purpose of the argument, that Congress
might grant to immigration officials such a power over 
aliens, a statute should not be so construed if any other interpretation
can be given it. </p>
<p>We submit that this statute shows on its face that the
hearing must be confined to the charge made in the warrant.</p>
<p>It has been so construed by the courts:-</p>
<p>Davies vs. Manolis, 179 Federal 818 Supra.</p>
<p>U.S. vs. Sibray. 178 Fed. 145 Supra.</p>
<p>The local authorities have no power to arrest except 
upon such a warrant; they have no power to hold a trial except
by virtue of such a warrant; they have no power to act at all
except within the orders containted in the warrant.</p>
<p>The warrant in this case charged "that said alien is 
a prostitute and has been found practicing prostitution subsequent
to her entry into the United States," and directs, "that
you take into custody said alien and grant her a hearing to 
enable her to show cause why <add>she</add> should not be deported in conformity
to law."</p>
<p>(P. 38 of Return to Order to Show Cause.)</p>
<p>The hearing was had, testimony taken, and the following
findings made by the Immigrant Inspector:</p>
<pb/>
<fw>-8-</fw>
<p>FINDINGS.pp. 22 and 23.</p>
<p>A At the time of the arrest of this woman I talked to
her in the presence of Detective Majewski, who acted as
interpreter; she at the time told me that she had been 
living with Joe or John Jurin as his wife since coming to
Seattle, and that she had been intimate with a number of
men in the hose where she was living. She was living in 
a house in the Austrian quarter, she being he only woman 
in the house, and there being anywhere from four to five
to a dozen men living there from time to time. From the
condition of her room there is no question in my mind but
what she was practicing prostitution, and in view of these
facts I find that Tonka Bajlo is an alien, a citizen of 
Austria; that she entered the United States at the port of
New York, on the S.S. "Oceanic", March 9, 1911; that she has
been found practicing prostitution since her entry to the 
United States, and I, therefore, respectfully recommend that 
she be deported to the country from whence she came or of
which she is a citizen or subject in conformity with law.</p>
<p>Ellis DeBruler, local commissioner, wrote to the
Commissioner General of Immigration, (see letter p. 12 of return,)</p>
<p>"From the evidence adduced it appears that this woman
was of the excluded class at the time of entry, i. e. a person
who admits having committed an offense involving mortal turpitude,
and a person likely to become a public charge, and she has been
found practicing prostitution."</p>
<p>The finding and order of deportation (p. 5 <add>of return)</add> recites:-</p>
<p>"Hearing having been granted following named alien, 
Tonka Bajlo, alian Ivanica Bajlo, alien found practicing 
prostitution after entry, person likely to become public
charge at time of entry, etc."</p>
<p>These findings, if the letter of DeBruler and the
contents of the order can be called such, recite three distinct
grounds for deportation:</p>
<p>1st. That she is likely to become a public charge.</p>
<p>2nd. That she is a person who admits having committed
an offense involving moral turpitude before entering the 
country.</p>
<p>3rd. That she has practiced prostitution since entering
the United States.</p>
<p>We have already pointed out that only the third ground
was covered by the warrant, and have pointed out that under the
statute and the authorities, all the proceedings except those
based on the third ground were unwarranted. It follows that
so far as the first and second findings are concerned the woman
is clearly held without warrant of law and would have to be discharged.</p>
<pb/>
<fw>-9-</fw>
<p>On the first two grounds therefore, there was not only 
no fair hearing such as is contemplated by law, but there was no
legal hearing at all. The County Wreckmaster has just as much
authority to make findings and order her deported on these grounds
as did the persons making the order without a warrant. For the
tire being therefore, we will drop the first two grounds of deportation
and confine ourselves to a discussion of the third, the
only one contained in the warrant, to-wit; that the alien is a 
prostitute and has been found practicing prostitution since entering
the United States.</p>
<p>The statute, Section 3 of the Act of February 20, 1907, 
as amended by the act of March 26, 1910, does not contain the 
words:"Any one who is a prostitute", but reads:"Any alien who shall
be found * * * practicing prostitution after such alien shall
have entered the United States, etc.", so we do not need to concern
ourselves with the first expression, except as it may be included
in the second. The word prostitution means common, indiscriminate,
ilicit, and not sexual intercourse exclusively with one man.</p>
<p>Words and Phrases 5741 and cases cited.</p>
<p>"A prostitute is a female given to promiscuous sexual 
intercourse with men for gain."</p>
<p>Words and Phrases 5740 and cases cited. Anderson's 
Dictionary of Law. p. 839.</p>
<p>It has been held that both the warrant and the 
findings in order to support an order of deportation must
charge and find the commission of a specific act or acts,
showing that the party comes within the statute.</p>
<p>But we need not be so technical in this case. There is
absolutely no evidence to show,or even tending to show, that this
woman ever practiced prostitution in the United States. If there 
was no such evidence this court has jurisdiction to issue the writ
and order her discharged.</p>
<p>Questions of fact are for the jury
alone, <del>in jury alone</del> in jury cases, but that question as
to whether there is any evidence to support a verdict is one of
law for the court to pass upon <add>and</add> is elementary and analogous to
<pb/>
<fw>-10-</fw>
to the proposition here made.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court of the United States in Zakowaite
vs. Wolf, Vol 33, Supreme Court Reporter, page 31 Supra, uses
this language:-</p>
<p>"As to the first point, an examination of the evidence
upon which the order of deportation was based convinces us
that it was adequate to support the Secretary's conclusions
of fact. That being so and the appellant having had a fair
hearing, the findings are not subject to review by the courts."</p>
<p>This case was decided by the Supreme Court of the united
States in December 1912.</p>
<p>It was contended "that there was no evidence before the
Secretary of Commerce &amp; Labor sufficient to warrant the findings
of fact upon which the order of deportation was based." The 
Supreme Court took jurisdiction of that question, examined the
evidence and passed on its sufficiency.</p>
<p>We now invite your Honor's attention to the evidence
in this case: <add>Ask you to examine it as did the Supreme Court,</add> and ask you to determine whether there was any
evidence to support the findings and the charge made.</p>
<p>The woman charged with the offense was herself called
as the first witness at the hearing. She positively and unqualifiedly 
denied that she had been practicing prostitution. Her 
denial shows also that she had not cohabited with any man, save 
her husband, since coming to the united States.</p>
<p>It is quite true that her testimony does show that she
lived with a number of men in Seattle, but it conclusively appears
from other language in her testimony that what she mean by living
with them was that she lived in a house rented orcontrolled
by them, and that she kept house and cooked for them and received 
therefore, her board, lodging and wages. That these statements
are absolutely true is shown beyond doubt by the testimony of the 
other witnesses examined at the hearing, and by affidavits of 
neighbors and acquaintances, copies of which are attached to this
brief.</p>
<p>The next witness called was Jack Bajlo, who is the 
husband of this witness. He beat and otherwise abused her to
such an extent that she could not live with him. After she 
was forced to leave him on account of these abuses, he followed
<pb/>
<fw>-11-</fw>
her from Pittsburg to Seattle, and where she again refused through
fear, notwithstanding his threats, to live with him. He was
suspicious of her and jealous. All of this conclusively appears
from his own testimony taken at the hearing and from that of his
wife and otehr witnesses; also from the affidavits of NICK
RADOVICH and L. G. RASHO.
attached hereto. It was on the complaint and affidavit of this
jealous, immoral and bestial husband, prompted by a spirit of 
revenge against her because she would not live with him and submit
to his foul practices, that the warrant in this case was
issued.</p>
<p>In paragraph "I" of Rule 35 promulgated by the Secretary
of Commerce and Labor, whcih can be found on P. 147 of Volume 178
of Federal Reports, we find the following language:</p>
<p>"Officers are especially cautioned not to lend their aid
in causing the arrest of aliens upon charges arising out
of personal spite or enmity, unless the truth of such
charges are clearly established."</p>
<p>Notwithstanding the vengeful spirit of this witness, 
and notwithstanding the fact that the examiner at the hearing
evidently did all he could through leading and suggestive questions
by a system of cross examination, he did not give <add>one</add> word of testimony
which could possibly be said to support the charge made in the 
warrant, unless it be found in the following testimony.</p>
<p>Q. How long did your wife live with you in Pittsburg? A. 
One Year. Q. During that year what did she do? A. Kept 
boarders.</p>
<p>Q. Did she practice prostitution during that time. A. 
Some of the boarders told me that she did once, and I beat 
her for that.</p>
<p>And further relating to the time when she was in
Seattle:</p>
<p>Q. Who was she living with when you came here first? A.
Four men in the house.</p>
<p>Q. Did you know who they were? A. Only the one that
<pb/>
<fw>-12-</fw>
she lives with.</p>
<p>Q. Did you go to that house and see them. A. I went to 
the house and saw them, but spoke only to my wife.</p>
<p>Q. What did you say to her? A. I told her to come
with me and that I would forgive her, and I told her that
if I beat her any more she could have me arrested.</p>
<p>Q. Then what did she say. A. She said she would not
trust me any more; she would not go with me.</p>
<p>Q. Did she say to you that you were no longer master of
her body and that she would practice prostitution if she
wished? A. She told me that day before yesterday. Mr
Gorin was with me at that time.</p>
<p>Q. Did you know whether or not she was practicing prostitution 
in this city? A. When I first came here two men 
told me that she did so, but I do not know whether she did 
or not. I would not know these men by sight.</p>
<p>As to this testimony it is apparent that the statements
made as to her practicing prostitution were the rankest kind of 
hearsay; that they were statements or conclusions made by third
parties and not statements of any fact, and repeated at the 
hearing by this beast seeking revenge. Whether he or the
persons whom he stated told him of these things know or knew
what prostitution is, does not appear. The first statement:
"Some of the boarders told me that she did once," even if it
had been true and shown by competent witnesses in a proper way,
would not establish any charge for which she could be deported,
because a single act of sexual intercourse is not practicing
prostitution and is not a ground for deportation. In this
respect the second statement is but little better because he
says: "When I first came here two men that she did
so," is so very indefinite and uncertain, that aside from it
being hearsay and a conclusion of <add>third</add> parties not present, that it
can hardly be considered more than an intimation that she might 
have committed the act of sexual intercourse once, but when
the witness says: "I would not know these men by sight," and
"I do not know whether she did or not," the whole fabric must
<pb/>
<fw>-13-</fw>
fall to the ground as absolutely unworthy of consideration, or
even of belief. Hearsay evidence is not evidence at all in
the sense that it may be said to sustain any proposition, and
in this respect a statement of mere conclusions recited by a 
third party is much worse. Of course, it is not necessary 
to argue the proposition that the affidavit upon which the warrant
was issued is not evidence such as could be considered supporting
the order of deportation. If it were, no hearing would be necessary.</p>
<p>For the same reason the recital in the findings made 
by Mr. Fisher, Inspector, that: "She at the time, (meaning when
she was arrested) told me that she had been living with Joe or
John Jurin as his wife since coming to Seattle, and that she
had been intimate with a number of men in the house where she was
living," cannot be considered as any testimony whatever to support
the findings or the order of deportation. The further fact that
such a recital is made in the findings and such statements as that
of Jack Bajlo were allowed to be put in the evidence, particularly 
in view of the fact that the woman was not represented by counsel, 
and no cross examination was made except that of the prosecution
cross examining its own witnesses apparently for the purpose of
forcing out of them damaging statements, all show that the hearing
and findings were unfair and not held according to law or the rules 
of the department.</p>
<p>It is true that this is not a criminal proceeding, but
the offense charged is one in its nature criminal and the evidence
of guilt certainly should be specific, competent, and of facts
not mere conclusions.</p>
<p>In U.S. vs. Sibray, Vol. 178, p. 150, three hearings
were held, one in the presence of the alien, and two not in her
presence, and the court held that hearing in deportation
<pb/>
<fw>-14-</fw>
proceedings of which the alien had no notice and was given no
opportunity to be present, at which witnesses were sworn and 
examined, were improper. How much more improper therefore, is 
it to take a statement found only in the findings and not brought
out by examination of a sworn witness at any hearing at all.</p>
<p>On page 599, Volume 185, Federal Reporter U.S. vs. 
Williams, the court uses this language:-</p>
<p>"Aliens if arrested, are at least entitled to the rights
which such a system accords them, and if they are deprived of
any such right the proceedings is clearly irregular, and any
order of deportation issued in it, invalid."</p>
<p>Ignorance and inability to speak the language will not
of course in themselves be sufficient to entitle an alien to appeal
to the courts where the proceedings appear otherwise to have been
irregular and unfair, but when it comes to the question of considering
whether or not a hearing was fair, these elements must be
taken into consideration, for what would be a fair hearing for a 
lawyer, for example, posted on the subject of the hearing, would
not in any sense be a fair hearing for one who was ignorant of the 
laws and customs of the country, and particularly when the language
in which the proceedings are held is not understood by the 
accused. Whether the woman fully understood the charge against
her, and knowing that she was not guilty stated that she did
not want counsel, and also had no money to pay for one, does not
appear affirmatively on the record, but if she had understood the
proceedings she certainly would have had a right to expect help
of counsel when called upon to defend herself against the charge
made in the warrant. She was not apprised of any other charge
or charges, and even if the officers had had the right to go
beyond the authority given them by the warrant of arrest, it
<pb/>
<fw>-15-</fw>
is apparent that she had absolutely no opportunity to procure
proper counsel, or obtain witnesses, or make any kind of a
defense to such charge.</p>
<p>It does not appear that the testimony of any of the
witnesses was read over to them, or signed by them after being
translated by the interpreter and transcribed by the reporter.
We know of no <del>relief</del> <add>rule</add> or law requiring this; neither do we know
of any rule or any law making such testimony as reported, conclusive
as to its correctness. An incorrect record of testimony 
upon which findings and an order of deportation are based certainly
would be unfair, unjust and misleading. The testimony as 
reported in this case is erroneous in several very material 
respects. Furthermore, a portion of the statements made by the
accused at the time of the hearing under oath were not translated
at all and not made a part of the record.</p>
<p>See affidavit of Tonka Bajlo, marked Exhibit A., and 
attached hereto.</p>
<p>The finding and order of deportation on the first 
two charges to-wit: That she is a person likely to become
a public charge, and a person who admits having committed an
offense involving moral turpitude before entering the country,
was not justified or supported by any evidence. We have
already shown that she had no legal hearing whatever on either 
of these charges because they were not included in the warrant,
and that if there could have been a hearing on them without the 
warrant making the charges that such hearing was unfait and not
such as contemplated by law, because she was not apprised either
before at the time of the hearing that she was to be tried on
any such charges, and that she therefore had no opportunity to 
make any defense thereto.</p>
<pb/>
<fw>-16-</fw>
<p>We now propose to show that if she had had such hearing 
as the law contemplates, that there was no evidence to support 
either charge.</p>
<p>On the proposition that she was likely to become a 
public charge we can find no evidence whatever. The testimony 
all goes to show that she was perfectly capable of supporting and
taking care of herself, and that as a matter of fact she did do 
so. Her husband testified that after being admitted at the port
of New York they went to Pittsburg and lived for one year; that 
during that time he was a cast iron chipper; that his wife during 
that year kept boarders. Her own testimony and that of all the 
other witnesses show that as soon as she came to Seattle she obtained
employment as housekeeper and cook for a number of people of 
her own nationality, and she was still engaged in that occupation
when arrested. There is no where a single word of testimony 
that she was incapable of earning her own living in a perfectly 
legitimate and proper way, and the evidence shows that she 
actually did so.</p>
<p>We need not argue to this court that for a woman in her
class of life to keep house in the manner she is shown to have
done is a legitimate and proper occupation and a very common
thing, and does not in any way reflect upon her character.</p>
<p>On the other hand it is commendable, for we have
invited, in the interests of the growth of our industries and 
development of our country, the immigration of just such people 
as these workmen are, and it is necessary that they should have
some one to cook for them and look after their household affairs.</p>
<p>There is a doctor's certificate attached to the testimony, 
(p. 25), showing that she has inflammation of the pelvic organs, 
and that in the majority of cases the disease is the result of
gonorrhea. The certificate also states that she is in no
<pb/>
<fw>-17-</fw>
danger and does not require special care and attention, and that
it may have existed for a year or more. As a matter of fact 
this condition had existed for that length of time, yet as the
evidence shows it did not prevent her from keeping boarders in
Pittsburg, or from keeping house and cooking and earning her own
living in Seattle. Furthermore, it is a fact which appears from
her affidavit attached hereto, that the condition resulted from  
a disease communicated to her by this beautiful husband of hers,
who is now trying to have her deported.</p>
<p>The second charge that of committing an offense involving 
moral turpitude is evidently <del>based</del> an attempt to show that
she was a person within the meaning of the statute which specifies 
whatpersons are within the excluded class. This portion of the statute
applicable reads:</p>
<p>"Persons who have been convicted of, or admit having
committed a felony or other crime or other misdemeanor involving
moral turpitude."</p>
<p>We concede that the evidence shows that she gave birth
to a child after her marriage and at a time when her husband had 
been in America for a period of nearly three years. We have 
already shown that the record which seems to indicate that she 
gave birth to a child before her marriage is incorrect; that she
did not so testify, and that her husband's testimony as given 
corroborates this statement, for he did not so testify. the 
bare statement of the fact that she gave birth to such a child 
is the only evidence on the subject. It does not appear whether 
or not during her husband's absence she had been legally separated
from him and married to another man, or whether or not the birth 
of the child was the result of rape or some unlawful act committed
without her consent. It appears as a necessary conclusion 
that she had sexual intercourse, but whether with more than one
person, or on more than one occasion does not appear, nor can
<pb/>
<fw>-18-</fw>
any evidence upon that subject be drawn from the testimony. 
Clearly this child may have been legitimate, or may have been
conceived without any moral or legal offense having been 
committed upon her part. Furthermore, it is not made to
appear that any act constituting an offense against the laws
of Austria, or against the laws of the United States as a nation,
such as would be covered by the language of the statute, was 
committed. It must be shown that the act committed was a 
crime or a misdemeanor under the laws of Austria for which she
might have been punished, and that the act involved moral 
turpitude.</p>
<p>In U.S. vs. Sibray, 178 Federal, p. 149, we find this
language:</p>
<p>"The relator is married and lived with his wife in
Vienna until he left for the United States. He did admit
to commission of one act of sexual intercourse with an
unmarried woman shortly before leaving Vienna. That is 
all the record discloses as to his conduct prior to his
landing at New York. That act is to be depricated. Yet
it was not a felony or crime under the law. It is doubtful
if adultery was an offense at common law in this country.
It was not in Vermont, Virginia and South Carolina. (See
Wharton's American Criminal Law, Sec. 2648.) It is doubtful
if the act of relator was adultery in Austria under the 
Roman law to constitute the offense, the woman must be
married. The same is the law in many places. It is 
doubtful also if fornication was a misdemeanor at common 
law. The better opinion is in the absense of statute, 
unless the offense partakes of the nature of public, and 
offensive lewdness, it is not inditable. (See Wharton's 
American Criminal Law, 2667; also Clark's Criminal Law, 
Hornbook Series, 312, and authorities cited in footnotes.)</p>
<p>From the opinion of Judge Gibson of Pennsylvania in
Maurer vs. Mitchell 9 Watts &amp; S. 69, it will be seen that
the offense of fornication and bastardy was "little more than
a private wrong." See also Rohrheimer vs. Winters, 126
Ps. 253 17 At. 606. The Judge in that case added:-</p>
<p>That such deportation should be the punishment of such a
man for such an offense is almost incredible."</p>
<p>In this connection we might also add that the husband
knew of the birth of this child prior to the time of bringing
his wife to America. From this it musst be either that 
this child was conceived without fault upon the woman's part, 
or that the husband fully forgave her and condoned the offense.</p>
<pb/>
<fw>-19-</fw>
<p>Under such circumstances we believe we are safe in
stating that no man or woman has ever been punished in any
state in the union. It is universally considered a private 
wrong.</p>
<p>It appears from the evidence and from affidavits 
attached hereto, that the child was born some two years or more
after the husband left Austria; that he returned to Austria 
after being in this country about three years; that he knew
all about the birth of said child; that he remained in Austria
about three years and then brought her to this country as his
wife. This beyond question would evidently be a full forgiveness
of the offense, if it appeared, (as it does not), that 
she had committed one.</p>
<p>Respectfully Submitted,</p>
<ab>Chas H Ennis</ab>
<ab>Fenley Bryan
Attorneys for Tonka Bajlo.</ab>
<pb/>
<fw>-20-</fw>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>