<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0180.016.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Affadvit.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0180.016</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Affadvit.</title>
<date when="1913-11-03">November 3, 1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2628AlbertYoung&amp;KamasaburoSugiura</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-11">November 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Sugiura, B. K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Hunter, B. A.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Harris, Walter P.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>White, A. T.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Washio, Shotaro</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Saito, Hana</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fukuye</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Hanaki</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Okajima</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Thayer</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Keên</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Nakada</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Okayashi</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Umeda, K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Ito, K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>A</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>


<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
</keywords>


<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Sacremento, California</term>
</keywords>


</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Young, Albert H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sugiuro, Kamasaburo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Myers, H. A. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>McClellan, R.W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Johnstone, Walter L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, G. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>Exhibit "D" Department of Labor
Immigration Service</p>
<p>Seattle, Washington
November 3, 1913</p>
<p>In the matter of the arrest
of ALbert H. Young and B.K.
Sugiura</p>
<p>B. A. Hunter, Inspector 
Examiner
Walter P. Harris
Stenographer
A. T. White
Inspector</p>
<p>Attorney McClelland Also Present</p>
<p>Shotaro Washio, witness, being duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>
<p>Q By Inspector Hunter: What is your name? A Witness: Shotaro
Washio.</p>
<p>Q Are you the same Shotaro Washio that testified in the trial of
Albert H. Young and B.K. Sugiura for transporting a girl named Hana
Saito from Seattle to San Francisco? A Yes</p>
<p>What was that woman's occupation? A At that time or after she
got there.</p>
<p>Q Before she left San Francisco to comee here and after she returned 
to San Francisco? A Prior to her departure from San Francisco she
was sick and didn't do anything and after her return to Frisco she was
a prostitute.</p>
<p>Q Did she prostitute herself any after leaving San Francisco?
A Yes, she was a prostitute before I had anything to do with her.</p>
<p>Q Did she practice prostitution when you were living with her?
A No, she was sick and couldn't do any business.</p>
<p>Q Did she ever give you any money? A No</p>
<p>Q Did Mr, Young and Sugiura know what her character was when they
helped you to take her to San Francisco? A Yes</p>
<p>Q How did they know it? A I told them</p>
<p>Q Did you tell both of them or only one? A I told Sugiura and
whether he told Young or not I don't know.</p>
<p>Q Did you tell Young yourself about her character? A No, I asked
Mr. Sugiura to help me and he got Young, I never asked Young to help
me to take the girl down myself, Sugiura made those arrangements.</p>
<p>Q Did you testify at the trial that you told Young and Sugiura that 
she was a prostitute? A I don't remember having said it -- ues if
I testified at the trial I must have said that I only told Sugiura, I 
don't remember ever having told Young that the girl was a prostitute.</p>
<p>Q Did you testify that they wanted totake her to Sacremento instead
of San Francisco that they could get more money in Sacramento than 
Frisco.? Young &amp;
A Yes,/Sugiura told me that so I testified to that.</p>
<p>Q By Attorney McClelland: When you came to Seattle to hunt Hana
or to get Hana, what hotel did you stop at? A At the Great 
Northern Hotel.</p>
<p>Q Who kept that Hotel? A Mr. Fukuye.</p>
<p>Q Did you know Fukuye before you came and stopped at his hotel
A I knew five years ago when he was connected with the Oriental
Trading Company</p>
<p>Q Did you know the clerk in that hotel, Hanaki? A I didn't kknow
him before this time, I met him there for the first time.</p>
<p>Q How did you happen to meet Sugiura? A Mr. Fukuye had asid there
was an interpreter here from the Province of Aichi Ken and as that
was the Province I was from I said it was the same province and Mr. 
<fw>17</fw>
<pb/>
Fukuye introduced me to Sugiura.</p>
<p>Q Did you know Sugiura before Mr. Fukuye introduced you to him?
A No.</p>
<p>Q Did you know any of his people back in Japan? A My father
had said that he knew Sugiura's father, I didn't know him.</p>
<p>Q How did you meet Young. A I requested Sugiura to help me in
this girl's transportation to San Francisco and I was in his office
and met Young and he had known Young and introduced me.</p>
<p>Q Do you know whether you had ever met Young prior to that time?
A No.</p>
<p>ow you hired another Interpreter by the name of Okajima before
you got Sugiura or Young, didn't you? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q You got him for the same purpose that you got Young and Sugiura
didn't you? hat is to help you about getting Hana?
A I only employed him to go with me to the detective agency as an
interpreter.</p>
<p>Q What detective agency did you go to see? A I don't know the 
name.</p>
<p>I was the Burna Detective Agency? A Yes</p>
<p>And who did you see there, do you remember the name of the man?
Mr. Thayer was it? A I don't know</p>
<p>Q Well it was the same man that testified in the trial wasn't it,
Mr. Thayer? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Now what did you teel Fujuye that you were up herefor? And what 
did you teel him you wanted an interpreter for?
A Only that I was here looking for this woman, he didn't talk very
much about the thing and introduced me to an interpreter.</p>
<p>Q You told Mr. Fujuye and the girl Hana that Hana was your wife and 
that you were up here hunting for her and that she had run away 
from you with Saito didn't you? A No, I don't remember having 
said that she was my wife.</p>
<p>Q You just told him then that you were up here hunting for the
woman Hana? A Yes</p>
<p>You didn't tell him anything about what relation she was to you?
A No.</p>
<p>Q And when Fukuye took you to Sugiura and introduced you what did 
you tell Sugiura, didn't you then tell Sugiura that your wife had
run away from you with Saito before, that you were up here hunting
her and that you wanted him to help you get her?
A I didn't say that she was my wife, she was not my wife, I don't 
remember having told Sugiura she was my wife.</p>
<p>Q What did you tell Sugiura? A Just mentioned the girl's name
Hana.</p>
<p>Q Was that all you told Sugiura? A It was over a year ago I 
can't remember exactly.</p>
<p>Q Why did you testify a few minuted aho that you told Sugiura that
she was a prostitute? A Yes, that was prior to the time I had
anything to do with the woman, I told them that.</p>
<p>Q Did you not also tell Okajima that Hana was your wife? A I
told Okahima that she was a woman that was to be my wife and that she
had fooled me and left me and that I wanted to see if I could get the
woman and have her arrested.</p>
<p>Q Was that the same story you told Mr. Thayer? A That was what I 
asked the interpreter Okajima to say.</p>
<p>Q And you paid the detective for his services didn't you? Paid him
$10 didn't you? A I paid him something. I don't remember what,</p>
<p>Q And you paid Okajima for his services didn't you.
<fw>18</fw>
<pb/>
A Yes, but I don't remember the amount that I paid him.</p>
<p>Q Now in the first trial against Young and Sugiura you were one of
the defendants weren't you? A Yes</p>
<p>In that trial <del><unclear/></del> you defendants were all charged with the consumated
acts of having transported Hana from Seattle to San Francisco
for purposes of prostitution alone? A Yes</p>
<p>Q And you had an attorney, Mr. Keên, didn't you? A yes.</p>
<p>And in that trial you pleaded not guilty, didn't you? A No, yes
I pleaded not guilty.</p>
<p>Q That was at the first trial? A Yes</p>
<p>Q And you testified in that trial didn't you? A yes.</p>
<p>Testified in your own behalf? A yes</p>
<p>And st that trial you testified that you told Fukuye and Sugiura
and everybody that you talked with up here, that Hana was your wife
didn't you, that was the way you testified? A Yes, Mr. Sugiura
told me twenty or thirty times in jail that I must state always that
Hana was my wife, otherwise I would be convicted.</p>
<p>Q And when you were convicted you felt soure against Sugiura didn't 
you, that was the way you testified? A Yes, <del><unclear/></del> 
because I thought they had fooled me I testified that way they told
me to testify and I didn't understand any English and got myself in
bad.</p>
<p>Q And when you have that testimony you gave it with the understanding
and purpose of getting clear didn't you? A Yes, because they
told me if I testified that way there wouldn't be any casue and they
couldn't convict me.</p>
<p>Q And that is the reason you testified? A They told me that all
three were under the same indictment and if I was convicted they
would be convicted, and if I testified the way they told me the three
of us would be acquitted.</p>
<p>Q And that was the story you told you attorney, Mr. Keene, wasn't
it? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q And at the second trial you pleaded guilty to the conspiracy and
having entered into a conspiracy with Young, Siguria, and others to
transport Hana to San Francisco didn't you? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q And did you know that you were only to have thirty days punishment
for pleading guilty? A No, I don't know anything of that.
A I didn't know what punishment it would be.</p>
<p>Q How did you happen to plead guilty at the second trial when you
had pleaded not guilty at the first trial? A I knew I was guilty
and felt sure I would be acquitted and decided to plead guilty.</p>
<p>Q And you were also dissappointed in having been given thirty days
punishment in the second trial were you? A When I pleaded guilty
I didn't know what sentence I would get, I expected to get more than
I did get.</p>
<p>Q You said just a moment aho that you said you expected to be acquitted?
A I knew I was guilty and expected that I would be convicted
and pleaded guilty and htre myself on the mercy of the Court.</p>
<p>Q Your entire talk then in regard to Hana was with Sugiura was it?
A Yes.</p>
<p>You had no talk with Young about it?
<fw>19</fw>
<pb/>
A Only that Young just said, "Just leave it to us, leave the matter
in our hands." I went to Young's room and had a talk with him in 
his own room.</p>
<p>Q When was that? A Just before we went to San Francisco.</p>
<p>Q That was when you got him to help you exchange your railroad
ticker wasn't it? A No, Sugiura took me to his room</p>
<p>Q Well, That was the time you got him to exchange the ticket?
A No, You came to me in the hotel and got the tickets.</p>
<p>Q How did you but the first two tickets that you got to go back 
to Frisco? A Mr. Suguria bought them.</p>
<p>Q How is it that you didn't go on those tow tickets? A I heard
that those tickets were not for the boat leaving from Seattle so I 
decided not to go.</p>
<p>Q Well then did you try to get it exchanged? A Yes, I got Mr.
Young to change them.</p>
<p>Q While you were in jail waiting for your first trial what tank were
you kept in? A First in the north tank and then I went to the east 
tank and then I went to the south tank.</p>
<p>Q And what tank did they keep Sugiura in do you know? A Young
and Suguira and I were all in the same room.</p>
<p>Q When? A We moved in there about January, News Years sometime.</p>
<p>Don't yopu know it to be a fact that Young and Sugiura were in the
North tak all the time and you were in teh south tank, is it not a 
fact that the Government authorities put you boys all in separate
tanks to keep you apart? A When we first came to jail I was in the
north tank, Young in the south tank and Sugiura in the South tank and
afterwards they put all a federal prisoners in the south tank and
we were together.</p>
<p>Q How long were you in the south tank with Sugiura? A It was over
a month, from about New Years when we moved there until Feburary at
the time of the trial.</p>
<p>Q When did you meet and make arrangements with your attorney, Mr.
Keene, to defend you? A I saw him once shortly after my being put
in jail.</p>
<p>Q And who interpreted between you and Mr. Keen at that time?
A Okayashi.</p>
<p>Q How many conversations did you have with Mr. Keen your attorney?
A He came here the first time at my request and I signed papers 
appointing him as my attorney but I didn't see him again until my
trial.</p>
<p>Q Didn't you have a short conversation with Mr. Keen up here just a d
say or two after your arrest as you testified a little while ago?
A I never said I had a conversation with Mr. Keen up here just engaged 
his services</p>
<p>Q And you told him and the interpreter and others that you talked
with that you wanted to have a separate attorney and that you didn't 
want to be connected with Young and Sugiura didn't you?
A I said I wanted a different attorney but I didn't say that I cared
about a separate trial.</p>
<p>Q Now in that first trial the woman Ito was <add>a</add> defendant wasn't she?
A Yes.</p>
<p>Q And don't you know it to be a fact that she at first had the court
appoint me as her attorney also to defend her and then afterwards had
me discharged? Claiming that she dissired to appear separate from
Young and Sugiura? A I don't know.</p>
<p>Q Don't you remember the day that you defendants were all arraigned
in the Court and the court asked the woman Ito if she had an attorney
and she said no and asked if she wanted McClelland to defend her
that was the day you were first arraigned? A Yes.</p>
<fw>20</fw>
<pb/>
<p>Q And you know that the prosecution was dismissed as to her afterwards
and she testified as a witness in the case? A Yes</p>
<p>Q Now what talk did you and she have together as to what your testimony
would be? A I had no talk with her, never saw her in
jail.</p>
<p>Now you are certain in your memory that when you boys were first 
put in jail that Young was put in the East tank and Sugiura in the
North tank and you in the South tank, you are sure about that are you?
A yes.</p>
<p>Q And you stayed there until after New Years when you and Young were 
put in the south tank together where you stayed up until the time of
the trial? A Young adn I were both put in the south tank with
Sugiura.</p>
<p>Q That was after the New Years? A Yes</p>
<p>Q So that whatever arrangements and conversations you had with your
attorney and statements that you made to him when you first came to
jail were made before you boys were put together, wasn't it?
A. Yes, it was no conversation, just simply engaged the services of
the attorney.</p>
<p>Q hen did youhave a conference with your attorney?A I didn(t
see him until we were in court and I had a little talk with him</p>
<p>Q Do you mean to say that you being defended in a serious
charged and hired an attorney and never had any conversations with him
up until the time you appeared in court? A Yes, I had engaged the
services of the attorney and I supposed he would look after my interest.</p>
<p>Q Did you expect the attorney to guess what you were charged with and
whether you were giulty or not? A I suppose that he would have me testify in court and know my story and they so when I went up to
court I testified the way Young and Sugiura wanted me to</p>
<p>Q Did you pay your attoney for his services? A Igave the money
to the interpreter and let him pay the attorney. I haven't paid him 
anything yet but the interpreter said he would arrange it.</p>
<p>Q How long did you and Hana live together in San Francisco before
she ran away from you? A About five month from January to about
May, about four months, the 7th of May.</p>
<p>Q Was that when she ran away, the 7th of May? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q It was your intention to make her your wife at that time wasn't 
it? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q And you wrote back to Japan to the father for permission to marry
her didn't you? A Yes.</p>
<p>And when you came up here you had in your mind to take her back
or intended to make her your wife didn't you? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q It wasn't your intention to put her into prostitution then when
you came up here? A My intention was to take her back and live
with me as my wife but not to put her in a house of prostitution.</p>
<p>Q And you hired Sugiura and Young to help you get her with that idea
and that intention didn't you? A I asked them to bring her to Seattle.</p>
<p>Q Where did you and Hana live together in San Francisco before she
ran away? A At 1020 Stockton Street.</p>
<p>Q And that was the house you took her back to when you and Young and
Sugiura went down to San Francisco? A Yes. </p>
<fw>21</fw>
<pb/>
<p>Did you rent a room for her or did she rent a room herself?
A I didn't, I don't know whether the girl rented it or not, I didn't
rent it.</p>
<p>Q Do you know Nakada? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q do you know about the incident when he telephoned to Ito and to
Umeda to hide Saitom Hana, away that the officers were coming to get
her,? A No, I don't know.</p>
<p>Q When was Hana arrested by the officers and brought back up here
after you and Young and Sugiura took her down? A I don't know.</p>
<p>Q Well she had been down there a month or so, a month or six weeks,
before she was brought back here hadn't she? A I guess it might
have been about six weeks, I don't know whenshe was arrested.</p>
<p>Q Didn't you know about Ito paying Nakada $40. for the purpose of
protecting Hana against being brought up here? A No.</p>
<p>Q How long did Young and Sugiura stay in San Francisco when they 
helped you take Hana down there? A I don't know, I didn't see him
after their arrival there.</p>
<p>Q When did you see them last? <del>A I don't know, I didn't see him</del>
A I saw them that night when we got down and I think, I am not sure,
I saw them on a sidewalk.</p>
<p>Q You never saw them again at the house at 120 Stockton Street after
taking the woman there did you? A I don't remember whether I saw
them in that house</p>
<p>Q How much did you pay Young and Sugiura for taking Hana down there?
A Didn't pay them.</p>
<p>Q Who paid them? A Ito.</p>
<p>Q Do you know whether or not they paid it to Young and Sugiura?
A They say that when the money was paid Ito, Umeda, Young and
Sugiura were at this Kimparo but I don't remember having been there,
I might have been but I can't remember having been there.</p>
<p>Q Do you know what hotel Young and Sugiura stopped at in San Francisco?
A At the Imperial hotel one night.</p>
<p>Q Didn't you know that Ito and Umeda paid them this $20. up at 
their room in the Imperial Hotel? A. I don't know.</p>
<p>Q You don't know whether the money was paid them? A Umeda and Ito
say that I was there but I don't remember having seen it paid,</p>
<p>Q Do you remember about going with them up to the Imperial Hotel
to see Young and Sugiura? A No.</p>
<p>Certified a true transcript</p>
<ab>(signed) Walter P. Harris.
Stenographer</ab>
<fw>22</fw>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>