<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0176.007.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Marie Miler v. United States of America.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0176.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Marie Miler v. United States of Americas. Return Brief.</title>
<date when="1913-05-08">May 8, 1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2457MarieMiler</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-05">May 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Miler, Mary</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Riddell, C. F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Breakway, E. B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Cushman, Edward E.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington Territory</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>United States District Court
Western District of Washington
Northern Division</p>
<p>In the Matter of The Application
of Marie Miler for a Writ of
Habeas Corpus. } No. 2457
Brief.</p>
<p>The first question to be determined is the legal right
of an alien in regard to deportation. Under the 5th
amendment to the Constitution, an alien, being a "person"
shall not be "deprived of life, liberty or property without
due process of law". The Act of Feburary 20, 1907; Sections
20 and 21, as amended by the Act of March 26, 1910, provides
in effect that an alien may be deported when the Commissioner
of Commerce and Labor (now the Commissioner of Labor) is
satisfied that the alien has been practicing prostitution.
Section 22 provides for the enforcement and the promulgation
of rules not inconsistent with the law, which should be laid
down by the Commissioner-General of Immigration. The rules
as shown by the amended return provide:</p>
<p>"During the course of the hearing the alien shall be
allowed to inspect the warrant of arrest and all the
evidence on which it was issued; and at such stage
thereof as the officer before whom the hearing is
held shall deem proper, he shall be apprised that
he may thereafter be represented by counsel and shall
be required then and there to state whether he desires
counsel or waives the same and his reply shall be
entered on the record. If counsel be selected, he 
shall be permitted to be present during the further
conduct of the hearing, to inspect and make a copy
of the minutes of the hearing, so far as it has
<pb/>
proceeded, and to offer evidence to meet any evidence
theretofore or thereafter presented by the Government.
Objections and expceptions of counsel shall
not be entered on the record, but mauy be dealt with
in an accompanying brief."</p>
<p>It is well settled that a summary hearing, instituted under
this law, constitutes as to the alien, due process of
law guaranteed by the Court.</p>
<p>DeBruller v. Gallo, 184 Fed. 566, and cases there cited;
United States v. Ju Toy, 198 U.S. 253, 49 L. Ed. 1040;
Chin You v. United States, 208 U.S. 8, 52 L. Ed. 369;
Bottlier v. Donseuguey, 130 U.S. 238, and
numerous subsequent decisions.</p>
<p>We do not understand petitioner to very seriously
question these doctrines, though on page 6 of its brief
an attempt is made to draw an impossible distinction between
the determination on the evidence as to whether the
petitioner did belong to the deportable class of aliens
(a determination which it is admitted this court cannot
review on habeas corpus), and the regularity of the subsequent
deportation based on such evidence. The remarks
of the court in Zaonaito v. Wolf, 226 U.S. Sup. Ct. Rep.,
272, of course had reference to a case where if all the
evidence were true it would not be "adequate and sufficient"
to warrant deportation; in other words, where a demurrer
to evidence would have been sustained in a civil action,
and where to "satisfaction" of the Secretary was not a
true exercise of discretion at all, but entirely unwarranted
by any evidence before him. Where there is any
evidence whatever of the liability to deportation the action
of the Department is not reviewable by the court by habeas
corpus or in any other manner.</p>
<p>DeBruller v. Gallo, 184 Fed. 566, and cases there cited;
United States v. Ju Toy, 198 U.S. 253, 49 L. Ed. 1040;
Chin You v. United States, 208 U.S. 8, 52 L. Ed. 369;
Bottlier v. Donseuguey, 130 U.S. 238, and
numerous subsequent decisions.</p>
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
<p>That this is a case where there is evidence, which if
true, justifies the action of the Department, cannot be
denied. The returns on file show this unqualifiedly, and
defendants do not deny it, but only say that such evidencee
is false. Under the authorities cited this matter of the
truth or falsity of the evidence is not a matter for the
determination of this court.</p>
<p>As to the statements in petitioner's brief touching
the right of appeal, it is enough to say that the cases
relied on were decided under statutes where the decision
in the first instance was made by an examining officer,
and then, if asked, an appeal was granted to a superior officer.
The statute under which this alien is being deported
provides for deportation only on the order of the Secretary
in the first instance, and hence no appeal is required or
mentioned. The Commissioner here merely recommends, as
was done in this case. The Secretary of Labor is the one
who must be "satisfied", and has been so "satisfied" as
shown by the return in this case. Hence there is no further appel,
for the highest officer has already decided
the matter.</p>
<p>Petitioner's main plea however is that she was not
granted a fair trial by the Department and this involves a
close examination of the petition, return and reply. Disregarding
the conclusions of law in the pleadings and confining
attention, as we must to the specific allegations
of the pettioner's return and rely so to just exactly
what did occur at the trial, we find that the only real
complaint is this, to-wit: that after petitioner had
selected and employed an attorney he entirely failed to
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
to produce evidence in her behalf, which she now says she
has. We have already noted the requirements of the rules
of the Department in regard to attorneys. The return shows
that this rule was acrupulously followed. Before final 
hearing and long before the sending in of the report to the
Secretary of Labor, the petitioner was notified as to her
rights, she acted on them, and thereafter every opportunity
was given the petitioner's attorney to put in any evidence
which he might wish and to examine the prior proceedings.</p>
<p>Taking all the allegations of the petition and reply
to be true in so far as they differ in material respect
from the showing made by the return, we would find the 
following to be the facts: that prior to the hearing
petitioner has retained counsel (Pet. Par. 4) though she
was not informed of her right thereto until after the 
hearing (Reply Par. 2). We think that this allegation as
to the time of her being advised as to her right to counsel,
is explained by the fact appearing by the return (Report
page 26) that this notification, was given at the close
of the first hearing, but long before the final close of
the matter and in ample time to enable the petitioner or
her attorney to introduce any evidence they might have.
And in this connection it should be noted that the rules
are satisfied if at some stage of the proceedings, the
alien is informed of this right, the exact time being left
to the officer before whom the hearing is held, and if 
thereafter opportunity is given such attorney to be present
and introduce his evidence on behalf of the alien. Obviously
neither the rule nor the procedure in this case was in any
manner unfair, or in any such sense as to prevent the 
<fw>4</fw>
<pb/>
proceeding from constituting fair play or a fair proceeding.</p>
<p>Petitioner furhter denies that the immigration officers
made the specific efforts set forth in the return to get said
petitioner's attorney to be present and protect her interest.
But they no where allege that the officers of the Government
in any manner either by action or omission to act,
prevented her attorney from presenting her evidence, or took
any unfair advantage to prevent said attorney from so
representing her. Even if such allegation of the return
were true, and the officers did not make the active efforts
they allege to get Marchetti to not, no blame can be
attached to them. If, in truth they did take the steps
they allege they went far beyond any duty they owed to the 
alien, and teated her with marked generosity. But nowhere
is there any allegation that they acted in any unfair 
manner in going ahead and sending in their report many days
after his appointment. Especially would this be true where,
as petitoner herself admits he did not appear or make any
effort to produce any other or futher evidence. The very
general allegation that petitioner was ready and willing
to procure futher evidence but was "prevented" from so
doing, without showing how or by whom or when or in what
manner she was so prevented, or when or in what manner
or to whom she made any offer to produce any such evidence,
does not even raise a question of fact as opposed to the
clear and specifics showing of the return with its detailed
report of just exactly what did occur.</p>
<p>The gist of the proceeding as shown by the petition,
the return, the reply and petitioner's brief, all taken
together is simply this - Marie Miler being a prostitute
<fw>5</fw>
<pb/>
and an alien and hence subject to deportation by her own
admission (see Report attached to return <add>Page 40</add>, claims that her
husband and certain others are worse than she is, that
they are seeking to deprive her of her property, and that
her attorney failed to properly present to the Deparment
her side of the case. There is nothing in all of this
to show any unfair or arbitrary or despotic procedure or
departure from due process of law by the department. It
is the old bitter ory of the defeated litigant, "The court
was unfair and my attorney sold me out". But if there
is anything settled in the law, it is that the litigant
even in a court bound by the strictest rules of law, cannot
allege any error on account of his attorney's neglect of
duty. Having selected this attorney he must stand or fall
by his conduct. had this neglect of her attorney, which
she seeks to make the basis of a charge against the fairness
of the Department, occured even in the strictest court of
law, default would have followed and no error could have
been predicted on such ruling.</p>
<p>Cyc Volume 23 - Judgements - page 939 et seq.
and cloud of cases there cited.</p>
<p>How much less will such circumstances fail of showing
an unfair, arbitrary or despotic procedure by the Department
which will prevent its ruling on the case from constituting
the "due process of law" on which the alien must
rely.</p>
<p>There therefore conclude:</p>
<p>I.
A deportation under order of the Secretary of Labor,
<fw>6</fw>
<pb/>
after he has become "satisfied" as to the facts, by a
summary hearing held under the rules established by the
Commissioner-General of Immigration, and shown in the
amended return, constitutes "due process of law", and does
not justify the interference of a court by habeas corpus."</p>
<p>DeBruller v. Gallo, 184 Fed. 566, and cases there cited;
United States v. Ju Toy, 198 U.S. 253, 49 L. Ed. 1040;
Chin You v. United States, 208 U.S. 8, 52 L. Ed. 369;
Bottlier v. Donseuguey, 130 U.S. 238, and
numerous subsequent decisions.</p>
<p>II.
Where, as in this case, there is evidence which if
true, justified a finding of facts authorizing deportation,
the court does not have authority to in any manner review
such evidence. The evidence on which the order of deportation
is based, could only be reexamined by this court
(and then the authority of the court would be doubtful),
where the facts which it tends to establish would not
justify deportation. It is not even claimed that this 
is such a case.</p>
<p>DeBruller v. Gallo, 184 Fed. 566, and cases there cited;
United States v. Ju Toy, 198 U.S. 253, 49 L. Ed. 1040;
Chin You v. United States, 208 U.S. 8, 52 L. Ed. 369;
Bottlier v. Donseuguey, 130 U.S. 238, and
numerous subsequent decisions.</p>
<p>III.
The report of the proceedings shown in the return shows
on its face an absolutely fair hearing, in accordance with
the law and the rules of the Department.</p>
<p>Disregarding, as must be done, conclusions of law as
to the regularity and fairness of the proceedins, and
considering only the specific allegations of the petition
and reply, such return and report are uncontradicted, except
in the one particular; as to the specific steps
<fw>7</fw>
taken by the Department to induce petitioners attorney
to introduce any evidence he might have, and as to this
matter, there is nowhere any allegation of any unfair
practice by the Department or its officers, against either
the petitioner or her attorney, but only that the attorney
failed in his duty. This, even if true, does not constitute 
the unfair arbitrary or despotic conduct of the
summary investigation, which will justify the review of
the Secreatry's descretion by the courts.</p>
<p>DeBruller v. Gallo, 184 Fed. 566, and cases there cited;
United States v. Ju Toy, 198 U.S. 253, 49 L. Ed. 1040;
Chin You v. United States, 208 U.S. 8, 52 L. Ed. 369;
Bottlier v. Donseuguey, 130 U.S. 238, and
numerous subsequent decisions.</p>
<p>We therefore respectfully contend that the writ 
should not issue</p>
<p>Respectufully submitted</p>
<ab>C. F. Riddell
United States Attorney. </ab>
<ab>E.B. Breakway
Assistant United States Attorney.</ab>
<p>In connection with the ases above cited in this bried
we would call His Honor's attention to Zakonaite v. Wolf,
U.S. Sup. Ct. Reports, 226, page 272, a case decided under
this same statute and reaffirming the doctrine announced in
the earlier cases.</p>
<pb/>
<p>2x No. 2457</p>
<p>In the District Court
of the United States
for the
Western District of Washington</p>
<p>In the Matter of The 
Application of
Marie Miler
For a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Reply Brief</p>
<p>filed in the 
U.S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington
May 8 1913
Frank L. Crosby, Clerk.
By EML Deputy</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>