<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0272.009.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Columbia George v. Charles B. Hopkins. Answer and Return to Order.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Czapla, Ethan P" xml:id="epc">Ethan Czapla</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0272.009</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Columbia George v. Charles B. Hopkins. Answer and Return to Order</title>
<date when="1906-03-26">March 26, 1906</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno>1390ColumbiaGeorgeIndian</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1906-03">March 1906</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Toy Toy</term>
<term>Edna, Annie</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Salem, Oregon</term>
<term>Umatilla Indian Reservation, Oregon</term>
<term>McNeill's Island, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>George, Columbia</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Hopkins, Charles B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Slater, R. J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Frye, Jesse A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#epc">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>No. 1390</p>

<p>In the Circuit Court of the United States for the W. Dist. of Washington, Northern Division</p>

<p>In re application of Columbia George for writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Answer and return to order to show cause</p>

<p>Filed Mar 26, 1906. A Reeves Ayres, Clerk. By A. N. Moore, Deputy</p>

<pb/>

<p>In the United States Circuit Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Columbia George, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. No. 1390.</p>

<p>Answer and Return to the Order to Show Cause Issued Herein.</p>

<p>In obedience to the order to show cause heretofore issued in this matter, come now the respondents,
       C.B. Hopkins, United States Marshal for the Western District of Washington, and the United States of
       America, by Jesse A. Frye, United States Attorney for the Western DIstrict of Washington, and in answer
       to the petition adn order to show cause filed and issued herein, stating that while said peition on file herein
       is not paged, paragraphed nor the lines numbered, it being therefore difficult to put the return thereto in
       systematic form, but waiving said irregularity, certify, return and answer as follows:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>The respondents deny, generally and specifically, each and every allegation, and each and every part
       thereof, contained on teh first page of said petition, except that the petitioner, Columbia George, together
       with one Toy Toy, was on the 21st day of October 1901 indicted by a Grand Jury of the United States of
       America sitting in and for the District of Oregon, and that thereafter said petitioner was tried in said court upon
       said indictment, and convicted of murder without capital punishment and sentenced to be imprisoned at hard 
       labor for life in the</p>

<pb/>

<p>Oregon State Penitentiary at Salem, Oregon, and thereafter by order of the Attorney General of the United States
       said petitioner was transferred to the custody of C.B. Hopkins, United States Marshal for the Western District of
       Washington, and that said petitioner is now in the cusotdy of said United States Marshal for the Western District of
       Washington in the United States Penitentiary on McNeills Island, Washington.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>The respondents deny generally and specifically each and every allegation and each and every part thereof contained
       on page two of said petition, except that Columbia George is now and was at the time of the indictment set forth in paragraph
       One of this return, a full blood Indian, and that the person mentioned in said indictment as having been murdered by said
       Columbia George and Toy Toy, was a full blood Indian, and that said crime was committed on the Umatila Indian Reservation
       in the State of Oregon, and that the said Columbia George and Toy Toy were at the time said murder was committed, tribal
       Indians belonging to the Cayuse Band of Indians, and resided upon said Umatilla Reservation.</p>

<p>And respondents for a further return to said petition and order to show cause, state that on the 21st day of October 1901, at
       Portland, Oregon, in the Circuit Court of the United States for the District of Oregon, an indictment was returned against the
       applicant and petitioner, Columbia George, jointly with Toy Toy, which said indictment was and is in the words and figures
       following, to-wit:</p>

<pb/>

<floatingText><body><p>In the Circuit Court of the United States District of Oregon</p>

<p>{United States of America, vs. Columbia George and Toy Toy} No. 2699.</p>

<p>District of Oregon, ss.</p>

<p>The Grand Jurors of the United States of America, choosen, selected and sworn within and for the District of Oregon,
       in the name and by the authority of the United States of America, upon their oaths do find and present:</p>

<p>That Columbia George, an Indian, and Toy Toy, an Indian, did on the 24th day of August 1900, upon the Umatilla
       Indian Reaservation, within the State and District of Oregon, purposely and of thier deliberate and premeditated malice
       and forethought kill and murder one, Annie Edna, an Indian woman, by then and there administering to her the said
       Annie Edna, a lethal dose of poison, namely, strychnine, from which said Columbia George and Toy Toy, Indians
       aforesaid, the said Annie Edna then and there died, contrary to the form of the statute in such case made and provided,
       and against the statute in such case made and provided, and against the peace and dignity of the United States of America.</p>

<p>Dated at Portland, Oregon, this 21st day of October 1901.</p>

<p>Chas. E. Ladd, Foreman of United States Grand Jury.</p>
<p>John H. Hall, United States District Attorney.</p>

<p>That thereafter a trial was had of said Columbia George and Toy Toy in the above entitled court upon said indictment, and the said
       Columbia George and Toy Toy were convicted of murder without capital punishment, and sentenced to imprisonment at hard labor
       for life in the Oregon State Penitentiary at Salem, Oregon, upon a commitment issued by the Judge of the United States Circuit Court
       for the District of Oregon, which said commitment was issued under a judgment in said cause rendered by the said Circuit Court of the
       United States for the District of Oregon, on the 3rd day of December 1901; that thereafter by an order of the Attorney General of United
       States, the said petitioner, Columbia George, was transferred to the custody of C.B. Hopkins, United States Marshal for the Western
       District of Washington,</p>

<pb/>

<p>and that said Columbia George is now in the custody of the said United States Marshal in the United States Penitentiary on McNeills
       Island, Washingotn, and that said petitioner is being held in said penitentiary pursant to the commitment issued by the United States
       Circuit Court for the District of Oregon, and pursuant to an order of the Attorney General of the United States, and that the custody of 
       the said Columbia George by the said United States Marshal for the Western DIstrict of Washington is legal, and that the United States
       Circuit Court for the District of Oregon had jurisdiction in the premises, and the Attorney General of the United States had power and
       authority to transfer said petitioner from the Orgeon State Penitentiary at Salem, Oregon, to the custody of the United States Marshal for
       the western District of Washington, that the term of sentence of the saod Columbia George has not expired according to law and according
       to the terms of the commitment issued in the premises; that C.B. Hopkins, is now, and for a long time prior thereto has been, the duly appointed,
       qualified and acting United States Marshal for the Western District of Washington, and that the petitioner, Columbia George, is in his custody
       as such United States Marshal, and that said petitioner is now being legally detained in the United States Penitentiary on McNeills Island, 
       State of Washingotn; that at the time of the return of said indictment as herinabove set forth the said Columbia George and the said Toy Toy
       were full blodd Indians, and that the person murdered by them was a full blood Indian, and that the crime commited by them was commited upon
       the Umatilla Indian Reservation in the State of Oregon,</p>

<pb/>

<p>and that the said Columbia Goerge was at the time of the return of said indictment and at the time of his trial and commitmet, and is now, a tribal
       Indian belonging to the Cayuse Band on Indians, and that at the time of the commision of said crime and during said trial, and until sentenced, he
       was residing upon said Umatilla Inidan Reservation in the State of Oregon:</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, your respondents having shown to this Honorable Court that said petitioner is held by due and lawful process, prays that said rule
       and order to show cause herein, be quashed , and that said prisoner be held to await the expiration of his sentence as provided by law.</p>

<p>Jesse A. Faye
       United States Attorney for the Western District of Washington</p></body></floatingText>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>