<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0376.019">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Junichi Yamamoto v. Luther Weedin. Exhibit "A"</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="ka">Salma J. Silva</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0376.019</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Junichi Yamamoto v. Luther Weedin. Exhibit "A"</title>
<date when="1922-01-10">January 10, 1922</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1922-01">January 1922</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Kahl, Arthur J.</term>
<term>Yasutake, Jack</term>
<term>White, Alfred T.</term>
<term>Sakamatsu</term>
<term>O'Brien, Margaret</term>
<term>Hiroshi, Junichi</term>
<term>Yamamoto, Wai</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Japan</term>
<term>South Park, Washington</term>
<term>Georgetown, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Yamamoto, Junichi</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Weedin, Luther</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Hellsell, Frank P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Gates</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Falkner, Judson J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Cushman, Edward E.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-10" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>EXHIBIT "A"</p>

<p>U.S. DEPARTMENT OF LABOR
IMMIGRATION SERVICE.</p>

<p>REPORT OF HEARING
In the case of
JUNICHI YAMAMOTO.</p>

<p>Under Department Warrant No. (Telegraphic), Dated 
January 10th, 1922.</p>

<p>Hearing Conducted by Arthur J. Kahl, Immigrant Inspector
at Seattle, Washington, on January 10th, 1922, Minutes taken 
and transcribed by Arthur J. Kahl, Immigrant Inspector.</p>

<p>Said JUNICHI YAMAMOTO being unable to speak and under
stand the English language satisfactorily, an interpreter,
Jack Yasutake, competent in Japanese was employed.</p>

<p>Said Junichi Yamamoto was then informed that the purpose
of said hearing was to afford him an opportunity to show cause 
why he should not be deported to the country from whence he came,
said warrant of arrest being read, and each and every allegation
therein contained carefully explained, to him. Said person was
then offered an opportunity to inspect the warrant of arrest
and the evidence upon which it was issued, which privilige was
accepted; and <gap></gap> being first duly sworn the following
evidence was then and there presented</p>

<p>Q (By Inspector Kahl) At the hearing under this warrant
of arrest you have the right to be represented by coun-
sel. Mr. Sakamatsu, Proprietor of the Pacific Hotel 
in this City was sent you this letter stating that he
has asked Mr. Alfred T. White to represent you in these
proceedings. Do you desire to have Mr. White represent
you or not?</p>

<p>(Attached to this hearing is original letter in Japanese
characters, together with translation into English, show-
ing letter to be addressed to Mr. Yamamoto, and signed
"Sakamatsu").</p>

<p>A I would like to telephone to Mr. Sakamatsu first.</p>
<p>(Alien is allowed to telephone to Mr. Sakamatsu.)</p>

<p>Q What have you decided to do about retaining Mr. White 
to represent you?</p>

<p>A I want to see Mr. White first.</p>

<pb/>

<p>(Alien consults with Mr. Alfred T. White).</p>

<p>By Alien: I would like to have Mr. White represent me.</p>

<p>NOTE: At request of attorney hearing is deferred until
January 16th, 1922 at 10 A.M.</p>

<p>ATTEST:</p>

<p>Arthur J. Kahl</p>

<p>Immigrant Inspector</p>

<p>35348/2-9</p>

<p>Case of JUNICHI YAMAMOTO</p>

<p>Seattle, Washington</p>
<p>January 16, 1922</p>

<p>Arthur J. Kahl, Immigrant Inspector</p>

<p>Jack Yasutake, Interpreter</p>
<p>Margaret O'Brien, Reporter</p>

<p>A.T. White, Counsel for alien,
Present.</p>

<p>Alien sworn.</p>

<p>Q. (By Inspector Kahl) State the date and place of your birth</p>

<p>A.- December 22, 1890, Hiroshima ken, Saiki gun, Hera mura,
Japan.</p>

<p>Q Are you married of single?</p>

<p>A Single</p>

<p>Q Are you of the Japanese race?</p>

<p>A Yes</p>

<p>Q Are you able to read and write in any language?</p>

<p>A Only Japanese.</p>

<p>Q Have you ever used any other name besides Junichi Yamamoto?</p>

<p>A No.</p>

<p>Q Haven't you been known by the name of Junichi Hiroshi?</p>

<p>A I used that name a little while among friends.</p>

<p>Q You were known by that name at the Pacific Hotel where
you were arrested, were you not?</p>

<p>A Yes.</p>

<p>Q How long did you live in Japan?</p>

<p>A 27 years.</p>

<p>Q What kind of work did you do in Japan?</p>

<p>A Mostly working on the farm.</p>

<p>Q Are your parents living in Japan now?</p>

<p>A My mother is still living but my father is dead.</p>

<p>Q What is your mother's name and where does she live?</p>

<p>A Wai Yamamoto, in the same place where I was born.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Q Where did you go after leaving Japan?</p>

<p>A Then I came to the United States.</p>

<p>Q Where did you land in the United States?</p>

<p>A Seattle.</p>

<p>Q What was the name of the steamer?</p>

<p>A "Taiyo Maru".</p>

<p>Q What was the date?</p>

<p>A September 17, 1917.</p>

<p>Q Did you come as a passenger or as a seaman?</p>

<p>A As a seaman</p>

<p>Q Were you discharged or did you desert?</p>

<p>A Deserted.</p>

<p>Q Did you have a passport when you left the vessel?</p>

<p>A No.</p>

<p>Q Why didn't you have a passport?</p>

<p>A I never tried to get a passport.</p>

<p>COUNSEL FOR ALIEN: Was it necessary to have a passport to get on board that steamer?</p>

<p>A No, I didn't need a passport to get on board.</p>

<p>INSPECTOR KAHL: The records of this office show that this alien
deserted from the crew of the "Taiyo Maru" in Seattle, Wash-
ington, September 17, 1917.</p>

<p>Q (To alien) Where did you go after leaving the vessel?</p>

<p>A I went to South Park.</p>

<p>Q What kind of work did you do there?</p>

<p>A Laboring on the farm.</p>

<p>Q Have you done any other work besides farm labor since you
have been in this country?</p>

<p>A I was working in a sawmill a little while.</p>

<p>Q What other kind or work have you done?</p>

<p>A Worked in the round house in Georgetown.</p>

<p>Q What kind of work were you doing in the round house?</p>

<p>A Hostler's helper.</p>

<p>Q Have you ever done anything besides laboring work in your
life?</p>

<p>A No, mostly on the farm.</p>

<p>Q At the time you left the vessel in September, 1917 did you
see an immigration officer?</p>

<p>A No sir.</p>

<p>Q Was it your intention to remain in the United States then?</p>

<p>A Yes.</p>

<p>Q Dod you own any property or have you any resources of any
kind here?</p>

<p>A I have one truck; I bought that Ford truck for $1260.</p>

<p>Q Is it paid for?</p>

<p>A $250 more to pay.</p>

<p>Q Do you own it by yourself or have you some partner.</p>

<p>A Myself.</p>

<p>Q Have you any other property or resources?</p>

<p>A I have about $500 loaned to somebody.</p>

<p>Q Have you a promissory note or any security for that?</p>

<p>A I have a note for $120 but I haven't got it for the rest.</p>

<p>Q Have you ever been arrested in the United States?</p>

<p>A No.</p>

<p>Q Were you ever arrested or convicted of any crime before you
left Japan?</p>

<p>A No. </p>

<pb/>

<p>INSPECTOR KAHL: That is all.</p>
<p>COUNSEL FOR ALIEN:</p>

<p>Q (To alien) A little while back in the hearing you made the
statement that you also had been farming. Mr. Yasutake
(interpreter), this alien stated that he had been farming?</p>

<p>INTERPRETER: Yes, I overlooked saying that.</p>

<p>Q (To alien) Where as this?</p>

<p>A In South Park.</p>

<p>Q How much land did you have leased?</p>

<p>A Yes, it was leased.</p>

<p>Q Have you still that farm under lease?</p>

<p>A No, it has expired now.</p>

<p>Q About when did it expire?</p>

<p>A I think it was to the end of November, I intended to have 
it renewed.</p>
<p>(Alien exhibits lease dated April 8, 1920, covering two acres
of land for a period of two years from March 1, 1920, rental
of $150 per annum,</p>

<p>INSPECTOR KAHL: Have you any statements to make or any evidence
to introduce to show cause why you should not be deported
from the United States in conformity with the law?</p>

<p>A No, I have nothing to say</p>

<p>INSPECTOR KAHL: (To Counself for alien) Do you intend to file
a brief in this case?</p>

<p>A I couldn't say, I don't think so. I will let you know later.</p>

<p>Attest:</p>
<p>Margaret O'Brien</p>
<p>Stenographer, Notes transcribed January 17, 1922,BK 1305.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>