<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0225.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Thomas L. Thurston v. O.P. Halligan. Return to Petition for Writ</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0225.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Thomas L. Thurston v. O.P. Halligan. Return to Petition for Writ.</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-12">December 27, 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Thomas L. Thurston</term>
<term>O.P. Halligan</term>
<term>Clay Allen</term> 
<term>Albert Woods</term>
<term>Charles E. Bunnell</term>
<term>Agnes V. Thurston</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>McNeils Island, Washington</term> 
<term>Iditarod,Territory of Alaska</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Thomas L. Thurston</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>O.P. Halligan</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>J. Henry Denning</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Clay Allen</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName><!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>Western District of Washington, Northern Division</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-02" who="#AS">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Petition
of Thomas L. Thurston for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus } No. 3128</p>

<p>RETURN TO PETITION FOR WRIT.</p>

<p>Comes now the respondent, O.P. Halligan, as Warden
of the United States Penitentiary, McNeilisland, Washing-
ton, and for answer and return to the petition of Thomas
L. Thurston, filed herein, does affirm, deny and allege:</p>
<p>-I-</p>
<p>Respondent admits the allegations contained in para-
graph one of the petition.</p> 
<p>-II-</p>
<p>Respondent denies the allegations contained in para-
graph two of the petition, that the petitioner is unlaw-
fully detained and restrained of his liberty by the re-
spondent herein, an alleges the true fact to be that the
petitioner is now lawfully and rightly detained and re-
strained of his liberty by the respondent, as an officer of
the Department of Justice of the United States, to-wit, as
Warden of the United States Penitentiary, at McNeil Island,
washington, pursuant to and as a consequence of an indict-
ment,<add>arraignment</add> plea of not guilty, trial, verdict, judgment, sent-
ence and commitment had, in due and proper course in a crim-
inal cause in the United States District Court for the Ter-
ritory of Alaska, Fourth Judicial District, sitting at
<pb></pb> 
Iditarod, Alaska, the same being cause No.44-1, wherein
the United States was plantiff and Thomas L. Thurston
and Agnes V. Thurston, were the defendants, and the said
confinement and restraint by the respondent are in ac-
ordance with and the result of the judgment entered in
said cause.</p> 
<p>-III-</p>
<p>The respondent admits the allegations contained in
paragraph three of the petition, that said custody is
by color of the authority of the United States, but
denies that such custody is in violation of the consti-
tution and laws of the United States</p>
<p>-IV-</p>
<p>The respondent in answer to the allegations con-
tained in paragraph four, the respondent denies each and
every allegation therein contained, except such as are
hereinafter specifically admitted, and more particularly
denied that the indictment and judgment filed and entered 
in said cause were pretended.</p>
<p>In further answer to the allegations of said para-
graph, the respondent alleges that on or about the 23rd
day of July, 1914, a legal and proper indictment was re-
turned by a Grand Jury of the United States, duly and
regularly qualified, impaneled and sworn, in the Fourth
Judicial Division of the United States District Court,
sitting at Iditarod, against the above named petitioner
and one other defendant, charging the petitioner and his
co-defendant with detaining, delaying and embezzling mail
matter in violation of Section 195 of the Penal Code,
and thereafter upon the appearance of said defendants,
both in person and by counsel <add>on arraignment,</add> a plea of not guilty wa
<pb></pb> 
entered by the petitioner and the other defendant there-
in; thereafter, upon the issue so joined a jury was reg-
ularly empaneled which returned its verdict into the 
court finding the petitioner and the other defendant,
and each of them guilty under the allegations of the in-
dictment and issues joined thereon; thereafter a judgment
and sentence upon said verdict was duly and regularly en-
tered by Hon. Charles E. Bunnell, trial judge of said
court, a copy of which said judgment is hereto attached,
marked exhibit "A" and made a part of this answer and
return; that the said indictment,/<add>arraignment</add>plea, verdict and judg-
ment, and each of them, was entered in the docket of
said court as a part of the proceedings in cause No.44-1
of the criminal causes of said court; that under the
terms and conditions of the said judgment so entered, the
marshal for said Division of the Territory of Alaska was
required to deliver the body of the defendant, Thomas L. 
Thurston, to the warden of the United States Penitentiary
at McNeil Island, Washington; that pursuant to the re-
quirments of said judgment so entered, the said Marshal
did, on the <gap></gap> day of <gap></gap>, 1915, deliver to this
respondent at the United States Penitentiary the body of
the petitioner, Thomas L. Thurston,and as a commitment
and warrant for his said action delivered to this re-
spondent under the seal of the Clerk of the District
Court for the District of Alaska, Fourth Division, a
certified copy of the judgment, hereinbefore referred to,
a copy of which said certificate is hereto attached and
made a part of this answer and return.</p>  
<pb></pb>
<p>-V-</p>
<p>In answer to paragraph five of plantiff's petition,
the respondent denies each and every material allegation
therein contained, and more particulary denies that no
proper or legal mittimus or other legal authority was de-
livered to said respondent, and alleges that he isa hold-
ing said prisoner by reason of the said judgment so en-
tered, a certified copy thereof transmitted to him as a 
commitment in said action.</p> 
<p>-VI-</p>
<p>In answer to paragraph six of the plantiff's peti-
tion, respondent denies that the petitioner herein is not
guilty of the crime herein charged against him and denies 
each and every material allegation contained in said para-
graph six.</p> 
<p>WHEREFORE, the respondent herein prays that the body 
of Thomas L. Thurston be remanded to and continue in the
custody of this respondent as Warden of the United States
Penitentiary; that said petitioner may be required to keep
and preform the judgment and sentence entered in said
criminal cause; that this action be dismissed with preju-
dice; and for all further and proper relief in the premises.</p>
<p>Clay Allen</p>
<p>United States Attorney, for 
Respondent.</p> 

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON 
COUNTY OF KING } ss.</p> 
<p>Clay Allen, being first duly sworn, upon his oath de-
poses and says; That he is United States Attorney for the
Western District of Washington, and as such attorney is
<pb></pb>
familiar with the facts set forth in the foregoing answer 
and return; that he has read said answer and return and 
make this verification for and on behalf of the respond-
ent, who is not now present; that each and all of the
facts hereinbefore recited is set forth upon information
and belief of this affiant, except the facts relative to
the existence of the said judgment and certificate here-
inbefore described; that the records hereinbefore referred
to are in the Territory of Alaska, a remote distance from
this District.</p> 
<p>Clay Allen</p> 
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me and this 27th day of 
December, 1915.</p> 
<p>Albert Woods
Notary Public in and for the State of
Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>