<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>United States District Court
Western District of Washington
Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Ching Hing for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus. } NO. 2875
Reply Memorandum Brief</p>
<p>I will not burden this Honorable Court with a lengthy
Answer to the argument presented by the Learned Counsel for the
Government in the last Memorandum Brief filed by him, but will
simply reiterate the stand I took in open court before your Honor,
that an issue having been made upon the record in this case, the
Court should then determine what was the statute of the detained at 
the time the issue was made up. Therefore, it resolves itself
into this question - did Mr. Denamore, at the time he affirmed the
decision of Commissioner White, act without authority?</p>
<p>Your Honor has allowed us to ask by interrogatory of the
Assistant Secretary, if he was in Washington at that time. Mr.
Justice Gould hass upheld the right to obtain this information from 
the Assistant Secretary in the decision which your Honor has before 
you. Therefore, it would seem to me that the only orderly procedure
in upholding the dignity of your Honor's Court, and the dignity of
the District Court, presided over by Mr. Justice Gould, would be 
that your Honor must allow this case to take the orderly couse of
procedure; or if your Honor feels that the Government has, by its 
pleadings, admitted that Mr. Denamore acted without authority at
the time he did act, then make such a decision, in either dismissing
the alien, or sending the record back for review by the proper
officer, to wit: - the Secretary or Assistant Secretary.</p>
<p>To allow counsel at this time to amend his return, after
the issue has been made, would be to subvert the course of justice
and orderly procedure of this Court. As Mr. Justice Dooling said
in a decision before your Honor, that the detained has a right to
<fw>1.</fw>
<pb/>
have his plea heard by the proper officer. This was ratified by
Mr. Justice Gould in his decision, and I think your Honor should 
follow this ruling and not allow any arbitrary action taken after
the issues are made up, and more especially, I may say, without 
even asking permission of this Court to allow the same ot be taken,
but to come in on the morning of the hearing, as was done in this 
case, and make a return after a prior return had been made, and
the issue then made up to ask your Honor to dismiss the case when
the first return showed that the original record was before this 
Court. In my estimation it would be denying to this detained the
rights allowed by law and the treaties between nations.</p>
<p>For a moment let me cite an illustration which might occur 
if this rule of procedure was allowed to exist. Mr. Denamore might
act at such times as he saw fit, regardless of whether the Secretary
and Assistant Secretary were present or not; the detained
might apply for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, might prepare his defense
and meet the issues, and then Counsel for the Government could come 
in and say in each and every case - "It is true that Mr. Denamore
has acted without authority, but all we have to do is to have a
carbon copy of the proceedings before the Court and wire the Secretary
to affirm the COmmissioner's decision, show this to the
Court and the case falls."</p>
<p>It would seem to me that it would place a man in this position
under the original facts, as in this case - he would have
a right to present a case where one had deprived hm of his liberty
without authority, he would have to engage counsel at an expense,
file papers at a further expense, and then the Immigration Department
could hold for naught orderly and regular proceedure, and act
at the eleventh hour without notice, without giving counsel for
the detained, the right to present sound argument to the Secretary 
in favor of the detained, and deprive the detained of his libery,
and hold for naught the inalienable right of habeas corpus procedure,
and equitable and just hearing upon the issue made when
<fw>2.</fw>
<pb/>
the Writ was issued and return made by the Government, and the
case, upon those facts, properly placed before this Court.</p>
<p>I sincerely trust that your Honor will not tire of the effort
I have made in behalf of this poor Chinaman, but will grant to him
the protection ofthe strong arm of this Court, in order that this
Chinaman may have granted unto him such orderly procedure and such
rights as we would want an American citizen granted were he before
a tribunal of a foreign Court, seeking what this Chinaman seeks -
simple justice;</p>
<p>And I, Therefore, respectfully pray that your Honor will
deny the petition and demand of the Governmnet, and will make
such order in this case, as to your Honor may seem just and equitable.</p>
<ab>Respectfully submitted.
John J Sullivan</ab>
<pb/>
<p>No. 2875
Original</p>
<p>In the
<del>Superior</del><add>District</add> Court
<del>State</del><add>Western District</add> of Washington
King County
Northern Division</p>
<p>In the Matter of the 
Application of Ching Hing
for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>Reply Memorandum Brief.</p>
<p>Beeler &amp; Sullivan
Lawyers
510-11 White Building
Seattle, Wash.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>