<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0364.023">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Tsunetaro Machida v. Luther Wedin. Decision</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0364.023</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Tsunetaro Machida v. Luther Wedin. Decision</title>
<date when="1921-09-16">September 16, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-09">September 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Machida, Tsunetaro</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Wedin, Luther</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Horner, Thomas R.</persName>
<persName>Judd, Edward</persName>
<persName>Lonergan, Pierce</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the United States District Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>No. 6190.</p>

<p>Decision.</p>

<p>Filed Sept. 16, 1921.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of TSUNETARO MACHIDA for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Thos. R. Horner, Attorney for Petitioner.</p>
<p>Charlotte Kolmitz, Asst. U.S. Atty, and Robert C. Saunders, U.S. Atty, Attorneys for United States.</p>

<p>NETERER, District Judge, - - - -</p>

<p>The petitioner charges that he is wrongfully deprived of his liberty by the Commissioner of Immigration. A show cause was issued and return avers that the petitioner is detained for deportation as an alien person not entitled to remain by virtue of an order issued by the Secretary of Labor. To the return is attached the record and file in the hearing before the Bureau. The petitioner is directed to be deported for the reason that:</p>

<p>"He has become a public charge within five years after his entry into the United States from causes not affirmatively shown to have arisen subsequent thereto; and that he was a person likely to become a public charge at the time of entry into the United States."</p>

<p>The court record of conviction, which is conclusive here, shows that the alien was responsible for the etnry of contraband aliens from Mexico, and on being indicted plead guilty and was sentenced to the Federal Prison for two years. He urges that the offense for which he was convicted is not urged as a ground for deportation, and that he is not a person likely to become a public charge, - a charge - where for some reason a person is to be supported:</p>

<p>"At public expense by reason of poverty; insanity and poverty; disease and poverty;"</p>

<p>and not for a reason which is included within the other provisions of the statute with relation to crime and conviction.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Sec. 3, Act. FEb. 5. 1917, Sec. 4289 bb. Comp. Stat. excludes:</p>

<p>"Persons who have been convicted of, or admit having committed a felony or crime involving moral turpitude****(and) persons likely to become a public charge."</p>

<p>Sec. 19. supra, 4289 1/4j, fixes conduct or condition of aliens admitted for which they may be deported:</p>

<p>(1) "Any alien who within five years after entry becomes a public charge from causes not affirmatively shown to have arisen subsequently to entry****; (2) any alien who is hereafter sentenced to imprisonment to a term of one year or more because of conviction of a crime involving moral turpitude, committed within five years after entry of the alien in the United States****".</p>

<p>A felony is an offense which may be punished by death or imprisonment for a term exceeding one year. Crim. Code. 335, Sec. 10509 Comp. Stat. Turpitude is defined by Webster to be inherent baseness or vileness of principal or acting.</p>

<p>"Everything done contrary to justice, honesty, modesty and good morals is said to be done with turpitude." Bouvier,</p>

<p>And moral turpitude is defined as:</p>

<p>"An act of baseness, villainy or depravity in the private social duties which a man owes to his fellow man or to society in general, contrary to the accepted and customary rule of right and duty between man and man. State vs. Mason, 29 Ore. 18; Blackburn vs. Clark, 41 S. W. 430; Baxter vs. Mohr, 76 N. Y. Sup. 982." Vol. V. Words &amp; Phrases, 4580.</p>

<p>Public is defined by Bouvier as "the whole body politic or all the citizens of the State." The public in this case is the people, the Government of the United States.</p>

<p>"Charge" (Webster) "to lay on or impose as a tax, duty or trust."</p>

<p>A judgment is a charge upon land. Darling vs. Rogers, 22 Wend. (N.Y.) 491. A married woman may charge her separate estate. Radford v. Carmile, 13 W. Va. 658. Charge may be said to be responsibility peculiar to the person affected, and a public charge to be a person committed to the custody of a department of the Government by due court of law. The alien in this case could not be excluded, because hehad not</p>

<pb/>

<p>been convicted of a felony, nor did he admit having committed the act at the time of entry. He may not be deported because of the offense, because it was committed before entry. When he was convicted he became a public charge and a tax, duty and trust was imposed upon the Government by his conduct; and at the time of his entry he was likely to become a public charge by reason of the crime which he had committed.</p>

<p>The intent of the Congress unquestionably was to exclude persons unfitted as defined to enter and made provision that if within a limited period it was disclosed that they were disqualified at the time of entry, deportation should be made, and the provision of statute being broad enough to include the charge which is not covered by any other provision, the writ will be discharged.</p>

<p>Jeremiah Neterer</p>
<p>Judge.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Sep 16 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S. E. Leitch Deputy</p>



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>