<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0420.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Martin J. McDonough v. Territory of Washington. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Lauren Hinton</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0420.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Martin J. McDonough v. Territory of Washington. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1887-02">February 1887</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1887-02">February 1887</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>McGraw, John H.</term>
<term>Hill, G.A.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McDonough, Martin J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Territory of Washington King County</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of Washington Territory and the Third Judicial District</orgName>
<placeName>King County</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-06" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>In the District Court of Washington Territory and for
the Third Judicial District therof, holding terms at
Seattle, for the counties of King and Kitsap
Territory of Washington - Plaintiff }
vs.
M.J. McDonough L. - Defendant.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application } Petition for
of M.J. McDonough for a             Writ of Habeas Corpus
Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>In the Hon. Judge of the above entitled court.
the petition of M.J. McDonough respectfully shows</p>

<p>1st</p>

<p>That M.J. McDonough is unlawfully imprisoned, detained,
confined and restrained of his liberty by John H. McGraw.
Sheriff of King County, Washington Territory, at the County
Jail in said County and Territory in the City of Seattle.</p>

<p>2nd</p>

<p>That the cause or pretense of each imprisonment
detention, confinment and restraint, according to the best
of the knowledge or belief of your petitioner is that your
petitioner has been adjudged, by one G.A. Hill, Justice of
the Peace, in and for Seattle Precinct, King County, Washington
Territory, to be guilty of an alleged crime, to wit, contempt of
court, and that after having him so adjudged guilty, as
aforesaid, he was sentenced by said Justice of the
Peace to pay a fine of five dollars and $17.60 cents</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>and that he stand committed until the same be paid,
and before any process was issued out of the Court of said
Justice of the Peace to collect said fine, and costs
or any demand made on your petitioner to pay the same
your petitioner was unlawfully arrested, committed, deatained,
confined and restrained of his liberty by virtue of an unlawful
and illegal and <unclear></unclear> commitment issued by said Justice
which commanded that your petitioner be so imprisoned and
restrained of his liberty until such fine and costs be paid
<del>and that your petitioner be allowed $2.50 per day
<unclear></unclear> imprisonment</del></p>

<p>3rd</p>

<p>That said imprisonment, detention, confinement and
restraint an illegal and that the illegality thereof
consists in this - to wit</p>

<p>1st That your petitioner is not guily of the offense for
which he was illegally tried, convicted, sentenced and
committed, as aforesaid.</p>

<p>2nd That your petitoner is illegally and unlawfully imprisoned and
restrained of his liberty, <unclear></unclear> and in this to wit, he has been
confined and committed by said Justice, as aforesaid, in
<unclear></unclear> of the punishment provided in statements.</p>

<p>3rd That the punishment presented for said alleged
offense of which your petitoner was so adjudged to
be guilty, to wit, resistance to the lawful order or
process issued by said Justice of the Peace and which
is alleged to have constituted the contempt of
Court complained of and as your petitoner believes</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>is, by section 1843 of the code of Washington-Territory
as follows "Punishment for contempt may be by fine,
not exceeding twenty-five dollars, or by imprisonment
in the County Jail not exceeding two days, at the
discretion of the Justice". The jurisdiction given to
the Justiec of the Peace is carefully limited, at his
discretion he may either fine or imprison but no
authority is given him to do both.</p>

<p>The form of the Judgement Entry to be made in the
docket of each Justice, as prescribed by section 1847
of said Code, is as follows "is convicted of the
contempt aforesaid and is adjudged by the
under signed to pay a fine of _____ dollars. The
date and signature of the Justice following. The form
goes no further and makes no provision for the
commitment and imprisonment of the defendant.
Excepting that should the Justice use the discretion
allowed him and imprison instead of fine, the
said form says in brackets ("or be imprisoned etc.")</p>

<p>How the punishment for said offense shall be
inflicted by said Justice is strictly laid down
and predefined by Section 1848 of said Code- as
follows. "If any person convicted of a contempt be 
adjudged to be imprisoned, a warrant of commitment
shall be issued by the Justice "<unclear>but</unclear>" If he be
adjudged to pay a fine a process may be
issued to collect the same" And no former
or authority, either express or implied, is given</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>said Justice to imprison until said fine and costs
of the proceeding are paid. Your petitoner is illegally
imprisoned, detained, confined and restained of his liberty
because the said Justice exceeded his jurisdiction and
the authority given him by statute in sentencing him
to pay a fine and at the same time sentencing him
to imprisonment until the same he paid.</p>

<p>4th That your petitoner has fees and is now illegaly committed
and is now illegaly imprisoned and restrained of his liberty
because the commitment issued by said Justice
<add>as aforesaid</add> upon
which the said Sheriff holds imprisons, confines and
restrains of his liberty your petitoner, was unlawfully
and illegaly issued, and said commitment was and is
unlawful, illegal and <unclear>void</unclear>.</p>

<p>5th Because your petitoner is deprived of his liberty
without due process of law.</p>

<p>6th Because your petitioner has never been lawfully informed
of the notion and cause of the accusation against him</p>

<p>7th Because the said Justice of the Peace in so committing
and causing to be imprisoned and restrained of his libery,
your petitoner as did without having authority in
the premises to commit as aforesaid</p>

<p>8th Because the said imprisonment is for <del></del>
for eleven days and time limited by the
statute in each case made and provided <del>
only for</del> only allows an imprisonment for
two days</p>

<p>9th Because he is imprisoned and sentenced to hard labor
and said Justice has no jurisdiction to so imprisonment and sentence him</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>10th Because said imprisonment is for an indefinite
time. There being no time but in the said
order of commitment from which the said
time of eleven days shall commence to <unclear></unclear></p>

<p>11th Because the said petitioner was so committed and
imprisoned before any return was made by the
<unclear></unclear> of said court on the hereby issued by said
court for the collection go said fine and costs as to
whether or no the said dine was or was not, or cruled
or could be collected</p>

<pb></pb>



               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>