<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>M. L. Coovert for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. Petition for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Russell, Ellie" xml:id="edr">Ellie Russell</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">M. L. Coovert for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. Petition for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1890-1901, vol 1</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1893-06">June 1893</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Coovert, M. L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="sheriff">
<persName>Nerton, George</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wood, C. E. S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
                  
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Clarke County</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#edr">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">
<pb/>
<p>Case 4.
To The Honorable Circuit Court of the United States
for the District of Washington:
Ex parte
M. L. Coovert } Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Your petitioner M. L. Coovert
complains and shows to the court as follows:
That he is a citizen and resident of the State of Washington, and that he is unjustly
and unlawfully detained and imprisioned by George Nerton
sheriff of the County of Clarke, State of Washington, at Vancouver, in the County of
Clarke and State of Washington, by virtue of a warrant of commitment issued by E. A.
Wiswall, Judge of the Superior Court of Washington for Clarke county, under the following
circumstances:</p>
<p>Your petitioner is a citizen of the United States, and so was at the time of his arrest,
and was and is a citizen of the State of Washington, and at the time of grievance
herein complained of was and is engaged in the business of a retail tobacco dealer, in
the City of Vancouver, County of Clarke and State of Washington.</p>
<p>That while so engaged in conducting his business as said retail tobacco dealer, he was
on the 9th day of June 1893, arrested by the sheriff of Clarke
County, State of Washington; one George Nerton
by the order of and upon a warrant issued by the Honorable E. A. Wiswall, sitting and
acting as judge of the Superior Court of the State of Washington for the County of
Clarke, a copy of which warrant is hereto attached marked "Exhibit No. 1," and which your
petitioner prays may be considered as part of this petition, the same as if it was
expressly incorporated in it. And he ever since has been kept in confinement and
under arrest, and now is under arrest as aforesaid and restrained of his liberty upon the
following charges: Violation of the following law of the State of Washington:</p>
<p>"Section 1. That it shall be unlawful for any person or persons whatever to manufacture,
buy, sell, give or furnish to any one cigarettes, cigarette paper or cigarette
wrapper.</p>
<p>"Sec. 2. That whosoever manufactures, buys, sells, gives or furnishes to any person
or persons cigarettes, cigarette paper or cigarette wrapper shall be deemed guilty of a
misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof shall be fined not more than $500 or imprisioned
in jail not exceeding six months, or both, for each offense.</p>
<p>"Sec. 3. This act shall be liberally construed to the end that its object shall be
enforced.</p>
<p>"Sec. 4. All laws or parts of laws in conflict with the provisions of this act are
hereby repeaed."</p>
<p>And upon the <del>information</del><add>affadavit</add>, of which a copy is hereto attached, and marked as
"Exhibit No. 2," and which your petitioner expressly makes a part of this petition, the
same as if incorporated in it, and prays that it may be so considered.</p>
<p>And that immediately upon the arrest of your petitioner, he was taken before the said
Honorable E. A. Wiswall, sitting and acting as judge of the Superior Court as aforesaid,
and as a committing magistrate. That before said magistrate testimony was given by
C. L. MacDonald and G. W. Stapleton
as follows: that your petitioner had sold to C. L. MacDonald
a package of cigarettes, marked Social Whiffs cigarettes
being ten <del>paper</del><add>tobacco</add>-wrapped cigarettes enclosed in a slide pasteboard
box having upon it the U. S. Revenue
stamp for ten cigarettes
<pb/>

<del>with the caution notice required by the laws of the United States printed on the side of
said <gap></gap>, and the United States internal revenue stamp for ten cigarettes pasted
across the end of said</del></p>
<p>And the said package so sold by your petitioner was produced before the committing
magistrate as evidence, and is herewith produced as "Exhibit No. 3" of this petition.</p>
<p>The aforesaid facts your petitioner admits to be true. <del>The said cigarettes were</del>
except as to said articles being cigarettes petitioner alleges
that they are small cigars, said cigars were sold in New York
to your petitioner by the American Tobacco Company, doing business in the state of
New York
and said cigar<del>ettes</del> were manufactured in New York, and were
shipped to your petitioner in <del>pasteboard</del><add>wooden</add> boxes, containing twenty five
such packages, exactly similar to said "Exhibit 3." <del>That said pasteboard boxes are
called "cartons" by the trade, and are used simply for the purpose of making convenient
parcels of the packages of cigarettes for enumeration and handling at the factory, and to
protect the cigarette packages when in storage, and one of such "cartons" is herewith
produced as "Exhibit No. 4" of this petition, and is more particularly described as follows:</del></p>
<p>That said wooden boxes a cartons were shipped to your petitioner by said American
Tobacco Company from the State of Oregon enclosed in common
pine shipping cases, being merely packing cases for the protection and safety of the
goods in transportation; and that heretofore, to wit: April 6, 1893, the Honorable the
Commissioner of Internal Revenue for the United States decided that such a package as
said "Exhibit 3," containing a statutory quanity of cigarettes and properly stamped and
cancelled, and bearing the caution label and number of the manufacturing district and
state, and the number of cigarettes contained therein, was an original package, as contemplated
by by United States law and regulations, and that the repacking of said packages
in additional coverings of wood, paper, etc., was optional with the manufacurer. A true
copy of the letter of said commissioner, announcing such decision, is hereto attached as
"Exhibit No. 5," which your petitioner prays may be considered as a part of this petition,
to the same effect as if incorporated in it.</p>
<p>That your petitioner is advised by counsel learned in the law that his detention is
unlawful, as being in contravention of the consitutional provision of the United States
contained in the Fourteenth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, Section
1. That said detention is also unlawful as being in contrvention of Article 1, Section
8, of the Consitution of the United States, and that said law under which your petitioner
was arrested and is now detained is invalid, as contraty to the provisions of the Constitution
of the United States, in that it abridges the privileges and immunities of citizens of
the United States and deprives your petitioner of liberty and property without due process
of law, and also that its effect is to probinit and regulate commerce among the several
States.</p>
<p>And your petitioner claims that said law is invalid in the premises, and that he is
held without jurisdiction or authority.</p>
<p>Wherefore, to be relieves of said unlawful detention and imprisonment, your petitioner
pays that a writ of habeas corpus, to be directed to the said George
Nerton, Sheriff of the County 
of Clarke in the State of Washington, may issue in this behald, so that your petitioner
may be forthwith brought before this court to do, submit to and receive what the law may
require. </p>
<p>M. L. Coovert
Petitioner.</p>
<p>C. E. S. Wood
Solicitor<del>s</del> for Petitioner.
Of Williams &amp; Wood 
Attys.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>