<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.269.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title> In Re: Ex Parte - Turner Jackson Petitioner For A Writ of Habeas Corpus </title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Banse, AD" xml:id="ab">AD Banse</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.269.001</idno>
<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">  In Re: Ex Parte - Turner Jackson Petitioner For A Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="2022-06-07"></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington </repository>
<collection> RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle </collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName> Turner Jackson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName> C.B. Hopkins</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>C.H. Hanford</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> 
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>  

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs ="hc.case.wa.269.001"/>

<!-- <p>Reproduced at the National Archives at Seattle </p>-->
<p>  In The United States Ciruit Court,For the Ninth 
        Juidicial Circuit, Western Division of the State of Washington, 
        Northern Division.</p>
<p>In Re Ex Parte: Turner Jackson, Petitioner. No. 1325 </p>
    
 <p>Petition for Appeal to the Circuit Court of Appeal for
     the Ninth Circuit, and Order allowing same. </p> 
    
<p>To the Honorable Cornelius H. Hanford, 
        Judge of the above entitled Court: </p>
    
<p> United Staes Marshal for the Western District
        of Washington, and the United States of America, in the
        above entitled matter, by its attorney, Jesse A. Frye, 
        United States Attorney for the Western district of 
        washington; and feeling and deeming themselves aggrieved 
        by the order and judgement of discharge made and entered
        and filed in the above entitled proceeding on the 11th
        day of September 1905; do hereby appeal from the said
        order and judgement of discharge to the United States
        Circuit Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, and pray 
        that their appeal may be allowed and that a transcript
        of the record all proceedings and papers upon which 
        said order and judgement was made and entred, duly au-
        thenticated, may be sent toe th United States Circuit
        Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit; petitioners 
        respectfully pray that on account thereof their appeal 
        be allowed to crrect the errors complained of and to 
        reverse, annul and set aside the said order and judgement.
        Your petitioner further pray, that tey have this
        day filed herein their assignment of errors committed </p>
<p> by the court in this proceeding and intended to be urged
    by your petitioners as appelants in the prosecution 
    of this suit upon appeal. </p>
    
    <pb/>
    
 <p> Petitioners further show that this appeal is
     prosecuted by and under the direction and authority
     of the Attorney Generela of the United States, and on
     behalf of the United States, and they respectfully 
     pray that said appeal may be allowed without bond.
    Dated this 12th day if September 1905.
 
     Jesse A Frye,
      United States Attorney 
       For the Western District of Washington</p>
    
<p> And now, to-wit, on the 12th day of September
    1905; it is ordered that the appeal in the above entitled
    proceeding to be allowed as prayed by the United Sates Marshal;
    and it is ordered that siad petitoner, 
    Turner Jackson, may be enlarged pending said appeal upon 
    ten thousand dollars 
    to the satisfaction of the Clerk of this Court for his
    appearance to answer the judgement of the United States 
    Circuit Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, and upon 
    failure thereof to give bail, to remain in the custody
    of the Warden of the United States Penitentiary on McNeill's 
    Island, Pierce County, State of Washigtonm until discharged
    by law. 
    C. H. Hanford,
    Distrcit Judge of the Western
    District of Washington</p>
    <p> </p>




</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>