<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.00462.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ah Jack v. C. D. Hanford. Petition of Intervention</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weekly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weekly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.00462.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ah Jack v. C. D. Hanford. Petition of Intervention</title>
<date when="1894-06-29">June 29, 1894</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1894-06">June 1894</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Jap, Ah</term>
<term>Gap, Ah</term>
<term>Hopkins, R. M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>China</term>
<term>British Columbia</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Jack, Ah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Emery, C. D.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Canoll, P. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Binker, William H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, Cornelius H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington, Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2021-05" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<ab>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.
NORTHERN DIVISION.</ab>

<ab>In the matter of the petition of Ah Jack,
a Chinaman, for a writ of Habeas Corpus.</ab>

<p>To the Honorable Cornelius H. Hanford, Judge of said Court:</p>

<p>The United States, having first obtained leave to intervene
herein come now and present their petition of intervention, in
this cause, and as grounds of intervention say <add>state</add></p>

<ab>FIRST.</ab>

<p>That the prayer of the petitioner in this cause ought not to be 
granted because intervenors say:-</p>

<ab>I.</ab>

<p>That they deny each and every allegation in the petition filed 
herein, except, that the said petitioner was apprehended on the
27th day of April, 1894, for being unlawfully in the United States
and that on the 30 th day of April, 1894, he was ordered to be
deported from the United States to China by C. D. Emery, United
States Commissioner.</p>

<ab>II.</ab>

<p>Intervenors further say that the said petition and prayer thereof
should not be granted for the reason that the said Ah Jack is a 
Chinese laborer, and that he was on the said 27th day of April, 
1894, unlawfully in the United States and not entitled to be or 
remain in the United States.</p>

<ab>III.</ab>

<p>That the said Ah Jack was on July 14, 1888, arrested and charged 
with being unlawfullyin the United States; that he was on said day
tried upon said charge before C. D. Emery, United States Commission</p>

<pb/>

<ab>-2-</ab>

<p>-er, he, the said C.D. Emery, having then and there competent
jurisdiction to hear, try and determine such charge, and <add>was</add> by the
consideration and judgment of said commissioner, ordered and ad-
-judged to be unlawfully in the United States, and was then and
there by said commissioner ordered deported from the United States
and returned to the Province of British Columbia, the foreign
country from which he came, and that said C. D. Emery then and 
there pursuant to said judgment issued his proper writ of deporta-
tion, directed to the Marshal of the United States for the District
of Washington, commanding the said Marshal to forthwith deport the
said Ah Jack from the United States to the Province of British
Columbia, and that the said United States Marshal did, without
delay, execute the said writ of deportation by taking the said Ah
Jack and removing him to the Province of British Columbia.</p>

<ab>IV.</ab>

<p>And that thereafter, and while said judgment was in full force,
unappealed, <add>from</add> and unreversed, the said Ah Jack, on <add>or</add> <del>and</del> about the 
first day of August, 1888, returned to the United States unlawfully 
and was again arrested under and by the name of Ah Jap, and charged
before said C. D. Emery with being unlawfully in the United States
and on the 4th day of August, 1888, the said Ah <add>Jack</add> <del>Jck</del> under the
name of Ah Jap, was tried before said C. D. Emery, United States
Commissioner, upon said charge, he, the said C. D. Emery, then
and there having competent authority to hear and determine the
same, and the said Ah Jack, under and by the name of Ah Jap, was
by the said C. D. Emery then and there adjudged to be unlawfully
in the United States, and ordered deported to the Province of
British Columbia; that said order of deportation was duly executed
by the Marshal of the United States for the District of Washington</p>

<pb/>

<ab>-3-</ab>

<p>by deporting the said Ah Jack to the Province of British Columbia;
That thereafter, and before the 21st day of August, 1888, and 
while the said judgment of deportation was in full force, unappeal-
ed from and unreversed, the said Ah Jack unalwfully returned  
to the United States, and was again arrested, and charged before
C.D. Emery, United States Commissioner, under and by the name of 
of Ah % Gap, with being unlawfully in the United States, and said
charge was duly tried before the said C. D. Emery, United States 
Commissioner as aforesaid, he, the said C.D. Emery, having com-
petent authority to hear and determine the said charge, and on
the 21st day of August, 1888, said commissioner upon full con-
-sideration adjudged the said Ah Jack, under and by the name of 
Ah Gap, to be unlawfully in the United States and ordered him to
be deported to the Province of British Columbia; that the said
order of deportation was duly executed by the Marshal of the United
States for the District of Washington by conveying the body of 
the said Ah Jack to the Province of British Columbia: That there-
after, at some time before the 16th day of August, 1890, the
said Ah Jack unlawfully returned to the United States, and was 
arrested, while the above mentioned judgments were all in full
force, unappealed, <add>from</add> and unreversed, and charged before said C. D.
Emery, said United States Commissioner, with being a Chinese
labor<del>o</del>r<del>e</del> unlawfully in the United States, he, the said C. D. 
Emery, having then and there competent authority to hear and de
-termine said charge, and the said Ah Jack, under and by the name 
of Ah Jack, alias Ah Jap, was on the 16th day of August, 1890,
tried before the said C. D. Emery, and the said C. D. Emery, after
hearing all the evidence, and upon full consideration adjudged the
said Ah Jack to be then and there unlawfully in the United States,</p>

<pb/>

<p>-4-</p>

<p>and ordered that he should be deported to the Province of British
Columbia, that the United States Marshal for the District of Wash-
-ington duly executed said order by conveying the said Ah Jack
to the Province of British Columbia; That thereafter the said
Ah Jack, while the aforesaid judgment of deportation was in full
force, unappealed from, and unreversed, unlawfully returned to
the United States, and was thereafter arrested, taken before the 
said C. D. Emery, and then and there charged with being unlawfully
in the United States, the said C. D. Emery having competent author-
-ity as aforesaid, adjudged the said Ah Jack to be then and there
unlawfully in the United States, and on May 3, 1894, ordered the
said Ah Jack to be deported to the Empire of China, and that the
said order and judgment of the said C. D. Emery is still in full 
force, unappealed from, and unreversed.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE the said intervenors pray that the said peiition be
dismissed, and that they recover their costs and disbursements 
herein expended.</p>

<ab><unclear> H. B</unclear></ab>

<ab>United States Attorney.</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Tx</ab>

<ab>No. 390</ab>

<p>In the United States 
Circuit Court
FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>

<p>Ah Jack
Petitioner <unclear>Exha</unclear>
<del>vs</del>
for writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<ab>Intervention
of the Miliel <unclear>Seates</unclear></ab>

<ab><del>FILED 6/29 1894
IN THE U.S.DISTRICT COURT
R M Hopkins
Clerk
By
Deputy</del></ab>

<ab><unclear>WM</unclear> H. <unclear>Brinker</unclear></ab>

<ab>Attorney for Intervenors
5 and 6 Colman Block
Seattle Wash</ab>

<ab>FILED June 29 - 1894
-IN THE-
U.S. CIRCUIT COURT.
A. REEVES AYRES
CLERK.</ab>

<ab>By R. M. Hopkins
DEPUTY </ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>