<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0359.004">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>A. C. Hallam v. Henry M. White. Points and Authorities and Brief of Respondent</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0359.004</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">A. C. Hallam v. Henry M. White. Points and Authorities and Brief of Respondent</title>
<date when="1921-02-02">February 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-02">February 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hallam, A. C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Myers, H.A.P</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>No 5779</p>
<p>Points and Authorities and Brief of Respondent.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of A. C. Hallam for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>AUTHORITIES</p>

<p>Consessions Co. v. Morris 109 Wash. 46</p>
<p>Chap. 3 and 4 Session Laws, 1917</p>
<p>37 CYC. 869</p>
<p>Levenworth R. Co. v. Lane 27 Kan. 749</p>
<p>Ex. P. Gaines 19 S. W. 602</p>
<p>Fleetwood v. Read 21 Wash. 547</p>
<p>Stully v. De Mattos 23 Wash. 71</p>
<p>Gerfinkle in re 37 Wash. 650</p>
<p>Percival v. Thurston Co. 14 Wash. 586</p>

<p>FACTS.</p>

<p>The Hotel in questions is situated on land purchased in the City of Bremerton, Washington, several years ago by the U.S. Government. The land originally consisted of two pieces of property, with a street running between them.</p>

<p>In the year 1918 the City of Bremerton, at the request of the Government, vacated the street; and the land in the street reverted to the abutting property.</p>

<p>Later the Government, or the U.S. Housing Corporation, built the Hotel in question.</p>

<p>The Hotel has been leased by the U. S. Government, or rather by the Navy Department, to different people, and now leases same to A. C. Hallam.</p>

<p><del>H. F. Gorman</del></p>
<p>City Attorney</p>
<p><del>200 12 Trust &amp; Saving Bldg.</del></p>
<p><del>Bremerton Wash.</del></p>

<pb/>

<p>-2-</p>

<p>The Hotel is used the same as any other hotel; the enitre public are welcome. In Connection with the Hotel is operated a dance hall, laundry, bakery, restaurant, cafeteria, pool-room, public halls, etc., all being open to the public.</p>

<p>Ordinance No. 464 of Bremerton, provides that anyone operating a public dance in the City of Bremerton, shall pay a license fee of $150.00 per year.</p>

<p>Mr. Hallam refused to pay this license and was brought before the police court and fined $10.00. Mr. Hallam refused to pay the fine, and a committment was issued and he was taken into custody, and seeks this writ on the ground that the city has no jurisdiction to license a business situate within the corporate limits of Bremerton, but located upon and conducted in Government property.</p>

<p>ARGUMENT.</p>

<p>We admit that Government property cannot be taxed.</p>

<p>But Government property used by a private individual in the operation or conducting of a trade for private gain, does not excuse the individual from paying an occupation tax or license in order to conduct the business. The National Bank and Telegraph cases are illustrative of this point.</p>

<p><del>H. f. Gorman</del></p>
<p>City Attorney</p>
<p><del>200 12 Trust &amp; Saving Bldg.</del></p>
<p><del>Bremerton, Wash.</del></p>

<p>2</p>

<pb/>

<p>Here the Government not having further need of said property in the conducting of its Navy Yard has leased it to a private individual to be used in the ordinary course of business; which takes the use of the property out of the exemptions created by the Constitution and by Statute: the Statute says they are exempt when used for the following purposes:</p>

<p>"FORTS, MAGAZINES, ARSENLS, <unclear>DOCKYARDS,</unclear> other NEEDFUL BUILDINGS, authorized by Act of Congress."</p>

<p>Here we have a unique situation. This building, so far as the writer can ascertain, was never authorized by act of Congress. The property on which the building is situated was never acquired with the consent of the State of Washington, as was the Camp Lewis property. The court will notice that it was believed necessary to pass a special act of the Legislature of the State of Washington (Laws 1917 p. 14) giving the consent of the State to the Camp Lewis acquisition. If it was necessary in that case, then it is just as necessary in the present case.</p>

<p>The writer contends that the writ should be denied on four propositions:</p>

<p>1. That the State of Washington never gave its Consent to the acquiring of this property.</p>

<p>2. That the building erected was not done under act of Congress.</p>

<p>3. That when the property and building ceased to be used for a Governmental purpose, and ceased to be a needful building, and was turned over to private interests for private gain, it lost its Governmental protection.</p>

<p>4. A license it not a tax on property; but is a right given to a private interest to engage in business.</p>

<p><del>H. f. Gorman</del></p>
<p>City Attorney</p>
<p><del>200 12 Trust &amp; Saving Bldg.</del></p>
<p><del>Bremerton, Wash.</del></p>

<p>-3-</p>

<pb/>

<p>The first two propositions have already been discussed.</p>

<p>Taking up the third proposition, it would seem that when the Government turned over its property to private interests in the course of ordinary business, that it would loose its exemption. The exemption thrown around Government enterprises, was for the purpose of not hampering the Federal Government in the prosecution of creating special privileges, and exempting one man from a tax or license, and giving him a special advantage over his competitors. For the court to hold that a man can lease Government property, for a private use, and thereby escape an occupation tax, is doing away with the principle of equity. It will destroy the business man of Bremerton. The Business man of Bremerton must pay taxes, assessments and licenses to maintain and keep up the city, and if Mr. Hallam, can conduct, as he is doing, a bakery, laundry, restaurant, pool room, furnish lodging, dancing halls and any other business that he may desire, in competition with the other business men of Bremerton, without paying a license, the U.S. Government becomes an agent of special privileges, and a destroyer of the legitimate business man and the man thay pays the upkeep and maintenance of our Government. This was never the intention of the framers of the Constitution, and is not now and has never been the intention of our law-makers; and when the courts know the intention of the Constitution</p>

<p><del>H. f. Gorman</del></p>
<p>City Attorney</p>
<p><del>200 12 Trust &amp; Saving Bldg.</del></p>
<p><del>Bremerton, Wash.</del></p>

<p>4</p>

<pb/>

<p>and the spirit of the law, then it is the duty of the court to construe the law in the light that the makers thereof intended. It is either unconstitutional for the U.S. Government to lease its property to private interests; or the individual is liable for the license tax when he uses the property for a private gain. One or the other must be true.</p>

<p>Taking up the last proposition:</p>

<p>LICENSE: 25 CYC, 597 "License, in its general sense, means a right or permission granted by some competent authority to do what is unlawful at common law, or is made so be statute, including the one authorizing or requring the license. A privilege is the exercise of an occupation or business which requires a license from some proper authority, designated by some general law, and not free to all or any, without such license. It follows that an occupation or privilege license is the permission granted to an individual by a competent authority to engage in and carry on the particular business or calling to which it refers.</p>

<p>The writer particularly wishes the court to get this distinction: The city is not trying, as in the Camp Lewis case, to tax any property that belongs to the Government. The city is attempting to make a private party, that has leased from the Government, Government property, and is using it in competition with other private interests, pay a license for the privilege of engaging in this business within the corporate limits. This is far from taxing Government property. The property pays no tax. The property cannot be restrained for the license; but the individual is personally responsible for the license, and cannot use the property</p>

<p><del>H. f. Gorman</del></p>
<p>City Attorney</p>
<p><del>200 12 Trust &amp; Saving Bldg.</del></p>
<p><del>Bremerton, Wash.</del></p>

<p>5</p>

<pb/>

<p>in the particular line or business without paying the license to engage in that line of business..</p>

<p>The writer can find no case that holds that a private concern can lease Government property; to be used in the conducting of a private business, and thereby escape a license that is placed upon other business concerns not leased from the Government.</p>

<p>The following examples lend color to the citys contention:</p>

<p>If Mr. Hallam owned the building situated on this Government property; the building would be subject to taxation:</p>

<p>(see) Fort Levenworth R. Co. v. Lowe, 27 Kan. 749.</p>

<p>holding that the state has power to tax railroad property belonging to a private corporation, although it is situated exclusively within the boundaries of a U.S. Military reservation,</p>

<p>There can be no dispute but what the interests of Mr. Hallam, in the lease, as lessee, can be taxed:</p>

<p>(see) Ex. p. Gaines, 19 S.W. 602</p>

<p>holding that the interest of a lessee in lands leased from the U.S. is not exempt from state taxation.</p>

<p>(see) 37 CYC. 869. (IV Possessory rights. The possessory interests which private individuals may hold in the public lands of the United States, for mining, agricultural, and various other purposes, constitute a species of property recognized by law and which is subject to taxation by the state."</p>

<p>The above examples surely show that having leased property from the Government, does not form a complete exemption from every kind of municipal responsibility;</p>

<p><del>H. f. Gorman</del></p>
<p>City Attorney</p>
<p><del>200 12 Trust &amp; Saving Bldg.</del></p>
<p><del>Bremerton, Wash.</del></p>

<p>6</p>

<p>but only shows that Government property, as property, is exempt from taxation.</p>

<p>A tax on trades, professions and occupations in the nature of a license is not a tax on property.</p>

<p>(See)</p>

<p>Fleetwood v. Read.... 21 Wash. 547</p>
<p>Stully v. De Mattos 23 " 71</p>
<p>Garfinkle in r. 37 " 650</p>

<p>Improvements on Government property, the title to which can never be acquired by a private individual are taxable:</p>

<p>Percival v. Thurston County 14 Wash. 586.</p>

<p>Respectfully submitted.</p>

<p>Marion Garland</p>
<p>City Attorney, Bremerton.</p>

<p><del>H. f. Gorman</del></p>
<p>City Attorney</p>
<p><del>200 12 Trust &amp; Saving Bldg.</del></p>
<p><del>Bremerton, Wash.</del></p>

<p>7</p>

<pb/>

<p>In the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington,</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>In the matter of the petition of A.C. Hallam, for writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Points &amp; authorities and Brief of Respondent</p>
<p>City of Brmerton</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Feb 2 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<p>Marion Garland</p>
<p>city attorney.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>