<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0153.001.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Earnest Hutchinson v. State of Washington. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Czapla, Ethan P." xml:id="epc">Ethan P. Czapla</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0153.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Earnest Hutchinson v. State of Washington. Petition</title>
<date when="1905-07-25">July 26, 1905</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno>1183ErnestHutchinson</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1905-07">July 1905</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Smith, L.C.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Tacoma</term>
<term>Seattle</term>
<term>Everett</term>
<term>Ypsilanti</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hutchinson, Earnest</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>State of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Carroll and Carroll</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Mackintosh, Kenneth</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C.H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court of the Ninth Circuit</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#epc">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In The United States Circuit Court of The Ninth Circuit In and For The Western District of Washington Northern Division</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of Earnest Hutchinson for Writ of Habeas Corpus. Petition For Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>To the Honorable C. H. Hanford, Judge</p>

<p>The petition of Earnest Hutchinson respectfully respresents to your honor.</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That your petitioner is a citizen of the United States and of the State of Michigan and a member of the firm doing business in
       the state of Washington under the firm name and style of "National Stamp Company", having their domicile and principal place
       of business in the city of Ypsilanti, in the said state of Michigan.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>That said company is engaged in business in the cities of Tacoma, Seattle, Everett and other places in the state of Washington; and
       that said business consists of general merchandising, advertising, and manufacturing for, and selling to the trade in the said state of
       Washington and in the several states of the United States where said company is carrying on business, buyers' stamps, otherwise
       called Trading Stamps.</p>

<p>III.</p>

<p>That the purposes and objects of said company are:
       To buy, sell, and exchange merchandise; to do a general merchandise and advertising business; to print, issue and circulate advertisements;
       to make and carry out contracts with corporations and individuals; to advertise their business by special and useful devices; to give merchandise
       in exchange for</p>

<pb/>

<p>Buyers' Stamps, commonly known as "Trading Stamps" and which said stamps are due bills, certificates or vouchers to be sold by said company,
       and to be redeemed by it in merchandise, according to its contracts, rules and regulations.</p>

<p>IV.</p>

<p>That said Buyers' Stamp is issued by and as a due bill of said National Stamp Company and is redeemed by said company in exchange for merchandise
       at the store or place of business o fthe said company in the cities of Tacoma, Seattle, and Everett, or any other city, town or place in the United States where
       said company has an office or is doing business as aforesaid.</p>

<p>V.</p>

<p>That said stamps of said company are sold to the trade at the rate of fifty cents a hundred and are given by the trade or merchant as a cash discount to each
       purchaser, one stamp to each ten cents represented in the purchase, and which said stamps are redeemed by said stamp company in merchandise at its place
       of business in said cities of Tacoma, Seattle and Everett, or any other city, town or place in the United States, and that said stamps are used only as a means of
       advertising the business of petitioners and of the merchants using the same, as a medium of co-operation and exchange for value:</p>

<p>VI.</p>

<p>Petitioner attaches hereto and makes a part hereof a stamp book used in the said business of petitioner marked Exhibit "A", which said Exhabit "A" is for the convenience
       and information of the people doing business with said company and the merchants using said stamps and which said book explains the method of obtaining, using
       and redeeming said stamps.</p>

<p>VII.</p>

<p>That at the ninth bi-ennial session of the Legislature of the State of Washington, the State Legislature passed and enact-</p>

<pb/>

<p>ed House Bill No. 340, entitled "An Act making it a misdemeanor to sell or exchange property under the representation, advertisement, notice or inducement that an undentified,
       unknown, unselected, or change prize, premium or premium gift, or that a stamp, trading stamp, coupon or other like device, entitling the holder to receive such a prize, premium,
       or premium gift, or that the redemption of such a stamp, trading stamp, coupon or other like device to said such sale or exchange, as aforesaid, and providing a penalty therefor.
       And which said act was approved by the Governor on or about the 14th day of March, A.D., 1905, a copy of which said act is hereto attached, and for greater certainty is made
       a part hereof and marked Exhibit "B".</p>

<p>VIII.</p>

<p>Petitioner attaches hereto and makes part hereof, marked Exhibit "C", a true and correct copy of the complaint, filed against petitioner and upon which he is unlawfully held and 
       deprived of his liberty and which said compaint is founded upon said House Bill No. 340.</p>

<p>Wherefore, your petitioner demurs to said complaint and for cause of demurrer alleges:
       1st. That the information and complaint against petitioner charages no offense or crime,
       2nd. The said House Bill No. 340 under which peitioner is deprived of his liberty and upon which said complaint is founded is unconstitutional and void. <del></del></p>

<p>IX.</p>

<p>That said act, (House Bill No. 340) passed as aforesaid, by said Legislature and approved by the Governor, is unconstiutional and void in this to-wit:</p>

<p>1st. That it is destructive of the lawful business of plaintiffs, and is destructive of their rights as indiviuals and citizens of the United States.</p>

<pb/>

<p>2nd. That said act is against public policy.</p>
<p>3rd. That said act is in restraint of trade and commerce between the people of this state.</p>
<p>4th. That asid act is in restraint of Inter)State trade and commerce.</p>
<p>5th. That said act is special and class legislation and wrongfully, unlawfully and unreasonably discriminates against the lawful business affairs of petitioner.</p>
<p>6th. That said act unlawfully, wrongfully and unconstitutionally deprives petitioner of his liberty and right to fully contract and carry on lawful business, trade and commerce.</p>
<p>7th. That said act unlawfully, wrongfully and unconstitutionally prohibits and restrains petitioner from engaging in lawful business and takes away and destroys property
       without due process of law.</p>
<p>8th. That said act imposes an unreasonable and unjust burden upon petitioner and upon trade and commerce, and is in violation of their constitutional rights.</p>
<p>9th. That said act is in violation of and in conflict with the Constitution of the United States and of the State of Washington; that said legislature of the state of Washington
       has not the legal power or authority to enact such law as herein complained of.</p>
<p>10th. That said act impairs and interferes with petitioner's right to engage in lawful business, and is a wrongful and unconstitutional exercise of the police power of the
       state of washington.</p>
<p>11th. That said act unlawfully interferes with and impairs the obligations of contract; and said act is an arbitary and unconstitutional interference with the right of private contract.</p>
<p>12th. That said act is oppressive, discriminative, pre</p>

<pb/>

<p>hibitory and unreasonable and is not a proper and lawful erercise of the police power of the Legislature of the State of Washington.</p>
<p>13th. That said bill embraces more than one subject, and</p>
<p>14th. That said subject of said bill is not expressed in the title.</p>

<p>X.</p>       

<p>That your petitioner is unlawfully restrained of his liberty by L. C. Smith, Sheriff of King County, State of Washington.</p>

<p>XI.</p>

<p>That said Sheriff pretends to and does hold petitioner a prisoner and unlawfully deprives and restrains petitioner of his liberty and constitutional rights under and by virtue
       of a pretended complaint and warrant based upon said unconstitutional and void House Bil No. 340.</p>

<p>Your petitioner therefore prays that a Writ of Habeas Corpus may issue, directed to the said Sheriff, commanding him that he have the body of said Earnest Hutchinson
       by him imprisoned and detained, together with the time and cause of said imprisonment and detention, before Hon. C. H. Hanford, Judge of the aforesaid Court at the 
       United States Courtroom in Federal buildingcor. 4th Ave. and Marion St., in the City of Seattle, County of King, State of Washington, at 10 A.M. on the 7 day of August, 1905,
       to do and receive what shall then and there be considered or ordered concerning the said Earnest Hutchinson, in pursuance of the statute in such case made and provided.</p>

<p>Dated this 26 day of July. A.D. 1905.</p>

<p>Carroll and Carroll</p>
<p>Attorneys for Petitioner.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>