<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0180.020.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Return.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace T." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0180.020</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Return.</title>
<date when="1914-01-07">January 7, 1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2628AlbertYoung&amp;KamasaburoSugiura</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-01">January 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>White, Henry M.</term>
<term>Washio, Shotaro</term>
<term>Hunter, B. A.</term>
<term>Harris, Walter P.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Young, Albert H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sugiuro, Kamasaburo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Myers, H. A. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>McClellan, R. W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Johnstone, Walter L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, G. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Cushman, Edward E.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States, for the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Petition
of Albert H. Young and
Kamasaburo Sugiura, alias B. K. 
Sugiura, aliens, for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus. } No. 2628
Return to Petiton
and Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>To the Honorable Edward E. Cushman, Judge of the Above Entitled
Court:</p>
<p>Comes now Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration,
at Seattle, and for answer to the Writ of Habeas
Corpus issued herein, and for answer to the petition filed
herein, states as follows:</p>
<p>I. 
That he has not knowledge and information sufficient
to form a belief as to the matters set forth in
Paragraph I of the said petition, and therefore denies the
same.</p>
<p>II.
That he admits that the warrant for arrest is in
terms and figures as set forth on page two and that the
warrant for deportation is as set forth on page three of the
petition, and that the petitioners were arrested and held 
under said two warrants; but he denies each and every other 
allegation set forth in said Paragraph II.</p>
<fw>1</fw>
<pb/>
<p>III.
That he admits the allegations set forth in Paragraph 
III. ending at the words "from the United States to
Japan" in line twenty-eight of page three of said petition.</p>
<p>That he admits allegations of Paragraph III
commencing at line thirty of page three and ending at the
end of the paragraph; but that he denies all of the other
allegations in Paragraph III save and except what is herein
especially admitted.</p>
<p>IV.
That he admits the allegation set forth in Paragraph
IV, ending at line twenty-six of page four, except
that the petitioners had a "pretended" hearing, and alleges
as a matter of fact that the petitioners' hearing on the
17th day of October, 1913, was a fair and regular hearing.</p>
<p>That he has not knowledge and information sufficient
to form a belief as to whether notice and opportunity
were given to the petitioners and their attorneys to appear,
and therefore denies the same.</p>
<p>He admits that the petitioners did not cross-examine
the affiants; admits that the petitioners were not
confronted by affiants, and that affiants at no time appeared
before petitioners; admits that the attorney for petitioner
appeared at the time of the taking of the affidavit
of Shotaro Washio, and that the petitioners did not appear
at that time; and denies each and every other allegation set
forth in Paragraph IV, save and except what is especially
admitted.</p>
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
<p>V.
As to allegation set forth in Paragraph V,
he admits that portion of the same ending at "United States" in line
twenty on page give, and denies each and every other allegation
set forth in Paragraph V.</p>
<p>VI. 
As to the allegation set forth in Paragraph VI,
he admits that portion of the same ending at the words
"being detained at said station" in line twenty of page 
seven, and denies each and every other allegation thereof.</p>
<p>VII.
That he denies each and every allegation of the
petition
for "a Writ of Habeas Corpus, save and except what 
is herein especially admitted.</p>
<p>And for a further and separate answer and return
to said application for a writ of Habeas Corpus, and for
Further Return to said Writ said Henry M. White alleges as
follows:</p>
<p>I. 
That on October 17, 1913, a hearing was had before 
B.A. Hunter, the Inspector and Examiner, at which hearing
the said petitioners appeared in person and by their attorney,
Robert W. McClelland, and that the testimony and all the 
proceedings were transcribed by the stenographer, Walter
P. Harris, and said transcript is marked "Exhibit A" and 
made a part of this return; that at such hearing the petitioners
were given opportunity to put in all their testimony
and there was no objection whatever raised to the exhibits
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
that were put in evidence by the Government, and that the
petitioners were especially questioned as to the sworn
affidavits or statements put in by the Government.</p>
<p>II. 
That is is impossible for the Department of 
Labor to make an investigation concerning the charges set
forth in said warrant without the knowledge of this office,
and that it never makes an investigation independent of the
local Immigration Officee, and that no hearing or investigation
was made other than that set forth in "Exhibit A".</p>
<p>III.
That there are sufficient facts shown in the
record to justify a finding that the petitioners should
be deported, and that the Court has no authority to determine
anything in a habeas corpus proceeding, except whether
or not the petitioners were deprived of a fair hearing, or
whether as a matter of law from the facts the petitioners
should be deported.</p>
<p>IV. 
That the testimony of Shotaro Washio shows that
petitioners should be deported on the warrant, and that the
only way the Court could grant a writ would be in reversing
the Department in its ruling on the facts; that the petitioners
are, therefore, being legally held on the warrant
set forth in Paragraph II of the petition and should be deported
as therein ordered.</p>
<p>Wherefore said Henry M. White prays the
<fw>4</fw>
<pb/>
above entitled court that the said writ be dismissed and
the application and petition denied.</p>
<p>United States of America,
Western District of Washington. } ss.</p>
<p>Henry M. White, being first duly sowrn, upon his
oath deposes and says: That he is the party named in the
foregoing answer; that he has read the same, knows the contents 
thereof and verily believes the same to be true.</p>
<ab>Henry M. White</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 7th day 
of January, A. D. 1914.</p>
<ab>Winter S. Martin</ab>
<fw>5</fw>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>