<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0459.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Moy Wah v. J. C. Drake. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0459.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Moy Wah v. J. C. Drake. Petition</title>
<date when="1893-06-06">June 6, 1893</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1893-06">June 1893</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Marks, J.E.</term>
<term>Hawks, Thomas</term>
<term>Plummer</term>
<term>Yuck, Moy</term>
<term>Pritchard, W.H.</term>
<term>Clifford, Miles E.</term>
<term>Murray, Charles A</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
<term>Hong Kong, China</term>
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Wah, Moy</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Drake, J.C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Snell, Marshall K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Circuit Court of the United States for the District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Washington, Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-09" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, FOR THE DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, <add>Northern</add> <del>WESTERN</del> DIVISION.</p>

<p>271</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of
Moy Wah for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Comes now the above named Moy Wah, and for his petition and
complaint in writing for a writ of habeas corpus, on oath respect-
fully shows to this court:</p>

<p>That on or about the 22nd day of January, A.D., 1892, he
left the City of Portland, Oregon, where he had resided for 14
years immediately prior to said time, and had been for Four years
last past engaged in the merchantile business, for Hong Kong, Chi-
na, and that he did, prior to taking his said departure, appear
before one J.E. Marks, a Notary Public and then and there sub-
scribe and make the certificate hereunto attached a copy marked as
exhibit "A" and making and forming a part of this his petition.</p>

<p>2. That all the facts and circumstances as set forth an said
statement are true; that petitioner for over four years last past
been actively engaged as a Chinese merchant in Portland, Oregon,
and was at said time doing business at 168 Fifth Street, and was a
<del>member</del> <unclear>22nd</unclear> of the firm of Gum Wing Chung &amp; Co., and as a member of
said firm still having and retaining all of his said interests in
said business, which was the sum of $1200, and still having and re-
ceiving his share of the profits from said business and was at
said time a bona fide owner and holder of about a one-fifth in-
terest in said business, the capital stock of said business being
$6,000 and your petitioner being one of the partners in said busi-
ness; that your petitioner fully and completely relied upon said
J. E. Marks as an attorney at law for the proper wording and
making of said certificate and fully believes that the same fully</p>

<pb/>

<p>-2-</p>

<p>and completely complies with the law as in such cases made and
provided; that the said certificate is attached a photograph of
your petitioner, which photograph petitioner had taken for the
purpose of having same attached to said certificate.; and petition-
er further states that at said time he did obtain the statement of
persons well and favorable known to him, one of said persons be-
ing Capt. Thomas Hawks, who was for a number of years a policeman
upon the beat upon which petitioner's business was located and
frequently met the said Hawks, and that afterwards said Thomas
Hawks was deputy tax collector in the city of Portland and had 
called upon this petitioner and collected taxes, and that the said
Capt. Thomas Hawks did sign said statement attached to said cer-
tificate, and that he is the same Thomas Hawks whose affidavit is
hereunto attached, and that the said certificate of petitiner is 
a correct copy of petitioner's certificate with the exception
of the photograph and <unclear>att</unclear> and marked as exhibit "A"
as aforesaid.</p>

<p>Our petitioner further states that he did, on or about the
22nd day of January, 1892, take his departure for Hong Kong, Chi-
na, and and did there remain and visit with his parents, rela-
tives and friends, and transact his business and the business of
his said firm, which was that of viewing, examining and ascertain-
ing the prices of goods and making arrangements for the buying and
shipping from the manufacturers in China; that thereafter, he did, 
about the 10th day of January, 1893, take passage on the steamer
Victoria at Hong Kong, China, to return to the United States of
America, and that he did pay his fareor said passage and did re-
turn to and was landed at the steamboat wharf at Tacoma, and did
then and there present his certificate and request to be landed;
that one Plummer, representing himself to be a deputy collector,
did, without any cause, right, or authority, and without explain-
</p>

<pb/>

<p>-3-</p>

<p>ing or making known to this petitioner any of his reasons for not
allowing him to land, refuse to allow your petitioner to land, al-
though your petitioner had in all ways and manner complied with
the laws of the United State of America, and did offer and was
willing to produce the witnesses who signed said statement to
said certificate, together with other witnesses both white and
Chinese who knew and would identify <del>him</del> your petitioner as having
<unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear> in the city of Portland for a number of years last past,
and as being a good, honest, upright and bona fide merchant in
said city and a member of the firm doing business at <unclear>H</unclear> S Fifth St
street, in the city of Portland, Oregon, but regardless of said of-
fer, said Plummer made to your petitioner or to one Moy Yuck who
well understands and speaks the English language, no satisfactory
explanation whatsoever, and gave him no reason whatsoever for re-
fusing to admit your petitioner, but did take from your petitioner
his certificate with his photograph thereto attached, and the
statement as thereto attached signed by the petitioner and re-
speciive parties as set forth in exhibit "A", and did refuse to re-
turn same to your petitioner and has ever since said tine retained
same and does still continue to retain same, and your petitioner
has not had or seen the same since said time, and the same is 
still had and retained by said Plummer or the Collector of Customs
or some one under him, without the consent and against the wish and
protest of petitioner, and petitioner further states that on the
evening of the 8th day of May, 1893 about the hour of 3 o'clock,
he was informed that Moy Wah the said steamer Victoria, with a large num-
ber of Chinese passengers, about two hundred in number, nearly all
of whome were strangers to this petitioner, and Moy Wah whome he knew
nothing, and had no relation, would, at 4 o'clock on the morning
of the 9th inst. loose from the wharf at Tacoma, and be cleared</p>

<pb/>

<p><unclear></unclear> and return upon her return trip to Hong Kong; and that your
petitioner, together with his two companions, who are likewise
merchants and who likewise ask for a writ of habeas corpus, would
be forcibly, unjustly, unlawfully and illegally, and without any
cause whatsoever, and without being informed as to any cause, com-
pelled to remain upon said vessel and thus be compelled to return
to Hong Kong. That your petitioner did cause to be made, diligent
search and inquiry to find and ascertain the whereabouts of this
Honorable Court to apply to it for a writ of habeas corpus, and
did apply <add>in the <unclear>above</unclear> <unclear></unclear> <unclear>court</unclear> <del></del></add> to the Commissioner of your Honorable Court for said
writ, which was refused by said Commissioner for the reason that he
had no authority to issue said writ, and that your petitioner was
then compelled to resort to and did apply to the Superior Court
of Pierce County, washington, for a writ of habeas corpus, setting
forth the facts and circumstances, which application was consider-
ed by the Court and by said Court, the Honorable W. H. Pritchard
<del>the</del> granted, said writ in the words following to-wit: "Let the
writ of habeas corpus and the warrant issue as prayed for in the
within complaint and petition. May 8, 1893. W.H. Pritchard,
Judge." That the said W. H. Pritchard was, at that time one of
the duly elected and qualified and acting judges of the Superior
Court of the State of washington, for the County of Pierce, said
cause being number 9689 as appears by the record and files of 
said Superior Court of the State of Washington, for the county of
Pierce; and that thereupon the clerk of said court did, under the
seal of said court, issue said writ of habeas corpus and warrant to
for the arrest of said Moy Nah as prayed for in said petition, and
under said writ the sheriff did proceed to the steamboat wharf
and to the steamer Victoris, and ask for the said Moy Wah who was
called for by the captain of said steamer, and without any fur-
ther orders and without any protest, ordered the said Moy Wah to
go ashore, which said Moy Wah did then and thereupon do, without
any protest or resistance or proceedings of any kind of rep-</p>

<pb/>

<p>resentative whatsoever of the United States of America; and that
the said captain did thereafter appear before the said Superior
Court and make and file his written answer to said writ of habeas
corpus, and that then and is thereupon, and upon the filing of said
answer, the said petitioner Moy Wah by his counsel demurred there
to, which demurrer was by the court sustained and after hearing
the respective counsel and arguments of same, the said <add>Moy Wah</add> was then
and thereupon by said court, in the presence of the officers of the
government discharged by the said Superior Court which he wasbe-
fore, all of which proceedings, including the said petition, or-
der of said court, writ of habeas corpus, warrant of arrest and
return of the officers upon it andsaid process, answer of the said
captain, the ruling and order of the court and record of the pro-
ceedings of the respective parties, appears of record in the rec-
ords of the Superior Court of the State of washington for the
County of Pierce in cause number 9689 as given, made and filed
therein.</p>

<p>That immediately upon the discharge of said Moy Wah as afore-
said he was then and thereupon arrested charged with being ille-
gally in the United States of America, and was taken before Honor-
able Miles E. Clifford, Court Commissioner of theCircuit Court
of the United States at Tacoma, who proceeded to inquire into said
cause, and did refuse to allow said petitioner to be turned over
to the United States marshall to be returned to said steamer Vic-
toria, which was still at the wharf at Tacoma and ordered that
said petitioner be held and returned by the United States marshall
for a hearing before him, which hearing was fixed for the 17th day
of May, 1893 at 10 o'clock in the forenoon, at which hearing evi-
dence was introduced for the respective parties and your said 
petitioner was by said Commissioner ordered deported, from which or-
der, judgment and ruling, with the consent of the United States
attorney waiving all forms and regularities of giving notice, an</p>

<pb/>

<p>appeal was taken to this Honorable Court, and upon the question of
jurisdiction of the United States Commissioner being, by the United
States Attorney raised, this Honorable Court did, on the 5th day
of June, 1893, order that your said petitioner be turned over to
and placed in custody of the United States marshal J. C. Drake,
who proceeded and took your said petitioner in possession, and
now forcibly, knowingly, unlawfully, without just cause is now
holding, detaining and retaining and keeping in confinement your
said petitioner, although he has demanded his liberty, refused to
recognize said demands, and still continues to hold, retain, de-
tain and deprive this petitioner, of his liberty, and your peti-
tioner states that he can, if allowed a hearing before this Hon-
orable Court, show that he has fully and completely complied with
all the laws of the United States and the rules and regulations
thereof, and regardless of said compliance, the Collector of Cus-
toms did wilfully, knowingly, arbitrarily, unjustly and unlawful-
ly, and without any cause, right or authority, refuse to admit
your petitioner and allow him to land, and that your said peti-
tioner is rightfully and justly entitled to land andbe and remain in
the United States and go his way to his former residence as here-
tofore stated and resume his business at the city of Portland.</p>

<p>Your petitioner further states that he is at this time im-
prisoned at the United States penitentiary at McNeil's Island, in
Pierce County, Washington, and within the jurisdiction of this 
court; that he is not detained by virtue of any order or process
issued by the United States Court, nor by virtue of any execution
or any other process, judgment, decree or final order of any <unclear>state</unclear>
court or other court other than herein stated as aforesaid: and
that he is not held for the violation of any law; rule or regula
tion or in punishment for any crime by him committed.</p>

<p>Petitioner further states that he is advised by Marshall K.
Snell, his counsel, who resides at Tacoma, Pierce County, Wash-
ington, and who is a counsellor of this court, having and holding
a certificate authorizing him to practice in and before this court, 
that such imprisonment is illegal for the reason and facts as
herein set forth, and that under andby virtue of the laws of the
United States a writ of habeas Corpus directed to the said United
States marshal should be issued by this Honorable Court to bring
before it your petitioner.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner ever prays and hereby applies for
a Writ of Habeas Corpus for the purpose of an inquiry into the
cause of such imprisonment and restraint, and delivering him threr-
from and discharging him from custody.</p>

<p>Dates this 6th day of June, 1893</p>

<p>Moy Wah (Chinese Signature)</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>

<pb/>

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, FOR THE DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, WESTERN DIVISION</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of
<gap></gap> for a Writ of
Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Moy Wah (Chinese signature) being first duly sworn on his oath deposes
and says:-</p>

<p>That I am the petitioner named in the foregoing petition;
that I have heard the same read and interpreted to me and know
the contents thereof; that all matters therein stated other than
the proceedings in court as therein recited, are to my personal
knowledge true, and as to those matters I verily believe them to
be be true, which matters referred to as stated upon information
and belief, are the proceedings in court had and referred to
in said petition.</p>

<p>Moy Wah (Chinese signature)</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me 
this 6th day of June, 1893</p>

<p><unclear>Charles</unclear> A <unclear>Murray</unclear></p>

<p>Notary Public in and for Pierce County,
Residing at Tacoma, Washington.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>