<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0365.019">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John Matthews v. Henry M. White. correspondents</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0365.019</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">John Matthews v. Henry M. White. correspondents</title>
<date when="1921-07">July 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-07">July 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Matthews, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>US DEPARTMENT OF LABOR
US EMPLOYMENT SERVICE
WASHINGTON</p>

<p>84904/149                       July 14, 1921</p>

<p>Mr. George F. Vanderveer,
c/o Seattle Central Labor Council,
405 Collins Building
Seattle, Washington.</p>

<p>Sir:</p>

<p>I beg to acknowledge the receipt of your letter of the 9th
instant, having relation to the case of Jack Matthews, an alien who
is now held in the United States Penitentiary at McNeil's Island,
Washington, and who has been ordered to e deported to Roumania, the
country of his nativity at the conclusion of his sentence. You advise
that Mr. Matthews first came to the United States in 1911, resided
here for nine years, then went to Canada and later to Alaska, where he
committed the offense for which he is now serving a prison term. You
also call attention to the difficulties which are likely to be encountered
in endeavoring to deport Matthews at the present time, particularly
in view of the passport requirements, and state that alien appears
to be a hard working man who would eventually develop into a good
citizen if given a proper opportunity.</p>

<p>The case of this alien was very carefully considered by the
Department before it directed that he be deported, and inasmuch as the
evidence in his case appears to be such as to quite clearly bring him
within the deportation provisions of the act, it seemingly will be
necessary to effect his deportation immediately that he is released from the
institution provided, of course, a passport for him can be obtained and
arrangments can be made for his ocean voyage and his passage from the
port of deportation into Roumania. If these arrangements can not be
made, consideration will, of course, be given to the matter of his
temporary release, as the Bureau would not like to see him held under custody
after his sentence has expired for no purpose other than that he might
be deported.</p>

<p>Respectfully,</p>

<p>Commissioner General.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>LEGAL BUREAU</p>

<p>SEATTLE CENTRAL LABOR COUNCIL
"ONE FOR ALL AND ALL FOR ONE"
SEATTLE, WASH.</p>

<p>July 2, 1921</p>

<p>U.S. Department of Labor,
Bureau of Immigration,
Washington,
D.C.</p>

<p>Gentlemen:</p>

<p>I am writing this with a request that Jack Matthews
whose deportation File Number is 54904-149, be release on
his personal recognizance until such time as the Department
is able to secure passport to Ukrania and execute the warrant
of deportation heretofore made.</p>

<p>Matthews was convicted in 1920 of sending obscene
matter thru the U.S. mail and sentenced to the United States
penintentiary at McNeil's Island for the term of one year.
The circumstances surrounding the offense are more or less
immaterial to the present question; Mathews is a laboring
man with an excellent reputation and many fine letters of
recommendation. He is is not in any sense depraved and I
am lead to believe that the sending of these obscene picture
which resulted in his conviction was the result of pure
thoughtlessness on his part. We have investigated the man
and his part record quite thoroly and satisfied of
his trustworthiness. In fact, this Bureau is willing in
behalf of organized labor of which Matthews is a member,
to assume the full moral responsibility for his appearance
at any time you may require.</p>

<p>Matthews was ordered deported in February,
1919 while still imprisoned at McNeil's Island. He
was released from there on April 4th, 1921, and for nearly
three months has been held a prisoner in the County Jail
in this county awaiting execution of the deportation warrant.
We are informed by the local immigration inspectors that
this delay is occassioned by your inability to secure passports
to Ukrania; and are led to believe that is is altogether
uncertain when, if ever, you may be able to do this.
</p>
<p>Under these circumstances. it seems to me that
Matthews should be released on his own recognizance until the
present situation clears up, and I hope you will make an
order permitting this and advise the local Commissioner.</p>

<p>Yours very truly,
Geo. F. Vanverveer.</p>

               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>