<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0187.018">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
    <title>Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0187.018</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
    <title level="m" type="main">Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal</title>
<date when="1914">1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-07">July 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
<term></term>
<term>Fishburne, George P.</term>
<term>Grayson, Marie Robina</term>
<term>Grayson, William</term>
<term>Neterer, Jeremiah</term>
<term>Shakespeare, Noah</term>



</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Nome, Alaska</term>
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
<term>Bretagne, France</term>
<term>New York</term>
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
<term></term>

</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Marie Robina Grayson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Noah Shakespeare</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>George P. Fishburne</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
    <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN RE MARIE ROBINA GRAYSON,
alias Marie Robina, for 
WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS, 
Petitioner. )
No. 2780.
Filed July 17, 1914</p>
<p>Fronts</p>

<p>ON PETITION FOR WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS. 
PETITION GRANTED.</p>
<p>Noah Shakespeare, Everett, Wash. For petitioner</p>
<p>George P. Fishburne, Asst. U. S. Atty. For United States</p>
<p>NETERER, District Judge.</p>
<p>On January 23, 1914, the acting Secretary of Labor
ordered the petitioner, who was born at Tridon, Bretagne, 
France, and who landed at the port of New York in 1903, to 
be deported for being in the United States in violation of 
the Act of Congress approved February 20, 1907, and amendments
thereto, in that the petitioner "is a prostitute and 
has been found practicing prostitution subsequent to her 
entry into the United States". The petitioner thereupon 
applied to this court for a writ of habeas corpus, on the 
grounds:</p>
<p>(a) That the petitioner is now, and at all times 
since the first day of April, 1912, has been, a citizen of 
the United States, she having on that date been united in
lawful wedlock to William Grayson, a native born citizen of 
the United States, and that the Department is without 
jurisdiction to order deportation, and,</p>
<p>(b) That she "was denied a fair and impartial 
hearing.:</p>
<p>It was admitted upon the hearing that William Grayson 
is a native born citizen of the United States, and that on 
the 1st day of April, 1912, he was united in lawful wedlock 
with the petitioner, in the City of Portland, Oregon.</p>
<fw>--1--</fw>
<pb/>
<p>It is alleged in the answer of the Commissioner of 
Immigration that "a warrant was issued for the petitioner, 
and she was arrested on the 14th of March, 1912, on a charge
of having been found practicing prostitution; that testimony
was taken in case on March 27, 1912, and she was on the 
same day released on bond; that she was married April 1, 1912,
to the best knowledge, opinion and belief of the respondent,
to prevent being deported; that at the time of her marriage
to the said William Grayson, she was aprostitute adn was practicing
prostitution; that she was still out on bond when she 
was married, and was not released until the 9th day of April, 
1912; that she has never been formally admitted to the United
States, and never has been naturalized, and that she should
be deported as ordered by the Secretary of Labor, afer a due 
hearing".</p>
<p>The testimony taken before the Commissioner of 
Immigration shows that the petitioner was accorded a fair and 
impartial hearing, and further shows that the petitioner has 
been practicing prostitution for nine years last past, except
during the time she lived with her husband and for one month 
prior to her marriage, in various cities, from Nome, Alaska, 
to San Francisco, and as far east as Salt Lake and that she 
met William Grayson, her husband, in a sporting house in 
Portland, Oregon. She lived with him "nearly seven months" after 
marriage, and upon her husband leaving her, she says, "I
went back rustling again". There is not evidence, either 
before this court or in the record, that the petitioner was 
a prostitute on entering the United States, or that she 
came for the purpose of practicing prostitution. The petitioner
contends that since the dawn of civilization the domicile
and citizenship of the wife became merged in that of the 
<fw>--2--</fw>
<pb/>
husband, and that such status was recognized by the common
law of England prior to George III, and became part of the 
fundamental law of the United States, and a definite and 
fixed status by congressional enactment under Section 1994, 
Revised Statutes of the United States, which provides that,</p>
<p>"Any woman who is now or may hereafter be married
to a citizen of the United States, and who might herself
be lawfully naturalized, shall be deemed a citizen".</p>
<p>By this provision, the very act of marriage, it is contended, 
confers citizenship as fully to all intents and purposes as 
could be done by decress of naturalization. The respondent
asserts that the language, "who might herself be lawfully
naturalized", excludes the petitioner from acquiring the 
franchise of citizenship, because Section 2 of the Act of 
1907, as amended, excludes "prostitutes or women or girls 
coming into the United States for the purpose of prostitution, 
or for any other immoral purpose", and Section 3, provides
that, "Any alien who shall be found *****practicing prostitution
after such alien shall have been in the United States******
shall be deported********". And the petitioner being a 
prostitute could not be lawfully naturalized.</p>
<p>That the husband of the petitioner is and was a 
citizen of the United States, and that the petitioner was 
lawfully married to him, is conceded. That such marriage was 
recognized by the Department of Labor imediately after her 
marriage, following her former arrest, by releasing her from 
such arrest on a similar charge, appears in the record. It 
has been held by the District Court in this Circuit, Leonard 
vs. Grant, 5 Fed. 11, that the clause, "might herself be 
lawfully naturalized", applies to the race or class or nationality
of persons who are excluded from citizenship in the 
United States, and not to the personal qualification of the 
individual whose class or race is not excluded, and does not
apply to the character of the individual. The Circuit Court of 
Appeals in this Circuit, in Hopkins vs. Fachant, appealed from 
<fw>--3--</fw>
<pb/>
this District, 130 Fed. 839, 843, says:</p>
<p>"The ruling is well settled that her marriage
to a naturalized citizen of the United States 
entitled her to be discharged. The status of the 
wife follows that of her husbnad--Rev. Stat., Sec.
1994; U. S. Comp. St. 1901, page 1268; Leonard v. 
Grant, C. C., 5 Fed. 11; Kelly v. Owen, 7 Wallace, 
496; U. S. v. Keller, C. C., 13 Fed. 82; Ware v. 
Wisnor, C. C., 50 Fed. 310; Broadis v. Broadis, C. 
C., 86 Fed. 951".</p>
<p>By the provisions of Section 1994, supra, citizenship
acquired is not a qualified or contingent one, but, until 
revoked by a court of competent jurisdiction, is as enduring
and unqualified as if she had been actually naturalized upon 
her own formal application--Leonard v. Grant, supra; U. S.
v. Keller, 13 Fed. 82. Citizenship is a valuable right and 
the most distinguished and honorable franchise which can be 
conferred by the Government of the United States, and when 
acquired, cannot be taken away without due process of law. 
Under the Constitution of Washington and the constitutions
of some of the other States, the right to own real estate
depends upon citizenship. If perchance, the petitioner 
acquired real estate by purchase in the State of Washington, 
after marriage and discharge from the former arrest because 
of her citizenship, such real estate, on deportation, because 
she is not a citizen of the United States, would become the 
subject of forfeiture by the State of Washington, and she 
therefore deprived of property acquired in reliance upon 
Section 1994 supra, and the former holding of the Department.
If the marriage of the petitioner was conceived in fraud, as
contended by the respondent, and executed for the purpose of 
evading the immigration laws of the United States and preventing
her deportation, such fact, from the history of this case
disclosed in the record, should be established in a court of 
competent jurisdiction, in an action commenced for the purpose, 
where she would be accorded the right of compulsory process
for the attendance of witnesses, and her right to remain be 
determined consistent with principles that inhere in due 
<fw>--4--</fw>
<pb/>
</p>












</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>