<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0366.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Copy of Amended Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0366.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Copy of Amended Petition</title>
<date when="1921-08-18">August 18, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-08">August 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Murray, George H. L.</term>
<term>Chard, Thomas Walter</term>
<term>McEchen, A. J. G.</term>
<term>McEwan, Frederick A.</term>
<term>Vigors, Henry James</term>
<term>Robinson, Cassius M. Clay</term>
<term>Robinson, Charles Burdette</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Britain</term>
<term>Ireland</term>
<term>Saskatchewan, Canada</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Decker, Fletcher</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, Adam</persName>
<persName>Sullivan</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-07" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Copy of Amended Petition</p>

<p>United States of America</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>ss.</p>

<p>George H. L. Murray being first duly sworn, on his oath deposes and says:</p>

<p>That he makes this complaint for the purpose of procuring the extradition from the Northern Division of the Western District of Washington to the Province of Saskatchewan in the Dominion of Canada, one of the Provinces of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, ruled by His Majesty, George the V, its king, of one FLETCHER DECKER, pursuant to the terms of Sas. 5270 of the Revied Statutes of the United States, as <unclear>amended</unclear> by an act of Congress approved June 6, 1900, entitled An Act amending action 5270 of the Revised Statutes of the United States," and the extradition convention between the United States of America and the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, proclaimed by the Precident of the United States on the 25th day of March, 1890, supplementary to the Tenth Article of the Treaty concluded between the same high contracting parties on the 9th day of August, <unclear>1813</unclear>.</p>

<p>Affiant further says that in the Province of Saskatchewan aforesaid, in the Dominion of Canada aforesaid, on the 15th day of November, A. D. 1915, near Wiwa Hill Post Office in said Province, he, the said Fletcher Decker, then and there being, did then and there take, steal and carry away about three hundred (300) bushals of flax, the property of one Claude Ficklin, of the value of Four Hundred Seventy-five Dollars ($475.00), with the intent then and there to commit an indictable offence, to-wit, the crime of theft, contrary to the Criminal <unclear>Code</unclear> of Canada.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Affiant further says, that at the time aforesaid, to-wit, on the 15th day of November, A. D. 1915, it was and now is provided by the said Criminal Code of Canada in and by Sec. 347 of said Criminal Code of Canada, the same then and now being in force in said Province of Saskatchewan, and in the Dominion of Canada aforesaid, as follows, to-wit: That</p>

<p>"347. Theft or stealing is the act of fraudulently and without colour of right taking, or fraudulently and without colour of right converting to the use of any person, anything capable of being stolen, with intent,-</p>

<p>(a) to deprive the owner, or any person having any special property or interest therein, temporarily or absolutely of such thing or of such property or interest; or,</p>

<p>(b) to pledge the same or deposit it as security; or,</p>

<p>(c) to part with it under a condition as to its return which the person parting with it may be unable to perform; or,</p>

<p>(d) to deal with it in such a manner that it cannot be restored in the condition in which it was at the time of such taking and conversion.</p>

<p>2. Theft is committed when the offender moves the thing or causes it to move or to be moved, or begins to cause it to become movable, with intent to steal it.</p>

<p>3. The taking or converstion may be fraudulent, although effected without secrecy or attempt at concealment.</p>

<p>4. It is immaterial whether the thing converted was taken for the purpose of conversion, or whether it was, at the time of the conversion, in the lawful possession of the person converting."</p>

<p>Affiant further says, that by the law of said Dominion of Canada now in force and in force on said 15th day of November, A. D. 1915, it is provided that the offence of theft and the offence of stealing are indictable offences in and by section 335 of the said Criminal Code of Canada.</p>

<p>-2-</p>

<pb/>

<p>Affiant further says, that by the law of said Dominion of Canada now in force and in force on said 15th day of November, A. D. 1915, it is provided in and by section 683 of the said Criminal Code of the Dominion of Canada, as follows:</p>

<p>"683. Every justice holding a preliminary inquiry shall cause the depositions to be written in a legible hand and on one side only of each sheet of paper on which they are written: Provided that the evidence upon such inquiry or any part of the same may be taken in shorthand by a stenographer who may be appointed by the justice and who before acting shall, unless he is a duly sworn official court stenographer, make oath that he shall truly and faithfully report the evidence.</p>

<p>2. Where evidence is so taken, it shall not be necessary that such evidence be read over to or signed by the witness, but it shall be sufficient if the transcripts be signed by the justice and be accompanied by an affidavit of the stenographer, or if the stenographer is a duly sworn court stenographer by the stenographer's certificate that it is a true report of the evidence."</p>

<p>Affiant further says that on the 14th day of June, A. D. 1921, at Regina in said Province of Saskatchewan, in the Dominion of Canada aforesaid, one Thomas Walter Chard, of Regina, in the Province of Saskatchewan, made oath in writing before one A. J. G. MacEchen, as a Justice of the Peace in and for said Province of Saskatchewan, he, the said A. J. G. MacEchen, then being Justice of the Peace as aforesaid, of the substance, tenor and effect following, that is to say,</p>

<p>That</p>

<p>"Information and Complaint</p>

<p>CANADA</p>

<p>Province of Saskatchewan</p>

<p>THE INFORMATION AND COMPLAINT of Thomas Walter Chard, of Regina, in the Province of Saskatchewan, taken this 14th day of June, in the year 1921, before the undersigned</p>

<p>-3-</p>

<pb/>

<p>A. J. G. MacEchen, one of his Majesty's Justice of the <unclear>Peace</unclear> in and fore the said Province, who <unclear>saith</unclear> that Fletcher Decker formerly of near Wiwa Hill Post Office, in said Province, on or about the 15th day of November, A. D. 1915, near Wiwa Hill Post Office, aforesaid, in the said Province did steal about Three Hundred (300) buchels of flax the property of Claude Ficklin and was thereby guilty of theft.</p>

<p>(Signature of Informant) (Signed) T. W. Chard.</p>

<p>SWORN before me the day and year first above mentioned, at Regina is the said Province.</p>

<p>(Signed) A. J. G. MacEchen.</p>

<p>A Justice of the Peace in and fore the Province of Saskatchewan."</p>

<p>and thereafter on the same day, the said Justice of the Peace did issue a warrant in the words, letters and figures following, to-wit:</p>

<p>"WARRANT TO APPREHEND</p>

<p>CANADA</p>

<p>Province of Saskatchewan</p>

<p>To all or any of the Peace Officers in the said Province:</p>

<p>WHEREAS Fletcher Decker formerly of near Wiwa Hill Post Office, in the said Province, has this day been charged upon oath before the undersigned A. J. G. MacEchen, a Justice of the Peace in and for the said Province, for that he, on or about the 15th day of November A. D. 1915, near Wiwa Hill Post Office, aforesaid, in the said Province, did steal about Three Hundred (300) buschels of flax the property of Claude Ficklin and was thereby guilty of theft.</p>

<p>THESE ARE THEREFORE TO COMMAND YOU, in His Majesty's name forthwith to apprehend the said Fletcher Decker and to bring him before no, or come other Justice of the Peace in and for the said Province, to answer the said charge and to be further dealt with according to law.</p>

<p>GIVEN under my hand and seal this 14th day of June A.D. 1921, at Regina, in the Province aforesaid.</p>

<p>(Signed) A. J. G. MacEchen (Seal) A Justice of the Peace in and for the Province of Saskatchewan."</p>

<p>-4-</p>

<pb/>

<p>Affiant further says that thereafter the following named persons, to-wit: Frederick A. McEwan, Wm. James Henry Vigors, Cassius M. Clay Robinson, and Charles Burdette Robinson, each being first duly sworn by and before said Justice of the Peace, on their several oaths did depose and testify as set forth in the paper hereto attached, marked exhibit "A" hereto and made a part hereof, the testimony and deposition of each of said persons therein appearing under his name, and that said depositions and testimony were taken on oath before him, the said A. J. G. MacEchen, Justice of the Peace aforesaid, and the said testimony and depositions were each signed by the said witnesses and the said Justice of the Peace did thereafter upon hearing said testimony declare that the offense with which the said Fletcher Decker was and is charged is the crime of theft as defined by the criminal code of Canada as hereinbefore fully set forth, and that under the law now in force in the Province of Saskatchewan and in force there during the nine years last past and more, a Justice of the Peace in and for the Province of Saskatchewan has power to receive a complaint or information charging a person with theft and with having committed any criminal offence known to the law, and he has also the power to issue a warrant, for the apprehension of the person charged with the criminal offense, and to hear the evidence of witnesses, and otherwise to hold a preliminary inquiry respecting the commission of a criminal offense, and at the conclusion of the examination amongst other powers to remand the accused to prison to be further dealt with according to law, and the disposition made by said Justice of the Peace is more fully set forth in the warrant to apprehend hereinbefore set forth.</p>

<p>The affiant is a British Vice Consul located in the</p>

<p>5</p>

<pb/>

<p>city of Seattle, King county, Washington, and makes this complaint on behalf of His Majest George V King of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, affiant prays that a warrant for the apprehension of the said Fletcher Decker may issue, and that he be brought before a United States Commissioner to the end that the evidenceof the criminality aforesaid may be heard and considered, and that if upon such hearing such commissioner shall deem the evidence sufficient to sustain the charge under the provisions of said convention, that he shall then certify the same, together with a copy of all the testimony taken before him, to the Secretary of State of the United States, that a warrant may issue upon the requisition of the proper authorities of the said Dominion of Canada for the surrender of him, the said Fletcher Decker, according to the stipulations of said convention, and that such Commissioner shall issue his warrant for the commitment of him the said Fletcher Decker, to the proper jail, thereto remain until such surrender shall be made.</p>

<p>George <unclear></unclear> Murray</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 18th day of August, 1921.</p>

<p><unclear>R</unclear> <unclear>M</unclear> McClelland</p>
<p>United States Commissioner.</p>

<p>LET WARRANT ISSUE</p>
<p>Robt C Saunders US Atty</p>
<p>By Charlotte M Kolmitz</p>
<p>Assistant United States Attorney.</p>

<p>Filed August 18th - 1921</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>