<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0224.017">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Lewis Johnson v. John M Boyle, United States Marshal. Return.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0224.017</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Lewis Johnson v. John M Boyle, United States Marshal. Return.</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-07">June 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Lewis Johnson</term> 
<term>George R. Tennant</term> 
<term>Hammond</term>
<term>John M. Boyle</term> 
<term>John C. Whitlock</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Lewis Johnson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>John M. Boyle</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Hammond and Hammond</persName> 
<persName>George R. Tennant</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Winter S. Martin</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court, For the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-03" who="#AS">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<pb></pb> 
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT, FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p> 
<p>In the Matter of the Application of
LEWIS JOHNSON, for a WRIT OF 
HABEAS CORPUS.</p> 
<p>3077
No. PETITION FOR WRIT OF 
HABEAS CORPUS.</p> 
<p>TO THE HONORABLE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, 
FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION:</p> 
<p>Your petitioner, Lewis Johnson, respectively represents
and shows to this Honorable Court that he is a citizen of the
United States and a resident of the City of Seattle, King County,
State of Washington.</p> 
<p>That at the present time, and since the day of <gap></gap> June,
A.D.1915, he is, and has been wrongfully and unlawfully detained
and imprisoned in the County jail of King County, Washington, by
John M. Boyle, United States Marshal for the Western District of
Washington, Northern Division:</p> 
<p>That according to your petitioner's information and belief
the cause of his detention is that on or about the <gap></gap> day of
June, A.D.1915, a complaint was filed before the Honorable John C.
Whitlock, United States Commissioner for the Western District of
Washington, Northern Division, whereby your petitioner was charged
with the crime of theft, alleged to have been committed in the
Dominion of Canada, which said charge was without probable cause,
and is and was untrue; and, that thereafter, the said John C. Whit-
lock, United States Commissioner aforesaid, ordered and directed
that said petitioner be held to answer said charge, and held and de-
tained, subject to the order of the authorities of the Dominion of
Canada, a Province of Great Britain, and to be deported thereto</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>to answer said charge so wrongfully and illegally made, which said
order and proceedings and all matters connected therewith are irre-
gular, illegal, and void.</p>
<p>Petitioner further shows to this Honorable Court that the
hearing before said Commissioner, John C. Whitlock, was without
authority; that the same was irregular and illegal; that no legal
evidence of any kind whatever was presented or submitted to the said
Commissioner, John C. Whitlock, upon which the sald Commissioner
could have based his order for the arrest and detention of said
petitioner, and that there was no probable cause for the filing of
said information, or the making of said order.</p> 
<p>WHEREFORE, to be relieved of said unlawful detention and
imprisonment, your petitioner prays that a Writ of Habeas Corpus, to
be directed to the said John M. Boyle, United States Marshal for the
Western District of Washington, Northern Division,aroresaid, may
issue in this behalf, so that your petitioner may be forthwith brought
before this Honorable Court to submit to and receive what the law
may direct, and that an order may issue herein directed to the said
John C. Whitlock, United States Commissioner, aforesaid, directing the
said John C. Whitlock, aforesaid, to certify to this Court a true
copy of all proceedings had and done before the said John C. Whitlock,
in connection with the arrest and imprisonment of your petitioner
herein, together with all papers, exhibits and other records in con-
nection with said matter.</p> 
<p>Lewis Johnson 
PETITIONER.</p>
<p>George R. Tennant</p> 
<p>Hammond &amp; Hammond
Attorneys for Petitioner.</p>
</div1> 
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>