<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE SUPREME COURT OF THE UNITES STATES.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE UNLAWFUL 
DENTENTION OF SEVENTY-THREE
HINDOO ALIENS.</p>
<p>No. 2532 
ASSIGNMENT OF ERROR</p>
<p>Come now the petitioning aliens and file the following
assignment of errors on which they will rely in the prosecution
of their appeal in the above entitled cause to the Supreme Court
of the United States from the District Court of the Western Dis-
trict of Washington.</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to grant the writ of
habeas corpus.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>The court erred in holding the decision of the
immigration department final, and that the court would not inter-
fere to see justice done where injustice was alleged, as the
allegation was made that there was no evidence and that the con-
struction of a statute was involved and a legal matter was at
issue as to the construction of Section 20, and in holding the
immigration decision final and in refusing to examine the evi-
dence for the purpose of testing the correctness of petitioners'
<pb></pb>
allegations</p>
<p>III.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to find that the
petitioners had been deprived of their constitutional rights
under Articles 5, 6, 8, and 14 of the amendments of the
Constitution of the United States.</p>
<p>IV.</p>
<p>The court erred in not holding that the examination 
at Seattle, Washington, after a due and proper exami-
nation by the immigration authorities at Manila, after resi-
dence in the Philippine Islands for several years, was not
an improper examination and an abuse of authority and discre-
tion.</p>
<p>V.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to hold that the exami-
nation and admission at Manila, a regular port of entry,
was not final and sufficient.</p>
<p>VI.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to find that the warrant
of arrest on authority of which the aliens were threatened
with deportation, was not faulty and contrary to law and not a
sufficient warrant on which to deport the aliens under author-
ity of the Act of February 20, 1907, and Section 20 thereof.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>VII.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to find that the
examination was not fair and impartial and in refusing
and failing to find that the immigration authorities
went outside of the law and acted contrary to law in
issuing the warrant and in threatening to deport.</p>
<p>VIII.</p>
<p>That the court erred in refusing to find and
failing to find that the immigration department violated
the Act of February 20, 1907, and particularly Section
20 thereof, in that no evidence was ever produced show-
ing that the aliens came within the confines or within
the provisions of said law.</p>
<p>IX.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to find that the
aliens had never violated any of the provisions of the
said Act of February, 20, 1907, and refusing to fina
that the immigration department officials transcended the
bound of their authority in holding that the aliens had
violated the provisions of the Act and came within the
provisions thereof.</p>
<p>X.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the de-
cision of the immigration department and the issuing of
the warrants was all contrary to law and in direct violation
of the Act of February 20, 1907.</p>
<p>XI</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>