<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p> To the Hon Henry Dusenbury 
<del> Judge </del> Law Com. of the St Louis County </p>

<p> Exparte 
John Jones 
otherwise call-
ed John Cook } </p>

<p> State of Missouri, Saint Louis County, 
and City of Saint Louis, Law Comm-
issioners Court. now in session. 
The petitioner states that he is a free 
collored man, that he was born in 
the state of Pennsylvania, and the has 
always resided in said state, until on 
or about the seventh day of June 1857, 
when he came to said City of Saint 
Louis and was, on said day arrested 
and committed to the County Jail 
of said County, and from there <unclear> hitheato </unclear> 
has been, and still is, imprisoned and 
detained in said Jail by Robert T Spogan, 
the keeper of said Jail, on a charge of 
being a run away slave, by virtue 
of a warrant of commitment issued by 
Berf Herkenrath Esqre a Justice of 
the Peace for said City and County 
of Saint Louis, a copy of which was 
<unclear></unclear> of Commitment is not herewith 
filed, because a copy of the same has 
been demanded of the said Logan the 
person by whom said petitioner is imp-
risoned as aforesaid and a copy of said 
warrant refused. </p>

<p> And the petitioner further states that 
he is unlawfully and wrongfully 
imprisoned as aforesaid, because he 
says that he is and always has been, 
by law a free man, and is not, 
and never has been by law a slave; which he is ready to verify. Wherfore the said John Jones otherwise called

John Cook, prays <sic> said said </sic> Court to issue a writ of Habeas Corpus, and cause <strike> the </strike> him to be brought before said Court and discharged from his said imprisonment by due course of law </p>

<p> And by way of Amendment to the foregoing petition, the petitioner states the Hon. Henry A Cloves the Judge of the Saint Louis County Circuit Court is absent from said County. </p>

<p> Dated at Louis the 24th day of Dec 1857 </p>
<p> John Jones otherwise called John Cook per J.R. Meraiams his attorney </p>

<p> Subscribed &amp; sworn to before me this 24h <strike> 185 </strike> Dec 1857 </p>
<p> W. Montfoat </p>