<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0183.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Gwoo Shee Ah Look v. United States. Affidavit.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0183.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Gwoo Shee Ah Look v. United States. Affadvit.</title>
<date when="1914-04-14">April 14, 1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2647GwooSheeAhLook</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-04">April 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Lakin, Edward M.</term>
<term>Clark, A. L.</term>
<term>Barbour, J. H.</term>
<term>Harms, L. A. </term>
<term>Wise, J. M.</term>
<term>Van Name, Ruth</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Multnomah County, Oregon</term>
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Look, Gwoo Shee Ah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Frye, Jesse A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wilbur</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Spencer</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, George P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Bean, R. S.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>


</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>Affidavit.</p>
<p>United States of America,
State of Oregon,
County of Multnomah.} ss. 2647</p>
<p>I, A.L. Clark, being first duly sworn according to law,
depose and day that I am a regular practicing attorney and connected
with the law firm of Wilbur &amp; Spencer in the City of Portland, State
of Oregon; that on the 5th day of November, 1913, the firm of Wilbur
&amp; Spencer in connection with this affiant was employed as attorneys
to defend and look after the interests of Gwoo Shee Ah Look, who
was arrested in a raid made by the police of the City of Portland,
on the night of the 4th of November, 1913; that thereafter I immediately
went to the said City Jail where I found J.H. Brbour, Inspector
of Immigration, who at that time was conducting an investigation 
and examination of certain Chinese persons including
Gwoo Shee Ah Look arrested the night previous; that thereafter within
a day or two the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look on the authority of the
said J.H. Barbour was removed to the County Jail where she was
confined on the charge placed against her named in the petition for
writ of habeas corpus; that white the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look was
confined in the County Jail and before her testimony had been taken
and before the testimony of other witnesses in said matter had been
taken this affiant informed said J.H. Barbour that he together with
the firm of Wilbur &amp; Spencer represented said Gwoo Shee Ah Look and
requested permission to consult and visit her in the County Jail,
which permission was refused.</p>
<p>I further depose and say that I thereafter and before said 
hearing had been had I requested the said J.H. Barbour for the
privilege of being present for the purpose of cross examination of
witnesses whose testimony might be taken; that the said J.H. Barbour
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer 
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
knew and stated to me that he would place my name as the attorney 
for the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look and that I would be advised of any
proceedings had at the proper time.</p>
<p>I further depose and say that the said J.H. Barbour, as
such Immigration Officer, thereafter took the testimony of the said
Gwoo Shee Ah Look and took the testimony of the said L.A. Harms
and J.M. Wise, the two police officers, without the presence of
the attorneys of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look or without their knowledge
that such examination and testimony was being taken; that 
after the conclusion of the taking of said testimony said J.H.
Barbour prsented to me a transcript of the testimony with the
statement that such testimony by way of affidavits as might be
thought useful could then be presented to him and that he would
attach the same to his record and forward the same to the Secretary 
of Commerce and Labor.</p>
<p>This affiant further says that although the said J.H. Barbour
well knew before the taking of the testimony of said witnesses
that this affiant together with the firm of Wilbur &amp; Spencer had
been employed to defend said Gwoo Shee Ah Look and had requested the
right and privilege of being present at the examination; that they
were not given the right nor advised of said hearing nor allowed
to be present at the time of said testimony.</p>
<p>Further affiant sayeth nothing.</p>
<ab>A. L. Clark</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 24th day of April, 1914.</p>
<ab>Ruth Van Name
Notary Public, State of Oregon.</ab>
<figure><ab>Ruth Van Name
Notary Public
State of Oregon</ab></figure>
<figure><ab>Wibur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-at-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<pb/>
<p>United States of America,
District of Oregon } ss.</p>
<p>Due and timely service of the within Affidavit and the
receipt of a duly certified copy thereof, all at the City of Seattle in the Northern District
of Washington is hereby admitted.</p>
<ab>G.P. Fishburne
Attorney for Respondent</ab>
<pb/>
<ab>No. 2647</ab>
<p>In the District Court of the
United States for the 
District of <del>Oregon</del>
<add>Wash</add></p>
<p>In the Matter of
the Amended Application
for a 
Writ of Habeas 
Corpus for Gwoo
Shee Ah Look.</p>
<p>Affidavit 
of
A.L. Clark</p>
<p>Filed <gap reason="blank"/> 191<gap reason="blank"/>
by <gap reason="blank"/> Deputy</p>
<p>2x
Filed in the 
U.S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington,
APR 27 1914
Frank L. Crosby
by EML Deputy.</p>
<p>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
A.L. Clark
Attorneys for Petitioner</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>