<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In the District Court of Washington Territory and for the
Fourth Judicial District thereof holding terms at the
county seat of Spokane County.</p>

<p>The Territory of Washington
vs.
Ray Raymond} Motion to <unclear>quash</unclear></p>

<p>Now comes the defendant and
moved the court to quash and set aside the
indictment returned into court by the Grand
Jury on the 20th day of March 1887 on the
grounds following to wit:</p>

<p>1.-That it is not entitled in this
court or in a court appearing to have
jurisdiction to receive it.</p>

<p>2.- That it is not entitled in
the cause in this that the peace of holding
court and the move of the court is not forth.</p>

<p>3.- The Grand jury finding the
indictment in above entitled cause was
not selected drawn or empannelled as requested
by law in this: That the list of said Grand
Jurors was drawn from an imperfect and
incomplete list of persons in Spokane 
County qualified to serve as Grand Jurors and
the list of names prepared by the County Commissioners 
from which said list was drawn
did not contain the names of all of the 
persons in Spokane County qualified to serve

<pb/>

as Grand Jurors, and other persons in
said Spokane County qualified to serve as
such Grand Jurors at the time said list
was prepared were omitted therefore and
their names do not appear thereon
and the present members composing the
Grand Jury were <del>drawn</del> selected and
drawn from such imperfect and
incomplete list 8 1/2 that no list such persons

<add>qualified grand jurors in spokane county and was fraud by the
commitment by the persons of grand jury from their defined district
and was named by the county. That said Grand Jury</add>

had no authority to entertain pais upon
or find any indictment against defendant
whatever for the reason defendant was
under recognizance for her appearance
at this term of court and therefore had
a right to challenge the panel or
any individual member thereof
of which right by this action the grand
jury she has been deprived.</p>

<p>5.- That an indictment is
now pending in this court charging defendant
with the crime of murder in the second degree
in the ruling of me James Frick
upon which issue is joined and was so
pending and issue joined at the time of the
finding of the indictment herein by the
plaintiff this for the same offense in fact.</p>

<pb/>

<p>6.- It appears that no effort
whatever was made by said Grand Jury
to discover the name of the party injured.</p>

<p>7.- That some of the members of
said Grand Jury were disqualified to 
act as Grand Jurors not being citizens
of the United States and served of said
Grand Jurors has serve so purposing
against deft that the emerged not have
a fair and impartial trial therebeing before then.</p>

<p>Justice Short</p>

<p>S.T. Cotno</p>

<p>J.T. Park</p>

<p>Atty. for Deft.</p>
