<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0208.008">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ichitaro Matsutsuyu v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0208.008</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ichitaro Matsutsuyu v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1919-12-02">December 2, 1919</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1919-12">December 1919</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>California</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Japan</term>
<term>San Franciso, California</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Matsutsuyo, Ichitaro</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wardell, Ray M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Moore, Ben L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-01" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>No. 4918</p>

<p>Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Ichitara Matsutsuyu to be Released on Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>To the Hon. Jeremiah Neterer, District Judge.</p>

<p>Now comes Ichitara Matsutsuyu and respectfully represents:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That the petitioner herein has been a resident of the United States continuously for nearly thirteen years last past and was domiciled in the state of Califorina for the period of eleven years. That at this time the petitioner has been ordered deported by the Department of Labor on the grounds that he is likely to become a public charge and the further ground that he has been convicted of a crime involving moral turpitude, within five years from last date of entry into the United States.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>Your petitioner avers that on the recommendation of Henry M. White, United States Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, the Department of Labor did sustain said finding and ordered the petitioner herein deported. Petitioner says that the findings and conclusions of said Henry M. White, as United States Commissioner of Imigration at Seattle,Washington, and findings of the Department of Labor are not sustained by the evidence taken before said Henry M. White, Commission, and said findings are not predicated upon the evidence established upon the hearing on the charges preferred against him.</p>

<pb/>

<p>III.</p>

<p>That your petitioner is now imprisoned, detained,confined and restrained of his liberty by the Honorable Henry M. White, as United States Commissioner of Imigration at Seattle, and within the jurisdiction of this Honorable Court.</p>

<p>IV.</p>

<p>Your petitioner states that he arrived from the Empire of Japan in San Francisco in the year 1906, and that he has continued at all times to reside within the United States; that he has at no time been out of the United States for a single day or night, and during all of said time had his residence within the United States and steadily employed doing business for himself; that he ahs at no time received assistance from any source whatsoever, nor has he at any time been in indigent circumsstances,; that during his residence he married in Los Angeles and is now the father of a child two and one-half years of age. The petitioner's wife having died within the past two years.</p>

<p>V.</p>

<p>That said order of Deportation and the restraints which followed was issued solely upon the evidence presented in the record, all of which said record is in the hands of Henry M. White, United States Commissioner of Imigration at Seattle, and all of which record your petitioner <add>desires</add> placed before this Court.</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that a Writ of Habeas Corpus issue and directed to the Honorable Henry M. White, as Commissioner of Imigration at Seattle aforesaid requiring, commanding and directing him to have the body of the petitioner before your Honor at a time and place to be specified, to do and receive that shall then and there be considered by this Honorable Court concerning him, together with time and cause of such detention and said Writ; and that he, your petitioner, may be restored to his liberty.</p>

<p>Ichitaro Matsutsuyu</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>

<p>Ray M Wardall</p>
<p>Attorney for petitioner.</p>

<p>Western District of Washington, Northern Division</p>
<p>ss</p>

<p>ICHITARA MATSUTSUYU, the Petitioner named in the foregoing petition, being first duly sworn on oath says that he has reas the foregoing petition, knows the contents thereof and beleives the same to be true.</p>

<p>Ichitaro Matsutsuyu</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 2nd day of December, 1919.</p>

<p>Ray Wardall</p>
<p>Notary Public</p>

<p>Western District of Washington,Northern Division</p>

<p>ss</p>

<p>Ray M. Wardall being first duly sworn says that he is the attorney for the petitioner in the above cause; that he appeared as counsel for the petitioner in the proceedings before the Immigration Department; that affiant is informed and verily believes that the petitioner will be immiediately deported, affiant being informed by the Imigration officer at Seattle that the next ship will leave for Japan on Wednesday, Dec. 3rd, upon which petitioner will be deported; that the facts stated are true as affiant verily believes, and further verifies this petition for writ of Habeas Corpus at the request of friends of said detained petitioner who have full knowledge of the facts in the premises that such proceedings will be brought and instituted.</p>

<p>RM Wardall</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 2nd day of Dec.1919.</p>

<p>W.M.Williams</p>
<p>Notary Public</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>