<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0465.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Charles W. Nordstrom v. William H. Moyer. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0465.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Charles W. Nordstrom v. William H. Moyer. Petition</title>
<date when="1897-04-03">April 3, 1897</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1897-04">April 1897</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Humes, Thomas H.</term>
<term>Jacobs, Orange</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Nordstrom, Charles W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Moyer, William H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Lewis, James Hamilton</persName>
<persName>Hemming, James Henry</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>McElroy, James F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
<persName>Fuller, Melville W.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Circuit Court of the United States for the District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Northern Division, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES
CIRCUIT COURT, FOR THE DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Charles W. Nordstrom for Writ
of Habeas Corpus and Relief thereon</p>

<ab>PETITION.</ab>

<p>To the Honorable Circuit Court of the United States,
for the District of Washington, and to the Judges thereof:</p>

<p>Your Petitioner, Charles W. Nordstrom, alleges and
shows:</p>

<p>1. That he is a citizen and resident of the United 
States, residing in the County of King, at the City of
Seattle, in the State of Washington.</p>

<p>2. That he is now being unlawfully detained and
unlawfully held in custody by William H. Moyer, Sheriff of
King County, and, against his wish, is being held by the
said Moyer under threats by the said Moyer, Sheriff of
King County, and, against his wish, is being held by the
said Moyer under threats by the said Moyer, as Sheriff of
King County, to take the life of this Petitioner under
alleged process and authority as hereinafter more fully
state.</p>

<p>3. Your Petitioner further alleges that the said
threat and attempt to take his life, which is set for and
arranged to be, your Petitioner understands, at once, and particularly
in the month of April on the day of the 23rd, is wholly 
without authority of law, without the jursidiction of any</p>

<ab>(1)</ab>

<pb/>

<p>Court, contrary to the law and contrary to the rights of 
your petitoner as a citizen of the United States under the
Constitution of the United States, as will more particularly
appear in matters hereafter stated.</p>

<p>4. Your petitioner informs the Court that on or about
the <gap></gap> day of <gap></gap>, he was
charged by the State of Washington by information of three
separate crimes in one count, to-wit: the crime of murder
in the first degree, to which the penalty of death attached
upon conviction; murder in the second degree, to which a
penalty of not less than 10 nor more than 20 years imprisonment
in the penitentiary attached, and the offense of manslaughter,
to which not less than 2 nor more than 10 years 
imprisonment in the penitentiary attached.</p>

<p>That your petitioner was tried upon the said information
upon issue joined in the Superior Court of King County.</p>

<p>That to said issue a jury trying your petitioner did
return him guilty of no greater offense than the offense of 
murder in the second degree, and by legal construction
granting inferences and all presumptions in favor of your
petitioner as accused, finding your petitioner guilty of
no higher offense than that of manslaughter.</p>

<p>That the said jury is no wise found your petitioner
guilty of murder in the first degree, to which the sentence
and penalty of th death could be inflicted.</p>

<p>That the said verdict was rendered about the <gap></gap> day
of <gap></gap>, 189 .</p>

<p>5. That your petitioner appealed from the decision
finding your petitioner guilty of murder in the second degree,
or of manslaughter, to the Supreme Court of the State</p>

<ab>(2)</ab>

<pb/>

<p>of Washington upon errors assigned, and the said judgment 
was affirmed.</p>

<p>And further, upon the validity of the process under
which your petitioner was charged, to-wit: as to whether or
not your petitioner was charged, to-wit: as to whether or
not your petitioner could be tried upon an information, for
his life, your petitioner appealed to the Supreme Court
of the United States upon that point and that point alone;
and that point alone being reserved and alone being presented,
the Supreme Court of the United States affirmed the
Supreme Court of the State of Washington, that your petitioner
could be tried by the process of an information for
an offense involving his life or liberty, returning the said
cause and all process to the Supreme Court of the State of
Washington to be dealth with as in manner and forms of the law
was both just and proper.</p>

<p>6. That at no time after the said verdict or upon any 
further hearing of the said cause upon appeal or pending 
any of its stages was ever any death-warrant issued by any
Judge or Court authorizing or assuming to take the life of 
your petitioner, or authorizing or assuming to order that
your petitioner's life be taken, or warranting any person, 
sheriff or otherwise, to take the life of your petitioner.
Thus there was no opportunity nor occasion to complain in
the Supreme Court of the State or any other Court as to the 
right to issue said death-warrant or the authority for the
same.</p>

<p>7. That at the time your petitioner was tried he was 
tried before the Honorable Thomas J. Humes, one of the 
Judges of the Superior Court of the County of King.</p>

<p>That after the said cause had been disposed of in the
Supreme Court of the State of Washington and the Supreme
Court of the United States and returned to the Superior Court</p>

<ab>(3)</ab>

<pb/>

<p>of the State of Washington for the execution of such process
as would be legal in the premises, the said Thomas J. Humes
had ceased to be Judge,- the said Thomas J. Humes being the
only Judge who had heard the evidence in the cause and who
had presided at the trial of your petitioner,- and succeeding
the said Thomas J. Humes came to the Honorable Orange Jacobs,
Judge of the Superior Court of King County, elected and
qualified.</p>

<p>8. That to-wit: on the 20th of February A.D. 1897,
the State of Washington moved that your petitioner be brought
up for judgment and for other process against him, and moved
the said Orange Jacobs, Judge, to execute a warrant of death
authorizing the taking of your petitioner's life for matters
and things alleged as was claimed in the record, to-wit:
upon the said verdict, and there was presented to the said
Judge a form of death-warrant reciting matters and things
in nowise true, in so far as the same assumed to recite
any conviction of your petitioner of the crime of murder
in the first degree, and your petitioner then and there duly
objected through his counsel James Hamilton Lewis to the
said Honorable Orange Jacobs assuming to pass sentence of
death upon your petitioner, and particularly assuming to
issue a death-warrant against your petitioner ordering the
taking of your petitioner's life by the said Sheriff W. H. 
Moyer on the 23rd day of April, 1897 or at any time whatsoever, 
and duly insisted that the Court was without jursidiction
to make such order; that the same was wholly in excess
of jursidiction, was wholly in want of jurisdiction and 
wholly without the authority of the law, particularly was
without any due process of law and was in violation of your
petitioner's rights as a citizen of the United States and of
the State of Washington, and particularly in violation of</p>

<ab>(4)</ab>

<pb/>

<p>Article 6 of the Federal Constitution of the United States
prescribing that the life of your petitioner or any other
citizen shall not be taken without due process of law, and particularly in violation of Article 14 of the Federal Constitution
of the United States specifically providing that
no State shall by law or otherwise deny to your petitioner
the right of exemption and immunity from unjust process, and
particularly providng and prescribing against the taking
of your petitioner's or any other citizen's life without
due process of law and save and except upon a due judgment
and conviction upon which the sentence of deaht necessarily
and as a matter of law absolutely followed, and that under
the laws of the State of Washington there was no authority
in the said Judge Jacobs or the said Superior Court or any
Judge thereof to order the taking of the life of your petitoner
upon a construction of the process or verdict or upon assumed constructions of the law, or upon any pretense or
authority.</p>

<p>9. That notwithstanding such objections duly presented 
before the said Judge, your petitioner was nevertheless
ordered to be executed by the Judge Jacobs, and the 
said Orange Jacobs did assume to and did order under his
hand that your petitioner shall on the 23rd day of April,
being Friday, of the year 1897, between the hours of 9 o'clock
in the forenoon and 4 o'clock in the afternoon, be executed
and his life be taken under and by authority of an alleged
judgment in the said cause ; that there was no authority for
such order, none permitted to the laws of the United States
and to the Constitution of the United States and to the
rights of your petitioner as a citizen of the United States.</p>

<ab>(5)</ab>

<pb/>

<p>10. That under the laws of the State of Washington
there was no time allowed further to appeal the said order
or cause to the Supreme Court of the State of Washington
from the order of the said Judge Jacobs as an original cause,
as the time had expired in which said cause could be taken
to the Supreme Court upon the wrongful order and upon the
said order and authority so exercised without jurisdiction. </p>

<p>That the next term of the Supreme Court of the State of
Washington is not until the month of May A. D. 1897, in
which there would be any authority on the part of the Court
by any proceedings to review the unauthorized act of the
said Judge Jacobs and of his Honor the Judge of the Superior
Court, and as there is no law under which your petitioner
can seek any stay pending any attempt to seek relief from
the Supreme Court of the State or from any other source,
your petitioner has the only remedy left him as a citizen
of the United States, of appealing to this Honorable Court
for rescue from an order seeking to take his life, upon the
ground that the same is wholly in excess of jurisdiction
and wholly void for want of jurisdiction and without authority.</p>

<p>11. Your petitioner further shows that he has duly
protested in every wise against the action of the said Court
and against the threatened action of the said sheriff, and
particularly protested against that particular action which
seeks in the manner and form herein state to execute and 
carry out an alleged conviction and sentence thereon of your 
petitioner.</p>

<p>12. That your petitioner does not seek at the hands 
of the Court absolute discharge unconditionally, but knowing the fact to be that an attempt to take his life is wholly
in excess of jurisdiction by or upon behalf of any Court of
the State of Washington, and a wholly unauthorized act on</p>

<ab>(6)</ab>

<pb/>

<p>the part of the sheriff of the County of King or any other
person, and knowing that under the law the only offense of
which your petitioner has been duly convicted and to which 
sentence could legally attach is the crime of murder in the
second degree, and under the reasonable construction granted
by the law possibly only the offense of manslaughter, and
under no circumstances by any construction of the law in
anywise applicable of the crime of murder in the first
degree, your petitioner seeks at the hands of the Court
the relief under such conditions as are allowable; that is,
that your petitioner either be permitted the election of
accepting his sentence upon a verdict of murder in the
second degree and that in the event of a failure on the part of the State of Washington to so act that your petitioner be
discharged or held upon order to re-try your petitioner
upon the offense alleged in the information, or that proceedings
against your petitioner be held void and the Court of
the State of Washington be ordered to pronounce sentence and
judgment against your petitioner as under the law appertaining
to convictions of murder in the second degree, and no
other could be had in the premises, or that upon due hearing
of the cause and upon examining the records of the cause
and the evidence in the cause, your Honor will make an order
discharging petitioner, subject to the jurisdiction of the
State Court to proceed against petitioner for such offense
only as it appears under the law to your Honor your petitioner
has alone been convicted of and which in law and in 
justice alone your petitioner could be sentenced upon.</p>

<p>13. That for due information of the Court, your
petitioner respectfully announces to the Court that the 
Journal entries and the records in the Superior Court of the</p>

<ab>(7)</ab>

<pb/>

<p>State of Washington in this cause known as Number 472 by
Writ of Certiorari duly certified before your Honor for
inspection and investigation, that the Court may be duly
advised in the premises, and that your Honor will grant unto
your petitioner a Writ of Habeas Corpus commanding your petitioner
to be brought before the Court at such time and
place as to the Court shall be convenient, whereat the Court
could inquire of the matters and things alleged by your 
petitioner, and that your Honor could issue a Writ of Certiorari
to the Superior Court of the County of King ordering
to be duly certified to the Court the records of this
said cause for information, particularly the alleged information,
the verdict, the judgment and the death-warrant
made in the premises, and all other journal-entries and
orders in the cause, that your Honor and the Court may be
informed of the premises, and that upon such record and upon
hearing of the cause, such further and other order can be
made as in the premises will be right and proper,
And your petitioner will every pray</p>

<ab>Charles W Nordstrom
Petitioner.</ab>

<ab>Jas Hamilton Lewis
Attorney for Petitioner.</ab>

<ab>J Henry Hemming
<unclear>AF Counsell, P</unclear></ab>

<ab>State of Washington.
County of King.

ss.</ab>

<p>Charles W. Nordstrom being first duly sworn, on 
oath says: That he is the petitioner herein; that he knows 
the matters and things set forth in the petition, and of the
matters of his own knowledge says they are true, and the other
matters of law he is advised by his counsel that they are true
and therefore believes the whole of said petition to be true.</p>
<ab>Charles W Nordstrom</ab>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this
3" day of April, 1897.</p>

<ab>J Henry Hemming
Notary Public in and for the State of
Washington, residing at Seattle.</ab>

<ab>(8)</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Tx</ab>

<ab>NO. 604</ab>

<p>In the Circuit Court
OF THE UNITED STATES,
FOR THE
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In re Application of
Charles W. Nordstrom
for Writ of 
Habeas Corpus
and Relief Thereon</p>

<ab>Petitioner</ab>

<ab>Jas Hamilton Lewis
<del>STRATTON, LEWIS, GILMAN.</del>
attorney for Petitioner</ab>

<ab>101-106 OCCIDENTAL, BLOCK, SEATTLE.</ab>

<p>Copy of within
received and due service of the same
acknowledged this <gap></gap> day of
1896.</p>

<ab>Attorney for</ab>

<p>Filed April 3 1897
IN THE 
U.S. CIRCUIT COURT.
A. REEVES AYRES,
CLERK.</p>

<ab>By R M Hopkins
DEPUTY.</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>