<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0114.014"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Jones et al. v. George. Memo from Judge</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0114.014</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Jones et al. v. George. Memo from Judge</title>
<date when="1885-03-12">March 12, 1885</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1885-03">March 1885</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Doyle, William H.</term>
<term>Hanford, C.H.</term>
<term>Jones, William</term>
<term>OBrien, R.G.</term>
<term>Roberts, W.H.</term>
<term>Smith, Eben</term>
<term>Williams, Fred</term>
<term>Woods, Alfred</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Olympia, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Jones, William</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Doyle, William H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Williams, Fred</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Woods, Alfred</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>George, Jesse W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Robinson, Joseph W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, John B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hoyt, John P.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the 2d Judicial District of the Territory of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Olympia, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018" who="nl">transcribed.</change> 
<change when="2019" who="sab">encoded, edited transcription.</change>  
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0114.014"/>

<note>No 2427</note>

<p>In The Matter of the Application of William Jones, William H. Doyle, Fred Williams, and Alfred Woods, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>And now on this 12th of March 1885 the above named Petitioners and each of them having been brought before the Judge of this court by the United States Marshal, upon the writs heretofore issued herein and being now personally present and the said Marshal having made due return of said writ and being now present and C.H. Hanford assistant United States Attorney for Washington Territory being also present and appearing on behalf of the United States as well as the said United States Marshal and the Judge having heard the petition on file

<pb...></pb...>

and the return aforesaid and the evidence introduced and arguments of Counsel for said Petitioners as well as the Marshal and the United States aforesaid and Eben Smith Esq. United States, Commissioner, the officer by whom the said petitioners were Committed to the custody of the said Marshal having by leave of the Judge of this Court <del>amended</del> issued an amended warrant of Commitment directed to said marshal commanding him the said Marshal to receive into his custody the said petitioners and them to safely keep so that they be produced at the District Courts of the Third Judicial District of Washington Territory Holding terms at Seattle at the next regular term thereof, to testify as witnesses, in a certain criminal proceeding therein an behalf of the

<pb...></pb...>

United States and said amended warrants of Commitment being now produced and <unclear>judgments</unclear> to the inspection of the Judge of this Court and the said Judge being now sufficiently advised in the premises, finds that the said Petitioners and each of them have been heretofore <del>are now</del> lawfully taken into custody by the said Marshal under process duly issued by competent authority in accordance with law; and that sufficient</p>

<p><del>Wherefore by virtue of the law</del> caues has not been shown for dischargingthe said petitioners or either of them from custody.</p>

<p>Wherefore by virtue of the law and by reason of the premises It is considered and adjudged by the Court that the application of said petitioners and each of them to be discharged from custody be and the same

<pb...></pb...>

is hereby denied and that William Jones, William H. Doyle Fred Williams, and Alfred Woods, the said petitioners and each of them be and they are hereby remanded into the custody of the United States Marshal for Washington Territory, to be by the said Marshal safely kept until they shall by discharged by due course of law.</p>

<p>And it is further considered and adjudged by the court that the United States of America do have and recover of and from the said William Jones, William H. Doyle, Fred Williams, and Alfred Woods the costs and expenses of this proceeding to be taxed, and that execution issue thereupon</p>

<p>John P. Hoyt
Judge</p>


<p>Received &amp; Filed
MAR 13 1886</p>
<p>RG O'Brien Clerk.</p>
<p>By W H Roberts Deputy</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>