<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0152.001"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0152.001</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">December 1, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date></term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>
Corbin, Jerome C.
Corbin, Frank E. 
Hanford, C. H.
Root, Elihu
Rowan, A. S.
Lueders, H. W.
Ayres, A. Reeves
Matthew, H. M.
Roberts, A. H.
Matthews, W. F.
Huston, J. F. 
</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington'
Vancouver, Washington
Tacoma, Pierce County, Washington
Clarke County
County of King
</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Corbin, Jerome C.</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Corbin, Frank E.</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName> Lueders, H. W.
</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>
</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H. </persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Circuit Court of Washington, 9th District</orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0152.001"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT FOR, THE NINTH CIRCUIT, FOR THE DISTRICT
OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of Jerome C. Corbin,
For the Writ of Habeas Corpus of
Frank E. Corbin, a minor.
</p>
<p>To the Honorable C. H. Hanford, Judge of the United States Circuit 
Court for the District of Washington, Northern Division,.</p>
<p>The petition of Jerome E. Corbin respectfully shows:-</p>
<p>1st. That he is the father of Frank E. Corbin, a minor, who was
born on the second day of July, 1884 in the State of Michigan, and was
at all the times hereinafter mentioned, and is now under the age of 21
years, to-wit:- of the age of 19 years and 4 months old, and that your
petitioner has never emancipated said son, and is now entitled to his
custody, control, assistance and support.</p>
<p>2nd. That said Frank E. Corbin wrongfully and unlawfully and without
the knowledge or consent of your petitioner enlisted as a soldier in the
United States Army at Seattle, Washington, on November 30, 1903, and was
sent to Co. B, 19th Infantru at Vancouver Barracks, Vancouver, Washington,
about December 1st, 1903, and was (from said Co. B. transferred to Co. D.
19th Infantry, United States Army, stationed at Vancouver, Washington,
where he is now wrongfully and unlawfully detained from your petitioner
and your petitioner deprived of his assistance, his support and of his
custody and control. </p>
<p>3rd. That said minor enlisted in said military service of the
United States on the 30th day of November, 1903, being then and there
between the age of 18 and 21 yearsm and wrongfully represented to the
recruiting officers at Seattle, Washington, that he was of the age of 21
years and 4 months, which was in fact untrue.</p>
<p>4th.That your petitioner had no knowledge of said mis-representation
on the part of said minor to said recruiting officers and that your
minor desired petitioner to give his consent to said minor's enlistment
in the United States Army. That your petitioner then and there at the
time absolutely declined and refused to consent to said enlistment and
and refused to permit said minor, Frank E. Corbin, to enlist in the
United States Army, because of his tender age, and because of the
physical condition of your petitioner he was unable to spare him
as a means of his assistance and support. That said Frank E. Corbin
is a boy of extreme youthful appearance, though tall in 
statute, in so much that the recruiting officer, Sergeant Louis
H. Mohr, sent a letter by him on November 9, 1903, requesting
petitioner to certify as to said minor's age, which petitioner has
at all times declined and refused to do.</p>
<p>5th. That your p etitioner demanded the discharge and release of
said minor, Frank E. Corbin, from the Army, of the Secretary of War,
the Hon. Elihu Root, in accordance with the regulations of the
United States Army and Articles of War, as well as the Acts of
Congress relating to the Military Service of the United States, on
December 22, 1903, before said minor, Frank E. Corbin, was entitled to
any pay or allowance, and before he had yet receoved any pay of
allowance or compensation on account of his enlistment as such
soldier, and your petitioner further offered to bear the expense
of his transportation from Vancouver Barracks, Vancouver, Washington,
to Tacoma, Washington, and at the same time duly served upon the
Captain of the Co. D. 19th Infantry, U.S.V. at Vancouver, Barracks,
Vancouver, Washington, a copy of said application to the Secretary
of War, and requested the discharge of said minor, and duly gave
notice of the illegality of said minor's enlistment, and duly
asserted then and there his rights to the custody and control of
said minor,Frank E. Corbim. </p>
<p>6th. That said Secretary of War, through Assistant Adjudant
General refused and declined to comply with the demand of your
petitioner, and that your petitioner has no other adequate and
speedy remedy whereby he can recover or obtain control and
custody of his said minor child.</p>
<p>7th. That said Frank E. Corbin had not in anyway been adjuged
or condemned by any Court Marshall or other Military or Legal
Tribunal, and is unlawfully imprisoned and detained, confined and
restrained of his liberty by the Captain of Co. D., 19th Infantry
at Vancouver Barracks, Vancouver, Washington, under command of
Captain A. S. Rowan in the County of Clarke, and State of 
Washington.</p>
<p>8th. That the said imprisonment, detention, confinement and restraint
are illegally, and that the illegality thereof consists in said
Military authorities restraining and holding said Frank E. Corbin
as a duly and legally enlisted soldier in the service of the
United States Army, he neing then and there between the age of
19 and 20 years, without the consent of petitioner, his father and
natural guardian, W he is by law entitled to his care, custody and
control under and by virtue and maintenance of the United States
Army and rules and regulations made and promulgated in pursuance 
thereof.</p>
<p>WHereFore your petitioner prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus
may be granted directed to said A. S. Rowan, Commander of Co. D.
19th Infantry, United States Army, and his inferior and superior
Officers at Vancouver Barracks, Vancouver, Washington command him
to have the body of Frank E. Corbin before your Honor at a time
and place therein to be specified, to do and receive what shall
then and there be considered by Your Honor, concerning him together
witht the time and the cause of his detention, and said Writ; and
that he may be restored to his liberty, and to have such other re-
dress as the Court may deem proper in the premises.</p>
<p>Dated on the 9th day of Janurary, A. D. 1904</p>
<p>HW Lueders</p>
<p>Attorney for petitioner.
408 Luzon Building,
Tacoma, Washington.</p>
<p>Jerome C. Corbin
Petitioner</p>
<p>State of Washington,
SS.
County of Pierce.
</p>
<p>Jerome C. Corbin being first duly sworn on oath deposes and
says: that he is the petitioner above named: that he has read 
the foregoing petition and knows the contents thereof, and that
the facts therein stated are true.</p>
<p>Jerome C. Corbin</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 8th day of January, 1904.
HW Lueders
Notary Public in and for the
State of Washington, residing
at Tacoma, Pierce County, Wash.</p>
<p>1166</p> 
<p>In the Matter of the 
Application for
Writ of Habeas Corpus
Frank E. Corbin a minor
J. C. Corbin petitioner
Petition
</p> 
<p>FILED IN THE
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JAN 9 1904</p>
<p>A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk.</p>
<p>HM Matthew
Deputy</p>
<p>HW Lueders atty
for Petition Tacoma Wa.
United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
for Writ of Habeas Corpus of
Frank E. Corbin a Minor
Jerome C. Corbin petitioner</p>
<p>No. 1166</p>
<p>Appearance</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>To the Clerk of the above Entitled Court:
You will pleas eneter my appearance as attorney
for Petitioner
in the above entitled cause</p>
<p>HW Lueders
408 Luzon Bldg- Tacoma Wash
Phone Red 1654</p>
<p>NOTICE- Attorneys will please endorse their own Filings. Rule 47,</p>
<p>no. 1166</p>
<p>United States Circuit Court
District of Washington</p>
<p>In re-
Jerone C. Corbin
vs.
Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Appearance</p>
<p>Filed FILED IN THE 
U. S. Circuit Couty
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
190</p>
<p>JAN 9 1904 Clerk.</p>
<p>A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk.</p>
<p>HM Matthew 
Deputy Depty Clerk.
For</p>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT, NINTH CIRCUIT, DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION,
HOLDING TERMS AT SEATTLE, WASHINGTON.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the petition
of Jerone C. Corbin for the Erit
of Hbeas Corpus for Frank. E.
Corbin, a minor.</p>
<p>The President of the United States of America.
To A. S. Rowan, Captain of Co. D, 19th Infantry,
United States Army, and your Subordinate Officers,
At Vancouver Barracks, Vancouver, Washington.</p>
<p>Greeting:-</p>
<p>WE COMMAND YOU, that you have the body of Frank E. Corbin
a minor, under the age of 21 years, now imprisioned and detained and
restrained of his liberty by virture of being impressed as a 
Private Soldierin Co. D. 19thInfantry, United States Army, and
unlawfully detained by you at Vancouver Barracks, in the County of
Clarke and State of Washington, without the consent of his father,
the petitioner, Jerome C. Corbin,as it is said in said petition
filed herein, together with the time and cause of such imprison-
ment, restraint and detention, by whatsoever, name said Frank E.
Crobin shall be called or charged, before me at a stated term of
the Circuit Court of the United States for the District of
Washington, Northerin Dicision, to be held in the United States
Court Rooms in the City of Seattle, and County of King, and State of 
Washington, on the 18th day of January, A. D. 1904 at 10 o'clock A. M., to do and receive
what shall then and there be considered concerning said Frank E.
Corbin, a minor, and have you then and there this writ; with due
return thereon.</p>
<p>Witness the HONORABLE C. H. HANFORD, JUDGE OF SAID COURT, this
9th day of January, A. D. 1904.</p>
<p>A Reeves Ayres
Clerk</p>
<p>HW Leuders
Attorney for Petitioner.
408 Luzon Building.
Tacoma, Washington.</p>
<p>By HM Matthew Deputy</p>
<p>Let the Writ issue
CH Hanford
Judge</p>
<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA,
ss
District of Oregon,</p>
<p>I hereby certify that on the 14th day of January 1904 at
Vancouver, Washington, Clark County in the District of Washington, I duly
aerved the Origional Writ of Habeas Corpus upon Colonel, J. F. Huston
officer in charge of Company D, 19th infantry United States Army</p>
<p>W. F. Matthews,
United States Marshal</p>
<p>By A. H. Roberts
Deputy</p>
<p>1166</p>
<p>In the Matter of
Habeas Corpus of
F. E. Corbin a minor
</p>
<p>Copy-</p>
<p>Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Marshall please attach
return of service on
the copt of Writ and
mail to Clerk or to
attorney below</p>
<p>FILED IN THE
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JAN 18 1904</p>
<p>A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk</p>
<p>H. M. Matthew
Deputy</p>
<p>HW Lueders- atty for
petitioner</p>
<p>408 Luzon Bldg Tacoma Wa</p>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT, NINTH CIRCUITM DISTRICT
OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In re Frank E. Corbin
(Writ of habeas corpus--Return of respondent.)</p>
<p>To the Honorable Judge of the said Court.</p>
<p>The respondent, Colonel Joseph F, Huston, 19th Infantry,
upon whom hasbeen served a writ of habeas corpus for the pro-
duction of Frank E. Corbin, respectfully makes return and
states that as Commanding Officer of the Military Port of Van-
couver Barracks, Washington, he holds the said Frank E. Corbin
by authority of the United States under the following circum-
stances:</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>