<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0225.008">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Thomas L. Thurston v. O.P. Halligan. Memorandum Brief</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0225.008</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Thomas L. Thurston v. O.P. Halligan. Memorandum Brief</title>
<date when="1916">1916</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-01">Month 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Thomas L. Thurston</term> 
<term>Horace Gray</term>
<term>Clay Allen</term>
<term>E Lakin</term>
<term>Frank L. Crosby</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>McNeil Island</term>
<term>United States District Court Western District of Washington Northern Division</term> 
<term>Territory of Utah</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Thomas L. Thurston</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>O.P. Halligan</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>J. Henry Denning</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Clay Allen</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName><!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>Western District of Washington, Northern Division</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-02" who="#AS">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>No. 3128</p>
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT
OF THE UNITED STATES 
FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p> 
<p>In the Matter of the Petition 
of Thomas L. Thurston for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus</p> 
<p>S T I P U L A T I O N.</p>
<p>FILED IN THE 
U.S. District Court, 
Western Dist. of Washington, 
NORTHERN DIVISION 
JAN 3 - 1916 
FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk, 
by EmL Deputy 
2x</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION</p> 
<p>In the Matter of the Petition
of THOMAS L. THURSTON for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus } No. 3128</p>  

<p>MEMORANDUM BRIEF.</p> 

<p>In oral argument counsel has submitted two points to
the consideration of the court.</p>
<p>First, that no proper commitment was issued upon
which the defendant, a prisoner at McNeil Island, can 
properly be confined.</p>
<p>Second, that the judgment entered in this case is
fatally defective and void by reason of the fact that
it omits to mention, either by reference to section or
descriptive terms the crime for which the defendant was
punished.</p>
<p>The respondent has filed herein his answer and stip-
ulation, and to the facts recited therein the attention
of the court is directed</p> 
<p>Counsel for petitioner has submitted in oral argu-
ment and in writing a memorandum referring to Section
1028 of the Revised Statutes, found at page 335, volume
2 Fed. Stat.Annot, and cites in support of his possition
Davis v. Utah, 151 U.S. 362, 38 L.Ed.155; Crane v. U.S.
162 U.S. 625. 40 L.Ed.1097; Howard v.U.S., 75 Fed.986;
Ex parte Wilson, 114 U.S. 417.</p>
<p>Section 1028 R.S. referred to by counsel is an en-
<pb></pb>
actment of February 26, 1853, and reads as follows:</p> 
<p>"(Copy of writ to be jailer's authority; original re-
turned). Whenever a prisoner is committed to a
sheriff or jailer by virtue of a writ, warrant, or
mittimus, a copy thereof shall be delivered to such
sheriff or jailer, as his authority to hold the
prisoner, and the original writ, warrant, or mit-
timus shall be returned to the proper court or
officer, with the officer's return thereon."</p> 
<p>All of the decisions referred to by counsel for peti-
titioner and those cited herein, are decisions handed down
since the enactment of the foregoing section.</p> 
<p>Referring to the case of Davis v. Utah, supra, the
Supreme Court considered the sufficiency of the indict-
ment filed in the United States Court for the Territory
of Utah. There is no question presented in this case of
the sufficiency of the judgment or the commitment issued
thereon. The sole question which is presented to the
Supreme Court were questions having reference to the suf-
ficiency of the indictment. The Supreme Court held the
indictment good.</p> 
<p>Reference to the case of Crane v. U.S., supra, shows
that the question here presented is as to the sufficiency
of the indictment. It was also contended in this case
that the record should show that the defendant had entered
a plea to the indictment. The Supreme Court conceded the
importance, especially in a charge of murder, of arraign-
ment and plea, and that due process of law requires that an
accused person shall plead or be ordered to plead, or in a
proper case that a plea of not guilty be filed for him be-
fore his trial can rightfully proceed, and the record of his
conviction should show distinctly and not by inference.
It should appear affirmatively from the record that 
<pb></pb>
every step necessary to the validity of the sentence has
been taken in the trial court, otherwise the judgment will
be erroneous.</p> 
<p>It will be noted that counsel for the petitioner in
this case has already stipulated, for it is un-
doubtedly the fact, that all the essential and proper
steps preceeding the entry of the judgment had been taken
in the Thurston case.</p> 
<p>reference to the stipulation shows that it is agreed
by counsel that in cause no. 44-1, in which the judgment
was entered, -</p> 
<p>"An arraignment of the defendant Thomas L. Thurston
was had, a plea of not guilty was entered by each of
the defendants, and thereafter, in the same entit-
led cause, a jury was empaneled and a verdict of
guilty was rendered against the said defendants, and
and numbered cause, a judgment was entered, a copy
of which is attached to and made a part of the
respondent's return herein."</p> 
<p>It will thus be seen that the criticism which was made 
of the record of the court in the Crane case cannot be con-
sidered as present in the case at bar.</p> 
<p>Counsel cites for consideration of the court the case
of Howard v. U.S. and Ex parte Wilson. It is respectfully
suggested to the court that neither of these cases sustain
the position of counsel, but seem to negative the con-
tention made in behalf of the prisoner.</p> 
<p>The Howard case, decided by the Circuit Court for the 
Sixith Circuit, quotes and discusses Section 1028 R.S. above 
quoted. It was there in two separate appeals urged upon
the Circuit Court of Appeals that the commitment issued by 
the Clerk upon a conviction which charged several viola-
tions in various counts, failed to include the phrase</p> 
<pb></pb>
<p>"from date of" after the period of the first sentence,
the judgment being a cumulative sentence on each of the
several counts. The Circuit Court of Appeals states
on page 989-</p>
<p>"The warrant or order of commitment is simply an
authority and direction to the marshal to take
the prisoner to the penitentiary named. The copy
furnished by the marshal or clerk to the warden is
merely evidence, and evidence only, of the judgment
and sentence of the court and the mittimus issued
thereunder.* * * The prisoner is not committed by
virtue of the copy, but by virtue of the judgment
of the court, and the mittimus issued pursuant
thereto; the real valid authority under which the
mittimus is issued being the sentence of the court."</p> 
<p>The writ in the Howard case was denied.</p> 
<p>Reference to the case of Ex parte Wilson, decided
by the Supreme Court, Mr. Justice Gray delivering the
opinion, divulges the faact that the prisoner therein
raised the same contention as that made on behalf of the
prisoner Thurston, to the effect that the-</p> 
<p>"Keeper had no warrant or mittimus authorizing him
to hold the prisoner, as required by Rev.Stat.1028."</p>
<p>The decision of the Supreme Court in the Wilson case, in
my judgment, fully and definitely decided the first point
above mentioned as being raised by counsel. It is ap-
parent in the Wilson case that no mittimus was actually
issued by the Clerk of the Court, there being used in-
stead-</p> 
<p>"A certified copy of the record of the sentence to
imprisonment in the Detroit house of correction."</p> 
<p>The Supreme Court dismissed the matter, in this short but
definite phrase-</p> 
<p>"The certified copy of the record. of the sentence 
to imprisonment in the Detention House of Correction,
if valid upon its face, is sufficient to authorize
the keeper to hold the prisoner, without any warrant
or mittimus."</p>
<pb></pb>  
<p>There is cited in support of that declaration-</p>
<p>People v. Nevins, 1 Hill (N.Y.) 154.</p>
<p>It will be noted that the Supreme Court has before it
for consideration at this time Section 1028 referred to by
counsel.</p> 
<p>There is cited on behalf of the regpondent herein the
following cases which are deemed as especially in point
and decisive of the above contentions of counsel.</p>
<p>The attention of the court is first directed to
Section 1035 of the Revised Statutes, page 340, volume
3 Fed. Stat.Annot.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>