<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0187.028">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0187.028</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Marie Robina Grayson</title>
<date when="1914">1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fishburne, George P.</term>
<term>Grayson, Marie Robina</term>    
<term>Shakespeare, Noah</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Marie Robina Grayson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>George P. Fishburne</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
    <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>In the Matter of the 
Application of MARIE ROBINA
GRAYSON, alias MARIE ROBINA,
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus )
n.g.
No. 2780. 
MEMORANDUM BRIEF OF 
RESPONDENT</p>

<p>FACTS IN THE RECORD.</p>

<p>It appears that the petitioner was practicing 
prostitution at the time of her marriage. To sustain this see 
page 2 of the first hearing, where she said she was a sporting 
women nine years ago, and on page 3, of the same hearing, 
that she was practicing prostitution when she met her 
husband.</p>
<p>To sustain the proposition that she was married while 
released on bond, pending a hearing before the Immigration 
authorities, see the files of the Immigration Office. </p>
<p>STATUTE CONTROLLING CASE.</p>
<p>Mr. Shakespeare correctly quotes Section 19994 R.S.,see
Vol. 1 Fed. Stat. Annot page 786, which is in the following 
language:</p>
    <p>"Any woman who is now, or may hereafter be married to 
    a citizen of the United States, and who might herself 
    be lawfully naturalized, shall be deemed a citizen."</p>
<p>We agree with Mr. Shakespeare, that Mr. Bishop is 
correct in giving the law, ass follows:</p>
    <p>"That by the very act of marriage, citizenship is 
    conferred upon a woman, who by previous laws was capable 
    of becoming naturalized. His citizenship conferred 
    citizenship on her."</p>
<pb/>
<p>MEANING OF STATUTE.</p>
<p>In the case of Kelly v. Kahoe, 19 L. Ed. 284, the 
Supreme Court in construing this Act says:</p>
    <p>"It confers the privileges of citizenship upon women 
    married to citizens of the United States, if they are 
    of the class of persons for whose naturalization the 
    previous acts of Congress provide."</p>
<p>And the court further says:</p>
    <p>"The terms 'who might lawfully be naturalized under the 
    existing law' only limit the application of the law 
    to free white women. The previous naturalization
    act existing at the time only required that the person 
    applying for its benefits should be a free white 
    person, and not an alien enemy,"</p>
<p>And the Supreme Court cites the naturalization act of April 
14, 1802, 2 Stat. L. p. 153.</p>
<p>But the naturalization law in force <del>at the time of the 
marriage of the petitioner was different from that in force 
at the time of the decision of the Supreme Court in the Kelly</del>
v. Kahoe case, supra <del>and</del> is correctly quoted by Mr. 
Shakespeare in hsi brief as being as follows:</p>
    <p>"The applicant must be a free white person, or a person 
    of African descent or nativity. The applicant must have 
    resided within the United States five years, must have 
    a good moral character, attached to the principles of 
    the Constitution of the United States, and well disposed 
    to the good order and happiness of the same, and must 
    have renounced all titles or orders of nobility, if 
    any applicant has."</p>
<p>There is no more reason for dispensing with the 
requirement, that a woman have a good moral character, than
there is for dispensing with the requirement, that she be a 
free white person.</p>
<gap/>
<p>some loathsome disease, or possess any other of the inabilities
whic exclude them from the United States by the 
Immigration Law.</p>

<ab>Respectfully submitted, 
G. P. Fishburne, 
Assistant U.S. Attorney</ab>
<pb/>
<p>No.2780</p>

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT 
OF THE UNITED STATES 
FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>

<p>In the Matter of the 
Application of MARIE ROBINA 
GRAYSON, alias Marie 
Robina, for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>MEMORANDUM BRIEF OF 
    RESPONDENT.</p>
<gap/>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>