<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<note>906</note>

<p>Territory of Washingto Agt. James Riley</p>

<p>Criminal Action Justices Court Pierce Co W.T.</p>

<p>August 24 1861 before M. J. West J. P. both parties appear. Defendant why by his Attorney for further time to obtain the testimony of John McCloud and the same was granted until the 27 day of August at 10 o'clock A.M.</p>

<p>August 27 1861</p>

<p>The party defendant appears in Court. Ordered by the Court that William H. Wood be and he is hereby appointed Counsel on behalf of the Territory.</p>

<p>Come now the defendant <unclear>&amp; me</unclear> being <unclear>ansigned</unclear> pleaded "Not guilty". Thereupon Robt. White and Henry E. Bradley were sworn as witnesses and both parties. plaintiff and defendant, rested and after the argument of Counsel the case was submitted to the Court.</p>

<p>Thereupon the Court considers and being fully advised in the premises is of the opinion that defendant James Riley is guilty of the offenses of "Assault with intent to kill John McCloud" and of "Malicious Mayhem" <del></del> which are not within the jurisdiction of this court.</p>

<p>Therefore it is ordered by the Court that the said defendant James Riley enter into bonds in the sum of two thousand dollars with approved security for his appearance at the next term of the District Court in and for the Second Judicial District of the Territory of Washington to be begun and held on the First Monday in September next and that he be placed in the custody of the Sheriff

<pb...></pb...>

of Pierce County, W.T. until this order be <unclear>compleed</unclear> with or until he is discharged by due course of law.</p>

<p>On motion of W. H. Wood, Acting <unclear>Pronartoing</unclear> Attorney, it is ordered by the Court that Carl Ggoric Thomas N. Han, Dominick Corcoran, John Walmskley, Mrs Esther Bradley and Thomas Tallertine be and they are hereby ordered to enter into bonds in the sum of two hundred dollars each with approved sureties for their appearance as witnesses on the part of the Territory in the above entitled cause, at the next term of the District Court in and for the second Judicial District of the Territory of Washington to be begun and held at Olympia on the first Monday in September next</p>

<p>In case either or all of the above named witnesses shall fail to enter into the required bonds the Sheriff of Pierce County W.T. is hereby directed to commit them to the County Jail, there to remain until they shall comply with the foregoing order of Court or be otherwise discharged according to law.</p>

<p>Ordered by the Court that Seventy five Dollars be and the same is hereby allowed to W. H. Woods for his services as Attorney for the Territory, the same to be paid by the said County of Pierce, and the said sum to be taxed as a part of the costs in this cause.</p>

<p>Comes now Robert White and enters into a Recognizance for his appearance at said term of Court as witness for the Territory, in the sum of two hundred dollars</p>

<p>I certify that the foregoing is a true transcript from my docket</p>

<p>M. J. West.. Justice of the Peace</p>