<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0458.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Wah Ni v. State of Washington. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0458.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Wah Ni v. State of Washington. Petition</title>
<date when="1893-06-06">June 6, 1893</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1893-06">June 1893</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Marks, J. E.</term>
<term>Yuck, Moy</term>
<term>Pritchard, W. H.</term>
<term>Clifford, Miles K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
<term>Hong Kong, China</term>
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Ni, Wah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Snell, Marshall K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-12" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COUTY OF THE UNITED STATES, FOR THE DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, <del>WESTERN</del> <add>Northern</add> DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of
Wah Ni for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Comes now the above named petitioner Wah Ni, and for his pe-
tition and complaint in writing for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, on
oath respectfully shows to this court:</p>

<p>That on or about the 11th day of January, A.D., 1892, he 
left the City of Portland, Oregon, where he has resided for ten
years immediately prior to said time, and had been for six years
last past engaged in the merchantile business, for Hong Kong, Chi-
na, and that he did, prior to taking his said departure, appear
before one J. E. Marks, a Notary Public, and then and there sub-
scribe and make the certificate hereunto attached and marked as
exhibit "A" and making and forming a part of this his said peti-
tion.</p>

<p>2. That all the facts and circumstances as set forth in said
statement are true; that petitioner had, for six years last past,
been actively engaged as a Chinese merchant in Portland, Oregon,
and was at said time doing business at 254 Morrison Street and was
a member of the firm of Yee Wah &amp; Co., and as a member of said
firm still having and retaining all of his said interests in said
business, which was the sum of $1,000, and still having and re-
ceiving his share of the profits from said business and was at
said time a bona fide owner and holder of a one-tenth interest in
said business, the capital stock of said business being $10,000,
your petitioner being one of the junior partners in said business;
and your petitioner fully and completely relied upon said J. E. 
Marks as an attorney at law for the proper wording and mak-
ing of said certificate, and fully believes that the same fully</p>

<pb/>

<p>-2-</p>

<p>completely complies with the law as in such cases made and
<unclear>provided</unclear>; that the said certificate is attached a photograph of
your petitioner, which photograph petitioner had taken for the
purpose of having same attached to said certificate.; and petition-
er further states that at said time he did obtain the statement of
persons well and favorable known to him, one of said persons be-
ing Capt. Thomas Hawks, who was for a number of years a policeman
upon the beat upon which petitioner's business was located and
frequently met the said Hawks, and that afterwards said Thomas
Hawks was deputy tax collector in the city of Portland and had
called upon this petitioner and collected taxes, and that the said
Capt. Thomas Hawks did sign said statement attached to said cer-
tificate, and that he is the same Thomas Hawks whose affidavit is
hereunto attached, and that the said certificate of petitiner is
a correct copy of petitioner's certificate with the exception
of the photograph and attached hereto and marked as exhibit "A"
as aforesaid.</p>

<p>Your petitioner further states that he did, on or about the
11th day of January, 1892, take his departure for Hong Kong, Chi-
na, anndt and did there remain and visit with his parents, rela-
tives and friends, and transact his business and the business of
his said firm, which was that of viewing, examining and ascertain-
ing the prices of goods and making arrangements for the buying and 
shipping from the manufacturers in China; that thereafter, he did,
about the 10th day of January, 1893, take passage on the steamer
Victoria at Hong Kong, China, to return to the United States of 
America, and that he did pay his farer said passage and did re-
turn to and was landed at the steamboat wharf at Tacoma, and did
then and there present his certificate and request to be landed;
that one Plummer, representing himself to be a deputy collector,
did, without any cause, right, or authority, and without explain-</p>

<pb/>

<p>-3-</p>

<p>ing or making known to this petitioner any of his reasons for not
allowing him to land, refuse to allow your petitioner to land, al-
though your petitioner had in all ways and manner complied with
the laws of the United States of America, and did offer and was
willing to produce the witnesses who signed said statement to
said certificate, together with other witnesses both white and
Chinese who knew and would identify <del>him</del> your petitioner as having
resided in the city of Portland for a number of years last past,
and as being a good, honest, upright and bona fide merchant in
said city and a member of the firm doing buisness at 254 Morrison
street, in the city of Portland, Oregon, but regardless of said of-
fer, said Plummer made to your petitioner or to one Moy Yuck who
well understands and speaks the English language, no satisfactory
explanation whatsoever, and gave him no reason whatsoever for re-
fusing to admit your petitioner, but did take from your petitioner
his certificate with his photograph thereto attached, and the
statement as thereto attached signed by the petitioner and re-
speciive parties as set forth in exhibit "A", and did refuse to re-
turn same to your petitioner and has ever since said tine retained
same and does still continue to retain same, and your petitioner
has not had or seen the same since said time, and the same is
still had and retained by said Plummer or the Collector of Customs
or some one under him, without the consent and against the wish and
protest of petitioner, and petitioner further states that on the
evening of the 8th day of May, 1893 about the hour of 5 o'clock, 
he was informed that the said steamer Victoria, with a large num-
ber of Chinese passengers, aobut two hundred in number, nearly all
of whom were strangers to this petitioner, and of whome he knew
nothing, and had no relation,would, at 4 o'clock on the morning
of the 9th inst. loose from the wharf at Tacoma, and be cleared</p>

<pb/>

<p>for and return upon her return trip to Hong Kong; and that your
petitioner, together with his two companions, who are likewise
merchants and who likewise ask for a writ of abeas corpus, would
be forcibly, unjustly, unlawfully and illegally and without any
cause whatsoever, and without being informed as to <gap></gap> cause, com-
pelled to remain upon said vessel and htus be compelled to <gap></gap> <unclear>return</unclear>
to Hong Kong. That your petitioner did cause to be made, <unclear>diligently</unclear>
search and inquiry to find and ascertain the whereabouts of this 
Honorable Court to apply to it for a writ of habeas corpus, and
did apply <add>in Absence of the Court</add> to the Commissioner of your Honorable Court for said
writ, which was refused by said Commissioner for the reason that he 
had no authority to issue said writ, and that your petitioner was 
then compelled to resort to and did apply to the Superior Court
of Pierce Count, washington, for a writ of habeas corpus, setting
forth the facts and circumstances, which application was consider-
ed by the Court and by said Court, the Honorable W. H. Pritchard
<del>who</del> granted, said writ in the words following to-wit: "Let the
writ of habeas corpus and the warrant issue as prayed for in the
within complaint and petition. May 8, 1893. W. H. Pritchard,
Judge." That the said W. H. Pritchard was, at that time one of
the duly elected and qualified and acting jusges of the Superior
Court of the state of washington, for the County of Pierce, said
cause being number 9688 as appears by the record and files of
said Superior Court of the State of Washington, for the county of
Pierce; and that thereupon the clerk of said court did, under the
seal of said court, issue said writ of habeas corpus and warrant fo
for the arrest of said wah Ni as prayed for in said petition, and
under said writ the sheriff did proceed to the steamboat wharf
and to the steamer Victoria, and ask for the said Wah Ni, who was 
called for by the captain of said steamer, and without any fur-
ther orders and without any protest, ordered the said Wah Ni to
go ashore, which said wah Ni did then and thereupon do, without
any protest or resistance or proceedings of any kind of any rep-</p>

<pb/>

<p>resentative whatsoever of the United States of America; and that
the said captain did thereafter appear before the said Superior 
Court and make and file his written answer to said writ of habeas
corpus, and that then and thereupon, and upon the filing of said 
answer, the said petitioner Wah Ni, by his counsel demurred there
to, which demurrer was by the court sistained andafter hearing
the respective counsel and arguments of same, the said Wah Ni was then 
and thereupon by said court, in the presence of the oficers of the 
government discharged by the said Superior Court which he was be-
fore, all of which proceedings, including the said petition, or-
der of said court, writ of habeas corpus, warrant of arrest and
return of the officers upon it andsaid process, answer of the said
captain, the ruling and order of the court and record of the pro-
ceedings of the respective parties, appears of the record in the rec-
ords of the Superior Court of the State of Washington for the
County of Pierce in cause number 9688 as given, made and filed therein.</p>

<p>That immediately upon the discharge of said Wah Ni as afore-
said he was then and thereupon arrested charged with being ille-
gally in the United States of America, and was taken before Honor-
able Miles K. Clifford, Court Commissioner of theCircuit Court
of the United States at Tacoma, who proceeded to inquire into said
cause, and did refuse to allow said petitioner to be <del></del> turned over
to the United States marshall to be returned to said steamer Vic-
toria. which was still at the wharf at Tacoma and ordered that
said petitioner be held and returned by the United States marshall
for a hearing before him, which hearing was fixed for the 17th day
of May, 1893 at 10 o'clock in the forenoon, at which hearing evi-
dence was <del>take</del> introduced for the the respective parties and your said
petitioner was by said Commissioner ordered deported, from which or-
der, judgment and ruling, with the consent of the United States
attorney waiving all forms and regularities of giving notice, an</p>

<pb/>

<p>appeal was taken to this Honorable Court, and upon the question of
jurisdiction of the United States Commissioner being, by the 
United States attorney raised, this Honorable Court did, on the
5th day of June, 1893, order that your said petitioner be turned
over to and placed in custody of the United States marshal, J. C.
Drake, who proceeded and took your said petitioner into possession,
and now forcibly, knowingly, unlawfully, without just cause is 
now holding, detaining and retaining and keeping in confinement
your said petitioner, although he has demanded his liberty, re-
fused to recognize said demands, and still continues to hold, re-
tain, detain and deprive this petitioner of his liberty, and your
petitioner states that he can, if allowed a hearing before this
Honorable Court, show that he has fully and completely complied 
with all the laws of the United States and the ruels and regula-
tions thereof, and regardless of said compliance, the Collector of
Customs did wilfully, knowingly, arbitrarily, unjustly and un-
lawfully, and withou any cause, right or authority, refuse to ad-
mit your said petitioner and allow him to land, and that your said
petitioner is rightfully and justly entitled to land and be and re-
main in the United States of America, and go his way to his former 
residence as heretofore stated and resume his business at the city
of Portland, Oregon.</p>

<p>Your petitioner further states that he is at this time impris-
oned at the United States penitentiary at McNeill's Island, in 
Pierce County, Washington, and within the jurisdiction of this
court; that he is not detained by virtue of any order or process
issued by the United States Court, nor by virtue of any execution
or any other process, judgment, decree or final order of any state
court or any other court other than herein stated as aforesaid; and
that he is not held for the violation of any law, rule or regula-
tion or in punishment for any crime by him committed <del>other than
herein stated.</del></p>

<p>Petitioner further states that he is advised by Marshall K. 
Snell, his counsel, who resides at Tacoma, Pierce County, wash-
ington, and who is a counselor of this court, having and holding
a certificate authorizing him to practice in and before this court,
that such imprisonment is illegal for the reason and facts as
herein set forth, 'and that under and by virtue of the laws of the
United States, a writ of habeas corpus directed to the said United 
States Marshal should be issued by this Honorable Court to bring
before it your petitioner.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner ever prays and hereby applies for
a Writ of Habeas Corpus for the purpose of an inquiry into the
cause of such imprisonment and restraint, and delivering him there-
from and discharging him from custody.</p>

<p>Dated this 6th day of June, 1893</p>

<p>(Chinese signature)</p>
<p>Wah Ni</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>

<pb/>



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>