<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0468.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>The State of Washington vs. John W. Considine. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0468.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">The State of Washington vs. John W. Considine. Petition</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>McGraw, John H.</term>
<term>Feighan, J. W.</term>
<term>Johnson, Knox</term>
<term>Fleming, Thomas</term>
<term>Swartz, Edgar</term>
<term>Miller, A.</term>
<term>Solomon, Ben</term>
<term>Rumpff, Peter</term>
<term>Brooks, W. L.</term>
<term>Lane, A. G.</term>
<term>Files, Jacob</term>
<term>Patterson, Florence</term>
<term>Davis, Mae</term>
<term>Watts, Lulu</term>
<term>Lester, Eva</term>
<term>Morris, William</term>
<term>Swartz, Louis</term>
<term>Willis, W. E.</term>
<term>Winston, Patrick Henry</term>
<term>Wiley, John</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Considine, John W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>State of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Feighan, J. W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Circuit Court of the United States for the District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>District of Washington, Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
NORTHERN DIVISION.

IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION 
OF JOHN W. CONSIDINE for Writ of 
Habeas Corpus.

No.
PETITION.

To the Honorable Circuit Court of the United States, For the District 
of Washington, Northern Division

Your Petitioner, John W. Considine, respectfully represents and 
shows to the Court that he is a natural born citizen of the United States,
and a resident of the State of Washington; that he is unjstly and unlawfully
detained and imprisoned in the County jail of Spokane County,
State of Washington, by C C <unclear>Dempsey</unclear> Sheriff
of said County by virtue of a Warrant of commitment issued out of the
Superior court of the State of Washington, in and for the County of
Spokane in the case of The State of Washington vs. John W. Considine. 

Your Petitioner further shows, your Honor, that on the 1st day of 
March 1895 the House of Representatives, of the State of Washington, in
so far as it had the constitutional power, duly enacted, by the requisite
vote, the following alleged pretended statute:

"(H. B. No. 405.)(

Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Washington:
Section 1. No female person shall be employed in any capacity 
in any saloon, beer hall, bar room theatre, or place of amusement, where
intoxicating liquors are sold as a beverage, and any peron or corporation
convisted of so employing, or of participating in so employing, any such
female person shall be fined not less than five hundred dollars; and any 
person so convicted may be imprisoned in the County Jail for a period of 
not less than six months. 

<pb/>

Passed the house March 1st, 1895

Passed the senate March 14th, 1895

Approved March 19th, 1895

Your Petitioner furhter shows that on the 14th day of March 1895
the senate of the State of Washington, in so far as it had the constitutional
power duly enancted, by a requisite vote, the said Statute; and 
duly and regularly, in so far as it had the constitutional power, by a
requisite vote, concurred in the action of the said house of representatives.

Your petitioner further shows that the said house of representatives
and the said senate constitute the legislative body of the State of 
Washington.

Your petitioner further shows that, within the time required by law
and on to-wit: March 19th 1895, John H. McGraw, Governor of the State
of Washington, duly approved the said Statute in so far as he had the
constitutional power to approve the same.

Your petitioner further shows that, on the 24th day of September 
1895, J. W. Feighan, the duly elected, qualified and acting Prosecuting
Attorney in and for the County of Spokane, State of Washington, filed
in the Superior court of the State of Washington, in and for the County
of Spokane, the following information, to-wit:

State of Washington
County of Spokane 

ss IN THE SUPERIOR COURT, IN AND FOR SAID COUNTY 
AND STATE.

THE STATE OF WASHINGTON
Plaintiff
vs.
JOHN W. CONSIDINE
Defendant.

No. 550.
INFORMATION for employing females 
in a place where intoxicating 
liquors are sold.

<pb/>

I, J. W. Feighan, Prosecuting Attorney in and for the County of
Spokane, and State of Washington, comes here into Court, and in the
name and by the authority of the State of Washington, gives the Court
to understand and be informed that the said defendant John W. Considine
is hereby charged with the crime of employing females in a place where
intoxicating liquors are sold, committed as follows: That on the 16"
day of September A.D. 1895 at the County of Spokane, and State of Washington
John W. Considine then and there being, did then and there unlawfully
knowingly and wrongfully employ and participate in so employing
female persons in a saloon, beer-hall, bar-room, theatre and place of
amusement where intoxicating liquors are sold as a beverage contrary to
the statute in such case made and provided, and against the peace and
dignity of the State of Washington.

J. W. Feighan
Prosecuting Attorney

State of Washington
County of Spokane

ss

J. W. Feighan, being first duly sworn, upon his 
oath says that he is the duly elected, qualified and acting Prosecuting 
Attorney in and for the County of Spokane, State of Washington, that the
foregoing information is true, that he makes said information for the
reason that the Grand Jury is <del>charged</del>not in session and this Court is
in session, and the defendant is on bail charged with a misdemeanor.

J.W. Feighan

Subscribed and sworn to before me this 24th day of September A.D.
189

Kox Johnson
Deputy Clerk.

Names of witnesses known to the Prosecuting Attorney at the time
of filing this information:

Thomas Fleming, Edgar Swartz, A. Miller, Ben Soloman, Peter Rumpff,
W. L. Brooks, A. G. Lane, -- Jacob Files, -- Florence Patterson, -- Mae
Davis, -- Lulu Watts, -- Eva Lester, William Morris, Louis Swartz,

<pb/>

Johson, Ed. Bartholonew, -- J. G. Hinkle, -- &amp; Geo. Dyer
Elmer Bartlett, -- W. d. Knight.

No. 550.

IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF SPOKANE COUNTY, WASHINGTON.

THE STATE OF WASHINGTON
vs.
JOHN W. CONSIDINE

INFORMATION FOR EMploying females Etc.

Filed Sept. 24, 1895

W.E. Willis 
Clerk

Knox Johnson 
Deputy.

J. W. Feighan
Prosecuting Attorney.

Your Petitioner further shows that the pretended information was and
is based upon the Statute herein set forth and descried; that the said
Prosecuting Attorney in said information intended and sought to charge
your Petitioner with the violation of the said statute.

Your Petitioner further shows that a warrant of arrest issued for
your Petitioner and that the he was arraigned upon the said pretended information
and thereupon interposed thereto a demurrer in words and figures
as follows, to-wit:

State of Washington}
County of Spokane }

ss

<pb/>

IN THE SUPERIOR COURT, IN AND FOR
SAID COUNTY AND STATE

THE STATE OF WASHINGTON
Plaintiff
vs.
JOHN W. CONSIDINE
Defendant.

INFORMATION.

No. 550.

For

Employing females in a place
where intoxicating liquors are sold

Comes now the defendant John W. Considine, and demurs to the information
filed x against him in the above entitled cause, on the 26th day
of September, 1895, upon the following grounds:

1st. That said information does not substantially conform to
the requirements of the criminal code of the State of Washington.

2nd. More than one crime is charged and attempted to be charged
therein, in this: that defendant is charged therein with employing
female persons in a saloon, and also in the same information with participating
in employing the same in a saloon

3rd. The facts charged in said information do not constitute
a crime, and said information does not state facts sufficient to constitute
any offense whatsoever against the laws of the State of Washington.

4th. That the facts stated in said information do not show a 
violation of any law of the State of Washington, but, on the contrary,
do show that defendant has never been quilty of any offense against the
laws of the State of Washington.

WHEREFORE, defendant prays to be discharged, and his bond exonerated.

Griffitts and Nuzam
Attorneys for Defendant.

Your Petitioner further shows that the said Demurrer was in due
time by said Superior Court over-ruled, and that thereupon your Petitioner
entered his plea of not guilty to the said information.

Your Petitioner further shows that afterward, to-wit: on the </blank>
L89 the said Cause came on regularly for

<pb/>

trial upon the issue made by the said information herein set out and
described, <del>to</del> and your Petitioner's plea of not guilty duly made thereto,
and thereupon a jury of twelve men were called, empanelled and sworn to
try said cause, and that afterward the said cause proceeded to trial,
witnesses were sworn and examined on the part of the State, after listening
to the argument of Counsel and the instructions of the Court the
said Jury retired to consider of their verdict, and subsequently returned 
into Court and answering to their names said that, they found
your Petitioner guilty as charged.

Your Petitioner further shows to the Court that within the time required
by law <del>the jury</del> he duly and regularly filed his Motion for a new 
trial in said Cause, and that the same was by the said Court over-ruled
and your Petitioner sentened to pay a fine of Five hundred dollars and
costs and to stand committed to the County jail at Spokane until said
fine and costs were paid.

Your Petitioner further shows to the Court that Wtihin the time
required by law your Petitioner prosecuted his appeal, from said judgment,
to the Supreme Court of the State of Washington, the same being
the highest tribunal in said State, and such proceedings were had that
on the 12th day of January 1897 the said Cause came on duly and regularly
for hearing in the Supreme Court of the State of Washington; the said
State of Washington appearing by J. W. Feighan, Prosecuting Attorney
for Spokane County, and Patrick <add>Henry</add> Winston, Attorney General, and the
said John W. Considine appearing by his Attorney John Wiley, the said
Cause was duly argued and submitted to the said Court; and that afterward,
to-wit: on the 26th day of January 1897 the said Court duly and regularly 
handed down its opinion in said Cause, <del>approving</del> affirmming the judgment of the
Superior court of the State of Washington, for the County of Spokane:
that afterward, and within the time required by law, to-wit: on the 25th 
day of February 1897 Your Petitioner duly filed, in said Cause, his petition
for re-hearing, and that on the 24th day of April 1897 the said
Supreme Court of the State of Washington denied the said petition for
re-hearing and remanded the said Cause to the Superior Court of the State

6

<pb/>

in and for the County of Spokane; that afterwards, on the 5 day 
of May 1897 the Remittitur of the Supreme Court of the State of Washington,
ins said Cause was duly and regularly filed in the office of the Clerk
of the Superior court of the State of Washington, in and for the County of Spokane.

Your Petitioner further shows that afterward, and on to-wit: the
</blank> day of May 1897 a warrant of arrest and committment for the arrest
<add>and commitment</add> of your Petitioner, upon said judgment, issued out of the Superior Court
of the State of Washingotn, in and for the County of Spokane, under the
<del>of</del> hand of the Clerk of said Court, and the seal thereof, and was delivered
to the Sheriff of Spokane County, Washington, directing the said Sheriff 
to take into his custody and detain <add>and imprison</add> your Petitioner in the County jail
of said County until the said judgment and costs were fully paid.

Your Petitioner further shows that, under and by virtue of said
warrant of commitment the said Sheriff of Spokane County, Washington, arrested
and now detains your Petitioner in imprisonment by virtue of
said warrant of commitment and not otherwise.

Your Petitioner further shows that his detention and imprisonment
as aforesaid are illegal in this, to-wit:

1st. That the sentence under which your Petitioner is held is 
illegal and void.

2nd. That the commitment under which your Petitioner is held
is illegal and void.

3rd. That the Court was without jurisdiction to impose the
particular sentence under which your Petitioner is held.

4th. That the Court was without jursidiction or power to sentence
your Petitioner to imprisonment for the offense of which he was
concicted.

5th. That your Petitioner's imprisonment and detention under
said sentence is contrary to the laws of the United States.

6th. That the said pretended Statute under which said prosecution
was brought is illegal, null and void and is unconstitutional, in 
this, to-wit; that it is in direct violation of

<pb/>

First,-- Section 3 of Article One of the Constitution of the State of 
Washington, which is as follows:
No person shall be deprived of life, liberty or property without due
process of law."

Second,-- Section Twelve, Article one of the Constitution of the State
of Washington, which is as follows:

"No law shall be passed granting to any citizen or class of citizens or 
corporation, other than municipal, privileges or immunities which upon
the same terms shall not equally belong to all citizens or corporations"

Third,-- The Fourteenth Amendment to the Constitution of the United
States, which is as follows:

"All persons born in the United States, and subject to the jurisdiction 
thereof, are citizens of the United States, and of the State wherein
they reside. No State Shall make or enforce any law which shall abridge
the privileges or immunities of citizens of the United States. Nor
shall any State deprive any person of life, liberty or property without
due process of law, nor deny to any person within its jurisdiction the 
equal protection of the law"

Wherefore to be relieved of said unlawful detention and imprisonment
your Petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus, to be directed to
C. C. Dempsey, Sheriff of Spokane 
County, Washington, may issue in this behalf, so your Petitioner may
be forthwith brought before this Court to do, submit to, and recieved what
the law may direct.

John W. Considine
by John Wiley on his behalf

Wiley &amp; <unclear>Bont</unclear>
Attorney for Petitioner.

State of Washington}
County of King.}

ss






































</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>