<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0117.022"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Lelah-Puc-ka-Chee and Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha v. W.G. Malin and G.N. Nellis. Petition for Writ of Habeas-Corpus</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0117.022</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Lelah-Puc-ka-Chee and Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha v. W.G. Malin and G.N. Nellis. Petition for Writ of Habeas-Corpus</title>
<date when="1899-11-08">November, 1899</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1899-12">December 1899</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Healy</term>
<term>Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee</term>
<term>Malin, W.G.</term>
<term>Nellis, G.N.</term>
<term>Shiras, O.P.</term>
<term>Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Kansas City</term>
<term>Tama County, Iowa</term>
<term>Toledo, Iowa</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Malin, W.G.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Nellis, G.N.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Lamb, Jacob W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Shiras, O.P.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court in Northern District Iowa</orgName> 
<placeName>Toledo, Iowa</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="sab">transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0117.022"/> 

<p>Copied at the National Archives at Kansas City</p>

<p>reside on their reservation with the other SAC and fox Indians in Tama County Iowa. That said Sac and Fox Indians have always been and are still Tribal Indians and a community entirely dependent on the United States Government. That by the laws of the Federal Government the said Tribal Indians retain and control all their moral, social,and domestic relations under their tribal laws and costumes, independent of the laws of the State of Iowa. That the defendant, W,G, Malin was on the first of march 1899 and is still the United States Indian agent of said Indians, and that the defendant G,N,NELLIS on the first day of September 1898 was and still is the superintendent of the United States Indian School at Toledo Iowa. That the defendants wilfully, n unlawfully, and maliciously conspiring together or the unlawful prupose of depriving your petitioners of each other,s society,and for the further unlawful purpose of depriving your petitioner, LELAH-PUC-KA-CHEE, of her liberty and marital rights, did on about november the first 1899 cause a special subpoena to issue in a certain case then pending in the case of the State of Iowa VS one James Peters, and further caused the said subpoena to be served on the petitioner, LELAH-PUC-KA-CHEE, as a witness in behalf of the State, for the wilful and premeditated, and unlawful purpose of siezing her body, That afterwards, on the first. day of november 1899, while your petitioners, were attending court in Toledo Iowa in obedience to said subpoena, the defendants, wilfully, unlawfully, corruptly and maliciously, caused your petitioners to be unlawfully and violently assaulted with force and violence, with intent to commit great bodily injury; And that by threats of sending your petitioner, TA-TA-PI-CHA, to jail for one year nad by wounds and injuries then and there unlawfully inflicted on the bodies of your petitioners, finally succeeded in subdueing your petitioners, and by force and main strength further succeeded in separating your petitioners, and against</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
