<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0225.012">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Thomas L. Thurston v. O.P. Halligan. Writ Denied</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0225.012</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Thomas L. Thurston v. O.P. Halligan. Writ Denied</title>
<date when="1916">1916</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1916-01">January 6, 1916</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Thomas L. Thurston</term> 
<term>Clay Allen</term> 
<term>J. Henry Denning</term> 
<term>Jeremiah Neterer</term> 
<term>Frank L. Crosby</term> 
<term>E. Lakin</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>United States District Court, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</term> 
<term>Territory of Alaska</term> 
<term>McNeil Island, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Thomas L. Thurston</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>O.P. Halligan</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>J. Henry Denning</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Clay Allen</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName><!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>Western District of Washington, Northern Division</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-02" who="#AS">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION</p> 
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE PETITION
OF THOMAS L. THURSTON, 
FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS }</p>
<p>No. 3128.
Filed January 6, 1916.</p> 

<p>WRIT DENIED.</p>  

<p>J. Henry Denning, of Seattle, Washington,  For Petitioner.
Clay Allen, U.S. District Attorney, For Government.
NETERER, District Judge:</p> 
<p>Petitioner was indicted in the District Court for the Dis-
trict of the Territory of Alaska, Fourth Judicial District, for
violation of Section 195 of the Criminal Code; was arraigned, 
pleaded not guilty, and upon trial before a jury was found guilty
as charged in the indictment. The defendant was sentenced to one
year and three months imprisonment in the federal prison at McNeil 
Island in this district. He has filed his petition for a writ 
of habeas corpus, alleging that he is unlawfully restrained of
his liberty by the warden of the prison, and prays that he be
released and discharged. He claims, First, that no commitment
was issued upon which he can be legally held, Section 1028 Rev-
ised Statutes U.S; and Second, that no judgment was, entered upon
which he could be legally sentenced.</p>
<p>The first objection is answered by the Supreme Court, In Re
Wilson, 114 U.S. 417, in which the court held that a certified
copy of the record of sentence to imprisonment is sufficient to
authorize the retention of the prisoner without any warrant or
mittimus. In the instant case the United States Marshal was dir-
ected in the order of sentence to take the prisoner in custody
and deliver him to the United States penitentiary at McNeil Island
in which he was sentenced to be confined for the time given, and
a certified copy of the order and record of conviction was deliv-
ered to the warden of the prison. The second objection is disposed
<pb></pb> 
by the Supreme Court in Pointer v. U.S., 151 U.S. 396, 
which holding was followed in Sandy White v. U.S., 164 U.S.
100. The specific objection of the petitioner is that the order
of sentence does not state the offense of which he was convicted
or that he was guilty of any crime. Judgment entered recites 
as follows:</p>
<p>"And the court having asked the defendants and each
of them if there was any reason or cause why judgment
should not be pronounced, and it appearing to the court
that no reasonable cause exists why judgment should not
be pronounced, NOW, THEREFORE, it is the judgment should not
the law and the sentence of this court that the judgment of
Thomas L. Thurston be confined in the United States Peni-
tentiary at McNeil Island for a period of one year and 
three months, and that he be committed to the United
States Marshal for the Fourth Division, Territory of
Alaska, for the execution of this sentence, and said mar-
shal is hereby ordered to take said defendant Thomas L. 
Thurston in custody and deliver him to the United States
penitentiary at McNeil Island, State of Washington as in
this judgment provided."</p> 
<p>This judgment is certified by the Clerk of the Court.</p> 
<p>From the facts as disclosed by the record in this case, 
it is clear that the crime for which the prisoner was indicted
and all the proceedings thereon through trial and verdict up to
conviction and sentence, fully appear in the record, and all
parts of the record must be considered together, and if a defi-
ciency in one place can be made up by giving effect to other por-
tions of the record, it must be done, 1st Bishop Criminal Procedure, 
Sections 1347-1348, Pointer v; U.S., supra, and the failure in 
the sentence to name the crime for which the prisoner is sentenced 
is not fatal where this is supplied by reference to other parts 
of the record of the trial, Pointer v. U.S. supra, and this mani-
festly appears from the record in this case.</p> 
<p>The petition for writ will be denied.</p>  
<pb></pb>
<p>No. 3128.</p> 
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT 
OF THE UNITED STATES 
FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
Northern Division.</p> 
<p>FILED IN THE 
U.S. District Court, 
Western Dist. of Washington, 
NORTHERN DIVISION 
JAN 6 - 1916
FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk, 
By Edm Deputy 
2x</p>  


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>