<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0177.015.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">May 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Bajlo, Jack</term>
<term>Bajlo, Tonka</term>
<term>Brockway, E. B.</term>
<term>Bryan, Fenley</term>    
<term>Cushman, Edward</term>
<term>Ennis, Charles H.</term>
<term>Riddell, C. F.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Austria</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Tonka Bajlo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Charles H. Ennis</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>C. F. Riddell</persName>
<persName>E. B. Brockway</persName>    
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Edward Cushman</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>No. 2459</p>

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT 
OF THE UNITED STATES
FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION
OF TONKA BAJLO FOR A WRIT
OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>

<p>DECISION</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington.</p>
<p>May 14, 1913</p>
<ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk,
by EML Deputy</ab>
<pb/> 
    
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES,
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION 
OF TONKA BAJLO FOR A WRIT OF 
HABEAS CORPUS. ) </p>
<p>NO. 2459
FILED May 14, 1913.</p>

<p>CUSHMAN, District Judge.</p>
<p>Petitioner seeks discharge from the custody of the 
Commissioner of Immigration upon an application for a writ 
of habeas corpus. In the petition it is alleged that she was
arrested upon a warrant issued by the Secretary of Labor, 
charging her with bein "an alien found practicing prostitution
after entry"; that, at the hearing held April 7, 1913, the
said Tonka Bajlo was compelled to testify against herself upon
a criminal charge; that she was not informed that she had a
right to refuse to testify against herself; that she had no
opportunity to present evidence for or on her behalf; that, on
the evidence produced at said hearing, the Secretary of Labor 
ordered that she be deported from this country to Austria from 
whence she came upon a criminal charge, that of practicing 
prostitution after entry into this country; That she does not
understand the English language and did not understand the 
nature of the proceeding against her, and when informed of 
the result thereof she demanded that she have counsel and a 
rehearing; that the order for her deportation has been made 
by the Honorable Secretary of Labor without an opportunity 
for a hearing before the Commissioner of Immigration at the
Port of Seattle; that she is imprisoned and restrained of her
liberty by reason of false charges made and instigated against
her by Jack Bajlo, her husband, who is seeking to wreak revenge
<pb/>
upon her because of the fact that she refused to live with 
him by virtue of his inhuman treatment of her and his constant
and continuous brutal acts of cruelty.</p>
<p>The foregoing allegations are denied by the return. 
It is alleged affirmatively that, upon an affidavit charging
petitioner "with being an alien found in the United States
in violation of the Act of Congress approved February 20,
1907, and amended by the Act of March 26, 1910, to-wit:- That
she was an alien found practicing prostitution after her entry
into the United States", a warrant was issued by the
Secretary of Labor, upon such evidence, being satisfied that 
petitioner was subject to deportation under the laws of the 
United States, ordered her deported to the country from whence
she came. A copy of the evidence taken upon the hearing is
made a part of the return to the writ.</p>
<p>The jurisdiction of the court to review the acts of 
the Secretary of Labor is denied. The matter is now submitted 
to the court upon the sufficiency of the return to the writ.</p>

<p>C. F. Riddel, United States 
Attorney, and E. B. Brockway, 
Assistant United States 
Attorney,</p>
<p>For Respondent, Immigration
Commissioner,</p>
<p>Charles H. Ennis,</p>
<p>For Petitioner.</p>

<p>The petitioner relies upon the following authorities:</p>
<p>Chin Yow vs. U. S., 208 U.S., 8;
Davis vs. Manolis, 179 Fed., 818;
United States ex rel. Bosny et al. vs. 
Williams, 185 Fed., 598;
Ex parte Koerner, 176 Fed., 478;
United States ex rel. Huber vs. Sibray,
178 Fed., 145;
United States ex rel. Nicola vs. Williams,
173 Fed., 626;
Zakonaite vs. Wolf, 33 Sup. Ct. R.,
33;
Davies vs. Manolis, 179 Fed. 818;</p>
<pb/>
<fw>-2-</fw>
<p>In addition to certain authorities cited by petitioner, 
respondent relies upon the following authorities:-</p>
<p>DeBruller v. Gallo, 184 Fed., 566;
United States v. Ju Toy, 198 U.S., 253; 
49 Law Ed., 1040;
Bottlier v. Donseuguey, 130 U.S., 238.</p>
<p>The warrant upon which petitioner was arrested
gave a ground therefor that she was "a prostitute adn 
has been found practicing prostitution subsequent to her entry
into the United States". The warrant of deportation,
after hearing had, recites, as additional grounds therefor, 
that petitioner was "a person liable to become a public charge 
at the time of entry." The Commissioner of Immigration also 
found from the evidence taken at the hearing that petitioner 
was "of the excluded classsesat the time of entry; i.e., a 
person who admits having committed an offense involving moral
turpitude."</p>
<p>It is argued that petitioner had no hearing because
the warrant upon which she was arrested did not contain 
these two letter grounds. So far as this case is concerned, 
that may be conceded, for it was found, and the warrant or 
deportation does recite as a ground therefor, the charge and 
recital in the warrant of arrest that she was a prostitute 
and had been found practicing prostitution Therefore, petitioner
cannot complain that she was arbitrarily deprived of 
a fair hearing on the latter charges and ordered deported, 
unless there was no evidence to support that first charge.</p>
<p>It is claimed that petitioner's husband made the
affidavit upon which she was arrested and testified against
her before the Immigration officer through spite and jealously;
that the admissions and testimony taken upon the hearing, both 
of petitioner and other witnesses, were misunderstood and misinterpreted.
These arguments, themselves, show that a hearing
was had and evidence given, that petitioner, herself, admits
requires explanation. Even if it were conceded that the 
<pb/>
record of the evidence may be attacked by the affidavits of 
witnesses afterwards, nothing is shown in the way of mistake
in the evidence that would justify the conclusion that the
order of deportation was controlled by the disputed testimony.</p>
<p>The evidence shows that petitioner had a hearing; 
that she waived representation by counsel, in effect, because
she did not deem that she could afford to employ an attorney,
and her petition, itself, shows that she only requested an 
opportunity to have an attorney after she learned of the decision.</p>
<p>No oppressive nor unfair means appear to have been
employed. There was evidence adduced at the hearing sufficient
to support the finding and order.</p>
<p>Complaint is made that the Immigration officer 
included in his report an expression of his opinion, formed 
from an examination of the house in which petitioner lived
with a number of men, that the conditions he found had led 
him to believe that she must have engaged in the practice of 
prostitution.</p>
<p>Without deciding the effect of this, in the absence
of any hearing on this subject, in the case, it is sufficient 
to say that petitioner was fully heard concerning this house
and her life therein. If there was any explanation to be made, 
she had an opportunity to make it. The court will not 
undertake to review the action of the Secretary of Labor on the 
ground that immaterial or irrelevant evidence was admitted, 
even if that of which complaint is made is considered to be
such. It is sufficient to say that the petitioner was not 
being tried upon a criminal charge, which is a complete 
answer to the other grounds set out in her petition.</p>
<p>If it were conceded that the husband of petitioner 
was acting against her through malice, that is a matter that 
would affect the weight and credibility of his evidence ---matters
solely to be considered by the Secretary and within his
discretion---and not going to its competency. The husband's
<pb/>
sworn testimony must be considered as evidence.</p>
<p>The order to show cause is discharged.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>