<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0222.022">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Francis Stephen Medcraf vs. Robert T. Hodge. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
    

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0222.022</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Francis Stephen Medcraf vs. Robert T. Hodge. Criminal.</title>
<date></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Francis Stephen Medcraf</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Robert T. Hodge</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
                  
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-07" who="#rp">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE PETITION
OF FRANCIS STEPHEN MEDCRAF
FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS. )
No. 3038
Petition.</p>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE JEREMIAH NETERER, JUDGE OF SAID COURT;  </p>
<p>The petition of Francis Stephen Medcraf respectfully 
shows;</p>
<p>That he is forty-(40) years of age and has declared
his intention to become a citizen of the United States.</p>
<p>That your petitioner is unlawfully imprisoned, detained, 
confined and restrained of his liberty by ROBERT T. HODGE,who is 
the Sheriff of and for -----------------, King County, Washington at 
Seattle in said state in this district.</p>
<p>That the said imprisonment, detention, confinement and 
restraint are illegal and that the illegality thereof consists in 
this, to-wit:</p>
<p>That on the 18th day of May A. D. 1915, one H. F. 
Conover did make and file in writing, under oath, a compaint before 
<add>Justice</add> Reah M. Whitehead who was then and still is a Justice of 
the Peace in the State of Washington in and for Seattle Precinct in 
the County of King, which said complaint charged this petitioner 
with having on the third day of May 1915 committed the crime of
"practicing dentistry without a certificate as follows:</p>
<p>He, said John Doe Medcraf" (meaning this petitioner)
"in the county of King, state of Washington, on the 3rd day of May,
1915, did then and there wilfully and unlawfully practice dentistry
and did then and there perform operations and parts of operations,
and did then and there treat diseases and lesions of the human teeth
and jaws of said H.F. Conover, said H. F. Conover then and there
being a human being, and did then and there receive from said H. F.
Conover, in payment therefor, the sum of two dollars ($2), without
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
having first filed for record and having recorded in the office of 
the Auditor of the county wherein he then and there practiced, to wit,
in the office of the Auditor of King County, State of Washington, a 
certificate from the Board of Dental Examiners of the State of 
Washington, authorizing him to so practice as provided by law,
contrary to the form of the statute in such case made and provided,
and against the peace and dignity of the State of Washington.</p>
<ab>(Signed) H. F. Conover</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 18th day of May 1915</p>
<ab>(Signed) Reah M. Whitehead
Justice of the Peace, Seattle Precinct,
King County, Washington."</ab>
<p>That thereupon the 21st day of May the said Reah M. 
Whitehead as such Justice of the Peace, issued a warrant in the name
of the State of Washington in words and figures as follows:-</p>
<p>"WARRANT OF ARREST"</p>
<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON
COUNTY OF KING ) SS
IN JUSTICE COURT, SEATTLE PRECINCT</p>
<p>To the Sheriff or Any Constable of said County:</p>
<p>Whereas H. F. Conover has this day complained in writing,
under oath, to the undersigned one of the Justices of the Peace in 
and for said County, that on the 3rd day of May 1915 in said County
and State, John Doe Medcraf did commit the crime of Practicing 
dentistry without a certificate.</p>
<p>Therefore, in the name of the State of Washington, you are
commanded forthwith to apprehend the said John Doe Medcraf and bring
him before me to be dealt with according to law.</p>
<p>Given under my hand this 21st day of May 1915.</p>
<ab>(Signed) Reah M. Whitehead
Justice of the Peace."</ab>

<fw>-2-</fw>

<pb/>

<p>And thereupon on that day your petitioner was arested by authority
of said warrant, by Edward Shrewsbury, a constable, and taken before
said Justice of the Peace who thereupon required him to give bail for 
his appearance to answer to said charge on the 3rd day of June 1915
at 1-30 o'clock P? M. and to stand committed to the county jail i 
default of such bail. That petitioner gave such bail and on said date
his trial was<add>c</add>ontinued until June 9th 1915 at 1-30 o'clock P. M. at
which time he duly appeared before said Justice and moved to quash said
writ and discharge petitioner upon the grounds and all thereof
hereinafter stated;- towit, the unconstitutionality of the statutes of 
the State of Washington hereinafter set forth as hereinafter specified.
Said motions being denied, the Court holding said laws to be 
valid and constitutional, received evidence and all the facts 
hereinafter recited were fully shown. Thereupon the said court found 
petitioner guilty as charged and adjudged him to pay a fine of $
and to stand committed until such fine be paid, to the County Jail
of King County, <add>not exceeding 20 days,</add> and thereupon issued the warrant of commitment in 
pursuance of said judgment and your petitioner is now in custod 
thereunder and is so detained by the Sheriff of King County 
Washington (Annotated) whish are as follows;</p>
    <p>"8416. (3025*) Examinations-Certificate.</p>
<p>Any person or persons seeking to practice dentistry
in the state of Washington, or to (own) , operate or cause to be
operated, (or to run or manage) a dental office or place for the 
practice of dentistry in the state of Washington after the passage of this 
act shall file his or her name, together with an application for 
examination, with the secretary of the state board of dental examiners,
and at the time of making such application shall pay to the secretary\
of the board a fee of twenty-five dollars. and to present him
or herself at the first regular meeting thereafter of said board to 
undergo examination before that body. No person shall be eligible
for such an examination unless he or she shall be of good moral
character and shall present to said board his or her diploma from 
some dental college in good standing and shall give satisfactory 
evidence of his or her rightfu possession of the same: Provided, 
this section shall not apply to persons engaged in the practice of 
dentistry at the time of the passage of this act who are bona fide 
citizens of the state of Washington. All persons successfully passing 
such examination shall beregistered as licensed dentists in the 
board register as hereinafter provided, and also receive a certificate,
said certificate to be signed by the president and secretary 
of said board and in <unclear/></p>
<p>This is to certify that  is hereby licensed to practice
dentistry in the state of Washington. This certificate must be 
filled for record in the offie of the auditor of any county in 
which the party holding such certificate desires to practice, and 
it is unlawful for him (or her) to practice dentistry in any county 
in which said certificate is not filed for record.</p>
<p>Dated at this day of , A. D. 190 . </p>

<ab>((President of said board of examiners.)
           (Secretary of said board.)</ab>

<pb/>

<p>"8417. (3026) Certificate to be Recorded.</p>
<p>The certificates in this chapter provided for shall entitle 
the holder thereof to practice dentistry in any county in the state 
of Washington: Provided, such certificate shall first be filed for 
record in the office of the auditor of the county in which such 
holder desires to practice, and nothing herein contained shall be 
construed to permit any holder of any certificate to practice in any 
county in this state unless such certificate shall have been first 
recorded in the office of the auditor of such county as herein 
provided: Provided further, that any such holder of a certificate may 
practice in more than one or any number of counties in this state 
on having such certificate recorded in each of such counties in 
which such holder desires to so practice. Said board of dental 
examiners shall, upon satisfac</p>
 


















</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
