<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0375.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ichitaro Akagi v. Luther Weedin. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="ka">Salma J. Silva</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0375.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ichitaro Akagi v. Luther Weedin. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1922-03-03">March 3, 1922</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1922-03">March 1922</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Weedin, Luther</term>
<term>Martin, Winter S.</term>
<term>Harshberger, F. M.</term>
<term>Leitch, S. E.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Japan</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Akagi, Ichitaro</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Weedin, Luther</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Martin, Winter S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-10" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT</p>
<p>WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>No. 6612</p>

<p>PETITION FOR WRIT
OF HABEAS CORPUS</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION
OFAKAGI, ICHITARO,
For Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>AKAGI, ICHITARO, Petitioner
vs.
LUTHER WEEDIN, Commissioner of Immigration, Respondent</p>

<p>Comes now Ichitaro Akagi, by his attorney, Winter S.
Martin, and respectfully shows to the Court:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That your petitioner is a citizen of the Empire of Japan,
who came to the United States on board the Japanese Steamer,
"Eastern Glen", arriving at the Port of Seattle, on May 9th, 1920,
as a seaman on said boat.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>That on the day of his arrival your petitioner deserted
his said ship at the Port of Seattle, and thereafter remained in
the United States and in the State of Washington until he was
arrested and taken into custody as hereinafter set forth.</p>

<p>III.</p>

<p>That on the 31st day of January, 1922 a warrant for his
arrest was issued by the Department of Labor on the ground that he
was a laborer unlawfully in the United States without a passport</p>

<p>-1-</p>

<pb/>

<p>in violation of Rule 11 and the Presidential Proclomation of
February 24th, 1913, and that he was person likely to become a
public charge at the time of entry. That on said day your peti-
tioner was arrested and taken into custody by the Immigration
Officers of the United States at the Port of Seattle where he
since has been and now is, to-wit, at the United States Immigra-
tion Station at Seattle aforesaid.</p>

<p>IV.</p>

<p>That thereafter by Departmental Order of February 25th,
1922, your petitioner was ordered deported to the Empire of Japan
upon a ship which will leave the Port of Seattle at 10:00 o'clock
A.M. March 4th, 1922, to-wit, tomorrow morning. That the grounds
for deportation are that your petitioner is a Japanese laborer, who
is and was unlawfully in the United States without a passport, and
that he was a person likely to become a public charge, all in
violation of the President's proclomation and the Immigration Laws
and Rules in that particular provided.</p>

<p>V.</p>

<p>That your petitioneer alleges that Rule 11 of the Immigra-
tion Rules adopted and promulgated on May 1, 1917, do not apply
to petitioner in and for the reason and the President's Proclomation
of February 24th, 1913 only touches and applies to those alien 
laborers, who have and had passports limited to some Country or
place other than the Continental United States, and who seek to
enter the United States from said Country; that is to say that
said proclomation does not touch or reach persons coming directly
into the United States from the Empire of Japan, and that there is
no law requiring a laborer or any other person coming directly from
Japan to the United States to have a passport;</p>

<p>-2-</p>

<pb/>

<p>VI.</p>

<p>That in addition to the matters and things hereinbefore
alleged, your petitioner alleges that the American Consul at the
Port of departure upon the voyage upon which petitioner entered the
United States, visaed the crew list of said ship. That your petition-
er was a seaman member of said ship, duly entered upon her Articles.
That in visaing the crew list your petitioner was not required by law
to have any other or further passport to enter the United States.
That as a seaman he was entitled to enter the United States and be
and remain in the United States until he had taken ship to other 
Ports or places in the world. That deportation is not sought in
this case upon any of said grounds.</p>

<p>VII.</p>

<p>That by reason of the premises your petitioner is illegally
restrained from his liberty by Luther Weedin and his deputies,
officers and inspectors of the United States Immigration Service at
the Port of Seattle. That said Weedin and said officers are threaten-
ing to deport your petitioner herewith. That unless said Weedin and
said Immigration Officers, deputies and inspectors are enjoined by
order of this Court, they will execute their threat and your
petitioner will be deported to the Empire of Japan and be without
relief.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE your petitioner prays:</p>

<p>1. That a Writ of Habeas Corpus may be issued to your
said petitioner and that he may be discharged from said illegal restraint and unlawful arrest;</p>

<p>2. That pending a hearing upon an application for this
Writ of Habeas Corpus that said Luther Weedin, Commissioner of
Immigration, and his deputies, be hereby enjoined and restrained</p>

<p>-3-</p>

<pb/>

<p>from deporting your petitioner from Seattle to the Empire of Japan;</p>

<p>3. That an order show cause issue forthwith directed
to the said Luther Weedin, Commissioner of Immigration, requiring
him to be and appear in the above entitled Court, at a time to be
fixed by this Honorable Court, to show cause, if any he has,</p>

<p>Ichitaro Akagi,</p>
<p>Petitioner</p>

<p>Winter S Martin</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner</p>

<pb/>

<p>State of Washington
County of King</p>

<p>ss.</p>

<p>AKAGI, ICHITARO being first duly sworn
on oath says: That he is the Petitioner
in the above entitled action; that he has had the foregoing
petition read to him by an interperter
knows the contents thereof and believes the same to be true.</p>

<p>Ichitaro Akagi</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 3rd day of March 1922</p>

<p><unclear>Ren Harvey</unclear></p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle, Washington</p>

<p>No.</p>

<p>In the United States
District Court
FOR THE
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLI-?
CATION OF AKAGI, ICHITARO,</p>

<p>FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS
CORPUS</p>

<p>Petition for A Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>FILED IN THE
UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Mar 3 1922</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<p>ALLEN, MARTIN &amp; WARDALL</p>
<p>WINTER S. MARTIN</p>

<p>ATTORNEY for PETITIONER</p>

<p>703-4-5-10 NEW YORK BLOCK
SEATTLE</p>
<p>MAIN 7465</p>

<p>Copy of within petition
received and due service of the same acknowl-
edged this <gap></gap>
day of March 1922</p>

<p>Attorney--
Proctor---

for Respondent</p>

<p>Service of all subsequent papers in the 
within named action, except writs and pro-
cess, may be made upon <gap></gap>
by serving the
same upon the udnersigned, as</p>

<p>Attorneys
Proctors</p>

<p>for said <gap></gap>
at 704 New York Block, Seattle, Washington.</p>

<p>ALLEN, MARTIN &amp; WARDALL</p>

<p>Attorneys
Proctors</p>

<p>for said <gap></gap></p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>