<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0199.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Rudolph Tschahle v. Henry M. White. Return and Answer of Respondent</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0199.005</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Rudolph Tschahle v. Henry M. White. Return and Answer of Respondent</title>
<date when="1918-12-30">December 30, 1918</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1918-12">December 1918</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fisher, Thomas M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Tschale, Rudolph</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Moore, Ben L.</persName>
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2019-11" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="#hc.case.0199.005"/>

<p>No. 4476</p>

<p>In the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Rudolf Tschable for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Dec 30 1918</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>

<p>By S.E. Lietch Deputy</p>

<p>No. 4476 Return and Answer of Respondent Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Rudolph Tschable for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Comes now the respondent herein Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration, at Seattle, Washington, and responding to the order to show cause heretofore entered by the court herein and answering the petition of the above named applicantfor a Writ of Habeas Corpus, herein respectfully certifies and shows to the court as follows:</p>
<p> That this respondent denies each and every allegation of the petition or complaint herein of the above named applicant, except as hereinafter admitted, and this respondent further certifies and respectfully shows to the court as follows:</p>
<p>1. That Henry M. White is now and at all of the times mentioned herein and mentioned in the petitioner's complaint has been United States Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington.</p>
<p>2. That the said petitioner Rudolf Tschable, alias Rudlof Czable, was duly and regularly arrested and detained under and by virtue of a warrant of arrest duly and regularly issued by the Secretary of Labor on January 25,1918, which said warrant is included herein and shown as a part of Exhibit A, hereinafter referred to and hereto attached and made a part hereof; that the said petitioner was thereafter duly and regularly detained in custody under and by virtue of arrest until the issuance and service of the warrant of the Secretary of Labor for the deportation of said petitioner.</p>
<p>3. That on, to wit: the 30th day of April, 1918, the said petitioner was examined by and had a hearing beforethe United States Immigration Inspector Thomas M. Fisher with relation to the matters and facts set forth in said warrant of arrest.</p>
<p>4. That on said hearing the said Inspector found that said petitioner, an alien, was a person likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry into the United States and recommended the deportation of said alien. That on, to wit, the 8th day of August, 1918, the Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, concurred in the said finding and recommendation of the said Immigration Inspector.</p>
<p>5. That on the 14th day of December, 1918, upon due consideration of the proceedings and hearings of said petitioner and alien that warrant of deportation was duly and regularly issued by the Secretary of Labor and that ever since the issuance and service of said warrant for deportation the said petitioner has been detained under and by virtue <del>of</del> thereof.</p>
<p>6. That the said petitioner, Rudolf Tschable, has had a full and fair hearing as provided by law and that a record of he proceedings had with relation to the deportation of said petitioner <del>of said</del> as aforesaid including transcript of testimony adduced in said proceedings, and including the said warrant of arrest and the said warrant of deportation is hereto attached marked Exhibit A. and by reference made a part hereof.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE this respondent prays that said order to show cause be discharged and that the said application for a writ of habeas corpus be denied.</p>

<p>John H Sargent</p>
<p>Atty Commissioner of Immigration</p>

<p>Robert C. Saunders</p>
<p>United States Attorney.</p>

<p>Ben L. Moore</p>
<p>Assistant United States Attorney</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>