<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1891">1891</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-06" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
NORTHERN DIVISION.

In the Matter of the Application of 
Adolph Krug, for a Writ of Habeas 
Corpus.

Filed March 10, 1897.

It is shown by the petition in this case that the petitioner 
was prosecuted under the laws of the State of Washington, for the
crime of embezzlement of public moneys received by him in the
capacity of city treasurer of the city of Seattle; that he was convicted
and sentenced to serve a term in the state penitentiary; that
the judgment against him has been affirmed by the Supreme Court of
the State of Washington; that he sued out a writ of error from the
Supreme Court of the United States for the purpose of having his
case reviewed in that court, but the case was dismissed without
hearing upon the merits. The application of a writ of habeas corpus
is based upon the ground that the indictment upon which he
was tried is invalid because it does not set forth facts sufficient
to constitute a crime, and does not apprise him of the particular
accusation against him, and because the indictment is insufficient
he alleges that he is being deprived of his liberty without due 
process of law, and deprived of the equal protection of the laws,
contrary to the provisions of the constitution of the United States.

James Hamilton Lewis, Attorney for Petitioner.
HANFORD, District Judge:- (Orally)

If this petition tendered an
issue of fact upon which the right of the petitioner depended, I 

<pb/>

(1-1/2)

would be bound to grant the writ and allow an issue to be joined,
and to hear the testimony and determine the question of fact in
the usual manner. But where it appears plainly as a matter of
law on the facts alleged in the petition that issuance of a writ
of Habeas Corpus would be an unwarranted interference on the part
of this court with the execution of the laws of the state, I cannot
conceive that it is the duty of the court to issue the writ. This 
application is something more than an application to the court to
issue a summons or a notice to bring in the opposite party to join
issue here. It is an application to this court to issue a writ

by which to take the defendant out of the custody of the sheriff
of the county, who has him in custody, pursuant to a final adjudication
of a court of competent jurisdiction; and before issuing
a writ to interfere with the execution of the laws of the state,
the court should properly inquire into the facts or require the
facts to be set forth in the application, so that the court can
see that there is a proper case to be investigated in this manner.
There are cases wherein individuals complain of being deprived of 
their liberty in violation of the constitution or a law of the
United States, where it is shown that the state authorities are
attempting to punish a man for an act which is right under the
constitution and laws of the United States, sometimes

<pb/>

(2)

times for performing a duty pursuant to a law of the United States.
Such a case is the Neagle case. In every such case as that the
federal court will not require the petitioner to go through the
form of a trial in the state court, but will at once issue its process
to afford him the protection of the constitution and laws of
the United States, without any hesitation, without any delay, and 
without requiring him to submit himself to the jurisdiction of the
state court. There are other instances in which individuals seek
the process of a federal court by writ of habeas corpus to protect
them against infringement of rights claimed under the constitution
and laws of the United States, where they do not pretend that the
act for which the authorities are proceeding to punish them or deprive 
them of their liberty is a lawful act, but they complain that
the manner in which the officers are proceeding is in violation of
the constitution and laws of the United States. Such an instance
as that is the Frederick case, where Mr. Frederick by his petition
to this court set forth that he was convicted of the crime of murder,
and had been sentenced to be imprisoned in the penitentiary for
a period of twenty years, and he complained that the manner in
which the authorities had arrived at this judgment was contrary to
the provisions of the constititution and laws of the United States,
and therefore he was entitled to be protected by the federal court.
Now, in cases of that kind the supreme court has laid down the rule 
in the Royal case and adhered to it in the Frederick case, that the
court to which the application is made has a right to exercise its 
discretion whether to grant the writ in the first instance or wait
until the party has been arraigned in the state tribunal and been
tried, and then after a conviction to wait until he has exercised
his right to a review in the appellate court by a writ of error.
The reason why the court is authorized to exercise this discretion
is that in the one case no matter what the determination of the 
state court may be, the act itself cannot be punished without coming

<pb/>

(3)

in conflict with the constitution and laws of the United States,
while in the other case the mere form and manner of procedure can
be as well determined and the rights of the parties presumably will
be as well protected and guarded by proceedings according to the
state laws, in the state courts, as in the federal court, and instead
of the federal court attempting to draw to itself the whole 
of the criminal practice of the state by listening to peitions
setting forth that they have reason to fear that they are going
to be proceeded with in an irregular manner, and they are not wiling 
to trust the state court, and therefore the federal court
should exercise its power by the writ of habeas corpus to take the
matter up and take their cases out of the state courts entirely.
From the difference in the nature of the applications which may be
made to the federal court arises the necessity for the exercise of
discretion in determining whether the writ shall issue in the first
instance, or whether the parties should be left to submit to the
procedure in that state court first. But after all--after a decision
of a court of competent jurisdiction, when it is still contended
that the federal constitution has been violated, the federal court
has the power, and it is the duty of the federal court, to interfere
for the protection of rights of this nature, when it is shown
that they have been violated. It is a matter that is of transcending
importance, however, that the federal court shall not issue its 
writ to interfere with the execution of the laws unless there is a 
plain case requiring it. Before I issue this writ I must look to
the facts which Mr. Krug sets forth in support of his general claim
that he is being deprived of liberty in violation of the constitution
and laws of the Untied States. Now, what is his claim? He
claims that he has not been proceeded against by indictment, as
provided in the sixth amendment to the constitution of the United 
States. Well that part of the constitution, and no part of the
constitution, gives him the right to insist that he cannot be tried
for violating a law of the state except upon an indictment.

<pb/>

(4)

(Interruption by Col. Lewis.) We are not making that contention
(Judge Hanford:) You stated in arguing here that this is not
a good indictment, and therefore no indictment, an therefore he
has not been indicted, and therefore this provision of the constitution
is violated, because he is being deprived of liberty upon a 
conviction that was not founded upon an indictment. I say that it
is not true that the petitioner has any right to insist that the
federal constitution is viiolated by a procedure against him without
a good indictment, -- without an indictment that informs him fully of
the facts alleged to be criminal. There is nothing in the constitution
that reaches that point of his case. Now there is no statute
of the United States that has been violated by this proceeding. The
use of public money by an officer of this state or of a municipality 
of this state in a manner to make a profit for himself is not an
act that comes under the protection of any clause of the constitution
or any statute. We are relegated then to the proposition that
under the fifth amendment and the fourteenth amendment he is entitled
to due process of law before he can be deprived of liberty, and
it is a violation of the constitution to deprive him of the equal 
protection of the laws because he is a citizen. Now let us see
about that: The supreme court has determined the matter, and puts 
it certainly beyond any question of power in this court to inquire
further, that the mode of pleading in criminal cases, the manner in
which a defendant may be arraigned and accused by state laws, is a 
matter entirely of state regulation. The constitution of the United
States does not attempt in any way to say how the state shall regulate 
its procedure in criminal cases in enforcing its own laws.
There is, therefore, no deprivation of liberty without due process
of laws by a proceeding that is in conformity with the state law, no
matter how the state has seen fit to legislate as to procedure. Then
comes the question whether Mr. Krug has been deprived of the equal
protection of the laws. It is said that this indicment would not
be a good indictment--the supreme court would not have held it to be

<pb/>

(5)

a good indictment--on account of its insufficienty of details in
regard to the facts charged, had it been any other crime than the
crime of using money unlawfully by a public officer. It appears
by the opinion of the Supreme Court of the State of Washington held
in Mr. Krug's case that as a general proposition of law under the
ordinary rules and under the common law requirements, the indictment
would not be sufficient, but that this case is governed by
Sec. 58 of the Penal Code, which provides that:

"In prosecutions for the offenses named in the next preceding
section, (the section under which this indictment was brought), it
shall be sufficient to allege generally, in the information or indictment,
that any such officer . . . . . has made profit out of 
the public money in his possession or under his control, or has
used the same for any purpose not authorized by law, to a certain 
value of amount, without specifying any further particulars in
regard thereto; and on the trial evidence may be given of all the
facts constituting the offense and defense thereto."

State v. Krug, 12 Wash. 288-309; 41 Pac. 126.

Now that is a statute relating wholly to offenses committed by
officials, but it bears equally and alike upon all, whether taking
office before or since Mr. Krug's conviction. It bears equally
and alike upon all who take office and violate the law, subsequent
to the enactment of that statute. It is equal and uniform in its
operations as to all who come within its scope, just the same as a
statute punishing larceny-- it could only apply to persons accused
of committing larceny, but it would operate equally and uniformly as 
to all who are brought under it. Mr. Krug cannot truthfully say
that he has been singled out as a vitctim and convicted by a mathod 
of procedure not applicable in other cases of the same kind. and
further than that I do not concede that the legislature of the state
is limited in its power to legislate as regards purely statutory
offenses, as this one is. The law may prescribe that an indictment 
by a Grand Jury shall be essential in some kind of cases, or require
an information to be filed setting forth in plain and unmistakeable
terms, fully and minutely, all the facts constituting a particular
offense. In other cases, as in misdemeanors, it may authorize an

<pb/>

(5-1/2)

accused person to be proceeded against in a police court, upon a
simple affidavit of the arresting officer or any citizen, charging
an officse in general terms. Now the supreme court of the state
of Washington is practically the court of final resort for the determination
of questions of state law. Whether in the interpretation
or construction or application of the constitution of the state
or the statutes of the state, this court and the supreme court of
the United States is bound to follow the decisions of the supreme
court of the state. As to whether the legislature had power to make
such a statute as this, prescribing an indictment or information
charging in general terms an offense of this character, is a question
that the supreme court has the absolute power to decide and determine,

<pb/>




</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>