<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0187.10">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0187.010</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1914">1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-06-26">June 26, 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Grayson, William</term>
<term>Grayson, Marie Robina</term>
<term>Lakin, Edward M.</term>    
<term>Merrick, Louis A.</term>    
<term>Shakespeare, Noah</term>    
<term>Turner, C. A.</term>
<term>White, Henry M.</term>

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Bretagne, France</term>
<term>St. Louis, Missouri</term>    
<term>Salem, Oregon</term>    
    
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Marie Robina Grayson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
    <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN 
DIVISION OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In re Marie Robina Grayson
alias Marie Robina for 
Writ of Habeas Corpus. 
Petitioner.</p>

<p>No 2780
PETITION
<unclear/></p>

<p>No 1.</p>
<p>TO THE HONORABLE THE JUDGES OF THE COURT ABOVE ENTITLED:
Now comes Marie Robina Grayson, alias Marie Robina, represents 
and shows unto yourhonors, that she is a citizen of teh 
United States of America, over the age of twenty-one (21) years, 
a resident and citizen of the State of Washington, and the 
District and Division of the above entitled court before 
specified. That your petitioner is a native of the Province
of Bretagne, in the Republic of France, and came to the United 
States of America in December of 19o2 where your petitioner has
since resided.</p>
<p>No 2.</p>
<p>That your petitioner intermarried with William Grayson at 
Salem, in the State of Oregon, on the 1st day of April 1912, 
and thereafter at all times has been and still is the lawful 
wife of the said William Grayson. That at the time of said 
intermarriage of your petitioner and William Grayson in teh 
said State of Oregon, in the said United States of America, 
the said William Grayson was a natural born citizen of the 
United States of America, having been born in the City of St. 
Louis, in the State of Missouri, in the said United States of 
America, and never having renounced the alegiance acquired by 
such birth. That thereafter and on or about the 23rd January 
1914 your petitioner was taken into custody by one C. A. Turner
Immigration Inspector of the United States upon a warrant 
issued by the Assistant Secretary of the Department of Commence
and Labor of the United States charging yourpetitioner with 
being an alien in the United States of America, and of 
<pb/>
<fw>page 2.-</fw>
practising prostitution after her entry into the United States of 
America. That thereafter a hearing was had before the said 
C. A. Turner as such Immigration Inspector upon such charge
and thereafter your petitioner was taken into custody and is 
now in custody of Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration
under and by virtue of a warrant issued by the Secretary of the 
Department of Commerce and Labor of the United States of 
America, directing that yourpetitioner be deported the United 
States of America, and transported to the Republic of France 
for the reason as stated in such warrant, that your petitioner 
<add>is an alien</add> to the United States of America and has been found practising
prostitution in such United States of America.</p>
<p>No 3.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further avers that she is restrained of 
her liberty by the said Henry M. White as such Commissioner of 
Immigration under a claim that she is subject to deportation 
for a violation of the laws of the United States of America, 
in that, being an alien she was found practising prostitution
in the United States of America.</p>
<p>No 4.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further avers that she is held in custody 
under and by virtue of a claim that she has violated the laws 
of the United States of America and isbeing held in such custody 
within the District and Division aforesaid.</p>
<p>No 5.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further avers that she is unable to attach 
hereto a copy of the process under which she is held in 
custody and restrained of her liberty, for the reason that she has 
no copy in her possession and for the reason that she has not 
been furnished with such a copy.</p>
<p>No 6.</p>
<p>Your petitioner however avers that she is being now 
restrained of her liberty and held in the custody of Henry M. 
White, Commissioner of Immigration, under a pretense of a law 
of the United States of America.</p>
<pb/>
<fw>page 3.-</fw>
<p>No 7.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further avers that at the hearing before 
the said C. A. Turner, Immigration Inspector, it appeared
conclusively and without contradiction that your petitioner at 
all times since her said marriage wi th the said William Grayson
has been a resident of the said United States of America
and a citizen thereof, andthat the said warrant of the Secretary 
of the Department of Commerce and Labor is invalid and of no 
force and effect in law, for the reason that yourpetitioner 
is not an alien, and has not been an alien since the institution
of such deportation proceedings.</p>
<p>No 8.</p>
<p>You petitioner now complains that she is unlawfully 
restrained of her liberty by the said Henry M. White under
the pretense that she has violated a law of the United States 
of America which pretense and claim is unfounded in fact as is 
to the said Henry M. White adn to the Secretary of the Department
of Commerce and Labor well known.</p>
<p>No 9.</p>
<p>Your petitioner avers that in her said confinement by the 
said Henry M. White, her rights as an American citizen are
infringed adn she is deprived of her liberty without any 
warrant of law, and that such restraint is illegal and invalid.</p>
<p>No 10.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further avers that in the hearing before 
the officers of the Immigration Service of the United States
she was denied the right to cross examine the witnesses, to 
meet the witnesses fact to face, and that your petitioner in 
such hearing before the officers of the Immigration bureau
of the United States was denied a fair and impartial hearing,and 
that there was no testimony taken before the said C. A. Turner
tending to show or which did show that your petitioner was at 
the time of the institution of such proceedigns or at anytime 
subsequent to her said intermarriage with said William Grayson 
an alien to the United States of America.</p>
<pb/>
<fw>page 4.-</fw>
<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner prays that she may be allowed
the writ of right, a writ of habeas corpus to the Honorable 
Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration directed, commanding
and requiring the said Henry M. White to produce before 
your honors at a time and place to be specified, the body of 
your petitioner together with the cause alleged for her detention
by the said Henry M. White, and that she further be awarded
a writ of certiorari to the Hon. Henry M. White, Commissioner 
of Immigration, commanding and requiring said Commissioner to 
certify untothis court, all and singular the proceedings had 
before C. A. Turner as such Immigration Inspector respecting
the matter of the deportation of yourpetitioner, and that 
thereupon, upon the return to such writ of habeas corpus and 
the coming in of the return of such writ of certiorari such 
order be had thereon by your Honors as upon due consideration
is consonant with law under and pursuant to the Constitution
of the United States of America, and as in duty bound, your
petitioner will ever pray.</p>
<ab>Mary Robina Grayson <lb/>
PETITIONER</ab>
<ab>Noah Shakespeare <lb/>
Louis A. Merrick <lb/>
ATTORNEYS FOR PETITIONER</ab>
<p>Scandia Building,Everett,Wash.</p>

<p>WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON. s.s.</p>
<p>MARIE ROBINA GRAYSON first being duly sworn,
upon her oath doth say: that she is the petitioner named in 
and by whom the foregoing petition is subscribed; that she knows
the contents thereof. and that all the matters and things in 
said petition set forth are true.</p>
<ab>Mary Robina Grayson <lb/></ab>
<p>Subsribed and sworn to before me this 26th June 1914.</p>
<ab>Noah Shakespeare <lb/>
Notary Public for Washington,at Everett.</ab>
<p>Let the writ issue as prayed.
Dated 26th June 1914. JUDGE.</p>
<pb/>
<p>No.</p>
<p>United States of America
for the Western District of 
Washington, Western 
Division.</p>

<p>In re:Marie Robina 
Grayson, Alias Marie 
Robina</p>

<p>Petition for 
Writ of Habeas 
Corpus</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington.
JUN 27 1914</p>
<ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk,
By EML Deputy</ab>

<p><add>Louis A. Merrick 
and</add> NOAH SHAKESPEARE
ATTORNEY AT LAW
EVERETT, WASHINGTON
PUGET PRESS EVERETT, WASH.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>