<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0183.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Gwoo Shee Ah Look v. United States. Writ.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0183.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Gwoo Shee Ah Look v. United States. Writ.</title>
<date when="1914-05-01">May 1, 1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2647GwooSheeAhLook</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-05">May 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Clark, A. L.</term>
<term>On, Wong</term>
<term>Batholomew, Walter</term>
<term>Line, Sue Key</term>
<term>Bean</term>
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Larken, Edward M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Look, Gwoo Shee Ah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Frye, Jesse A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wilbur</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Spencer</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, George P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>United States District Court
Western District of Washington
Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus for
Gwoo Shee Ah Look. } No. 2647
Filed April <gap reason="blank"/>, 1914.</p>
<p>Wilbur &amp; Spencer of Portland, Ore.,
A. L. Clark, or Portland Ore.,
Jesse A. Frye, of Seattle, Wash., 
For Petitioner.</p>
<p>Clay Allen, U.S. District Attorney,
Geo. F. Fishburne, Assistant District Atty. 
For Respondent.</p>
<p>Neterer, District Judge.</p>
<p>A writ of habeas corpus was issued in this case on the 13th 
day of January, 1914, upon the application of the petitioner, to
which return has been made. The return shows that on the 5th day
of November, 1913, a warrant for arrest of Gwoo Shee Ah Look was
issued, and she was taken into custody. It would appear that a 
general raid was made on November 4th, 1913, of the city of Portland
by the police officers of the city, and the petitioner
together with some other women were arrested. A report was
made to the immigration commissioner of the arrest of the petitioner,
and she was taken into custody under the warrant above
stated and given a hearing. On the same day the commissioner
was advised by Mr. Clark, representing the firm of Wilbur &amp;
Spencer, laywers, that they had been retained on behalf of
Gwoo Shee Ah Look, and desired to consult with her. This request 
was denied, as were also the subsquent requests which were
made practically every day until after the 17th day of November when
all of the testimony against the petitioner had been taken, except
that on November 10th a conference was permitted. On the 17th
the attorney for the petitioner was told over the phone to prepare
to present such evidence as he desired by way of affidavits
and the same would be forwarded with the report to the secretary
of labor. At the close of the petitioner's examination on
November 10th, she was advised:</p>
<fw>1.</fw>
<pb/>
<p>"Q. Do you desire to designate any attorney or representative
to appear for you at this hearing. A. I wish to notify Wong
On, Manager of the Kwong Man Yun Comapny in this city. Q. Do 
you know him personally. A. My husband knows him, I do not
know him."</p>
<p>This party was not advised, nor was counsel for petitioner
permitted to be persent at this hearing. <add>The petitioner does not
understand nor speak English.</add></p>
<p>The record discloses that the order of deportation was based
upon the testimony of two policemen who made the raid, which testimony
shows that they had the petitioner under surveillance for
some two or three weeks, and they had watched the room in which t
she was arrested in this building and had seen men go in and out 
of the room; that on the night of the arrest about 4 o'clock
in the morning they went to the door and knocked and the woman
opened the door, and that she and a man were in bed together.
The petitioner furnishes affidavits from Walter Bartholomew, a 
white man and a paper hanger, who papered the rooms in which
the petitioner was arrested about the 1st of November, and he
swears positively that the petitioner did not move into those
rooms prior to November 1st. Sue Key Line and his wife swear positively
that the petitioner lived at their home from the 18th 
of October to November 1st; and that the rooms to which they
moved in the building in which the arrest was made was rented
to the pettiioner by Mr. Sue Key Line.</p>
<p>The woman and her husband, who is represented to be a prosperous
merchant, appeared in court upon this hearing. They
have the appearance of being above the average Chinaman.</p>
<p>This court has to do only with the determination of whether
the petitioner was granting a fair hearing. The enforcement of
<add>the immigration laws</add> is vested by Congress in the immigration department, whose
findings are made final as to the facts in issue, provided a 
fair hearing is had. The rules of the department provide a procedure
to be followed when an alien is arrested as being improperly
in the country, and provide certain rights which should be
accorded to the arrested party, among which are permission to
secure advice and assistance of counsel to inspect the record,
<fw>2.</fw>
<pb/>
make a copy of the minutes of the hearing so far as they have been
presented, and to offer evidence to meet any evidence presented.
It is contended by the petitioner that she was not accorded such
a hearing as is contemplated b y the Immigration Act; that she was
denied the assistance of counsel; that she was not permitted to
meet <add>face to face</add> the witnesses who testified against her; that she was denied
the right of cross-examination of the witnesses; and that if
the right of cross-examination had been accorded to her that
every statement made by the policeman to which a wrongful conclusion
has been attributed could have been elucidated in such
a way from the statements of the witnesses themselves that
would have shown conclusively that no improper relations of any
kind had been sustained by the petitioner with the party in the
room at the time of the arrest or at any time; and that they were
in error as to the petitioner being in the room in question here
prior to November 1, 1913. The petitioner and the party who was in the room with her swear that they were not in bed together. The
Chinaman is stated to be a friend of the husband, and asked permission
to sleep there for the night. He lay on a bed in one room
and the petitioner lay on a sofa in another room. Both has
their clothing on; and that there had been nothing improper between
them.</p>
<p>A careful reading of the entire record convinces me that the
petitioner was not accorded a fair hearing, and that the right of
being represented by counsel and being afforded an opportunity of
cross-examining the witnesses being denied her, deprived her of
a right which the law accords, expecially under circumstances
disclosed by the record in this case. This denial was prejudicial 
to her. It has been repeatedly held that the rules provided
by the Immigration department contemplated a hearing at which the
alien is allowed to be present and be confronted with witnesses and
to have opportunity to cross-examine.</p>
<p>United States ex rel. Huber v. Sibray, 178 Fed. 144, 149;
United States ex rel. Bosny v. Williams, 185 fed. 598.
<fw>3.</fw>
<pb/>
Roux v. Commissioner, 203 Fed. 413, 416;
Hanges v. Whitfield, 209 Fed. 675.</p>
<p>It is contended by the Government that Low Wah Suey v. Backus,
225 U.S. 460, 56 L. ed. 1165, is decisive of the question here
raised. The court there said:</p>
<p>"From these rules it appears that, while provision is made
for an examination in the absence of counsel, it is provided
that a hearing shall be had at which the alien shall have full
opportunity to show cause why he should not be deported, and
that, at such stage of the proceedings as the person before whom
apprixed that he may thereafter be represented by counsel, who
shall be permitted to be present at the further conduct of the
hearing."</p>
<p>Neither the petitioner nor her counsel were permitted to be
present at any hearing or further hearing.</p>
<p>Judge Bean of the District of Oregonin the case of In re
Chin You Gen, April 20, 1914, in a similar case based upon practically
the same facts, the party being apprehended in the same
raid, in discharging the petitioner, said:</p>
<p>"The doctine seems to be that no person can be deprived of his
liberty and deported without an opportunity to show his right to remain
and to present such evidence to the officers whose duty it
is to pass upon this evidence.</p>
<p>Now, the warrant of deportation was issued by the authorities
at Washington based upon the record as made up before the
commissioner and it seems to me that under all the rules of procedure
the petitioner in this case should have been allowed
to have appeared either in person or by counsel, and that was
on the 10th of November, but notwithstanding that the commissioiner
took the testimony of the two material witnesses without the
presence of the petitoner and denied the right of her counsel to
be present at that hearing, and that, it seems to me, was a violation
of the rules prescribed by the department."</p>
<p>A warrant of deportation was issued upon the record transmitted
to the secretary of labor, in the preparation of which,
or in the production of any of the evidence, the petitioner and
her counsel were deprived of any participation, other than the
submission of affidavits after the case of the Government has been
closed.</p>
<p>I am forced to the conclusion that the action of the commissioner
in taking the testimony of the material witnesses to substantiate
the vital issue without the presence of the petitioner and in denying
her the right of counsel to be present at that hearing to secure
her the right of at least limited cross-examination, deprived
<fw>4.</fw>
<pb/>
the petitioner of a fair hearing such as is contemplated by
the rules of the department.</p>
<p>The petitioner is entitled to a discharge.</p>
<ab>Jeremiah Neterer
Judge.</ab>
<pb/>
<p>2x No. <gap reason="blank"/></p>
<p>In the District Court
of the United States
for the
Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Filed in the
U.S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington.
May 1 1914
Frank L. Crosby, Clerk,
By EML Deputy</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>