<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0492.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Pizzi, Annabella D." xml:id="adp">Annabella D. Pizzi</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>NSF</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0492.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant.</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-09-23">September 23, 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Medcraf, Francis Medcraf</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>The State of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Emery, Geo D.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Lundin, Alfred H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Helsell, Frank P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="justice_of_the_peace">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
                  
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#adp">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE APPLICATION OF
FRANCIS STEPHEN MEDCRAF
FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS}
No. 3038.
Filed September 23, 1915.</p>
<p>George D. Emery, For Petitioner.
Alfred H. Lundin, Prosecuting Atty.} For State.
Frank P. Helsell Asst Prosecuting Attorney} For State.</p>
<p>NETERER, District Judge:
The petitioner alleges that he is unlawfully detained
and restrained of his liberty by the Sheriff of King County,
Washington, upon a judgement of conviction for violation of the
provisions of Sections 8412-8425 Remington &amp; Ballinger's Codes
and Statutes of Washington, he being charged with practicing
dentistry for a fee in the state of Washington, without having
first filed for record and recorded in the office of the Auditor 
of the County wherein he then and there practiced, to- wit,
King County, a certificate from the Board of Dental Examiners
of the State of Washington, authorizing him to do practice as
provided by law. He alleges that at the age of thirteen he
was regularly apprenticed to a practicing dentist in London,
England, and served his apprenticeship the full term of five
years; that he "worked as dental assistant" to a surgeon dentist 
at Athens, Greece, for the term of two years, and as dental 
mechanic in the regular study and practice of that profession;
that he returned to London "for further study and prosecuted
such study in dental surgery for six months" under William 
Lombardi, under whom he served his apprenticeship; that in 1896
he was engaged in the office of Dr. Waldo Royce, dentist at 
Tunbridge Wells, England, a graduate of Harvard University, for
eight moneths, as general detnal assistant; that thereafter he 
was employed by Mr. James Shillcock, at Cannes, France, for five
months; and afterward entered the office of William Lombardi,
<pb/>
at London, and studied and practiced dental surgery for five
months, and then, at Nice, France, acted as generla assitant
and continued in that practice for the term of six months;
and in 1898 served for four months as dental mechanic at Mile
End Road, London, and then returned to Nice, France, where he
was employed for seven months in the practice of general dental
work; and, in 1899, acted as general dental mechanic for
four months in the office of Isador Clifford, in London, who 
treated "the then Prince of Wales, who is now the King of England";
did further assistant dental work in 1900, at Nice,
France, and in 1901 returned to London and opened an office
where he continued the practice of dentistry for two years; and 
then, on account of ill health, removed to Alberts, Canada,
where he practiced dentistry for five years, and in February,
1908, removed to Seattle, Washington, "where he has continued 
the practice of dentistry undisturbed until the issuance of the
warrant of arrest herein complained of." That before beginning
the practice of dentistry in Seattle, Wash. for license
to practice, he "tendered the legal fee and offered himslef for
examination pursuant to law, and in all things complied with
the requirement of the statutes in such cases made and provided, 
save onlt that he did not present any diploma from any
college of dentistry whatever for the reason that he did not
possess one and does not now possess any, having obtained his
professio, learning anfd skill at the places, by the practices
and study, and in the manner hereinbefore set forth." That the
State Board of Dental Examiners refused to receive the application
of petitioner, and refused to grant him any license; and
further stated that he is qualified to practice dentistry and
is willing to pay the fees, and sets forth in the petition the
sections of the act complained of, and alleges that the provisions
contravene Section 1 of Article 14 of the amendments to the 
Constitution of the United States, and Section 7 of Article 1
<pb/>
of the Constitution of the State of Washington, and Section 3
of Article 1 of the State Constitution.</p>
<p>Section 8416, Rem. &amp; Bal. Codes of Washington, in so far 
as pertinent, reads:
            "Any person ***** seeking to practice dentistry 
    in the State of Washington**** shall file his or her 
    name, together with the application for examination
    with the Secretary of the State Board of Dental Examiners,
    and at the time of making such application
    shall pay to the Secretary of the Board a fee of 
    $25.00 and to present him or herself at the first 
    regular meeting thereafter of said Board to undergo
    examination before that body.
            No person shall be eligible for such examination
    unless he or she shall presern to said Board his or
    her diploma from some dental college in good standing
    and shall give satisfactory evidence of his or her
    rightful possession of the same; PROVIDED, this section
    shall not apply to persons engaged in the practice
    of dentistry at the time of the passage of this
    act who are bona fide citizens of the State of Washington.*****"
The act fruther provides for the issuance of a certificate and
the record thereof in the Auditor's office and a penalty for the
violation of the provisions of the act, and Section 8424
defined dentistry as follows: "All persons shall be said to be
practicing dentistry within the meaning of this chapter, who
shall, contrary to this act, for a fee or salary of other reward, 
paid either to himself or to another person for operations or
parts of operations of any kind, treat diseases or lesions of
the human teeth or of jaws or correct malpositions thereof."
The underscored portion of the section of the statute is attacked.
These various constitutional provisions can be discussed
together, Section 1, Article 14 of the amendments to the Constitution
of the United States, provides:
        "****** nor shall any State deprive any person of l
    life, liberty or property without due process of law,
    nor deny to any person within its jurisdiction the 
    equal protection of the laws."
Article 5 of the Constitution of the United States:
        "***** No person**** shall be deprived of life,
    liberty or property without due process of law."
Section 12, Article 1 of the Constitution of Washington:
        "No law shall be passed granting to any citizen
    or class of citizens, or corporation, other than
<pb/>
    municipal, privilges or immunities which, upon the
    same terms, shall not belong equally to all citizens
    or corporations."
Section 7, Article 1:
        "No person shall be disturbed in his private
    affairs or his home invaded without authority of law."
Section 3, Article 1:
        "No person shall be deprived of life, liberty
    or property without due process of law."</p>
<p>It is strenuously urged on behalf of the petitioner 
that since the profession of dental surgery or dentistry is a 
profitable employment and an honorable profession, and of large
importance to the petitioner as a means of earning a livelihood,
and to the public in that it gives it efficient service, that
the act trangresses the several provisions of the Constitution
of the State and United States, in that it deprives the petitioner,
without due process of law, of that which to him is property
and which enables him to provide for himself and his family, and
 that it is not within the police power of the State.</p>
<p>Mr. Justice Gray, in Leiseyv. Hardin, 135 U. S. 127, in
speaking of the police power, said:
        "It is that power which is characterized as that inherent
    power essential to the very existence of civil 
    society and the safeguard of the inhabitants of the State
    against disorder, disease, poverty and crime."
Courts cannot place precise limits upon the police power of the
State. Each case must be controlled by the facts peculiar to its
situation and condition, but the exercise must be reasonable as
distinguished from arbitrary or capricious, and when no discrimination
between persons or classes upon any matter pertinent to
the legal purpose of the law appears, it is not in contravention
or any rights protected by the constitutional provisions, even 
though it may emphasize the condition or situation upon one more 
than upon another because of pecuniary situation of itself
does not make the law subject to the legal criticism. The right to 
<pb/>
enjoy life, liberty, property and the pursuit of happiness is
secured to everyone under the State and Federal Constitutions, 
and any act which deprives a man of the right to labor or restricts 
his liberty or capacity to earn wages over and beyond
any deprivation of all others does not afford such person the
equal protection of the law. This right and liberty, however,
is not unlimited, and if a restriction is placed upon all alike,
that right is not invaded. The State Court, in State ex rel
Thompson v. State Board, 48 Wash. 29, held the act in issue to 
be within the police power if the state and not in contravention 
of any constitutional provision, and at page 293 said:
        "The statute makes the same requirements of all
    applicants for examination. No favored or preffered
    classes are created or recognized. An applicant 
    who holds a diploma must also pass an examination. Rightful
    possession of his diploma does not of itself authorize
    him to practice, or entitled him to a license. The requirement 
    for both diploma and examination as a test
    of knowledge is not such and unreasonable or arbitrary
    one as to invalidate the statute. The right to determine
    what requirements must be met by an applicant is within the exclusive privinc of the legislature. This
    statute was considered in the case of In re Thompson, 36 Wash. 377, 78 Pac. 899, in which it was attacked as
    unconstitutional and was sustained by this court. Without
    further discussion, we now adhere to the ruling then
    made."

The same act was construed by the same court, In Re Thompson,
36 Wash. 377. Judge Mount, at page 380, said:
        "If we are correct in our conclusion that the legislature,
    in the exercise of its police power has
    authority, under the state and federal constitutions, 
    to regulate the practice of dentistry within the state
    by reasonable rules, it follows that the legislature
    may provided that an applicant must be possessed of a
    diploma from some dental college in good standing.
    There is nothing unreasonable in this requirement, nor
    is the other requirements name in the act. Such diploma
    is evidence of the ability of the applicant to
    practice dentistry. It is not conclusive of such ability,
    and the dental board may, therefore, provide reasonable
    rules for determining the actual; ability of
    the applicant."

The Supreme Court, in Reetz v. Michigan, 188 U.S. 5050,
at page 506, said:
        "The power of a state to make reasonable provisions
    for determining the qualifications of those engaging 
    in the practice of medicine and punishing those who attempt 
    to engage therein in defiance of such statutory
    provisions, is not open to question. Dant v. West Virginia,
<pb/>
    129 U.S. 114; Hawker v. N. Y., 170 U.S.
    189."

Justice Field, in Dent v. West Virginia, 129 U.S. 
114, at page 122, said:
        "The power of the State to provide for the general
    welfare at its people authorized it to prescribe all
    such regulations as, it its judgement, will secure or
    tend to secure them against the consequences of ignorance
    and incapacity as well as of deception and 
    fraud. As one means to this end it has been the practice 
    in different states from time immemorial to exact
    in many pursuits a certain degree of skill and learning
    upon which the community may confidently rely, their
    possession being generally ascertained upon an examination
    of parties by competent persons, or inferred from
    a certificate to them in the form of a diploma or license
    from an institution established for instruction
    on the subjects, scientific and otherwise, with which
    such pursuit have to deal. The nature and extent of 
    the qualifications required must depend primarily upon 
    the judgement of the State as to their necessity. If
    they are appropriate to the calling or profession, and 
    attainable by reasonable study or application, no objection 
    to their validity can be raised because of their
    stringency or difficulty. It is only when they have
    no relation to such calling, or profession, or are unattainable
    by such reasonable study and application,
    that they can operate to deprive one of his right to 
    pursue a lawful vocation."

and Justice Day, in Watson v. Maryland, 218 U.S. 173, at page
177 said:
        "In such statutes there are often found execptions
    in favor of those who have practiced their callings for
    a period of years. In the Dent case, supre, an exception 
    was made in favor of the practicioners of medicine who
    had continuously practiced their profession for ten
    years prior to a date shortly before the enactment of 
    the law. Such exception proceeds upon the theory that
    those who have acceptably followed the profession in the community
    for a period of years may be assumed to have
    the qualificatios which other are required to manifest
    as a result of an examination before a Board of 
    Medical experts."

and at page 178:
        "Before a law of this kind can be declared violative
    of the 14th amendment as an unreasonable classification
    of the subjects of such legislation because of the omission
    of certain classes, the court must be able to say
    that there is no fair reason for the law that would not
    require with equal force its extension to others whom
    its leaves untouched."</p>
<p>Justice Holmes, in Collins v. Texas, 223 U. S. 288, in
reviewing the act of the legislature establishing a Board of
medicial examiners in which it provided as a condition precedent
to exmination that they must have been graduated from a medical
<pb/>
school "whose entrance requiremtns and courses of instruction
are as high as those adopted by the better class of medicial 
schools in the U.S. whose course of instruction shall embrace
not less than four terms of five months each", plaintiff being
an osteopathm who claimed that he was deprived of his property
without due process of law and denied the equal protection of
the law, at page 296, said:
        "The state constitutionally may prescribe conditions
    to such practice considered by it to be necessary
    or useful to secure competence in those who follow
    it. We should presume, until the Texas courts
    say otherwise, that hte reference in par. 4 to the
    diploma of a reputable and legal college of medicine
    and the confining in par. 7 if examination to graduates 
    of reputable medical schools use the words medicine
    and medical with the same broad sense as in par. 
    13 and that the diploma of the plaintiff in error
    would not be rejected merely because it came from a 
    school of osteopathy. In short, the statute says, if
    you want to do what it call practicing medicine, you
    must have gone to a repuatbale school in that kind of 
    practice."</p>
<p>The Supreme Court of Minnesota, in determining the constitutionality
of an act which provided that "any person who
shall desire to beging the practice of dentistry in the State
after September 1, 1899, shall make application for examination
to the Board of Examiners**** and shall undergo an examination
such person shall present to said Board his diploma from some
dental college in good standing and shall give satisfactory
evidence of his rightful possession of the same, provided also 
that the Board may, in its discretion, admit to examination such
person as give satisfactory evidence of having been engaged in 
the practice of this act, in State v. Vanderlens, 43 N.W. 789, at
page 790, said:
            "What the particular objections of a constitutional
    character the appelant males to this section, are, it
    is somewhat difficult to determine from this breif, We 
    infer, however, that he claims the section to be objectionable 
    becuase no matter how well qualified by learning 
    and skill or experience one may be, he has a diploma 
    from a dental college of good standing, such good
    <pb/>
    standing to be determined by the Board, and this he
    claims to be discrimination between the rich and poor,
    because one may be pecuniarly able and another not
    able to attend a dental college. The mere fact of
    discrimination in such law is not objection to it. 
    Requiring a certain degree of learning and skill as 
    a condition of being allowed to practice is discrimination 
    between those who have and those who have not
    that degree of learning and skill- between those who
    are able and those who are not able to acquire it. 
    If there were discrimination between persons or classes
    upon any matter not pertinent to the legal purpose
    of the law, to- wit, to secure fitnedd and competency
    in those who shall per permitted to practice, it would
    be objectionable. As for instance, if it were as to 
    place of birth, color or religious belief. The requirement
    of a diploma from some college or learned society, 
    in order to practice medicine has been inserted in the 
    laws of many states, and questioned in but few. In 
    Mass. a law required the practitioner to have been licensed 
    by the Medical Society or been graduated a Dr. 
    in medicine at Harvard University. This was held constitutional
    in Hewitt v. Charier, 16 Pick. 356. The 
    statute of Nevada (1875) require a medicial education
    and a diploma from some regularly chartered medical
    School. This was held constitutional in Ex parte 
    Spinney, 10 Nev. 323. As the fact of having graduated
    and received a diploma from a school or college 
    devoted to teaching the particular science, medicine, 
    surgery or dentistry, bears directly upon the persons' 
    qualification to practice, we have no doubt the leglislature 
    might have made that the sole test. That this
    statute allows, in the discretion of the Board, ten
    years practice prior to the passage of the act as a
    substitute for the diploma of a college, furnished
    no objection on constitutional grounds to the act."</p>
<p>The Supreme Court of  Kentucky, in Webster v. State Board
of Health, 113 S.W. 415, at page 416, said:
            "The statute under consideration is a wise and
    beneficent exercise of the police power of the commonwealth,
    enacted for the purpose of protecting the
    people of the state from imposition by empirics and 
    quacks. It does not seek to prevent any honorable
    man or woman from practicing the profession of medicine. 
    It only requires that they shall show, by a 
    satisfactory examination before the State Board of 
    Health that they are qualified. There is no suggestion
    in the petition that the Board is acting arbitrarily 
    or that it unlawfully seeks to prevent the 
    appelant from obtaining a certificate, and we are
    not entitled, in the absence of such allegation, to 
    indulge in any presumption against its fairness. It
    is the nigh duty of the Board to protect the health and 
    safety of the public by requiring every applicant for
    a certificate to practice medicine to first show his
    qualifications. It is not necessary to demonstrate
    the constitutionality of the act. Such legislation
    has been uniformly held as an exercise of the police
    power of the state by our own court and other courts
    throughout the land."
<pb/>
This act, however, predicated the qualification upon a diploma
from a reputable medical colleg or the presetnation of evidence
of having been egnaged in practicing dentistry prior to the date
designated.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court of Michigan, in an attack upon an act
of the legislature requiring that no person shall practice medicine
or surgery who is not a graduate of a medical college, unless 
he has practiced in Michigan for five years when the act
takes effect, in Peiple v. Phippin, 37 N. W. 888, at page 897,
said:
            "An examination of this act, will, in our opinion, 
    not disclose any violation of the provisions of the constitution.
    What are the qualifications necessary to 
    practice in this state?" Every graduate of any legally
    authorized medical college in this state, or in any of 
    the United States, or in any other country after having 
    registered, etc., may practice in this state. It must
    be conceded from the cases cited, that the legislature
    has the power to deinfe the qualifications of those who
    shall be licensed to practice those callings of professions 
    the exercise of which may affect the public health
    and safety, and that this law would be entirely constitutional
    in that view if it stopped short with prohibiting
    all but medical graduates from practicing. But is
    is contended that the exception in favor of those who
    come under subduv. 1, par 2 of the act, ' that every
    person who shall have actually practiced medicine constinuously
    for at least five years in this state, and
    who is practicing when this act shall take effect, shall 
    be deemed qualified', etc., is not founded upon any natural, 
    fair, or reasonable distinction, and makes it a 
    discriminating law, within the prohibitions of the federal 
    constitution. This question was raised in Ex parte
    Spinney, 10 Nev. 328, and Mr. Justice Beatty, delivering
    the opinion of the court, in that case, says:
            'The second point was more strenuously insisted upon,
    the petitioner contending that there cannot be any reasonable 
    ground for a distinction between those who have practiced 
    ten years in this state and those who have practiced 
    ten years elsewhere. But I am not prepared to say 
    that there may not be grounds for such a distinction. The
    legislature may have thought the graduate is a man or
    science. His knowledge enables him to refer effects to
    their causes. It enables him to discriminate between 
    the essential relations of phenomena and their accidetnal
    coincidence. It is sufficiently comprehensive to
    anticipate the operation new causes and the influence
    of changed conditions. He will therefore be able to
    adapt his practice to the peculiar diseases or modifications
    of diseases of any locality. The mere practitioner,
    on the other hand, who has not pursued the 
    regular course of medical education, and who has learned 
    merely to meet a certain symptom with a certain
    drug, without knowing what pathological condition is
    indicated by the symptom, or what is the specific action
    of the drug, may do very well in the disease
    which he is accustomed to, or where the same symptom
    means the same thing, and the accustomed remedy meets
    <pb/>
    the same counteracting or co-operating conditions, 
    but he will be dangerous among new diseases or new
    modifications of disease.
        How much truth there may be in these suggestions,
    or how important it may be as a principle
    of discrimination is a question solely for the legislature.
    The question was one of policy and its decision 
    is not subject to our review.'"</p>
<p>The Dental Act of Missouri, which required a diploma
from an accredited college of dentistry as a condition precedent
to obtaining a license to practice within the state, except
as to persons who had personally obtained a license to so 
practice, was attacked as unconstitutional upon the grounds that
it discriminated against, First, A young man who had qualified 
himself to practice his profession out of college by his own industry
and has not been licensed to practice by the State Board 
of Missouri or any other state in the Union; Second, A person
learned in his profession, coming into the state from a foreign
country and becoming a citizen and not having been licensed by 
any other state or graduated from a college chartered by one of 
the state; Third, a person learned in the profession who has
practiced for many years in a state that does not recquire a license,
and who has not graduated from a college charted by one 
of the states, and, Fourth, A person graduated from a first- class
college not charted by one of the states of the Union, and who
has practiced his profession according to the laws of a territory 
or of the District of Columbia, however learned he may be. The
court, in State v. McIntosh, 103 S.W. 1078, at page 1985, said:
    "A certificate from the faculty of a collage attesting
that its bearer as a student, say in and day out, with 
scholarly patience and research, had equipped himself with
the technical knowledge taught in such college as contemplated
by the foregoing statute, is of the collage that its
holder attended lectures, possessed himself of the learning 
of his text under the eyes of his preceptors, and was
capabel of rendering professional service to the people
in accordance with the rules of his art; that he was, in 
the language of State ex rel Gregory, supra, ' no pretender,
no empiric, mountebank, charlatan, or quack'. It is manifest
that no practicable examination by a dental board
could go quite so deep or be so searchingly broad in its
meaning as an honest, well- earned diploma of that sort.
The law places its benediction on such a diploma, assigning
it not trifling officed, and public sentiment tends to 
support that theory."</p>
<pb/>
<p>The Dentistry Act of New York provided that applicants
for license shall have had a preliminary education equivalent
to a high school course and a professional education in a dental
or medical school. The Court of Appelas, in People v. Griswold,
106 N.E. 929, at pages 130-31, said:
        "The appellant complains that the door of the examination
    room has been closed to him regarldess of his 
    actual qualifications, his long experience in other
    states and of the fact that when he began the study and practice
    of dentistry no such preliminary and profesional
    requirements were imposed, and he asserts that 
    her is thus precluded from following in a lawful calling
    by an unreasonable, arbitrary, and discriminatory statute
    in violation of various provisions of the state and 
    federal constitutions. *****
        The general power of the state to exact proper skill
    and learning of theose who follow pursuits involving the
    public health, safety and welfare, and to prescribe appropriate 
    tests therefor, cannot at this date be questioned.
    It has been exercised from time immemorial and has 
    been sustained by repeated decisions of the courts. 
    (Citing cases)
        In determining whether statuatory requirements are
    arbitrary, unreasonable or discriminatory, it must be
    borne in mind that the choice of measures is for the 
    legislature, who are presumed to have investigated the
    subject and to have acted with reason, not from caprice. 
    Legislation passed in the exercise of police power, must 
    be reasonable in the sense that it must be based on 
    reason as distinct from being wholly arbitrary or capricious, 
    but when the legislature has power to legislate 
    on a subject, the courts may only look into its 
    enactment far enough to see whether it is in any view
    adapted to the end intended. If it is, the court must
    give it effect, however unwise they may regard it, ot
    give it effect, however unwise they may regard it, or
    however much they might, if given the choice, prefer
    some other measure as more fit and appropriate. 
        Coming then to the particular provisions of the act 
    in question, the requirement as to preliminary and professional
    education is not, in and of itself, either 
    arbitrary or unreasonable. A preliminary education equivalent
    to a four year high school course registered by the 
    regents and a professional education in a registered
    dental or medical school, or both, are certainly appropriate 
    to fit one to pursue the calling of dentistry,
    and with the wisdom of that requirement we have nothing
    to do.
        The appellant has no grievance from the provision
    that those duly license and registered as dentists in 
    this state prior to the 1st day of August, 1895, are 
    deemed licensed to practice. It is the rule for such
    acts to preserve the status of those lawfully engaged
    in the pursuit regulated ***** All persons in the same
    class, i. e., those licensed and registered in this
    state on a given date, are treated alike*****</p>
    <p>It may seem hard that the defendant, who had practiced
    dentistry for many years in other stated, cannot 
    be licensed here, or even permitted to take an examination 
    to test his qualifications, until he first
    acquires the requisite preliminary and professional 
    education; but it is difficult, of not impossible, to
    <pb/>
    make a classification which will not in particular
    instances seem unjust. All in the same class as 
    the defendant are treated alike."</p>
<p>The Supreme Court of California, in Ex Parte Whitley,
77 Pacific, 879, held constitutional and a valid exercise of
the police power of the state a statute creating a Board of
Dental Exmainers and making a diploma from a reputable dental
college a condition precendent upon the taking of the examination
for license to practice dentistry.</p>
<p>An act similar to the one in issue was sustained by the 
Supreme Court of Colorado, in Gothard v. People, 74 Pac. 890,
in which the court, at page 891, said:
    "The second assignment is based upon the proposition
that because power is given by the statute to the
state board to restrict the practice of dentistry to 
persons holding a diploma from a dental school, college
or university of the class designated, without 
respect to ability of the applicant to pass such an
examination as may be conducted by the board itself,
an unwarranted discrimination is thereby made in favor
of those holding a diploma against those who do not,
in favor of on class of citizens as against another.
This objection made to acts of this and similar character
has been repeatedly overruled by many of the most 
respectble courts of this country. While a citizen
of the United States has the undoubted right**** to
pursue any lawful profession in a lawful manner, nevertheless 
such pursuit is always subject to such reasonable
restrictions as may be lawfully prescribed by the
legislature of each state, in order to protect the
public health and promote the general interest of society;
and so long as such restrictions are reasonable,
not arbitrart or oppressive, and leave the field open 
for every citizen of the United States who comes endowed 
with all the necessary qualifications to practice
his profession, the law cannot be declared constitutional.
    Applying these tests to this statute, we cannot
sat that restrictions upon the right to practice
dentistry conatined therein have no relation to such
profession, or are arbitrary, or that the qualifications
thereby prescribed and unattainable by reasonable
study and application. Every citizen who desires
to practice dentistry is accorded the same opportunity,
and is bound by the same restrictions, which are applicable
to all, and we cannot say that it is an unreasonable
restriction that only such persons as hold a diploma
from some authorized dental school are entitled
to take the examination, or fit to practice dentistry."</p>
<p>The Supreme Court of Kansas, in State v. Creditor, 24 Pac.
346, in holding constitutional a dentistry act requiring a diploma
from some reputable dental college as a prerequisite to
practice within the state, at page 346, said:
<pb/>
        "If the regulations and conditions are adopted in
    good faith and they operate equally upon all who may
    desire to practice, and who possess the required qualifications,
    and if they are adopted to the legislative
    purpose of promoting the health and welfare of the
    people by excluding from the practice those who are ignorant
    and incapable, then the fact that the conditions
    may be rigorous, impolitical, and unjust will not render 
    the legislation invalid." </p>
<p>That the state has the right to regulate the practice of
dentistry and thereby protect the public from ignorant and incompetent
persons who may wrongfully and fraudulently announce
themselves as skillful and qualified practitioners, I think is
conceded, even though the liberty of an individual may be restricted
and rights contended for limited, and perhaops some
apparent hardship visited upon some indivudual becuiase of pecuniary 
sitaution. If the state thinks an evil exists it has
a right to legislate against it, and in Otis et al. v. Parker,
187 U.S., 607, the court says:
        "If the state thinks an admitted evil cannot be
    prevented except by prohibiting a calling or transaction
    not in itself necessarily objectionable, the 
    courts cannot interfere, unless, in looking at the
    substance of the matter, they can see that it is a
    clear, unmistakable infringment of the rights secured
    by the fundatmental law."
Justice Day, in Schmidinger v. Chicago, 226 U.S. 578, says:
        "This court has had frequent occasion to declare
    that there is no absolute freedom of contract. The 
    exercise of police power fixing weights and measures
    and standard arises must necessarily limit the freedom 
    of contract which would otherwise exist. Such limitations 
    are constantly imposed upon the right of contact 
    deemed necessary in the interest of the general 
    welfare."
The same rule would apply to the instant case.</p>
<p>Justice Hughes, for the court, in C.B. &amp; Q. Ry. Co. v.
McGuire, 219 U.S. 549, in considering an act of the legislature
making railway companies liable in damages for injury sustained
by any person, including employees, in consequence of the neglect,
mismanagement, or wilful wrongs of the employes or agents of such
corporations, in which it was held that the act did not interfere
with the liberty to make contracts or deny the equal protection
<pb/>
of the laws under the 14th amendment of the Constitution, said:
        "There is no absolute freedome to do as one wills
    or to contract as one chooses. The guaranty of liberty
    does not withdraw from legislative supervision that wide
    department of activity which consists of the making of
    contracts, or deny to government the power to provide
    restrictive safeguards, Liberty implies the absence of
    arbitrary restraint, not immunity from reasonable regulations
    and prohibitions imposed in the interest of the
    community."
and,
        "It is subject also, in the field of state action
    to the essential authority of government to maintain
    peace and security, and to enact laws for the promotion
    of the health, safety, morals and welfare of those subject
    to its jurisdiction."</p>
<p>Justice Holmes, in Noble State Bank v. Haskell, 219 U. S. 104,
said:
        "It may be said in a general way that the police
    power extends to all in the great publiv needs***** It
    may be put forth in aid of what it sanctioned by usage,
    or held by prevailing morality or strong and preponderany
    opinion to be greatly and immediately necessary to
    the public welfare."</p>
<p>In Halter v. Nebraska, 205 U.S. 35, Justice Harlan, for the
court, said:
        "Another vital principle is that, except as restrained
    by its own fundamental law, or by the Supreme
    law of the land, a State possesses all legislative 
    power consistent with a republian form of government.
    Therefore each state, when not thus restrained, and
    so far as this court is concerned, may, by legislation 
    provide, ***** for the common good as involved in the
    well- being, peace, happiness and prosperity of the
    people".</p>
<p>In Murphy v. California, 225 U.S. 623, in passing upon the
constitionality of an ordinace passed by the City of Pasadena,
Justice La Mar said:
        "The Fourteenth Amendment protects the citizen in 
    his right to engage in any lawful business, but it does 
    not prevent legislation intended to regulate useful occupations,
    which, becuase of their nature or location, may
    prove injurious***** to the public."</p>
<p>In many ways and phases have these constitutional provisions been 
before the Supreme Court of the United States, and in all of the 
cases has the exercise opf legislative discretion been held not
to be the subjects of judicial review in the absence of arbitrary
restraint. </p>
<p>In Holden v. Hardy, 169 U.S. 366, Justice Brown, for the
court said:
      "The question in each case is whether the legislature 
  has adopted the statute in exercise of a reasonable 
  discretion, or whether its section be a mere excuse
  for an unjust discrimination, or the oppression, or
  spoilation of a particular class."
The act in question does not prohibit any person from engaging
in the practice of dentistry. It does fix standards as a basis
for a license, and the state court having twice passed upon the
act and held it to be a reasonable regulation and not an arbitrary
restraint, and the same conclusion having been reached by the highest
courts of many of the other state with relation to similar
acts, I think the conlsusion in inevitable that this court should
not hold the act unconstitutional.</p>
<p>May cases are cited by petitioner in support of his contention.
In People v. Steele, 14 L. R. A. (N.S.) 368, the Supreme
Court of Illinois held unconstituional a statute making it unlawful 
to sell theatre, circus or amusement tickets at a price in advance
of the price printed thereon, and simply held that it was
not against public morals or welfare for a broker to sell at a
profit tickets which it is his business to sell, and therefore
deprive him of his property and his liberty.</p>
<p>In Kansas City Gas Co. v. Kansas City, 198 Fed. 500, and
ordinance which impaired the obligation of a valid contract entered
into between the City and the Gas Company was held inoperative.</p>
<p>In State v. Robinson Company, 42 Wash. Dec., page 79, the
Supreme Court of Washington denounced as class legislation and
violative of Section 12, Article 1 of the State Constitution an
act authorizing cereal and flouring mills to sell mixed and unmixed
feeding stuffs are required to sign a sworn statement as
to the character of ingredients and percentage of constituents,
affix same on a tag, etc., which was clearly a discrimination and
not within the issues in the insant case.</p>
<pb/>
<p>In Yick Wo v. Hopkins, 118 U.S. 326, the Court held
a statute making it unlawful for any person "to establish, 
maintina, or carry on a laundry within the corporate limits
of the City and County of San Francisco without having first
obtained the consent of the board of supervisors, except
the same be located in a building constructed either of brick or
stone", unconstitutional. The act was held not to be within
the police power of the state since as to persons desiring to 
establish or maintain laundries in wooden buil;dings, it was
arbitrary.</p>
<p>In Lochner v. New York, 198 U.S. 52, four Justices
disenting, the court held an arbitrary, unreasonable, and
unwarranted usurpation of the constitutional right to contract,
a stature providing that bakers should not be employed more 
than sixty hours a week or ten hours a day.</p>
<p>In State v. Goodwill, 6 L. R. A. 622, the West Virginia
Supreme Court held a statute regulating the method of payment
of employes engage in mining or manufacturing from mineral products
unconstitutional as discriminatory and an unreasonable interference 
and class legislation, other employes not being included 
within the provisions of the act.</p>
<p>In Barber v. Connolly, 113 U.S. 27, the court sustained
an ordinance prohibiting carrying on laundries in certain districts 
of the city between ten P.M. and six A.M. and held that 
the burdens were laid upon all alike in the same calling and condition. </p>
<p>In Raich v. Truax, 219 Fed. 273, the District Court for
the District of Arizona held an act requiring all employers of
labor within the stae to emply not less than eighty per cent 
of qualified elctos or native born citizens, unconstitutional
as denying to other classes the equal protection of the laws.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court of New Hampshire, in State v. Pennoyer,
<pb/>
5 L. R. A. 709, held unconstitutional an act requiring practitioners
of medicine, surgery or dentistry within the state to
resent a college degree or present a license upon examination, 
and pay a fee therefore, except persons who had resided and practiced 
their profession in the town or city of their present residence
all the time between January 1, 1875 and January 1, 1889.
The Court, at page 710 et seq, said:
        "The law cannot discriminate in favor of one citizen 
    to the detriment of another. The principle of equality 
    pervades the entire Constitution. The Bill of Rights 
    declares expressly that all government is instituted for
    the general good, for the common benefir, protection and 
    security of the whole community, and not for the interests
    or emolument of any one man, family, or class of men; that
    every member of the community has a right to be protected
    by it in the enjoyment of his life, liberty and property.
    
    No one citizen or class of citizens can by law be charged
    with the performance of duties or be subjected to burdens 
    not by law made incumbent upon all other citizens in the 
    same circumstances.*******"
and further states that the objection is that
        "Of those physicians who are declared by statute,
    or under its provision, are found, qualified to practice,
    some are and some are not subjected to the burden
    of obtaining a license. Exemption from that burden
    is made to depend, not on integrity, education and
    medical skill, but upon a continuous dwelling in one
    place for (at) a certain time. It is arbitrary discrimination
    permitting some and forbidding others to
    carry on their business without regard to their competency
    or to any material difference in their situation.
    The test is not merit but unchanged residence. 
    For the right to continue the pursiot of his profession
    one physician is not while another, his neighbor, who 
    may be his equal or superior in learning, experience and 
    ability, is, required to pay $5.00. This is not the 
    equality of the Constitution. The magnitude of the
    unequal burden is immaterial. If any inequality is
    permitted the discrimination might be made prohibitory
    and a monopoly of business given to physicians who have 
    residence in a town or city for a specified time."
In the instant case all are placed upon the same basis, but in
State v. Penneyer, supra, discrimination is made in favor of the
individual or individuals who have resided at one place for a 
certain lengeth of time.</p>
<p>In C.M. &amp; St. P. Ry. Co. v. Westby, 47 L.R.A. (N.S.)
97, the court heldm as class legislation, the Employer's Liability
Act of North Dakota, which imposed duties upon common carriers
<pb/>
and created causes of action in favor of employes therof for
injuries caused by the negligence of fellow servants, not imposed
upon other employers or granted to other employes.</p>
<p>In Bonnet v. Vallier, 17 L.R.A. (N.S.) 486, the court said:
        "There must be a reasonable ground for police interference
    and also the means adopted must be reasonably
    necessary for the accomplishment of the purpose in view".
in considering a statute containing regulations as to safety and
sanitary conditions of tenement, lodging anf boarding houses within 
the state, irrespective of the size of tiwns or cities, and 
requiring street courts of tenement houses to be six feet in width
under all conditions and in all localities.</p>
<p>In Wyeth v. Thomas, 23 L.R.A (N.S.) 147 (Mass.), the
court held obnoxious to the constitution an act requiring an undertaker
to obtain a license by showing that he is a graduate form 
an accredited embalming college.</p>
<p>In Smith v. Texas, 233 U.S. 630, an act making it unlawful
for any person to act as conductor of a freight train without
having previously served two years as conductor on such trains, 
was held unconstitutional. The courtm Justice Holmes dissenting,
held that as the public interest is the basis of such legislation,
the test and prohibition should be enacted with reference to that
object and so as not to interfere with private business or impose
unusual or unnecessary restraints upon lawful occupations, and
further stated that such a stature would shut the door without
a hearing upon many persons and classes of persons who were competent 
to serve, and deprive them of the liberty to work in a
calling which they were qualified to fill with safety to the 
public and benefit to themselves. </p>
<p>In People v. Shenck, 44 L. R. A. 46, the Supreme Court
of Illinois held unconstitutional as class legislation an act
forbidding the employment of persons to operate mery or buffing
wheels or belts in basements wholly or aprtly beneath the surface
<pb/>
of the ground, since such rooms may be as healthfully
lighted and ventilated as those above the surface, and can be
used for the prohibited purpose as healthfully as can be the
latter.</p>
<p>In Connolly v. Union Sewer Pipe Co., 184 U.S. 679, the
court held repugnant to the provisions of the 14th amendment,
the Illinois "trust act" of June 20, 1893, exempting agricultural
products or live stock in the hands of the producer or
raiser from the provsione which prohibited the regulation of
the price of articles sold by any trust or combination formed
in restraint of trade or competition in violation of that act. </p>
<p>A review of the cases would not justify this court in 
holding inoperative the act in question by reason of the constitutional
limitations.</p>
<p>The writ is denied.</p>
<p>Jeremiah Neterer
JUDGE.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>