<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0186.012">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Antonio Bisegna v. United States. Petition.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0186.012</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Antonio Bisegna v. United States. Petition.</title>
<date when="1914-02-16">Feburary 16, 1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2679AntonioBisegna</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-02">Feburary 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Lakin, Edward M.</term>
<term>White, Henry M.</term>
<term>Post, Louis F.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Aquila Province, Italy</term>
<term>British Columbia</term>
<term>Canada</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Bisegna, Antonio</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Shela, Louis, E.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Lundin, Alfred H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, George P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States for the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of
Antonio Bisegna, alias Disegna,
for Writ of Habeas Corpus } No. 2679
Petition for Writ of
Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>To the Honorable Jeremiah Neterer, Judge of the United
States District Court of the Western District of Washington,
Northern Division:</p>
<p>The petition of Antonio Bisegna respectfully represents
and shows to this honorable court as follows:</p>
<p>I. That your petitioner is unjustly and unlawfully detained
and imprisoned in the King County jail in the City of Seattle
in said County, State of Washington, by the United States Commissioner
of Immigration.</p>
<p>II.
That your petitioner is a white person, born in the Province 
of Aquila, Northern Italy, and left his native country of
his own free will and not by any reason of having committed any
offense against the laws of said country, and lawfully entered
the United States on Feburary 14, 1908, and has ever since made
this country his place of residence; that on April 17, 1910, he
left certain of his personal affects in said City of Seattle and
temporarily went to British Columbia, Deominion of Canda, where
he remained until October 22, 1913, when he returned to said
City of Seattle.</p>
<p>III.
Your petitioner further shows that he is of sound mind, in
good health, ablebodied and able to take care of himself, and
has ever had sufficient funds to meet all the requirements of
<pb/>
the laws of the United States, and did not enter the United
States as a contract laborer.</p>
<p>IV.
Your petitioner further shows that he has not been
been convicted of or admitted having committed a felony
or other crime involving moral turpitude, and that he
is not held by said Immigration Commssioner upon any final
process issued by a Court of common jurisdiction or
held upon any process or order for any contempt of any
Court, officer or body hving authority to commit or hold 
him, nor upon any warrant issued by any court of this
State upon indictment or infomration in this State, nor 
is there any lawful or valid reason for the detention of
your petitioner.</p>
<p>V.
That your petitioner is held by the said Commissioner
of Immigration upon the alleged ground that he was a person
likely to become a public charge at the time of his
entry into the United States as shown by a copy of the
warrant of arrest hereto annexed, but your petitioner avers
that the time and place of entry into the United States is
not as set forth in said warrant, but as hereinbefore set
forth, and that he was at the time of entry and now is
able to secure and save harmless the United States from
any damage of any kind and nature whatsoever arising from
<fw>(2)</fw>
<pb/>
inability of your petitioner to support and take care of
himself, and that he is amply able and willing and intends
to be a good and selfsupporting resident of the United 
States.</p>
<p>VI
Your petitioner further represents that he was not
given a fair and impartial hearing, as is contemplated by
law; that the Immigration officials and inspectors were
biased and prejudiced and are attempting to do indirectly
what they could not do directly, in that your petitioner
believes that the evidence upon which said officials bases
their charge was the commission of an assual on the third
degree, as defined by the statute of the State of Washington,
a misdemeanor not involving moral turpitude, by this
petitioner after his entry into the United States and for
which your petitioner was not responsible; that the special 
examining board and Secretary of Labor and said Commissioner
exceeded their authority and jurisdiction and acted in an
arbitrary manner and that there is no evidence to bring
this petitioner within the excluded classes at the time of
his entry, but all of the evidence is to the contrary and
shows that your petitioner had entered the United States
more than three years prior to the issuance of the warrant
of arrest herein, which warrant was issued contrary to and
without any foundation in law, and that your petitioner is
not amendable to the law which is the basis for the issuance
of said warrant.</p>
<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays:</p>
<p>1. That a Writ of Habeas Corpus issue out of this Court directed
to Henry M. White, the said Commissioner of Immigration,
in whose custody your petitioner now is, commanding and requiring
said Commissioner to have the body of your petitioner before
this Court on some special and convenient day to be determined
<fw>(3)</fw>
<pb/>
by this court, and then and there to show cause why this petitioner
is detained of his liberty, and why he should not be 
forthwith and immediatel discharged from said custody.</p>
<p>II. 
That the pending of the return of this Writ at the date so
to be fixed by this court to assure his appearance at the said
return day.</p>
<p>III.
That your petitioner be discharged from said custody and
that he have such other and further relief as this court may 
deem just.</p>
<ab>Antonio Bisegna
Petitioner.</ab>
<p>United States of America,
Western District of Washington. }ss:</p>
<p>Antonio Bisegna, being first duly sworn deposes and says:
That he is the petitioner named in the foregoing petition subscribed
by him; that he has <add>had</add> read the same <add>to him</add>, knows the contents
thereof and believes the same to be true.</p>
<ab>Antonio Bisegna</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 16th day of Feburary,
1914.</p>
<ab>Louis E. Shela
Notary Public in and for the State of
Washington, residing at Seattle, Wash.</ab>
<figure><ab><unclear/>Notary Public</ab></figure>
<fw>(4)</fw>
<pb/>
<p>Warrant - Arrest of Alien</p>
<p>United States of America
Department <del><unclear/></del> <add>Washington</add> Labor</p>
<p>No. 53628/66.</p>
<p>To Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration, Seattle, Washington,
Or to any Immigrant Inspector in the service of the United States.</p>
<p>Whereas, from evidence submitted to me, it appears that the alien
Antonio Bisegna, alias Disegna,
who landed at the port of Seattle, Washington, ex SS "Princess Victoria",
on <del><unclear/></del> the 22nd day of Oct. 1913, has been found in the United States
in violation of the Act of Congress approved Feburary 20, 1907, amended by the
Act approved March 26, 1910, to wit:</p>
<p>That the said alien is a member of the excluded classes in that he was a 
person likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry into the
United States,</p>
<p>I, Louis F. Post, Acting, Secretary of <del><unclear/></del> Labor, by
virtue of the power and authority vested in me by the laws of the Untied States,
do hereby command you to take into custody the said alien and grant him a 
hearing to enable him to show cause why he should
not be deported in conformity with law.</p>
<p>The expenses of detention hereunder, if necessary, are authorized, payable
from the appropriation "Expenses of Regulating Immigration, 1914",. Pending
disposition of his case the alien may be released from custody upon furnishing
satisfactory bond in the sum of $500.00.</p>
<p>For so doing, this shall be your sufficient warrant.
Witness my hand and seal this 5th day of December, 1913.</p>
<ab>(SD) Louis F. post,
Acting Secretary of <del><unclear/></del> Labor.</ab>
<p><unclear>13-g19</unclear></p>
<pb/>
<p>2x No. <gap reason="blank"/></p>
<p>In the District Court
of the United Sates
for the 
Western
District of Washington
Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Antonio Bisegna, alias
Disegna, for Writ of Habeas 
Corpus.</p>
<p>Petition for Writ of Habeas 
Corpus.</p>
<p>Filed in the 
U.S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington.
Northern Division
FEB 16 1914
Frank L Crosby, Clerk,
By EML Deputy</p>
<p>Service of papers in this case may be made
upon Alfred H. Lundin and
Louis E. Shela,
Attorneys for petitioner. at
No. <gap reason="blank"/> Street
Room 811 Lowman Bldg., Block
Seattle, Washington.</p>
<p>Lowman &amp; Hanford Co., Seattle, Wash. - Form No. 102</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>