<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0376.018">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Junichi Yamamoto v. Luther Weedin. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="ka">Salma J. Silva</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0376.018</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Junichi Yamamoto v. Luther Weedin. Petition</title>
<date when="1922-03-09">March 9, 1922</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1922-03">March 1922</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Yamamoto, Junichi</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Weedin, Luther</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Hellsell, Frank P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Gates</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Falkner, Judson J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Cushman, Edward E.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-10" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>No. 6617</p>

<p>PETITION</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION
OF JUNICHI, YAMAMOTO, FOR
WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>

<p>TO THE JUDGES OF THE ABOVE ENTITLED COURT:</p>

<p>Comes now Junichi Yamamoto and respectfully petitions
the above entitled court and represents as follows:</p>

<p>I</p>

<p>That your petitioner is a citizen of the Empire of
Japan and since September 17, 1917 has been a resident of the
Western District of the State of Washington.</p>

<p>II</p>

<p>That your petitioner was born December 22, 1890 in
Japan and at all times resided in Japan until on or about the
first day of September, 1917 when your petitioner shipped as
an able bodied seaman on the steamship "Taiyo Maru", a Japanese
vessel registered under the laws of Japan, and came by a direct
passage of said steamship from the Empire of Japan to Seattle,
Washington, without touching at any other country besides the
United States. That your petitioner in order to leave Japan 
and reach the United States was not required by any of the
official authorities of either the United States or Japan to
have a passport of any kind or description whatsoever, but your
petitioner came as a member of the crew of said steamship, and
your petitioner's name was carried upon the crew list of said
steamship, which was vised by the American Consul at the point</p>

<pb/>

<p>OF departure of said vessel in Japan. That at the time of
the arrival of said ship in a direct route from the Empire of
Japan to Seattle, Washington, your petitioner deserted said
ship and ever since September 17, 1917 has been and is now a 
resident of Seattle, Washington.</p>

<p>III</p>

<p>That Luther Weedin, United States Commissioner of
Immigration, located at Seattle, Washington, on the 10th day
of January, 1922, received by telegram from the United States
Department of Labor, a warrant for the arrest of your petitioner,
which warrant was in words and figures as follows, to-wit:</p>

<p>"Arrest following named alien and grant
hearing, forwarding record of proceed-
ings to Department: Jutichi Yamamoto.
Entered in Violation of Rule 11 of the
Immigration Rules. Likely to become
a public charge at time of entry."</p>

<p>IV</p>

<p>That after said arrest your petitioner was given a
hearing before Arthur J. Kahl, an Immigrant Inspector at the 
United States Immigration Office at Seattle, Washington. That
said hearing was held on the 10th day of January, 1922 and
thereafter continued to January 16th, 1922. That at said 
hearing testimony was taken and a complete transcript of all 
proceedings that occurred at said hearing is attached hereto
and marked Exhibit "A". That thereafter a transcript of said
proceedings before said Immigrant Inspector, an exact copy of
Exhibit "A" hereto attached, was sent by Luther Weedin, United
States Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, to
the United States Department of Labor at Washington, D.C.,
and upon the record as contained in Exhibit "A" and solely
upon said record, the Assistant Secretary of Labor at Washington,
D.C. issued a warrant directing the deportation of petitioner</p>

<pb/>

<p>to Japan.</p>

<p>V</p>

<p>That thereafter Luther Weedin, United States Commission-
er of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, notified your peti-
tioner, Junichi Yamamoto, to surrender himself into custody at
the United States Immigration Station at Seattle, Washington,
and your petitioner has, pursuant to said order surrendered
himself to said United States Immigration Commissioner and is
now in the custody of said commissioner and under arrest by 
said commissioner, pursuant to said warrant for deporatation
issued by the said Assistant Secretary of Labor at Washington,
D.C.</p>

<p>VI</p>

<p>That at no time prior hereto has this petitioner been 
a person likely to become a public charge. That at the time
your petitioner landed at Seattle, Washington, on September 17,
1917, your petitioner had in his possession eight hundred
Japanese gold yen, equivalent at that time to approximately
Four hundred Dollars in United States gold coin. That since
said time your petitioner has been engaged in farming, has 
paid $800.00 upon a Ford truck and has sent to his home in
Japan the sum of Fifteen Hundred Dollars. That your petitioner
recently sold his equity in said truck for the sum of Four
hundred and fifty Dollars. That your petitioner is healthy,
able-bodied and well able to earn his own living.</p>

<p>VII</p>

<p>That your petitioner is being unlawfully deprived of
his liberty in violation of Article V of <add>amendments to</add> the Constitution of
the United States. That your petitioner is being deprived of</p>

<pb/>

<p>his liberty without due process of law, in this: that under
the statutes of the United States in such cases made and pro-
vided, your petitioner cannot be deported from the United
States after the expiration of three years from the date when
your petitioner landed at Seattle, Washington; and in this:
that your petitioner has never at any time been brought before
a special board of inquiry for examination as to your petition-
er's qualification for admission into the United States. That
your petitioner is being deprived of his liberty without due
process of law, in this: That your petitioner has never at 
any time held a passport to proceed to any country other than 
the continental territoy of the United States, but came to
Seattle, Washington, without any passport whatsoever, while
acting as an able-bodied seaman upon a Japanese vessel. That 
your petitioner left the Empire of Japan on a direct passage
to Seattle, Washington, without being required to have any
passport of any kind whatsoever, and your petitioner during 
said passage did not touch at any country other than the con-
tinental territory of the United States. That your petitioner
does not come within any of the classes excluded by the
Immigration Laws of the United States; that your petitioner
did not enter and is not in the United States in violation of 
any law of the United States.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner prays that this court may
issue a writ of habeas corpus directing Luther Weedin, United
States Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, to
have the body of your petitioner before this Honorable Court at
a day to be fixed by said court, and that upon said day your</p>

<pb/>

<p>petitioner be discharged from the custody of said United States
Commissioner of Immigration, and be allowed to go hence; that 
this court adjudge your petitioner is being held without war-
rant of law and without due process of law, in violation of
Article V of the Constitution of the United States; that
pending the hearing upon said writ of habeas corpus, that this
court admit your petitioner to bail on furnishing a bond in
such penal sum as to the court shall seem proper, and for such
other and further relief as to the court shall seem just and 
equitable.</p>

<p>Junichi Yamamoto</p>
<p>Petitioner</p>

<p>Gates &amp; Helsell</p>
<p>Attorneys for Petitioner</p>

<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>COUNTY OF KING</p>

<p>ss.</p>

<p>JUNICHI YAMAMOTO, being first duly sworn,
on oath deposes and says: That he is the petitioner above
named; that he has read the foregoing petition, knows the
contents thereof and that the same are true as he verily belies.</p>

<p>Junichi Yamamoto</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me 
this 9th day of March, 1922.</p>

<p>Frank P. Helsell</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington residing at Seattle.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>