<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0463.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1891">1891</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-09" who="#lkw">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES
9TH. JUDICIAL CIRCUIT, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTION, <add>Northern</add> <del>Western</del> DIVISION.

In the Matter of the Application 
of
John McKinnon for a Writ of Habeas 
Corpus.

To the Honorable C. H. Hanford, Judge of the Circuit
Court of the United States, 9th Judicial Circuit, District of
Washington, Western Division.

The petition of John McKinnon respectfully shows to 
your Honor:

1st. That the said petitioner is now and was at all times hereinafter alleged a citizen of the United States.

2nd. That the said petitioner is now a prisoner imprisoned and 
confined in the custody of the United States Marshall in and for
the district of Washington in the County Jail of Spokane County,
State of Washington.

3rd. That the cause or pretense of the restraint of the said
petitioner according to the best of his knowledge and belief
is that on or about the 25th day of August, 1895 in the District 
and County of Yale in the Province of British Columbia, one, 
Cornelius O'Keefe filed his complaint with Price Ellison a Magistrate
in and for said district and county, charging that the said
petitioner did on the 18th day of August, 1895, at or near Vernon
in the County of Yale, Province of British Columbia, steal four
neat cattle, property of him, the said Cornelius O'Keefe, which
said complaint together with the depositions and evidence offered
upon the hearing of said charge with the warrant of arrest and warrant of commitment therein, marked Exhibits A. B. C. and D.
is as follows, and is hereby made a part of this petition.

<pb/>

Indictable Offences.

(A) Vide ss. 1 and 9.

Information and Complaint for an Indictable Offence.
Canada.
Province of British Columbia.
District or County of Yale.

"Exhibit A"

THE INFORMATION and complaint of Cornelius O'Keefe of 
Okanogan taken twenty fourth day of August in the year of our
Lord One Thousand Eight hundred and ninety five before the undersigned 
of her Majesty's Justice in and for the said District of
County of Yale. who saith that John McKinnon on or about the 18th
day of August instant at or near Vernon in the County aforesaid 
four neat cattle of the goods and chattles of the said Cornelisu
O'Keefe did unlawfully did steal.

C. O'Keefe.

SWORN before me the day and year first above mentioned.

Price Ellison.

<pb/>

Indictable Offences.

(S) Section 590.

Deposition of a witness.

Canada

Province of British Columbia. County of Yale.

"Exhibit B"

The deposition of H. R. Parke of Vernon taken
before the undersigned P. M. for the siad County of Yale this
24th day if August in the year 1895 at Vernon in the presence and 
hearing of John McKinnon who stands charged that upon or about
the 18th day of August instant, at Vernon in the District of Yale
for neat cattle of the goods and chattels of C. O'Keefe unlawfully 
did steal.

<pb/>

Harold R. Parke, sworn, saith:

I am Provincial Constable residing at the City of 
Vernon.

I produce a Hide-- On the evening of the twenty-third
of August instant I s w a portion of a hide projecting from under
John McKinnon's stable, the accused. I told Charles Emerson of the
hide being there.

The following morning Charles Emerson brought me a 
piece of paper with a drawing of the brand which he said was on
the hide I had told him about. I thought that it was Mrs. O'Keefe's
brand and told him to take O'Keefe with him to see the hide. A 
short time afterwards he, Charles Emerson and O'Keefe returned
bringing the hide produced with them (Exhibit A). Mr. O'Keefe
identified the brand on the hide produced as his brand, Mr. O'Keefe
then laid an information against John McKinnon and I arrested the
accused on the twenty fourth of August instant. After the arrest
I searched under McKinnon's stables and found two more hides. The
hide about to be produced is a reddish colored hide -- he ear cut
off -- The hide produced ("Exhibit B") I took out from under the
accused stables on the afternoon of the 24th day of August instant-
this hide has an indistinct brand on the left ribs resempling Mr.
O'Keefe's brand -- after that, still on the 24th day of August
instant, I went to the slaughter house where McKinnon, the accused
keeps his hides, and found one black hide branded with a triangle
on the left hip high up near the back bone, the top of the left
ear was cut off. I also found a small roan hide in the same place
with no brand on it that I could see, I also found a large red
and white hide with the ears cut off and left leg cutt off. These
last mentioned hides are now in my possession. On the 24th of August I also found in a cutter in the shed of 
<unclear/>

<pb/>

McKinnons a black calf without brand and head cut off -- I could 
discover no brands on the hides mentioned with the leg cut off.

Cross examined by Mr. Culey.

The brand on ("Exhibit B") resemples <gap></gap> this is on
the left ribs -- I believe this is a brand. When I saw a hide projecting
from under the stable I was climbing over the fence and not
more than ten feet way-- the floor of the stable was about two
feet from the ground. That side was hence all open. 

From what I knew of Charles Emerson's occupation I
told him of the hide being in the stables.

It was about six o'clock in the evening when I saw the
hide. -- about an hour or an hour and one-half afterwards I told
Emerson. Charles Emerson told me that he was a detective. He has no
done detective wrok for me before.

I have not got the paper emerson showed me. I never had
it in my possession. The hide (Exhibit A) when I saw it might have
been eight or ten days killed. The reason I told Emerson of the
projecting hide was that there was a reward of $500. offered for 
convictions of cattle stealing. I did not wish to work for a reward
as I am paid by the Government for my work.

I did not notice any other brands besides the one
mentioned, on the black hide found at the slaughter house. I think
I have seen Charles Emerson around here three or four months.

By the Bench.

The front of the stable is level with the ground and 
the side the manure heap fills up, the third side is blocked up
by a vehicle shed and the side where I saw the hide projecting is
about eighteen inches from the Govement fence.

the Government fence separates the building from the
Gaul and Government Building.

<pb/>

During the last week I have croseed the fence three times a day. I
always cross that way when I want to get meals for prisoners.

This place is in full view of any one crossing the fence 
but one cannot see anything under the stable without getting down
and looking.

Sometimes for months I never cross at all. The fence
is so close to the stables that anyone could see nothing under the 
stable without squeezing between the fence and building and getting
down to look.

When I first <del/> saw the hide the greater porion was
under the stable and the rest looked as if it had been pulled out
by a dog.

When I first spoke to Charles Emerson I intended to
continue the investifation myself. I used Emerson as a means.

I dont know of my own knowledge that the hide brought
by Mr? O'Keefe and Emerson on Saturday to me was the same hide
I saw on Friday morning.

I have seen Charles Emerson behind the Counter in
Shooke's fruit store apparently working. I dont know of any other
occupation.

H.R.Parke.

<pb/>

Charles Emerson, sworn saith: I am a Lathier.

Last Friday Mr. Parke informed me of a hide being under
McKinnon's stables he said I might look after it. I told him I 
would. About nine o'clock that night I went to McKinnons stable
I found the hide, (Exhibit A) there under the stable. The side of
the stable facing the fence is open from the ground. The fence is
about two feet from the stables. The fence is over four feet
high. The hide was under the stable all but one corner. I would
not have noticed it if I had not bee looking for it. I pulled the
hide out and started toward the sidewalk with it in my hand
In the morning of the 24th instant I examined the hide. after I
scraped off the hair I found a brand on it similar to the
There was an ear mark one ear was split. The other ear was not on
the hide. I left the hide in the brush behind the victoria stable
about five hours afterwards I took Mr. O'Keefe to see it. It was
in the same place where I had left it. I showed it to Mr. O'Keefe.
He said he would bring his rig and take the hide to the Jout House.
He did so. I saw the hide again on the 24th and again on the 25th.
I brought an hide into court this morning.

Const. Parke and myself found some more hides in a shed at 
McKinnons slaughter house between Vernon and Okanogah Lake. We fon
three hides. I found a brand on the Balck hide it was a triangle
The second hide was a roan hide. Could see not brand on it. The
third hide was a red and white. Could not see any brand or Marks
on it. These hides were sent to the Government house in an express
wagon. When I showed Mr. O'Keefe the hide exhibit A he said it was
his brand on it.

xd. When parke met me, he said good night. Then 
he said there was a hide under McKinnons stables. He said it might

<pb/>

pay me to look after it. I asked him whereabouts was under the
stable. He told me that it was near the southwest corner. It was
between half past six and seven or later. After I left Parke I
walked around town. I was in Hurks Barber shop part of the time. 
I did not say anything to Murk about what Parke had told me. I 
have been staying at Murks during the past week. I was also
in Davidsons fruit store and was about the street the rest of the
time until nine o'clock. It was dark at 9 o'clock just after
Parke informed me I walked past the place and saw that the hide
was there. When I went at nine o'clock for the hide I left it half 
way between the sidewalk and McKinnons shop. I wnet to the side-
walk as I saw a man there watching me. it was Mr. Birnie. He asked
me what I was doing there. I told him that I was taking a hide
out of there. I intended taking the hide to the brush. I was
scared the man on the sidewalk might say something about it. It 
was old Mr. Birnie-- after I spoke with Birnie I went back to the
hide and took it to the brush. I did not meet anyone else. I did
not tell anyone else that night what I had been doing. the hide
was not tied up. I saw Mr. Haron that night. he is night watchman. I
told him about the hide early Saturday morning. I told him about
taking the hide and asked him to come and see it after daylight. I
did not tell him what brand was on it as I had not seen it there. I 
told him I had not seen it there. I told him that I had left it
in the brush. Last a Wednesday night I slept either at Murks or
my own shack. I think I slept at Murks on Tuesday night. I remember
now I slept at Murks up to Friday night. I know a Half Breed named
Frank Pete. I saw him the say Smart was tried. in the afternoon.
it was nearly six. I saw him afterwards about eight o'clock, he
called me out of Davidsons. He was riding, he wanted me on business
he told me that there was counterfeit money among the six here.
He said he would be in Friday nights again. I saw him about four

<pb/>

o'clock on Friday. I am a detective. I have had experience on one
occasion. I have done detective work in the state before. I joined
the detective association. I have been in Vernon two years. I have
worked for Mr. Crowell. I have worked in Kelowna and Enderby.
I worked for Judge Spinks. I have had no permenent occupation
during the two years. there has not been enough lathing. I do not
know a siwash or half breed named Victor. I saw some siwashes on 
Friday night. The only one I saw at the Coral was Pete. There
were some whitemen strolling around. I took a walk with a white man
at the corral on Friday night. He left me with Pete, I saw Pete
twice that day. I did not say anything to Pete or Victor or any
siwash about the McKinnon business. 

C. EMERSON. 







</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>