<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>United States District Court
Western District of Washington
Northern Division</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Ching Hing for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus. } No. 2875
Memorandum Brief</p>
<p>It would seem that very little need be said in answer
to the Government's contention that your Honor should grant the petition
of said counsel and dismiss the application of the petitioner,
Ching Hing, fro to do so at the present statue of the case, would
seem, in my humble opinion, to destroy and usurp the dignity of this
Court by giving the right to an official of a department to supercede
the jurisdiction of your Honor in determining this case upon the
facts as the record shows at the time this application was filed
and return made therein.</p>
<p>The issue as it presents itself at this time, must be
the same issue according to Law, as presented itself at that time,
not taken under the order or permission of this Court who had, and
still has absolute jurisdiction over the subject matter and the person.</p>
<p>The petitioner alleged that he was illegally detained
in that J.B. Denamore acted without authority in signing the order
of deportation. The record shows respondent says the petitioner is
detained on the order of the Secretary of Labor. This is denied by
the petitioner, and the original mandate shows that the order of deportation
was signed by J.B. Denamore, Acting Secretary. Respondent
then, under my construction of the rules of evidence, must show that
Mr. Denamore was Acting Secretary under the order of the Executive,
because of the absence of the Secretary and Assistant Secretary, but
the petitioner denies that the Secretary and Assistant Secretary were
absent. This burden then is upon the respondent to show that the
Secretary and Assistant Secretary were absent when Mr. Denamore signed
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
the deportation order of the petitioner, Ching Hing. I respectfully
submit that if respondent, to meet the burden, can not show that the 
order of deportation and detention was made by one having authority,
the petitioner should be discharged.</p>
<p>There is no presumption of Law that the Secretary and 
Assistant Secretary were absent on September 26th, or that the solicitor,
Mr. J.B. Denamore, was Acting Secretary. It is a question of
fact to be proved by the one averring it, and again I submit that 
where the record shows that J.B. Denamore signed the warrant of
deportation, and the Government in its return to the application of
this petitioner on the 16th day of October, 1914, states that the
Secretary affirmed the order of deportation, that the burden of proof 
is upon them to show that J.B. Denamore acted with authority.</p>
<p>This same identical question has been passed upon by the
Honorable M.T. Dooling, Judge of the District Court of California,
First Division, in the case of the Application of Quan Wy Chung,
upon behalf of Tsuie Shee, his wife, and Quan Wy You, his son, for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus, wherein he held that the appellants and petitioners
therein were by Law entitled to appeal to the Secretary of Labor,
and were entitled to have their appeal reviewed and determined
by him, except in the absence of the Secretary and Assistant Secretary,
when the solicitor would be acting without authority, if it were proven
that he did act; and that the determination of their appeal by the
said solicitor, not authorized, is neither a fair hearing, nor due
process of Law.</p>
<p>Wherefore, this petitioner, Ching Hing, respectfully
submits that if it be proven that the Secretary or Assistant Secretary
were present in Washington when J.B. Denamore, solicitor, signed the
order of deportation of this petitioner, Ching Hing, that the same 
was without authority, not due process of Law, not a fair hearing, and
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
that the petitioner, Ching Hing, should be discharged.</p>
<p>Respectfully submitted,<lb/>
Beeler &amp; Sullivan<lb/>
Attorneys for Defendant</p>
<pb/>
<p>A copy of within Answers &amp; Petition
&amp; memorandum Brief
recieved and due service of same acknowledged this
21st day of April 191<gap reason="blank"/>
Winter S. Martin
Attorney for Asst US Atty</p>
<pb/>
<p>No. <del><unclear/></del> 2857
Original</p>
<p>In the 
Superior Court
State of Washington
King County</p>
<p>In re Application of CHing
Hing for a Writ of Habeas
Corpus.</p>
<p>Answer to Petition
and Memorandum Brief.</p>
<p>Beeler &amp; Sullivan
Lawyers
310-11 White Building
Seattle, Wash.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>