<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0487.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>In Re: Petition of Ham Hung Wah by Tom Sing for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Yu, Jingming" xml:id="jy">Jingming Yu</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0487.005</idno>
<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">In Re: Petition of Ham Hung Wah by Tom Sing for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</title>
<date when="2022-06-08">June 8, 2022</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Immigration</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1904-10"></date>October 1904</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Ham Hung Wah</term>
<term>C.H. Hanford</term>
<term>Tom Sing</term>
<term>Na Lay</term>
<term>Sistend Hillson</term>
<term>Charles H. Jackson</term>
<term>Robert M. Donaldson</term>
<term>Joseph H. Barker</term>
<term>E.M. Haremen</term>
<term>A.B. McPharson</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Montana</term>
<term>Boseman, Gallstin County, Montana</term>
<term>China</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Tom Sing</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Ham Hung Wah</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>C.H Hanford</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Ninth Judicial Circuit Court</orgName> 
<placeName>District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#jy">transcribed and encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>  

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0487.005"/>

<p>In re-
Ham Hung Wah
Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Order appointing <unclear/> ad litem</p>

<p>FILED IN THE
U.S. CIRCUIT COURT,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
OCT 7 1904
A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk
A.N. Moore
Dep.</p>

<p>United States of America,
District of Montana.</p>

<p>In the matter of the petition of Ham Hung Wah, for a writ of habeas corpus.</p>

<p>And now come <unclear>Sistend S. Hillson, Merchant. Charles H. Jackson, Merchant<unclear/> Pastor Presby Church, Joseph H. Baker <unclear/> Bozeman <unclear/> Real Estate <unclear/></unclear> <!--Signed-->and being severally duly sworn, upon their corporal oath, doth depose and say, each for himself, and not one for another, that he is and has been for more than ten years last past a resident of Boseman, Gallstin County, Montana. That he knows the Chinaman Tom Sing and his wife Na Lay, who, during a large portion of said period of time have resided in said Boseman; that when they first came to Boseman, they were reputed to be husband and wife, and lived and cohabited together as such. That after residing in said City some time, they adopted the habits of western civilization as to dress, abandoned the religion generally believed and practised by theire countrymen, and became members in good standing of the Presbyterian Church, which membership they now maintain. That they are persons of exceptional intelligence and propriety of demeanor, the Mother speaking the English language with a fluency and propriety equal to that of almost any native born American. That when they joined said church, in confirmation of their status of husband and wife, they were married according to the form sof the Presbyterian Church, having, as it was reputed, been theretofore married in the Empire of China. That the said Tom Sing is a credible witness, whose reputation for truth and veracity entitles him to be believed.</p>
<p>That his statement, with that of his said wife, as to the place and circumstances of the birth of said Ham Hung Wah, <unclear>conports</unclear> with what we know of it by reputation, and we believe teh same to be true, and that if an opportunity shall be afforded to take the testimony of producable witnesses, anad have it examined judicially, it will be made to appear that the said Ham Hung Wah was born in Montana, subject to the jurisdiction of, and a citizen of the United Statesw, and that in the matter of the attempted entry of him the said Ham Hung Wah, no attempt is being made to impose upon the authorities or to obtain an unlawful entry of a Chinese person within the United States.</p>
<p>And further affiants say not.</p>

<p><unclear>Sistend Hillson, Merchant
Charles H Jackson, Merchant
Robert M. Donaldson
Pastor Presbytarian Church Giver Oct 1st 1902
Joseph H. Barker<unclear/>
E.M Haremen Real Estate</unclear></p> <!--Signed-->

<p>Subscribed and sword to beforeme this Third day of October, 1904.
<unclear>A.B. McPharson</unclear><!--Signed-->
U.S. Commissions</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>