<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0456.004">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Albert Friedrich v. State of Washington. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0456.004</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Albert Friedrich v. State of Washington. Petition</title>
<date when="1892-08-09">August 9, 1892</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1892-08">August 1892</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Scherbring, Julius</term>
<term>Spencer, W. B.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Friedrich, Albert</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>State of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Tyler, W. B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Haight, James A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
<persName>Humes, T. J.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court, District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-11" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE, THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, DISTRICT
OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION OF
ALBERT FREDERICH FOR A WRIT OF 
HABEAS CORPUS.</p>

<p>THE COMPLAINT OF ALBERT FREDERICH RESPECTFULLY SHOWS THAT
HE IS NOW A PRISONER CONFINED IN THE STATE PENETENTIARY OF THE
STATE OF WASHINGTON, AT WALLA WALLA IN THE SAID STATE IN THE CUSTODY
OF <gap></gap> WARDEN OF SAID PENETENTIARY.</p>

<p>THAT HIS IMPRISONMENT IS BY VIRTUE OF A WARRANT <del>and judgment</del> A COPY OF
WHICH IS HERETO ATTACHED AND MARKED EXHIBIT "A" <add>"and B"</add>, AND NOT OTHER-
WISE; AND THAT THIS COMPLAINANT IS INFORMED BY HIS COUNSEL MESSRS
TYLER &amp; TYLER AND VERILY BELIEVES THAT HIS IMPRISONMENT IS ILLEGAL
AND THAT SUCH ILLEGALITY CONSISTS IN THIS TO-WIT</p>

<p>THAT COMPLAINANT WAS DULY INDICTED BY THE GRAND JURY OF KING
COUNTY, STATE OF WASHINGTON, ONE THE 17 DAY OF July
1891 FOR THE MURDER OF ONE JULIUS SCHERBRING, AND UPON SAID IN-
DICTMENT, HE WAS DULY ARRAIGNED, PLEADED NOT GUILTY WAS TRIED BY 
A JURY WHO FOUND HIM GUILTY OF MURDER IN THE FIRST DEGREE ON THE
26th DAY OF September 1891</p>

<p>THAT COMPLAINT MOVED SAID COURT FOR A NEW TRIAL WHICH WAS
DENIED, AND THERE UPON SAID COURT SENTENCED THIS COMPLAINANT TO BE 
HUNG.</p>

<pb/>

<p>THAT THEREUPON THIS COMPLAINANT APPEALED TO THE SUPREME COURT
OF SAID STATE FROM SAID JUDGMENT AND FROM THE ORDER OF SAID COURT
DENYING HIM A NEW TRIAL.</p>

<p>THAT UPON SAID APPEAL SUCH PROCEEDINGS WERE HAD IN SAID 
SUPREME COURT, THAT SAID COURT REVERSED, ANNULLED AND SET ASIDE THE
SAID JUDGMENT AND REMANDED SAID CAUSE TO THE SUPERIOR COURT WITH
INSTRUCTIONS TO THE SAID COURT TO SENTENCE THIS COMPLAINANT WITHOUT
ANY OTHER TRIAL OR VERDICT OF A JURY, AS FOR MURDER IN THE SECOND
DEGREE.</p>

<p>THAT ON THE 16TH DAY OF JUNE 1891 THIS COMPLAINANT WAS BROUGHT
BEFORE SAID SUPERIOR COURT. ADJUDGED TO BE GUILTY OF MURDER
IN THE SECOND DEGREE BY SAID COURT,BY DIRECTION OF SAID SUPREME 
COURT, AND SENTENCED TO IMPRISONMENT IN THE STATE PENETENTIARY OF 
THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, FOR THE TERM OF TWENTY YEARS.</p>

<p>THAT COMPLAINANT IS ADVISED BY HIS COUNSEL, AND VERILY BEL-
IEVES THAT HE HAS BEEN SINCE THE 16TH DAY OF JUNE,1892, AND IS 
NOW DEPRIVED OF HIS LIBERTY WITHOUT DUE PROCESS OF LAW, IN VIOLAT
ION OF THE XIV. AMENDMENT TO THE CONSTITUTION OF THE UNITED STATES.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, YOUR COMPLAINANT PRAYS THAT A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS
MAY ISSUE FROM THIS HONORABLE COURT COMMANDING THE SAID</p>

<p>WARDEN OF THE STATE PENETENTIARY OF WASHINGTON TO
HAVE THE BODY OF YOUR COMPLAINANT BEFORE THIS HONORABLE COURT, AT
SUCH TIME AS TO THE COURT SHALL SEEM MEET. THAT THIS HONORABLE
COURT ADJUDGE THE IMPRISONMENT OF YOUR COMPLAINANT TO BE ILLEGAL
AND DIRECT HIM TO BE DISCHARGED AND YOUR COMPLAINANT AS IN DUTY
BOUND WILL EVER PRAY ETC.</p>

<p>Albert Friedrich</p>
<p>COMPLAINANT.</p>

<pb/>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON,
COUNTY OF WALLA WALLA;</p>

<p>ALBERT FREDERICH BEING DULY SWORN DEPOSES AND SAYS: THAT
HE HAS READ THE FOREGOING COMPLAINT AND KNOWS THE CONTENTS THEREOF
AND THE SAME IS TRUE OF HIS OWN KNOWLEDGE.</p>

<p>Albert Friedrich</p>

<p>SUBSCRIBED AND SWORN TO BEFORE ME THIS 15 DAY OF JULY,
1892.</p>

<p>J<unclear></unclear></p>

<p>NOTARY PUBLIC IN AND FOR THE 
STATE OF WASHINGTON, RESIDING
AT WALLA WALLA.</p>

<pb/>

<p>(Exhibit A.)</p>

<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, FOR THE COUNTY OF KING.</p>

<p>THE STATE OF WASHINGTON,</p>
<p>PLAINTIFF,
VS.
ALBERT FREDERICH,
DEFENDANT.</p>

<p>NO. 370.</p>

<p>CONVICTED OF MURDER IN THE FIRST
DEGREE, ALTERED BY SUPREME COURT
UPON APPEAL, TO MURDER IN THE SEC-
OND DEGREE.</p>

<p>THE PROSECUTING ATTORNEY WITH THE DEFENDANT AND COUNSEL CAME
INTO COURT. THE DEFENDANT ALBERT FREDERICH WAS DULY INFORMED
BY THE COURT OF THE NATURE OF THE INDICTMENT FOUND AGAINST HIM
FOR THE CRIME OF MURDER IN THE FIRST DEGREE, COMMITTED ON THE 
14TH DAY OF JULY,1887,OF HIS ARRAIGNMENT AND PLEA OF NOT GUILTY
OF THE OFFENSE CHARGED IN THE INDICTMENT'' OF HIS TRIAL, AND THE
VERDICT OF THE JURY ON THE 26TH DAY OF SEPTEMBER, 1891, '' GUILTY
AS CHARGED IN THE INDICTMENT''.</p>

<p>THAT AFTER SAID VERDICT HAD BEEN RECEIVED AND JUDGMENT OF
DEATH PASSED THEREON IN ACCORDANCE WITH LAW, AN APPEAL WAS PRES-
ENTED TO THE SUPREME COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, WHICH COURT
AFTER DUE REFLECTION, CONSIDERATION AND EXAMINATION OF THE SAID
CASEK DIRECTED THAT THE JUDGMENT OF DEATH RENDERED IN THIS COURT
BE SET ASIDE AND VACATED, BUT THAT THE VERDICT OF THE JURY STAND</p>

<pb/>

<p>AND THIS COURT ENTER AND RENDER A NEW JUDGMENT OF GUILTY OF MUR-
DER IN THE SECOND DEGREE.</p>

<p>THEREFORE THIS COURT PROCEEDING UNDER THE ORDER OF THE SAID
SUPREME COURT AS IN SAID OPINION DIRECTED THIS DAY INFORMS THE
SAID ALBERT FREDERICHS OF THE OPINION AND CONCLUSION OF SAID SUP-
REME COURT IN SAID CASE AND ALLOWING THE SAID VERDICT SO TO STAND
THIS THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON FOR KING COUNTY
THIS DAY ORDERS AND ADJUDGES AND DECREES THAT THE SAID ALBERT
FREDERICH IS GUILTY OF THE CRIME OF MURDER IN THE SECOND DEGREE.</p>

<p>THE DEFENDANT ALBERT FREDERICH WAS THEN ASKED IF HE HAD ANY
LEGAL CAUSE TO SHOW WHY JUDGMENT SHOULD NOT BE PRONOUNCED AGAINST
HIM, TO WHICH HE REPLIES THAT <add>he</add> HAS none. AND NO SUFFICIENT CAUSE
BEING SHOWN OR APPEARING TO THE COURT, THEREUPON THE COURT RENDER-
ED ITS SAID JUDGMENT: AS FOLLOWS: THAT WHEREAS THE SAID ALBERT
FREDERICH HAVING BEEN DULY CONVICTED IN THIS COURT OF THE CRIME
OF MURDER IN THE FIRST DEGREE.</p>

<p>AND JUDGMENT OF DEATH RENDERED THEREON: THAT THEREAFTER
THE SAID ALBERT FREDERICH PROSECUTED AN APPEAL TO THE SUPREME
COURT OF THE SAID STATE OF WASHINGTON WHICH SAID SUPREME COURT
AFTER DUE DELIBERATION, EXAMINATION AND REFLECTION ON THE RECORD
OF SAID CASE DIRECTS THIS COURT THAT THE JUDGMENT OF DEATH REN-
DERED BY THIS COURT BE SET ASIDE AND VACATED; THAT THE VERDICT
OF THE JURY STAND; THAT THE COURT THIS DAY RENDER A NEW JUDGMENT
OF GUILTY OF MURDER IN THE SECOND DEGREE.</p>

<p>IT IS THEREFORE CONSIDERED, ORDERED AND ADJUDGED/<del></del> BY THE
COURT THAT THE SAID ALBERT FREDERICH IS GUILTY OF THE CRIME OF</p>

<p>MURDER IN THE SECOND DEGREE, AND THAT HE BE PUNISHED BY CONFINEMENT
AT HARD LABOR IN THE PENETENTIARY OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON FOR
THE TERM OF TWENTY | 20 | YEARS AND THAT HE PAY THE COSTS OF THIS 
PROSECTUTION.</p>

<p>THE DEFENDANT ALBERT FREDERICH WAS THEN REMANDED TO THE CUS-
TODY OF THE SHERIFF OF SAID COUNTY TO BE BY HIM DELIVERED INTO THE 
CUSTODY OF THE PROPER OFFICERS OF THE SAID PENETENTIARY.</p>

<p>OFFICE OF THE COUNTY CLERK OF KING COUNTY,</p>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>

<p>I, W. B. SPENCER, 
COUNTY CLERK AND EX-OFFICIO CLERK OF THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE
STATE OF WASHINGTON FOR THE COUNTY OF KING, DO HEREBY CERTIFY THE 
FOREGOING TO BE A TRUE AND CORRECT COPY OF THE JUDGMENT DULY MADE
ENTERED ON THE MINUTES OF THE SAID SUPERIOR COURT IN THE ABOVE
ENTITLED ACTION, AND THAT I HAVE COMPARED THE SAME WITH THE ORIG-
INAL; THAT THE SAME IS A CORRECT TRANSCRIPT THEREFROM AND OF 
THE WHOLE THEREOF.</p>

<p>Seal</p>

<p>ATTEST MY HAND AND THE SEAL OF THE
SAID SUPERIOR COURT THIS 17TH DAY OF 
JUNE, 1892,.</p>

<p>W. B. SPENCER |CLERK|</p>

<pb/>

<p>(Exhibit B.)</p>

<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON FOR THE COUNTY
OF KING.</p>

<p>THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, TO THE SHER-
IFF OF KING COUNTY AND THE WARDEN AND 
OFFICERS IN CHARGE AT THE PENETENTIARY
OF THE STATE OF WA SHINGTON, GREETING:</p>

<p>WHEREAS, ALBERT FREDERICH HAVING BEEN DULY CONVICTED IN THE
SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON FOR THE COUNTY OF KING
OF THE CRIME OF MURDER AND JUDGMENT HAVING BEEN PRONOUNCED AGAINST
HIM THAT HE BE PUNISHED BY <add>CONFINEMENT AT</add> HARD LABOR IN THE PENETENIARY/OF THE 
STATE OF WASHINGTON FOR THE TERM OF TWENTY |20| YEARS AND PAY THE 
COSTS OF THIS PROSECUTION ALL OF WHICH APPEARS TO US OF RECORD,
AND A CERTIFIED COPY OF THE JUDGMENT BEING ENDORSED HEREON AND
MADE A PART HEREOF.</p>

<p>NOW THIS IS TO COMMAND YOU, THE SAID SHERIFF OF KING COUNTY,
TO TAKE AND KEEP AND SAFELY DELIVER THE SAID ALBERT FREDERICH INTO
THE CUSTODY OF THE SAID WARDEN, OR OTHER OFFICER IN CHARGE OF THE
PENETENTIARY OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON AT YOUR EARLIEST CONVEN-
IENCE.</p>

<p>AND THIS IS TO COMMAND YOU, THE SAID WARDEN AND OTHER OFFICERS
IN CHARGE OF THE PENETENTIARY OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, TO RECEIVE
OF AND FROM THE SHERIFF OF KING COUNTY THE SAID ALBERT FREDERICH
CONVICTED AND SENTENCED AS AFORESAID, AND HE THE SAID ALBERT FRED-</p>

<pb/>

<p>ERICH KEEP AND CONFINE IN THE SAID PENITENTIARY FOR THE TERM OF
TWENTY |20| YEARS AND THESE PRESENTS SHALL BE AUTHORITY FOR THE
SAME. HEREIN FAIL NOT.</p>

<p>WITNESS. HON, T. J. HUMES.</p>
<p>JUDGE OF SAID SUPERIOR COURT, THIS 17TH
DAY OF JUNE, A.D. 1892.</p>

<p>ATTEST MY HAND AND SEAL OF SAID DUPERIOR
COURT THE DAY AND YEAR LAST
ABOVE WRITTEN.</p>

<p>W. B. SPENCER, |CLERK|</p>

<pb/>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>No. 186</p>

<p>IN THE <del>SUPERIOR</del> US Circuit COURT OF THE <del>STATE</del> District
OF WASHINGTON IN AND FOR
THE <del>COUNTY OF</del></p>

<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of <del>Plaintiff</del>
Albert Frederich for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus <del>Defendant</del></p>

<p>Petition</p>

<p>Received copy of the wihin <gap></gap>
this <gap></gap> day of <gap></gap> 189</p>

<p>Attorney for <gap></gap></p>

<p>FILED Aug 9 1892
IN THE 
U.S. CIRCUIT COURT.</p>

<p>A. Reeves Ayres.</p>
<p>CLERK></p>

<p>BY R.M. <unclear>Hopkins</unclear></p>
<p>Deputy</p>

<p>Tyler, <del>Hays</del> &amp; Tyler,</p>
<p>ATTORNEYS</p>

<p>For Petitioner.</p>

<p>228 and 229 Occidental Block, Seattle.</p>
<p>Hill-Landes Building, Port Townsend.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>