<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application 
of Seventy-six Hindus for a Writ
of Habeas Corpus.
) ) ) ) ) ) 
No. 2532 
ORDER DISCHARGING 
ORDER TO SHOW CAUSE.</p>
<p>The above entitled matter coming on regularly for
hearing on the petition, order to show cause why writ of
habeas corpus should not issue, return of the Honorable
Ellis DeBruler, Commissioner of Immigration, thereto, and
the petition for rehearing, and it appearing to the court
by such return and by the record of the proceedings of the
Bureau of Immigration filed therewith, that the following
Hindus named in said petition and order, to-wit: Faizand
Alli, Pala Singh and Nyzam Din, were released by said re-
spondent and said Bureau prior to the commencement of these
proceedings, and that another of said Hindus named in said
petition and order, to-wit: Buran Singh, died prior to the
cormencement of these proceedings:</p>
<p>IT IS HEREBY ORDERED, that as to said four Hindus above
named, these proceedings be and the same are hereby dismissed:
and the court being fully advised in the premises:</p>
<p>IT IS FURTHER ORDERED, that the petition for the writ of
habeas corpus, and the petition for rehearing, be and the
same is hereby denied, and that the order to show cause,
be and the same is hereby discharged, said denial of the
petitions and discharge of the order to show cause being
applicable to each of the petitioners, including the other
seventy-two Hindus named in said petition and order, to-wit:</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>Moola Singh, Talok Singh, Dalip Singh, Bhagwan Singh,
ala Singh, Rulia Singh, Kishan Singh, Harijan Singh,
Arjan Singh, Hire Singh, Bhag Singh, Duvan Singh, Naurang
Singh, Dalip Singh, Vir Singh, Ratan Singh, Nama Singh,
Bishan Singh, Bishen Singh, Rem Singh, Baboo Singh,
Bhagat Singh, Thakar Singh, Variam Singh, Harnam Singh,
Gurdit Singh, Kishan Singh, Gurbakhoh Singh, Khazan Singh.
Paren Singh, Milkha Singh, Narman Singh, Varian Singh,
Sham Singh, Kakoo Singh, Basant Singh, Pooran Singh,
Sher Singh, Santa Singh, Harnam Singh, Munshi Singh,
Prem Singh, Partap Singh, Naurang Singh, Ahas Ali,
Bahader Shah, Mir Ahdylla, Sultan Ali, Bagh Ali, Niaz
Mohd, Rahmat Alla, Nayat Khan, Amir Rhan, Amir Khan
Mohd Alam, Isay Khan, Amaret Khan, Shali Khar Khan,
Nandar Khan, Gulam Nodh, Sanday Khan, Baggn Khan, Umar Den,
Ali But, Hanz Mohd, Chiragh Din, Madda Din, Ibrahim Din,
Ismail Din, Rahmat Ali, Noor Khan, and Ishar Singh.</p>
<p>And it further appearing to the court that the filing
of this order has been delayed by the respondent on the
suggestion of the court and in order to give the petitioners
opportunity to file with the Bureau of Immigration a bond
satisfactory to said Bureau for the release of said
petitioners pending an appeal contemplated by them, and
their production to answer the order of the court on appeal
and that no such bond has been filed, now therefore,</p>
<p>IT IS FURTHER ORDERED that the order heretofore entered
for the holding of said petitioners by respondent to answer
the order of court in this proceeding, be and the same is
hereby entirely cancelled and dissolved, and said petitioners
are left in the custody of respondent and the Bureau of
Immigration for deportation or to be otherwise dealt with
in accordance with law,</p>
<p>PROVIDED, HOWEVER, that no one of the said petitioners
shall be deported pending said appeal for whom there shall
have been filed and kept good with said Bureau a satisfactory
bond as aforesaid, and for whose maintenance from this date
provision has been made as herein set forth, - that is to
Say: for each petitioner, whose bond has not yet been filed
<pb></pb>
and approved as aforesaid, there shall be forthwith deposit-
ed with the respondent, or in the registry of this court
the sum of six dollars ($6.00) for ten days maintenance of
said petitioner, and thereafter, and until said bond shall
be furnished and approved as aforesaid, a like sum of six
dollars ($6.00) for each ten days, payable in advance. In
case said deposits are made into the registry of this oourt
there shall be included therewith two percent (2%) extra
allowed the clerk of this court by law as compensation for
all money deposited in the registry thereof.</p>
<p>An exception is allowed petitioners and each of them
to the denial of the writ of habeas corpus herein contained,
and to the overruling of petitioner for rehearing, and to
the discharge of the order to show cause, and to the
rulings herein contained as to the custody of said petition-
ers pending said appeal.</p>
<p>Done in open court this 27 day of September, 1913.</p>
<p>Jeremiah Neterer 
JUDGE.</p>
<p>OK. Herbert Meyers</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>2x No. 2532</p>
<p>6013-4-270</p>
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT
OF THE UNITED STATES 
FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>In the Matter of the 
Application of 
SEVENTY-SIX HINDUS
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>ORDER DISCHARGING
ORDER TO SHOW CAUSE.</p>
<p>FILED IN THE
U.S. District Court, 
Western Dist. of Washington.
SEP 29 1913
FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk,
By Emy Deputy</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>