<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0195.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Frank Sulak v. Henry M. White. Complaint </title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0195.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Frank Sulak v. Henry M. White. Complaint</title>
<date when="1918-11-29">November 29, 1918</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1918-11">November 1918</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>W.P. Callahan</term>
<term>Jeremiah Neterer</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Austria</term>
<term>Everett, Snohomish County, Washington</term>
<term>New York</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sulak, Frank</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Moore, Ben L.</persName>
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2019-10" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="#hc.case.wa.0195.001"/>

<p>4405</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Dec 2 1918</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of FRANK SULAK, for a writ of habeas corpus.</p>
<p>4405</p>
<p> The complainant Frank Sulak, appearing by George F. Vandeveer and Ralph S.Pierce, his attorneys, complains to the court and alleges and petitions as follows:</p>
<p>1.</p>
<p> That at all times hereinafter mentioned, complainant was and is still a subject of Austria, lawfully domiciled in the United States of America;  that he is not restrained of his liberty on any charge or conviction of crime, nor on any process issued on any final judgement of court of competent jurisdiction, nor on any warrant, committment or other process issued on any indictment or information;  nor on any order or warrant of committment, otherwise than as hereinafter specified.</p>
<p>2.</p>
<p> That on the 4th day of January, 1918, complainant was arrested by an Immigration Inspector of the United States, at Everett, Washington, and given a hearing for the purpose of inquiring into the merits of said charge.</p>
<p> That he was questioned by said W P.Callahn and in reply to questions, answered that he was 25 years of age, single, and that he had entered the United States at New York in 1912;  was at that time examined by Immigration Officials;  that he joined the I.W.W. in 1916, believed in its principles, sold its papers and attended its meetings;  that he does not read English and never read any of the I.W.W. literature that was written in the polish language.  Asked if he believed in the following quotation, "There is but one bargain that the I.W.W. will make with the employing class, complete surrender of all control of industry to the organized workers," the complainant answered that he did.  That the complainant further answered that he was a laborer in saw-mills and camps;  that he had never begged, and that he worked all of the time;  that he had never destroyed any property, had no intention of destroying property, and would rather go to jail than do so. That said questions and answers were reported by a stenographer employed by the United States Department of Labor, and subsequently transcribed, and introduced in evidence against complainant in substantiation of the charges contained in the warrant of arrest hereinabove referred to, together with many other questions and answers having no bearing upon and in no manner material to said charges; and that said transcript constitutes the only evidence ever introduced against complainant in substantiation of said charges. That at no time was complainant questioned as to whether he had ever advocated or taught the unlawful destruction of property, or anyting else, or evern whether he believed in such unlawful destruction, except as above indicated, nor was he questioned about his ability to work and support himself, or about the likelihood of his becoming a public charge at the time of his entry into the United States, or at any other time, except as above indicated;  nor was any evidence of any character offered or received upon any of said questions except as above indicated.</p>
<p>3.</p>
<p> That complainant is now, and ever since the 4th day of January, 1918, has been continuously restrained of his liberty in the United States Immigration Detention Station at Everett, Snohomish County, Washington, by Henry M.White, United States Commissioner of Labor stationed at Seattle, under the pretended authority of the warrant of arrest issued by the secretary of labor, as hereinabove alleged, and not otherwise, and that said restraint is illegal for the following reasons,to-wit:</p>
<p> First:  That although ten months have elapsed since the warrant upon which complainant is held in custody, was originally issued, and complainant arrested thereunder, and more than eight months have elapsed since the hearing conducted in pursuance of the mandate in said warrant was fully concluded, and although complainant has at no time requested, consented to, nor in any manner been responsible for any delay in conducting or concluding said hearing or in deciding the issues presented thereon;  and although several months have elapsed since the record of the proceedings on said hearing was finally transmitted to the secretary of labor of the United States, for his decision and order, still said secretary has rendered no decision and made no order in said matter and by reason thereof and of the manner in which said hearing was conducted and complainant has been restrained of his liberty without due process of law and deprived of his rights under the provisions of the Fifth Article of the Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</p>
<p> Second:  That on the hearing conducted to inquire into the charges upon which complainant is restrained of his liberty above referred to, no evidence whatever was introduced to sustain the charge that complainant had ever advocated or taught or been found advocating or teaching the unlawful destruction of property, or that he was at the time of his entry into the United States, or at any other time, likely to become a public charge, upon which the secretary of labor of the United States could make an order directing that complainant be deported from the United States, or any other order in any manner restraining complainant of his liberty, and that any warrant or order which said secretary of labor might make other than an order discharging complainant from custody would be arbitrary and wholly void.</p>
<p>4.</p>
<p> That complainant is informed and believes that there are only two copies of the testimony introduced on the hearing of the charges upon which he is restrained of his liberty, and that one of said copies is in the possession of the secretary of labor of the United States of Washington,D.C., and the other in the possession of Henry M.White, Commissioner of Labor of the United States at Seattle,Washington. That complainant demanded a copy of said evidence in order that he might attach the same to this petition, but his demand therefor was refused by said Henry M.White.  That complainant is a common laborer and as a result of his long confinement and the deprivation of his usual means of support, he is unable, by reason of his poverty, to pay for the preparation of such a copy, but deponent is informed by his attorney, and believes that if the said Henry M.White is required to produce the transcript of said evidence, now in his possession, and make the same a part of his return herein, or exhibit the same to the court, the verity of complainant's allegations in relation thereto will clearly appear therefrom.</p>
<p> WHEREFORE, complainant prays an order directing the clerk to issue out of and under the seal of this court, a writ directed to Henry M.White, Commissioner of Labor of the United States, stationed at Seattle, Washington, requiring him to produce the body of complainant in the above entitled court, before the Hon.Jeremiah Neterer, a judge thereof, on the <gap></gap> day of 1918, at <gap></gap> o'clock in the <gap></gap>noon, and that he then said there show cause, if any he has, why the complainant should be further restrained of his liberty, and further directing that said Henry M.White also then and there produce, properly authenticated under his seal, a copy of the testimony taken at the hearing held pursuant to the mandate of the warrant of arrest issued by the secretary of labor, pursuant to which complainant Frank Sulak is restrained of his liberty by said Henry M.White.</p>
<p>George F Vanderveer</p>
<p>and</p>
<p>Ralph S Pierce</p>
<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON COUNTY OF SNOHOMISH</p>
<p>SS</p>
<p> FRANK SULAK being first duly sworn, says: That he is the complainant in the above entitled cause; and that he has read the foregoing complaint and knows the contents thereof, and that the same is true to his knowledge.</p>
<p>Frank Sulak</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 29th day of November 1918.</p>
<p>T.W. <unclear></unclear></p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>