<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0177.003.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">February 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Bajlo, Tonka</term>
<term>Bajlo, Jack</term>
<term>Bilin, Paska</term>
<term>Bolancia, Jerry</term>
<term>Cushman, Edward E.</term>
<term>DeBruler, Ellis</term>
<term>Ennis, Chas. H.</term>
<term>Fisher, Thomas M.</term>
<term>Jurin, Joe</term>
<term>Madison, Fany</term>
<term>Millowan, Frank</term>
<term>Radovich, Nick</term>
<term>Rasho, L. G.</term>
<term>Skorish, Ivan</term>
<term>Wilson, W. B.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Tonka Bajlo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Chas. H. Ennis</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON 
NORTHERN DIVISION</p>
    
<p>In the Matter of the Application 
of Tonka Bajlo for the Writ of 
Habeas Corpus )</p>
<p>2459
no. 1328
BRIEF SUBMITTED IN SUBSTITUTION
OF ARGUMENT IN ANSWER TO WRIT</p>

<p>BRIEF SUBMITTED BY RELATOR IN REPLY TO ANSWER OF
COMMISSIONER OF IMMIGRATION, ELLIS DeBRULER, and 
the SECRETARY OF THE DEPARTMENT OF LABOR in re
DEPORTATION OF TONKA BAJLO.</p>

<p>Pursuant to agreement entered into between Mr. Brockway,
Assitant United States District Attorney, and Chas. H.Ennis, 
attorney for Tonka Bajlo, and with the consent of Edward E.Cushman,
Judge of the United States District Court for Western District
of Washington, the following brief is submitted in substitution 
of oral argument:</p>
<p>STATEMENT OF CASE</p>
<p>Tonka Bajlo is a native and subject of Austria about 
30 years of age, the wife of Jack Bajlo, who landed in this
country at the port of New York on the S.S. "OCEANIC" on March
9, 1911, accompanied by her husband. She immediately after their 
arrival in company with her husband went to Pittsburg, Pennsylvania,
where they resided for a period of one year living together as man
and wife, and after she resided a year in Pittsburg living with 
her husband, then she came to the city of Seattle where she has
lived during the past year.</p>
<p>The reason for her leaving her husband was because of 
his continuous, inhuman and bestial cruelties. Upon her arrival 
in Seattle she obtained employment as housekeeper and cook
at 917 Addition Street for a man by the name of Paska Bilin,
at which place were some five or six Austrians who were employed
as laborers by the various contractors in the city of Seattle.
She remained in the employ of Bilin for some 9 or 10 months,
after which she obtained employment with Ivan Skorish and Paska
Bilin, at 815 Charles Street, as cook and housekeeper, at which
place she remained for about two months cooking for four Austrian
<pb/>
<fw></fw>
laborers, when she was arrested on April 7, 1913, by Thomas M.
Fisher, Inspector of Immigration, at the port of Seattle, upon
a telegraphic warrant issued by Hon. W.B.Wilson, Secretary of 
Labor, upon the charge of being found an alien practising prostitution
after entry in this country, and on said day a hearing
was had by Thomas M.Fisher, Inspector of Immigration at the 
Detention Station of the port of Seattle.</p>
<p>At such hearing Tonka Bajlo was the first witness to be
called, without the presence of an attorney. At the conclusion 
of her testimony on direct examination Inspector Fisher informed
her in the following language of her right to have an attorney:</p>
<p>Q. "You have a right to be represented by counsel if you
desire." A. "I have no money to hire an attorney."</p>
<p>Q. "Do you waive your right to be represented by counsel
at this or any future hearing of the case?" A. "Yes."</p>
<p>At this hearing teh testimony of Jack Bajlo, her 
husband, Ivan Skoric(or Skorich,) and Paska Bilin were taken,and the 
testimony of these witnesses is herewith submitted as part of 
the Government's case, and referred to by this relator as part
of this reply brief to the answer of the Commissioner of Immigration,
Ellis DeBruler, to the petition for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.
Upon the testimony, <add>statements and affidavits</add> herewith submitted. Inspector Thomas M.Fisher
made the finding that he had talked to her and that she told him
she had been living with John or Joe Jurin as his wife since
coming to Seattle, and that she had been intimate with a number 
of men in the house where she was living; that she was living in
a house of the Austrian quarter, she being the only woman there
and that there were from 4 to 5 to a dozen Austrians living there 
from time to time; that from the condition of her room he had no
question in his own mind but that she was practicing prostitution,
and that in view of these facts he finds that Tonka Bajlo is a 
citizen of Austria, and that she entered this country March 9, 
1911, at the port of New York, and that she had been found
practicing prostitution since her entry into the United States, 
and recommended that she be deported to the country from whence
<pb/>
<fw>-2-</fw>
she came.</p>
<p>On April 9, 1913, in a letter to the Commissioner 
General of Immigration, Ellis DeBruler, Commissioner of Immigration
at the port of Seattle, upon the findings made by inspector Thomas
M.Fisher, recommended the deportation of Tonka Bajlo in the following
language to-wit:</p>
<p>"From the evidence adduced it appears that this woman
was of the excluded classes at the time of entry, i.e. a 
person who admits having committed an offense involving
moral turpitude, and a person likely to become a public 
charge, and she has been found practicing prostitution.
I therefore recommend that she be found to be in the 
United States in violation of law, and ordered deported
to the country from whence she came at the expense of 
the importing vessel, etc."</p>
<p>On April 7, 1913, a warrant was issued by the Secretary 
of Labor ordering the arrest of Tonka Bajlo, from which the following
excerpts are quoted:</p>
<p>"Whereas, from evidence submitted to me it appears 
that the alien Tonka Bajlo who landed at the port of
New York ex SS. "OCEANIC" on or about the 15th day of 
March, 1911, has been found in the United States in 
violation of the Act of Congress approved February
20, 1907, amended by the Act approved March 25, 1910,
for the following among other reasons: That the said 
alien is a prostitute and has been found practicing
prostitution subsequent to her entry into the United 
States.</p>
<p>I, W.B.Wilson, Secretary of Labor, by virtue of
the power and authority vested in me by the laws of teh
United States, do hereby command you to take into custody
the said alien, and grant her a hearign to enable her to
show cause why she should not be deported in conformity
with the law. For so doing this shall
be your sufficient warrant. W.B.Wilson, Secretary of 
Labor."</p>
<p>On April 15, 1913, the Secretary of Labor ordered the 
deportation of Tonka Bajlo to Austria, the country from whence
she came, upon the finding made by Ellis DeBruler, Commissioner
of Immigration at the port of Seattle, and Inspector Thomas M.
Fisher, upon the testimony adduced at the hearing held by Thomas
M.Fisher on April 7, 1913.</p>
<p>On April 16, 1913, an order to show cause why a Writ
of Habeas Corpus should not be issued was signed by Hon. Edward
E.Cushman, Judge of the United States District Court for the 
Western District of Washington,in response to the petition of
relator, said order being returnable on April 21, 1914, and in
<pb/>
<fw>-3-</fw>
answer to said order, the commissioner of Immigration, Ellis 
DeBruler, through the United States District Attorney's Office
filed the records in case in this court, and denied the
jurisdiction of this <add>honorable</add> court to intervene, claiming that the action
of the immigration officers upon its approval by the Secretary 
of Labor is final and not reviewable in a court of law.</p>
<p>The grounds upon which the relator seeks the issuance
of the Writ of Habeas Corpus are:-</p>
<p>1. That she did not have a fair and legal hearing as prescribed
by law, and that no sufficient opportunity was allowed
to present counter-evidence to show cause whay she should not be
deported upon the warrant charging her with the offense of "being
an alien practicing prostitution in this country after entry," in 
this, that she did not understand the proceedings which were
conducted against her at the time of the hearing and that she
was without the assistance of counsel, and when informed what the 
result of the hearing was, she demanded a rehearing and services
of counsel, and the rehearing was denied.</p>
<p>2. That there was absolutely no evidence to support the 
charge made against her in the warrant of arrest issued by the 
Secretary of Labor.</p>
<p>3. That the statements alleged to have been made by her 
in the testimony as translated into English, are in some instances
absolutely false and have been misinterpreted by the interpreter.</p>
<p>4. That the interpreter, who was hired especially for this
hearing, refused and decline to translate the statements made by 
her in which she charged her husband as being irresponsible mentally 
and acting through malice.</p>
<p>5. That the affidavit made by Jack Bajlo, her husband,
which is part of the Government's answer to the relator's petition 
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, was made by said Baljo with the purpose
in view of wreaking vengeance upon his wife, because she
declined to live with him by reason of his extreme cruelty and 
inhuman treatment, and said Baljo has since the hearing admitted
such to be the fact, as evidenced by affidavits marked Exhibits
B and C.</p>
<pb/>
<fw>-4-</fw>
<p>In connection with statement 5 we especially draw the 
attention of the court to the affidavits of Nick Radovich, <add>and</add> L. G.
Rasho and marked Exhibits B. and C.</p>
<p>Previous to applying for an order to show cause why
a Writ of Habeas Corpus should not be issued discharging Tonka
Bajlo from the custody of the immigration officials, said Tonka
Bajlo applied to Ellis DeBruler, Commissioner of Immigration 
at the port of Seattle, for a rehearsing which was denied by Ellis
DeBruler as Commissioner on the ground that she had been ordered
deported by the Secretary of Labor upon the testimony submitted 
at the only hearing had and which is hereto referred to and
made a part of the Government's answer to the return of this 
application for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, and in this connection 
we submit the affidavits of Ivan Scorich, Fany Madison, Frank
Millowan and Jerry Bolancia, which affidavits were submitted to
the Hon. Commissioner of Immigration at the port of Seattle in 
support of the application for a rehearing in this cause before
the immigration officials. Said affidavits are marked Exhibits
D., E., F., and G.</p>
<p>We desire especially to call the attention of the court 
to the affidavit of Tonka Bajlo and marked Exhibit A, which recites
a tale of cruelties equal to any of those practiced in the Dark 
Ages, and her statements as to cruelties and as to her virtuous
conduct are borne out by the affidavits of Nick Radovich, L.G.
Rasho, Fany Madison, Jerry Bolancia and Frank Millwan.</p>
<pb/>
<fw>-4-</fw>






</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>