<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0467.001"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John Leonard v. State of Washington</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Ibrahim, Meyri" xml:id="mi">Meyri Ibrahim</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0467.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">John Leonard v. State of Washington. Writ of Habeus Corpus. </title>
<date when="1896-07-29">July 29, 1896</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives</repository>
<collection>Western District of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno>Case 625</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1896-07">July 1896</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Whitman County, Washington</term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>State of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Leonard, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Canfield, H. W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Handford, Cornelius H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Ninth Judicial Circuit Court</orgName>
<placeName>Whitman, Washington</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2021-09" who="mi">transcribed.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0467.001"/>

<p>In the Circuit Court of the United States. 
Ninth Judicial Circuit, District of Washington, <del> Eastern </del> <add> Northern </add> Division. </p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application of
John Leonard, for A Writ of Habeus Corpus. </p>
<p>To the Hon. C.H. Handford, Judge of the Circuit Court of the 
United States, Ninth judicial circuit, District of Washington <del> Eastern </del> <add> Northern </add> Division</p>
<p>The petition of John Leonard respectfully shows to your Honor;
First-That the said petitioner is now a prisoner imprisoned and 
confined in the County Jail at Colfax, Whitman County, State of Washington, in the custody of the Sheriff of Whitman County, State of 
Washington. </p>
<p>Sedond- That the cause or pretense of the restraint of the said
petitioner according to the best of his knowledge and belief is, that
on the 29th day of July, 1896, H.W Canfield as Prosecuting Attorney
in and for the County of Whitman, State of Washington, made and filed
with the Clerk of the Superior Court in and for Whitman County, an
information charging the above named petitioner with the crime of
Murder in the first degree, which said information is in writing in
words and figures as follows, to-wit;
State of Washington
County of Whitman. </p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON
FOR THE COUNTY OF WHITMAN. 
The State of Washington, Plaintiff, INFORMATION.
vs
John Leonard, Defendant.
Comes now H.W. Canfield, prosecuting and County Attorney, for 
the County of Whitman, State of Washington, and by this information
accuses John Leonard, of the crime of murder in the first degree, committed 
as follows, to-wit:
That the said John Leonard, in the County of Whitman, in the
State of Washington, on the 18th day of July, eighteen hundred and 

<pb/>

ninety -six, purposefully, and of his deliberate and premeditated malice
killed Jacob Malquist by then and there purposelyand of his deliberate 
and premediated malice, striking, beating and mortally wounding
the said Jacob Malquist upon the head of him the said Jacob Malquist,
with a piece of wood of the length of thirty inches, and of the width 
of three inches, and of the thickness of three inches, which said
piece of wood he the said John Leanord, in his hands then and there 
had and held, contrary to the form of the statute in such cases made
and provided, and against the peace and dignity of the state of Washington. 
Dated at Colfax this 29th day of July, A.D. 1896.
H.W. Canfield, Prosecuting and 
County Attorney, in and for said 
County and State </p>
<p>State of Washington,
County of Whitman,
H.W. Canfield, being first duly sworn on oath says, he is the 
duly elected, acting and qualified Prosecuting and County Attorney,
in and for said County and State, that he has read the foregoing information, 
knows the contents thereof and believes the same to be 
true.
H.W. Canfield
SUBSCRIBED AND SWORN TO BEFORE ME THIS "29TH DAY OF JULY, 1896.
C. A. R O S S
Clerk of said Whitman County, Washington. </p>
<p>WITNESSES: 
Ed Lewis, W.H. Steuart, C.O. Anderyson, Mrs. P. M. Silcott, Mrs. W.H. Steuart, Thos. Boling, Frank Perry, A.P. Brown, 
Roger Morrisy, James Barry, W.S. Elliott, Fred Bonney, Thos. Mosgrove
J.D. Whiteis, C.M. Boswell, R.J. Skaife, John K. Eacho, T.W.Osborne, D.H. Shaw, O Hansen. </p>
<p> Third- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in 
said cause in the Superior Court of Whitman County, State of Washington, 
that the jury which was impanelled and sworn to try the said petitioner upon the said charge in the said information, did on the
21st day of Aug. 1896, render and return into the said Superior Court 
their verdict in said cause, which is in writing in words and figures
as follows, to-wit;</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON
IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OFWHITMAN.
The State of Washington, Plaintiff,
vs.
John Leonard, Defendant.
We the jury in the case of the State of Washington, plaintiff, against John Leonard, defendant, find the defendant guilty of the crime
of murder in the First Degree as charged in the information.
Paul Bockmier, Foreman. </p>

<pb/>

<p> Fourth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in 
said cause, in the said Superior Court of Whitman County, that on 
the 24th day of Aug. 1896, the Hon. E.H. Sullivan as Judge of the
Superior Court in and for Whitman County, Washington, rendered and
made his judgment and sentence in said cause, which is in writing in
words and figures as follows, to-wit;
IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON
IN AND FOR WHITMAN COUNTY. AUGUST 24TH, 1896.
The State of Washington, Plaintiff,
vs. 
John Leonard, Defendant. </p>
<p> Now on this day comes the plaintiff by H.W. Canfield Prosecuting
Attorney and comes also the defendant into <del/> open Court in his
own proper person as well as by his attorneys John Pattison Esq., and
U.L. Ettinger, Esq., when this cause came on duly and regularly for
hearing upon defendants motion to set aside the verdict of the jury
heretofore rendered in this cause, and duly filed herein, and to grant
defendant a new trial herein said motion being duly argues to the 
Court by the said attorney's of the said parties respectively, and the
Court having heard all the argument s of the respective counsel there
on, and the Court being fully advised in the premises, overrules said
notion, to all of which the defendant excepts, and exceptions allowed. </p>
<p> And now on this day comes the defendant in his own proper person,
to receive the judgment and sentence of the Court, upon the verdict
of the jury heretofore entered and filed herein. And appeared
also his Counsel John Pattinson and U.L. Ettinger, Esq's. Comes also
H.W. Canfiled Prosecuting Attorney and attorney for the plaintiff
herein, and thereupon the said defendant was duly informed by the
said Court of the said verdict of the jury, heretofore rendered and
filed herein, and the defendant was thereupon asked by the Court if
he had anything to say or any legal cause to show why judgment and
sentence of the Court should not now be pronounced against him, and
he answered that he had not, excepting as he had heretofore said.
Whereupon all and singular the premises, being by the Court fully
understood, it is here now considered and adjudged by the Court, that
you the said defendant John Leonard, are guilty of the crime of 
Murder in the First degree as charged in the information herein against
you and as by said verdict found. </p>
<p> And it is further considered and adjudged by the Court, that you 
the said defendant John Leonard, be taken hence to the County Jail of
Whitman County, Washington, from whence you came and that you be
there by the Sheriff of Whitman County, Washington, safely kept and 
confined, and that on the day hereafter to be appointed, set and determined
you be by the sheriff of the said Whitman County, Washington 
taken from thence to the place of execution, and that you the said defendant
John Leonard be there hanged by the neck until you be dead.
E.H. Sullivan
Superior Judge. </p>
<p> Fifth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in
said cause, that the Supreme Court of the State of Washington, on the

<pb/>

18th day of May, 1897, made and rendered its decision in the said
cause, which decision is in writing in words and figures as follows
to-wit,
IN THE SUPREME COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON
May session A.D. 1897.
BE IT REMEMBERED, That at a regular sessin of the Supreme Court of
the State of Washington, begun and holden at Olympia, on the 2nd Monday
in May A.D. 1897, it being the tenth day of said Month, among
other the following was had and done, to -wit;
Tuesday May 18th, 1897
State of Washington, Respondent
vs.
John Leonard, Appellant. NO. 2491 J U D G E M E N T. </p>
<p>This cause having been heretofore submitted to the Court on the
Motin of the Respondant to dismiss the appeal from the judgment of
the Superior Court of Whitman County, and the Court having fully considered
the same and fully advised in the premises and having
filed its opinion in writing, it is now on the 18th day of May, A.D.
1897, on Motion of Thomas M. Vance Esquire, of Counsel for respondent
considered, adjudged and decreed that the appeal herein be, and the
same is hereby dismissed with costs, and the cause remained to the 
said Superior Court with directions to carry its judgment into effect, 
and that the said State of Washington have and recover of and from the
said John Leonard the costs of this action taxed and allowed at Nineteen
and 60/100 dollars, and that execution issue therefor. And it
 is further ordered that this cause be remitted to the said Superior
Court for further proceedigns according with the opinion herein filled. </p>
<p>I. C. S. Reinhart, Clerk of the Supreme Court of the State of 
Washington, do hereby certify that the foregoing is a true copy of 
the judgment and Decree in said cause, as the same now remains of 
record in my office. In testimony whereof, I have hereunto set my 
hand and affixed the seal of said Court at Olympia this 16th day of May, A.D. 1897.
C.S. Reinhart, Clerk of the Supreme 
Court, State of Washington</p>
<p> Sixth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in 
the said cause, that on the 24th day of May, 1897, William McDonald 
as Judge of the Superior Court of Whitman County, Washington, made an 
order fixing a day when the judgment and sentence of death rendered 
and entered into said cause, should be carried into execution, which
said order is in writing in words and figures as follows, to-wit;
IN THE SUPERIOR COURT IN THE STATE OF WASHINGTON
IN AND FOR WHITMAN COUNTY,
The State of Washington, Plaintiff, 
vs. ORDER
John Leonard, Defendant. </p>
<p> Now on this day the above entitled matter coming on to be heard 

<pb/>

in open Court, for the fixing of a day when the judgment and sentence
of Death heretoforerendered and entered herein, shall be carried
into execution, the said defendant appearing in his own proper person
and by John Pattidon and U. L. Ettinger his Attorneys, the plaintiff
appearing by John W. Mathews Prosecuting Attorney and County Attorney
for Whitman County, Washington, and H. W. Canfield of Counsel. </p>

<p> And the Court being fully advised in the premises, Friday, the
2nd day of July, A.D. 1897, is hereby set and appointed by the Court
as the day in which the judgment herein shall be executed.
Done in open Court this 24th day of May, 1897.
W I L L I A M MC DONALD.
Superior Judge. </p>

<p> Seven- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in
said cause in said Superior Court <del> , </del> that on the 24th day of May, 1897,
a Death Warrant was issued under the hand and seal of the said Judge
of the said Superior Court, which said Death Warrant is in writing in
words and figures as follows, to-wit, </p>
<p> IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON
IN AND FOR WHITMAN COUNTY.
The State of Washington, Plaintiff,
vs. DEATH WARRANT
John Leonard, Defendant.
THE STATE OF WASHINGTON.
To the Sheriff of Whitman Countt, Washington. </p>
<p> GREETING:
WHEREAS THE ABOVE NAMED DEFENDANT, JOHN LEONARD,
was by information of the prosecuting and County Attorney of Whitman
County, Washington, filled in <del/> this Court on this 29th day of July, A.D. 
1896, charged with the crime of murder in the first degree.</p>
<p> The above entitled cause came on regularly for trial in the above
entitled Court on the 17th day of August, A.D., 1896, and a jury
in said Court was duly and regularly empanneled and sworn to try the
issues of said cause; and said cause then proceeded to the taking of
testimony on behalf of the plaintiff and of the defendant and the
argument of Counsel to said jury and said jury was instructed by the
Court and retired to consider of their verdict in said cause; </p>
<p> And afterwards, and on, to-wit, the 21st day of August, 1896, 
the said defendant was convicted of the crime of murder in the first 
degree by the verdict of said jury, which said verdict was in the <unclear/>
<unclear/> of the said defendant and his Counsel returned into Court, and 
which said verdict was and is as follows, to-wit;
IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON
IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF WHITMAN.
The State of Washington, Plaintiff
vs. V E R D I C T
John Leonard, Defendant. </p>
<p> We, the jury in the case of the State of Washington, plaintiff,
against John Leonard, defendant, find thedefendant guilty of the
crime of Murder in the First Degree as charged in the information.
Paul Bockmier, Foreman. </p>

<p> And afterwards, on said verdict, the said defendant, John Leonard, 
was convicted of the crime of murder in the First Degree, and sentenced 
to suffer DEATH by the judgment and Sentence of the above entitled

<pb/>

Court, duly made and entered in this section on the 24th day 
of August, A.D. 1896, which said judgment and sentence is in words and 
figures as follows, to-wit;
IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON
IN AND FOR WHITMAN COUNTY.
The State of Washington, Plaintiff
vs. JUDGMENT AND SENTENCE>
John Leonard, Defendant. </p>
<p> And now on this day domes the above named defendant John Leonard,
in his own proper person, to recieve the judgment and sentence of the
Court, upon the verdict of the jury heretofore rendered, entered and
filed herein and appears also his Counsel, John Pattinson and U.L.
Ettinger, and comes also H. W. Canfield Prosecuting Attorney and Attorney
for the plaintiff herein, and thereupon the said defendant was
rendered, entered and filed herein, and the defendant was thereupon
asked by the Court if he had anything to say or legal cause to show
why judgment an sentence of the Court should not now be pronounced
against him, and he answered that he had not expecting as he had heretofore 
said. </p>
<p>WHEREUPON <del/>, all and singular the premises being by the Court
fully understood, it is here now considered and adjudged by the Court
that you, the said defendant John Leonard, are guilty of the crime of
Murder in the First Degree as charged in the Information herein against
you, and as by said verdict found. </p>
<p> And it is further considered and adjudged by the Court, that you
th e said defendant John Leonard, be taken from hence to the County
Jail of Whitman County, Washington, from whence you came, and that you
be there by the Sheriff of Whitman County, Washington, safely kept
and confined, and that on the day hereafter to be appointed, set and
determined, you be, by the said Sheriff of Whitman County, Wash ingotn,
taken from thence to the place of execution, and that you the
said defendant John Leonard, be there hanged by the neck until you
be dead."</p>
<p> And, afterwards, on the 25th day of September, 1896, she said
defendant John Leonard, filed in the above entitled Court and served
upon the Prosecuting Attorney for Whitman County, Washington, his notice
of appeal to the Supreme Court of the State of Washington, from
the judgment and sentence herein before mentioned. </p>
<p>And, afterwards, and on, to-wit, the 18th day of May A.D. 1897,
by the said judgment of the Supreme Court of the State of Washington
judgment and sentence heretofore entered herein, was at said time by said
Supreme Court <del/> dismissed and the above entitled
cause was reminded to the said Superior Court with directions
to carry its judgment heretofore recited into effect, and the remitti-
and executed under the seal of said Court, attached by the Clerk of
said Courts and filed in the office of the Clerk of the Superior
Court, of the State of Washington, in and for Whitman County.</p>
<p> NOW THEREFORE, Friday the 2nd day of July, A.D. 1897, is hereby
fixed set and appointed as the day in which the aforesaid Judgment an
sentence shall be carried into execution. </p>
<p> IN THE NAME OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, YOU, the said Sheriff
of Whitman County, Washington, are hereby commanded to take the said
defendant John Leonard, to the County Jail of Whitman County, State
of Washington, and him there safely keep and confine him from now until
Friday, the 2nd day of July, A.D. 1897, and that on said Friday the
second day of July, A.D. 1897, that you take the said defendant John
Leonard, from the said County Jail of Whitman County, Washington, to

<pb/> 

the place of execution and there hang him the said defendant, John
Leonard, by the neck until he be dead and due return of your doings
and proceedings hereon tomake, according to law; and herein fail not
at your peril.
Done in open Court this 24th day of May, A.D. 1897.
WILLIAM MCDONALD
Superior Judge. </p> 
<p> In Attestation and Testimony whereof
witness my hand and the seal of the
said Superior Court of the State of SEAL.
EWashington, in and for Whitman County
this 24th day of May, 1897.
C.A. Ross,
County Clerk and ex-officic Clerk
of the Superior Court of the State
of Washington, in and for Whitman
County. </p>
<p>Eight <del/> - That on account of the poverty of the said petitioner,
the attorneys for the said petitioner who depenfed him upon the said
charge contained in the said information in the Superior Court of
Whitman County, Washington, did not perfect an appeal from the said
Judgment and Sentence to the Supreme Court of the State of Washington
and on account of the failure to perfect said appeal, the <del/> said
Supreme Court of the State of Washington rendered the judgment of dismissal
aforesaid, and the said petitioner alleges, that the time for
taking said appeal has now wholly expired and the said petitioner has
no other remedy herein. </p>
<p> Ninth - That the said John Leonard is now restrained of his libert
by the Sheriff of Whitman County, State of Washington, at Colfax in
said Whitman County, and his said imprisonment and restraint is illegal
in this;
(a) That the said information upon which the said petitioner was
tried and convicted does not state facts constituting a crime or an
offense against the laws of the State of Washington or of the United 
States.
(b) That the said petitioner is imprisoned and held to answer for
a capital and infamous crime, without <add> having been </add> first indicted or presented
by a grand Jury as provided by Art. 5 of the Amendments to the Constitution
of the United States.
<del/> 
 
<pb/>
 
(c) That the said petitioner John Leonard is deprived of his liberty
and is about to be deprived of his life without hue process of
law and in violation of Art. 5 of the Amendments to the Constitution
of the United States, and in violation of Sec. 3 of Art. 1 of the
Constitution of the State of Washington.
(d) That the information upon which the said petitioner was trie
and convicted, did not inform the said petitioner of the
Amendments to the Constitution of the United States.
(e) That Sec. 21 of Art. 1 of the Constitution of the State of
Washington provides, that "Offenses heretofore required to be prosecuted
by information or by indictment, as shall be prescribed by law" 
is contrary to and in violation of Art. 5 and 14 of the Amendments
to the C onstitution of the United States, in that the said section
does not provide for a preliminary examination of the accused and does
not provide that prabable cause shell first be established before the
filing of an information against the accused, and in that it deprives
the accused of the right of a preliminary examination and of having 
probable cause of guilt first established before the filing of an
information.
(f) That the said petitioner is illegally restrained of his liberty
in that, the said Sec. 25 of Art. 1. of the Constitution of the
State of Washington and laws of the State of Washington, permitting
and allowing persons accused of crime to be prosecuted by information
are void and in conflict with Art's 5 and 14 of the Amendments
to the Constitution of the United States.
(g) That the said Superior Court of Whitman County, Washington,
who tried the said petitioner and rendered the said judgment and sentence
herein, had no jurisdiction to try the said petitioner or render
the said judgment and sentence upon the said information.
(h) That the said information and all of the proceedings had and
taken thereunder and thereon, were and are absolutely void and in
<del/> <add> violation of Art. <unclear/> of Art. 1 of the </add> Constitution of the State of
 
<pb/> 
 
Washington and in violation of Art.'s 5-6 and 14 of the Amendments
to the Constitution of the United States. </p>
<p> (1) That the said petiti oner is not held i custody under and by 
virtue of any process issu ed on any final judgement of a Court of competent
jurisdiction, or for any contempt of any Court, officer or
body having the authority in the premises to commit, or upon a warrant
issued, or upon warrant issued from any Superior Court upon any
indictment, or upon any valid or legal warrant issued from any Superior
Court upon any valid information, but the said petitioner alleges;
that the warrant or pretended warrant under which he is imprisoned
and detained is ilegal and void in that, the judgment and sentence
upon which the said warrant or pretended warrant was issued is
void. <del/> </p>
<p>WHEREFORE your said petitioner prays that a Writ of Habeus Corpus
may be granted to him, directed to the Sheriff of Whitman County, 
State of Washington,  commanding him to the said Sheriff to have and
produce the body of the said petitioner before this Honorable Court,
at a time and place in said Writ to be specified, to then and there
do and recieve what shall then and there be considered by your Honor
concerning the said petitioner, together with the time and cause of
the detention of the said petitioner, and that the said Sheriff have
then and there the said writ and his return thereto and thatyour
said petitioner may be restored to his liberty and discharged from
custody.
James E. Fenton
Del Leary Smith
Attorneys for petitioner. </p>
<p>  State of Washington
County of Spokane.
I, James E. Fenton, being duly sworn say, that I am one of the
attorney's for the above named petitioner, that I have read the foregoing  
petition, know the contents thereof and the same is true as I
verily believe; that I verify this petition for the reason that the
said petitioner is now confined in the County Jail at Colfax in Whitman
County, Washinton, and cannot be had to verify the same, and for
the addititional reason that all of the material facts alleged in the
above petititon are within my personal knowledge.
James E. Fenton
Subscribed and sworn to before me this ---- day of June, 1897.
<unclear/>
N O T A R Y   P U B L I C.
For Washington, residing at Spokane, Wash</p>

<fw type="footer"> &amp;</fw>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>