<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0088.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0088.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Type of document</title>
<date when="1887">1887</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1887">1887</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McKay, Alice</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, Della</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020-05" who="#lkw">encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#nl">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>KATIE McKAY, a witness called on behalf of the Petitioner, after being duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>Q. [Ronald] Where do you live? A. Tacoma.</p>

<p>Q. You are the daughter of Mrs. McKay A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know this little child here? A. Yes sir</p>

<p>Q. How long have you lived <sic>t</sic> at Tacoma? A. About eighteen years</p>

<p>Q. Living with your mother there? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. How long <sic>sinci</sic> your father and mother have been living together? A. I guess about four years.</p>

<p>Q. Has <sic>yur</sic> mother been keeping saloon since your father went away? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. What has your mother been doing for a livelihood since your father went away?</p>

<p>A. Washing and ironing, sewing <sic>andworking</sic>.</p>

<p>Q. Does she work all the time? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. You have been helping her any? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. How does your mother treat you and your little sister? A. Kindly.</p>

<p>Q. Do you get plenty to eat? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Who buys your clothing? A. Mama.</p>

<p>Q. Do you go to school? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>GILMAN: I dont know how that cuts any figure here?</p>

<p>The COURT: I will hear all sides of the case.</p>

<p>Q. How does she treat you and your sister? A. Kindly.</p>

<p>Q. Does your mother get drunk? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Have you ever seen her drunk? A. No sir I never saw her drunk.</p>

<p>Q. Does your mother have any man sleeping in the house at all? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Who sleeps with your mother every night? A. Me and my sister.</p>

<p>Q. Every <sic>yight</sic>? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Does your mother ever work out any? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. She comes home night dont she? A. About five o'clock in the evening.</p>

<p>Q. Who stays in the meantime in the house with your sister? A. Me.</p>

<p>CROSS-EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>Q. [Gilman] Have you ever seen your mother drink any? A. I seen her take a glass of beer once when she was hard at work</p>

<fw>[Katie McKay, D-EX.<gap/> 76--188.</fw>

<fw>12</fw>

<pb/>

<p>Q. Have you not seen her do that more than once? A. No.</p>

<p>Q. You have talked considerable with your mother about this case? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. She has never said a word to you about it? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You came up here without knowing why you came? A. Oh, yes I know why I was coming.</p>

<p>Q. You knew what would be expected,--that you would be expected to give evidence here? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Did not know anything about that? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Did not know that you would be called on the stand? A. Not until today.</p>

<p>Q. Did not your mother tell you what you were expected to testify to? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You are anxious to defend your mother <sic>heee</sic> are not you? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. You say there is no man living in the house there? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know Antoine? A. Yes, I know him.</p>

<p>Q. Where does he live? A. In tacoma.</p>

<p>Q. He is a friend of your family? A. We know him quite well.</p>

<p>Q. Is he not at your house quite frequently? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Has he ever been <sic>theee</sic> A. He was there once or twice.</p>

<p>Q. You have seen him only once or twice there? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Dont he and your mother go about considerably together? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Did he not come up here today with your mother? A. He did not come with my mother, he came on that steamer.</p>

<p>Q. You dont know <sic>wty</sic> he came? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q.</p>

<p>-------0-------</p>

<fw>[Katie McKay, C-EX.<gap/> 76--193.</fw>

<fw>13</fw>

</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>