<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0461.078">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>M. L. Coovert for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. Bond</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Russell, Ellie" xml:id="edr">Ellie Russell</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">M. L. Coovert for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. Bond</title>
<date when="1893-07-31">July 31, 1893</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1890-1901, vol 1</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1893-07">July 1893</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Coovert, M. L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Wiswall, E. A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="clerk">
<persName>Ayers, A. Reeves</persName>
</person>
<person role="deputy clerk">
<persName>Hopkins, Robert M.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Clarke County</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#edr">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<!-- <note>B&amp;S 1-114.</note> -->
<p>277
U.S. Circuit Court
District of Washington</p>
<p>Ex porte
M. L. Coovert</p>

<p>Bond</p>
<p>Jul 31 1893</p>

<p>Filed Jul 31 1893 1893<gap></gap>
In the 
U. S. Circuit Court.
A Reeves Ayres
Clerk
By R. M. Hopkins
Deputy</p>

<p>In the District Court of the United States for the Ninth Circuit,
District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>Ex parte
No.<add>(</add>3.<add>)</add> <add>277</add></p>
<p>M. L. Coovert. 
On Petition for Writ of 
Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>United States of America )
District of Washington ) SS
County of King )</p>

<p>Know all men by these presents, That
we, M. L. Coovert, of Vancouver, in the State of Washington, as
pricipal, and <unclear>MA Aribron</unclear>, of Seattle,
in the State of Washington, as surety, are held and firmly
bound unto the Clerk of the Circuit Court of the United States for
the District of Washington in the penal sum of Two Hundred and Fifty
($250.00) Dollars, lawful money of the United States,
for the payment of which, well and truly to be made, we, and each 
of us, bind ourselves, our heirs, executors and administrators,
jointly, severally and firmly by these presents.</p>
<p>Signed by our hands and sealed with out seals this 31 day
of July, 1893.</p>
<p>The Condition of the foregoing obligation is such that
Whereas, the said M.L. Coovert, principal above named, was, on
the 9th day of June, 1893, arrested by George Nerton, Sheriff of
the County of Clarke, in said state, at Vancouver, in said country
and state, by virtue of a warrant of commitment, issued by E. A.
Wiswall, Judge of the Superior Court of the State of Washington
for said County of Clarke, sitting and acting as committing magistrate
for an alleged violation by said Coovert of a certain law
of the said State of Washington declaring it to be unlawful for
any person or persons whatever to manufacture, buy, sell, give or
furnish to anyone any cigarettes, cigarette paper, or cigarette
wrapper; it being charged that the said Coovert has sold to one
C.M.McDonald a package of cigarettes, consisting of a box of packages
of paper-wrapped cigarettes, each enclosed in paper and tin foil wappers,
packed in a wooden packing case, and said case being packed
with others in a common pine shipping case, which said package
was shipped to said Coovert by the American Tobacco Company from
the State of Oregon to the State of Washington; all as more particularly
set forth in the petition of the said M.L. Coovert, heretofore
filed herein, for a writ of habeas corpus; and</p>
<p>Whereas, on the 22nd day of June, 1893, said cause was duly
heard in this court on a demurrer to the petition and on the return
to the writ of habeas corpus issued out of this court on the
13th day of June, 1893; and</p>
<p>Whereas, in said cause, on the 22nd day of June, 1893, an order
was duly made and entered discharging the said M.L. Coovert from
the detention and imprisonment complained of in said petition, as
aforesaid; and</p>
<p>Whereas, by said order of the 22nd day of June, 1893, it was
ordered and required that the said M.L.Coovert should enter into
a Bond in the sum of Two Hundred and Fifty ($250.00) Dollars, with
one or more suretites, for his apperance to answer the judgement of 
the appellate court herein,</p>
<p>Now, Therefore, if the said M. L. Coovert shall appear and
answer the judgement of the appellate court in the premises, and
abide by and obey such <del>o</del> judgment or order as the appellate court
may render or make, or cause to be rendered or made by the Circuit
Court of the United States above named, then this obligation to
be void; otherwise to remain in full force and virtue.</p>
<p>Signed, Sealed &amp; Delivered
in Presence of
M L Coovert (Seal)
LB <unclear>Seduia</unclear>
M.A. <unclear>Aribron</unclear></p>

<p>Taken and acknowledged before me this 31 day of July, 1893.</p>
<p>R. M. Hopkins
Deputy Clerk U. S. Circuit Court,
District of Washington.</p>
<p>United States of America )
District of Washington ) SS
Country of King )</p>
<p><unclear></unclear>
being first duly sworn, deposes and says: That he is the surety
named in the foregoing Bond: that he is not a sheriff, clerk of
court, attorney at law, or any other officer of any court in the
State of Washington; that he is a citizen, resident and freeholder
in said State of Washington, and is worth at least the sum of Two
Hundred and Fifty ($250.00) Dollars, over and above all his just
debts and liabilities, exclusive of property exempt from execution
<unclear>M. A. Arilbin</unclear></p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before
me this 31 day of July, 1893.
L. B. Andrews
Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, 
residing at Seattle, King County, in said state.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>