<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the United States District Court, For the Western District
of Washington. Northern Division</p>
<p>Petition of Ching Hing,
Through and by his attorney,
John J. Sullivan</p>
<ab>2857</ab>
<p>Comes now John J. Sullivan, as attorney for and in
behalf of Ching Hing, an alien, a subject of the Emperor of 
China, and a son of Chin Shew, merchant of New York City, and
respectfully makes this application for a Writ of Habeas Corpus
and alleges as follows:</p>
<p>I.
That said Ching Hing is imprisoned and restrained of
his liberty by the United States Commissioner of Immigration;
White and the United States Chinese Inspector, Henry Monroe, or
by person or persons acting through, by, or under them, and that
said Ching Hing is imprisioned at the Detention House at the
Immigration Station in the City of Seattle, under the charge that
the said Ching Hing has no lawful right to be admitted into the
United States and that he should be deported according to law,
and your Petitioner further informs the Honorable Court that said
imprisionment, confinement and restraint had Order of Deportation
is illegal and arises from the following facts, to-wit: That
Ching Hing arrived at the port of Seattle on a voyage from China
on the 5th day of August, 1914, and said Ching Hing was denied
admittance into the United States on the ground that he was not
legally entitled to be admitted therein; that said Ching Hing was
given a hearing by the Immigration officials and upon evidence
being presented on August 27th, 1914, an order was issued by the
Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, finding that said Ching
Hing was not entitled to admission to the United States and that
he should be deported; that an appeal was given by said Ching
<pb/>
Hing through his attorneys Stadden &amp; Stewart, of Washington, D.C.,
to the Secretary of Labor, and that on Spetember 26th, 1914,
the said Order of Deportation and said Finding of Commissioner of
Immigration of Seattle, Washington was affirmed and said Ching
Hing was ordered deported.</p>
<p>This Petitioner is informed and believes and so states the
facts to be that said Commissioner of Immigration White, in
charge of the district of Washington, and said Chinese Inspector
Henry Monroe, or officials or agents acting by, under of through
them or for the United States government, are about to deport
and return the said Ching Hing to China, in violation of the
treaty relations between the United States and China, and in violation
of the laws and statutes of the United States relating to
the Chinese Exclusion Act, and in violation of the laws relating
to the acts and powers of the Secretary of Labor and the Assitant
Secretary of Labor, in that said Ching Hing is being deprived of
his liberty without due process of law and without being given a 
fair hearing by said Commissioner of Immigration White and said
Chinese Inspector Henry Monore, or officials acting by, under or
through them for the United States government.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further alleges that the right of appeal
from said Findings of Commissioner of Immigration White and Chinese
Inspector Henry Monroe, or officials acting by, under or through
them or for the United States government in and for the district
of Washington, , by the statutes in such cases made and provided
for in relation to the Chinese Exclusion Laws, has been violated
and that his full rights have not been accorded to your Petitioner
Ching Hing, in this: That W. R. Wilson is the Secretary of Labor
and that Louis Post is his only assistant Secretary of Labor; that
both of said officials, as your Petitioner alleges upon information
and belief and knows to be the fact, were at their respective
offices in the capitol at Washington, doing the duties imposed upon
them on the day that the said appeal of Ching Hing was considered
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
and that upon said say and at said time that the appeal of the
said Ching Hing to the Secretary of Labor, from the decision
denying the right of entry to the United States of said Ching
Hing, come up for hearing and consideration, that said Secretary
of Labor and the Assistant Secretary of Labor were then and there
present in their respective offices and that the said Secretary of
Labor and Assistant Secretary of Labor were then and there
present in their respective offices and that the said Secretary of
Labor and Assistant Secretary of Labor under the statutes, should
have considered and determined the said appeal of said Ching Hing
from the said adverse decision of the said Commissioner of Immigration
and Chinese Inspector Henry Monroe, but that said Secretary
of Labor and Assistant Secretary of Labor failed, neglected
or refused so to do and hence the said Ching Hing has been denied
his right of appeal.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further alleges that one J.B. <del>Dennison</del> <add>Denamore</add>
is the Solicitor of the Department of Labor and further alleges
that said J.B. <del>Dennison</del> <add>Denamore</add> attempted to perform the duties of the
Secretary of Labour or Assistant Secretary of Labor while they
were present in their respective offices, adn the order of the
President of the United States, with due respect thereto, does not
authorize J.B. <del>Dennison</del> <add>Denamore</add>, or such Solicitor of the Department of
Labor to perform duties of the Secretary of Labor of the Assistant 
Secretary of Labor, save and except in their absence, adn therefore
the action of said J.B. <del>Dennison</del> <add>Denamore</add> in claiming to be the acting
Secretary of Labor furing the presence of said officials then and
there is a usurpation of the duties imposed upon the sadi Secretary
of the Department of Labor and the said Assistant Secretary
of Labor, by Congress, and the said J.B,. <del>Dennison</del> <add>Denamore</add> in assuming the
duties of the said Secretary of Labor and Assitant Secretary of
Labor and affirming the Finding of the Commissioner of Immigration
at Seattle, Washington, and the Chinese Inspector, Henry Monroe,
in relation to the case of Ching Hing, exceeded the statute, and
his action in sustaining the adverse decision in relation to the
right of entry of Ching Hing into the United States is null and
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
and the said Ching Hing has been denied the right of appeal as
provided by the statutes in such cases.</p>
<p>Dated this 29 day of September, 1914.</p>
<ab>John J Sullivan Atty for
Ching Hing</ab>
<p>State of Washington,
County of King } ss</p>
<p>John J Sullivan, attorney for the Petitioner
named in the foregoing petition, being first duly sworn, on oath
deposes and says: That he has read the said petition, knows the 
contents thereof, and that the same is true of his own knowledge
and that he believes said acts to be true.</p>
<ab>John J Sullivan</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 29th day of September, 1914.</p>
<ab>Adam Beeler
Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</ab>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>