<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0356.021">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Gin Kato v. Henry M. White. Record of Hearing</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0356.021</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Gin Kato v. Henry M. White. Record of Hearing</title>
<date when="1920-06-17">June 17, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-06">June 1920</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Strench, William G.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Ketchikan, Alaska</term>
<term>Kumamoto, Japan</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Kato, Gin</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Corrigan, John L.</persName>
<persName>Winston, Will H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>U.S. Department of Labor</p>
<p>Immigration Service</p>

<p>Ketchikan, Alaska, June 17, 1920.</p>

<p>William G. Strench</p>
<p>Inspector in Charge</p>
<p>Examiner and Reporter.</p>

<p>In the matter of the arrest of GIN KATO</p>
<p>Departmental warrant #54821/149 dated June 3, 1920.</p>

<p>Hearing held at Federal Jail, Ketchikan, Alaska.</p>

<p>The alien is informed that he has been taken into custody as directed in the above-described warrant, charging him with being in the United States in violation of law in that he has been found employed by, in, or in connection with a house of prostitution, and that the purpose of this hearing is to afford him an opportunity to show cause, if any there be, why he should not be deported to the country of which he is a subject. He was also given an opportunity to inspect the warrant, which was carefully explained to him.</p>

<p>Copy of Departmental warrant is attached to this record, marked "Exhibit A".</p>

<p>Alien duly sworn:</p>

<p>Q To alien: Do you understand English well enough to go ahead with this hearing without an interpreter? A Yes.</p>

<p>Q If not, we will get some one to act as interpreter? A No, I can understand much better than I talk.</p>

<p>Q You have the right to secure counsel to represent you at this hearing if you desire? A No, I want to go ahead without a lawyer.</p>

<p>Q Than you waive your right to counsel? A Yes.</p>

<p>Q What is your correct name? A GIN KATO.</p>

<p>Q How old are you? A Just 60.</p>

<p>Q Where were you born? A Kumamoto City, Japan.</p>

<p>Q When did you first come to the United States? A About the year 1884; I went ashore at San Francisco.</p>

<p>Q How many trips have you made back to Japan since then? A I have never been back to Japan. I worked on two U.S. revenue cutters; the last one was the "Bear".</p>

<p>Q How long did you work on the "Bear"? A About 18 years ago; I quit her in Alaska; I had a good discharge.</p>

<p>Q Are you married? A Yes, my wife is at home, Kumamato, Japan.</p>

<p>Q? Did she ever live in the United States? A Yes.</p>

<p>Q Have you any children? A No.</p>

<p>Q How long have you been in Ketchikan? A About 12 years; I had a noodle joint for 3 years, near the creek.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Q How long had you been working in this sporting house where I found you? A About four months.</p>

<p>Q How long have you been working in those houses, I mean the different houses of prostitution on the row? A About 7 months.</p>

<p>Q Are you aware that under the law of Alaska, any male person who acts as an employee or servant in a sporting house is guilty of a felony and that upon conviction he could be sentenced to a term of from two to five years in the penitentiary? A I didn't know that.</p>

<p>Q Have you any relatives in the United States? A No.</p>

<p>Q Do you own any property in this country? A No, I sold off everything.</p>

<p>Q Now have you anything to say as to why you should not be deported to Japan? A I would like to stay here; but I cannot help it if they send me back.</p>

<p>Q The bond in your case is $1,000; are you in a position to furnish that? A I have no money for bond.</p>

<p>Q Have you any friends who would put up bond for you? A I asked some friends but they said they cannot help.</p>

<p>On June 22nd the alien advised that he had engaged Mr. Will H. Winston as his attorney, who made request that additional testimony be taken. The request was granted.</p>

<p>June 22, 1920.</p>

<p>Q By Mr. Winston: How long have you lived in Ketchikan? A 11 years.</p>

<p>Q How long in the United States? A I came in 1884.</p>

<p>Q What have you been doing since you have been in Ketchikan? A I started a short-order restaurant and noodle joint near the creek.</p>

<p>Q How long were you in that business? A Four years.</p>

<p>Q Then where did you go? A I worked in Charley Ingersoll's logging camp; he had a contract for spruce. He asked me to cook for his logging camp, $115 a month; 6 months' job.</p>

<p>Q How long have you been working on the line? A 7 months altogether.</p>

<p>Q The first time how long? A 3 months.</p>

<p>Q Next time? A Four months.</p>

<p>Q Where did you eat? A At my cabin; I didnot eat over there.</p>

<p>Q Did you sleep over there? A No, at my cabin.</p>

<p>Q How many meals did you cook? A 2 meals; breakfast and dinner.</p>

<p>Q Did anybody ever tell you that it was against the law to work over there? A No; I did not know anything about that; If I knew it was against the law, I would not work; no sir.</p>

<p>Q Mr. Sharpe the marshal here, and all the city officials and federal officials, everybody knew you worked there? A Yes but they did not say nothing.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Q Nobody ever tell you not to work there? A No; nobody tell me.</p>

<p>Q Have you ever been arrested in this country? A Not one time.</p>

<p>Findings and Recommendation.</p>

<p>The alien is 60 years of age, a native and subject of Japan. He claims to have been in the United States since 1884 and that he has madeno trips to Japan.</p>

<p>He admits being employed as cook in a house of prostitution, and recommendation is respectfully submitted that he be ordered deported to his native country.</p>

<p>W. G. Strench</p>
<p>Examining Inspector &amp; Reporter.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>