<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0368.009">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Matoba Watari v. T.W. Lynch. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0368.009</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Matoba Watari v. T.W. Lynch. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1921-11-01">November 1, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-11">November 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Watari, Matoba</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Lynch, T.W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Allen</persName>
<persName>Martin</persName>
<persName>Wardall</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Faulkner, Judson</persName>
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-07" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>United States District Court Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>No. 6360</p>

<p>Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>In The Matter of the Application of MATOBA WATARI For WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS</p>

<p>Matoba Watari, Petitioner, vs. T.W. Lynch, Acting Commissioner of Immigration, Respondent.</p>

<p>Comes now MATOBA WATARI, by his attorney, Winter S. Martin, and respectfully shows to the Court:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That your petitioner entered the United States in the year 1900 upon and under a passport lawfully issued to him by the Empire of Japan. That he continuously remained in the United States since said date with the exception of two short trips to the Empire of Japan not exceeding four months on each occasion. That by reason of the premises your petitioner had, prior to June, 1921, acquired the status of resident friendly alien lawfully domiciled within said United States. That in June, 1921, your petitioner shipped on the United States Shipping Board Steamship "CROSS KEYS: as galley man for a voyage to Japan and return, not to exceed twelve calendar months, to be discharged at a port of the United States on the Pacific Coast.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>That in the Port of Kobe, in the Empire of Japan, on July</p>

<pb/>

<p>15th, 1921, your petitioner was given permission to remain ashore for several days while in the ports of Japan. That while so ashore, without any intention to desert or leave the said ship, he failed to present himself on board on the 15th of July when said ship sailed from the Port of Kobe for Chinese ports. That on said day he was by the master of said ship logged as a deserter notwithstanding that in truth and in fact he was not at said time a deserter from said ship, but on the contrary had at all times a fixed purpose to return to said ship and resume his duties on board.</p>

<p>III.</p>

<p>That thereafter, in the month of July, your petitioner joined the ship "Cross Keys" and returned to the United States entering on the 27th of August at and through the Port of Seattle. That upon arrival at said port he was by the immigration officers of the United States, acting under the authority of Thomas W. Lynch, Acting Commissioner of Immigration at the Port of Seattle, unlawfully detained and thereafter unlawfully hend and detained as a deportable alien.</p>

<p>IV.</p>

<p>That thereafter a board od special inquiry was convened by said officers, who, after hearing, denied your petitoner the right to enter the United States and ordered his deportation to the Empire of Japan. That your petitioner thereafter appealed to the Department of Labor, which appeal has been denied, and your petitioner has thereby exhausted all remedies for his release in and through the Department of Labor, Bureau of Immigration.</p>

<p>-2-</p>

<pb/>

<p>V.</p>

<p>That your petitioner is, as aforesaid, under unlawful arrest and detention by said Thomas W. Lynch, Acting Commissioner of Immigration, and his deputies, who unlawfully threaten to deport your petitioner from the United States and will, if they are not restrained by order of this Honorable Court, carry said threat into execution within the next two or three days.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE your petitioner prays:</p>

<p>1. That a writ of habeas corpus may be issued to your said petitioner and that he may be discharged from said illegal restraint and unlawful arrest:</p>

<p>2. That pending a hearing upon an application for this writ of habeas corpus that said Thomas W. Lynch, Acting Commissioner of Immigration, and his deputies, be hereby enjoined and restrained from deporting your petitioner from Seattle to the Empire of Japan;</p>

<p>3. That an order to show cause issue forthwith directed to the said Thomas W. Lynch, Acting Commissioner of Immigration, requiring him to be and appear in the above entitled Court, at a time to be fixed by this Honorable Court, to show cause, if any he have, why the said writ of habes corpus shall not be granted.</p>

<p>Watari Matoba</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>

<p><unclear>Winter S. Martin</unclear></p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner.</p>

<p>United States of America, Western District of Washington, Northern Divison.:</p>

<p>ss.</p>

<p>MATOBA WATARI, being first duly sworn by and through</p>

<p>-3-</p>

<p>an interpreter, upon his oath states:</p>

<p>That he has heard read to him this Petition for a writ of Habeas Corpus, and that the facts therein stated are true.</p>

<p><del>W</del> Watari Matoba</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 1st day of November, 1921.</p>

<p><unclear>Winter S. Martin</unclear></p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Nov 1 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>