<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT, FOR THE NINTH CIRCUIT.

IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION
OF LEE FONG FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS
CORPUS. 

PETITIONER'S BRIEF.


The Petitioner Lee Fong was arrested and detained in the
custody of the Chief of Police of the city of Seattle, upon a
charge made against him of having violated the provisions of 
Sections 6 and 7 of Ordinance 710 of the City of Seattle, approved
by the Mayor on the 6th day of February, 1886; and which is
entitled, "An Ordinance regulating the establishment and maintenance 
of Public Laundries and Public Washhouses within the 
limits of the City of Seattle". 

Said Section 6 referred to in in language as follows, towit:
"Section 6. It shall be unlawful, from and after the passage 
of this ordinance for any person or persons to establish, maintain,
or carry on a laundry within the corporate limits of the
City of Seattle, without having first obtained the consent of 
the common council, except the same be located in a building
constructed either of brick or stone and covered with a metal roof."
And so much of said Section 7 as provides for the punishment for
all violation of provisions of said Section 6, is in language
following, towit: "And any person who shall violate any of the
provisions of Section 6 of this ordinance shall be guilty of a 
misdemanor, and upon conviction thereof shall be punished bya
fine or not less than Five Dollars nor more than One Hundred
Dollars; or by <del>punis</del> imprisonment for not more than thirty days;
or by both said fine and imprisonment."

-1-

<pb/>

The complaint upon which the petitioner herein was arrested
and detained, charges the ofense alleged to have been 
committed in the language of said Section 6 of said Ordinance;
and that said alleged offense of the petitioner is contrary to
Ordinance No. 710, towit: Sections 6 and 7 hereinbefore quoted.
It will be observed that pursuant to the provisions of said
Section 6 of said recited ordinance, the consent of the Council
for the establishment, maintainance and carrying on of all laundries
within the corporate limits of the City of Seattle, is not 
required when said laundry is located or to be located in a 
building constructed either of brick or stone, and covered with
a metal roof. Buildings so constructed are exempt from the
requirements of said Section of said ordinance; but in the case 
of a laundry to be carried on in a frame building or other such
than is embraced in the exception to said section, the consent
of the council is demanded; and that consent is not conditioned 
upon any reference to the fitness of the building in which a proposed
laundry is to be established, for such purpose, nor upon
its protection against the dangers of fire or its satisfactory
sanatary conditions; but that such consent is dependent entirely
on the arbitrary will of council.

So that it follows, that if the person applying for such
consent is in all respects entirely worthy and deserving, and
that his building, intended for his laundry business, is possessd
of every possible sanatary provision; that all precautions 
and care has been taken to guard against the danger of fire, and
in every other respect fitted for the purpose of his business
and entirely free from objectionable features of whatever kind,
yet not withstanding all this, the Section puts it in the power
of council arbitrarily, without any reason and for prejudicial
or whimsocal causes, entirely, to withold the required. consent.

-2-

<pb/>

This, we contend, is in direct conflict with the provisions
of the Constitution of the United States, and especially of the
Fifth and Fourteenth Amendments thereto.

Fortunately for the petitioner herein, who has expnded
practically his entire means on the preperation of the building
for his proposed laundry, and that too upon an expressed permit
to do so from the Building Inspector of the City of Seattle, 
the constitutional question involved in this contention has been 
decided in his favor by the Supreme Court of the United States,
as will be shown by a citation of authorities contained in this 
brief.

The Honorable Court is first referred to the case reported
in 13th Federal Reporter, pages 229 and 233; being the case of "In
Re Quong," decided by Circuit Court of the District of California
in August 1882. In that case Justice Field, who delivered
the opinion, held on Writ of Habeas Corpus that "An ordinance
which makes it unlawful for any person to establish, maintain
or carry on any laundry within certain limits without first obtaining
the consent of the Board of Supervisors, which shall
only be granted upon the recommendation of not less than twelve
citizens and tax payers in the block in which the laundry is
proposed to be established, and which punishes by fine or imprisonment
for a violation of its provisions, is invalid.

In Re Wo Lee 26 Federal Reporter 471,

The Circuit Court of the District of California.

On January 26 1886, Justice Sawyer in delivering the opinion,
refers to the Laundry Ordinance cases in 13 Federal Reporter
229, the first case herein cited, and says: "That after that
decision, the Ordinance passed upon therein was amended by omitting
the requirement of the assent of twelve citizens and tax
payers in the block, but it still prohibited carrying on a
laundry business, after complying with numerous <del>monerous</del> conditions,
without in addition having first obtained a license,

-3-

or permit therefor, duly granted by resolution of Board of 
Supervisors, and it prescribed no specific conditions, the performance
of which should entitle the party to a license or permit,
but the license or permit, after performance of all the 
other  prescribed conditions, still depended upon the will of
pleasure of the Board of Supervisors. It simply struck out the
consent of the twelve tax payers in the block and left it to
rest upon the consent of the Board alone, thereby limiting the
number of parties to the consent,without abandoning the principle. 
For this reason in Jom Jong's case, the Circuit Judge 
thought the objection still remained unobviated. On this point
we think he is also sustained by authorities." The quotation
is from Judge Sawyer's opinion found on pade 427 of 26 Federal 
Reporter. After citing a number of cases therein upon the
question involved, Judge Sawyer says on page 473 of said case:
"If the court was right in those cases, then it seems to us that
the ordinance now in question must be void upon similar grounds."

"Section 1 provides that "It shall be unlawful, from and
after the passage of this order, for any person, or persons,
to establish, maintain or carry on a laundry within the corporate
limits of the city and county of San Francisco without having
first obtained the consent of the Board of Supervisors, except
the same be located in a building constructed of either brick
or stone".

In quite a lengthy opinion by Justice Sawyer in the case
just mentioned, he argues and holds on pages 474 and 475, "That
the ordinance passed upon by him in said case, (and of which the
Seattle Ordinance, alleged to have been violated in this case,
is a literal transcript, except as to the City and the body
whose consent is required,) is unconstitutional and in conflict
with the 14th Amendment of the United States Constiution. 
The Supreme Court of the State of California having, however,

-4-

previous to Judge Sawyer's opinion in the case just cited, held
in the case of Yick Wo, that the ordinance passed upon by Judge
Sawyer was not in conflict with <del>the</del> constitutional provisions;
he, Judge Sawyer, in deference to the previous adjudication of
the question involved by the Supreme Court of the State, discharged
the Writ of Habeas Corpus in the case before him and 
remanded the petitioner to the custody of the officer having him
in charge.

On appeal of the case just cited of Wo Lee from the decision
of Judge Sawyer, and also from the judgment of the Supreme
Court of the State of California, in the case of Yick Wo, the
Supreme Court of the United States, in an opinion delivered by 
Justice Matters, reversed both cases, that of Yick Wo vs
Hopkins, sheriff of the City and County of San Francisco, and
that of Wo Lee vs same, and held the California ordinance (which
as stated, is precisely like the Seattle ordinance under review,
in this case), to be unconstitutional. In the last mentioned
cases, towit: of Yick wo vs Hopkins and Wo Lee vs same, reported
in 118th United States Supreme Court Reporter from pages
356 to 374, Justice Matthews in the third paragraph of his
opinion, speaking of the ordinance referred to, said, "They seem
intended to confer and actually do confer, not a discretion to
be exercised upon a consideration of the circumstances of each
case, but a <del>marked</del> naked and arbatrary power to give or withold
consent, not only as to places, but as to persons. So that,
if an applicant for such consent being in every was a competent
and qualified person, and having complied with every reasonable 
condition demanded by any public interest, should, failing to
obtain the requisite consent of the Supervisors to the prosecution
of his business, apply for a redress by the judicial process 
of Mandamus to require the Supervisors to consider and act upon

-5-

<pb/>

his case, it would be a sufficient answer for them to say that
the law had conferred upon them authority to withold their assent,
without reason and without responsibility. The power given them
is not confided to their discretion in the legal sense of that
term, but is granted to their mere will. It is purely arbitrarily
and acknowledges neither guidance or restraint."

In quite a lengthy opinion on this subject, Justice Matthews
in the recited case, held the ordinance, (which as stated, is in language
similar to the Seattle ordinance on the subject), to be in
violation of the 14th Amendment of the United States constitution,
and reversed the decision both of the Supreme Court of the State
of Washington, and that of Judge Sawyer of the Circuit Court of
California, and directed the discharge of the petitioners from
custody and imprisonment.

It is unneccessary for petitioner's council to quote at
leangth from the opinion of Justice Matthews in the case just cited,
but the full text thereof is respectfully referred to the Honorable
Judge passing upon the petition herein; and especiallly to the
point made by his Honor Justice Matthews, that though said ordinance
on its face be fair, yet in giving to a board of supervisors an
arbitrary power, it made it possible for such a board to discriminate
and that it is obnoxious to the provisions of the 14th Amendment
to the constitution of the United States, <del>and</del> in that it has such
a tendency, and possibility; and although in the cases mentioned,
Justice Matthews sets forth that such discrimination in the cases
before him was actually shown and exercised on the laundrymen,
of chinense birth, yet the broad ground upon which he passes
his adjudication, is the fact that the ordinance referred to,
puts it in the power of a board, to grant or refuse consent arbitrarily.

<pb/>

By a comparison of dates it will be found, that his Honor
Judge Hanford, who whilst City Attorney of te City of Seattle,
framed Ordinance 710 of that City, which is being passed in review
in this case, wrote said ordinance, admittedly copying it
from the San Francisco ordinance, after the later had been held
by the Supreme Court of California to be invalid, but prior to
the adjudication upon appeal, of its unconstitutionality by the
Supreme Court of the United States, in the opinion by Mr. Justice
Matthews herein last <del>case</del> cited, the Seattle ordinance having
been approved February 6, 1886, and the opinion rendered by Justice 
Matthews on April 14 of the same year. 

In the Stockton Laundry case-in re Tie Loy- reported
in 26 Federal Reporter 611 to 616 (in which Justice Sawyer delivered 
the opinion) the syllabus is "A City ordinance that makes 
it an offense for any person to carry on a laundry where clothes
are washed for pay, within the habitable portion of the City is
unconstitutional, and that a party who is held in custody for 
the violation of a city ordinance that is in conflict with the
14th Amendment of the United States Constitution, is entitled
to be discharged on Habeas Corpus; and in said case the Court
held it to be a violation of the United States constitution
within the meaning of Section 733 of the revised statute which 
provides that the discharge of a person by habeas corpus, who
is illedgally held in custody or imprisonment, Said statute
giving jurisdiction to the United States District and Circuit
Courts to grant such relief. in

In re Sam Kee reported in 31st Federal Reporter 680 to 681, 
Justice Sawyer held that a city ordinance which makes it an
offense to keep a laundry wherein clothes are clensed for hire,
within the limits of the larger part of a city, without regard
to the character of the structure, or the appliances used for
the purpose, or the manner in which occupation is carried
on, is unconstitutional on various grounds, and void, and that

-7-

<pb/>



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>