<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>In Re: Ex Parte - Donald Kerracher - Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Banse, AD" xml:id="ab">AD Banse</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0270.008</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">In Re: Ex Parte - Donald Kerracher - Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="2022-06-13">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">2022-06-21</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName> Donald MC Kerracher</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName> C.B. Hopkins</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>C.H. Hanford</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

               
<div1 type="case">

<p> No. 1328 </p> 

<p>In the United States is admitted this, in  Circuit Court of  Dirstrict of Washington Ninth Judicial Circuit Northern Division </p>
<p>  Donald Mc. Kerracher, Petitioner. Complainant vs. Defendant. Petition for a writ of Habeas Corpus. Filed in the U.S. Circuit Court, Western Dist. of Washington. Sept 20 1905. Clerk by Deputy A. Reeves Ayres. A.N. Moody Dep.  </p>

 <p>In the United StatesCirtuit Court, For the Ninth Judicial Circuit, Western District of the State of Washington, Northern Division. </p>

<p> In Re. Ex Parte: Donald MC Kerracher, Petitioner. no. 1328 </p>

<p>  Answer in return to the Writ of Habeas Corpus. </p>
<p> In obedience to theWrit of habeas corpus issued on behaf of the petitioner herein, comes now the respondent, Charles B. Hopkins United States Marshal for the Western Distrcit of Washington, and Jesse A. Frye, United States Attorney for the Western District of Washington appearting for the United States intervening herein, and for the said Charles B. Hopkins, United States Marshal for the Western Distrcit of Washington, and in answer to said writ and petition filed herein, certify, return and answer as follows:     </p>
<p> 1. Answering paragraph one of said petition, these respondents admit that the petitioner is a citizen of the Untied States and of the State of Washington, and they deny generally and each and every part thereof contained in said paragraph one of said petition. </p>
<p> II. Answering paragraph two of said petition, these respondents admit the allegations therein contained, except the allegation in the words and figures following, to-wit:  " Which deduction under the law of the United amounts to eight (8) days for the each month of his sentence", which allegation these respondents deny generally and specifically, and each and every part thereof. </p>
<p> III. Respondents answering paragraph three of said petition, admit the allegations thereof.</p>
<p> IV. Answering paragraph four of said petition, these respondents deny generally and specifically each and every allegation therein contained, and eacfh and every part thereof: except that the respondents admit that the United States Marshal for the Western Distrcit of Washington refuses to discharge the petitioner from said penitentiary. </p>
<p> V.  Answering paragraph five of said petition, these respondents admit that teh petitioner is entitled to the benefits of the laws of the United States in force at the time of his sentence and incarceration;  and the respondents deny generally and specifically each and every allegation and each and every part thereof further contained in said paragraph five of said petitions.</p>
<p> Respondents further answering, and for further return to said Writ state:  </p>
<p>I. That the respondents Charles B. Hopkins, is now and for a long time has been, the duly appointed qualified and acting United States Marshal for the Western District of Washington, and that the petitioner, Donald McKerracher, is in his custody as such United States Marshal, and that the said petitioner is now detained in the United States Penitentiary on McNeil's Island. </p>
<p> II. That said petitioner was turned over to this respondent, Charles B. Hopkins, by his predecessor in Office, as United States Marshal for the then District of Washington, for the purpose of Incarceration in the United States penitentiary on McNeil's Island, in the then District of Washington, and on the 15th day of January 1902 under a sentence of imprisonment for the term of five years, by the United States District Court for the District of Washington, on the 14th day of January 1902, and on said 15th day of January 1902 said Donald McKerracher was duly imprisoned in the United States penitentiary on McNeil's Island in the State of Washington, and the said petitioner has since said date been held and confined in said penitentiary under said sentence, and is now detained therein under sentence, and which said sentence was duly and alwfully made by a court having jurisdiction of said petitioner, and that the commitment on said sentence was duly and lawfully issued, and that the imprisonment of said petitioner is lawful and according to law, and that said sentence of imprsionment has not expired and will not expire until the 14th day of April 1906. Wherefore, your respondents having shown to this Honorable cout that said petitioner is held by due and lawful process, nevertheless now produces before this honorable court, the body of said Donald McKerracher, petitioner herein, at the time and at the place as in said writ directed, and hereto attaches and makes a part of the return of said writ as upon the respondent Charles B. Hopkins served, and prays that said writ be denied, that the said petitioner be held to wait the expiration of his sentence as provided by law, and that the be remanded to the custody of the respondent Charles B. Hopkins, United States Marshal for the Western District of Washington.  </p>
<p>  Jesse A. Frye. United States Attorney for the Western District of Washington. </p>

<pb/>
<p>  Due and timely service of the within Answer, and the receipt of a true copyh thereof, acknowledged this 20th day of September 1905. </p>
<p> Metcalfe and Jurey, Attorneys for Petitioner. </p>
<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>