<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0216.040">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chin Hing v. United States of America. Deposition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Russell, Ellie" xml:id="edr">Ellie Russell</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0216.040</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Chin Hing v. United States of America. Deposition</title>
<date when="1914">1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-11">November 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hing, Chin</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Government, United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Stadden, Corry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Sullivan, John J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Stadden, Corry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Gould, Ashley</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#edr">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the United States District Court, for the Western District
of Washington Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the matter of
Chin Hing</p>
<p>#2857
Deposition of Louis F. Post, upon 
the annexed interrogatoriesand 
cross interrogatories, at Washington
D.C.</p>
<pb/>

<p>Be it remembered that at an examination of witneses under 
the Commission of this Honorable Court, begun on the 11th day of 
November, pursuant to a subpoena issued by the Clerk of the Supreme
Court of the District of Columbia, personally appeared before 
me, Thomas G. Lewis, Commissioner, the within named Louis F.
Post, who being produced as a witness of lawful age for and on behalf
of the Petitioner, Ching Hing, and being first duly sworn and cautioned
to tell the truth, the whole truth and nothing but the truth,
touching the matter at issue in the above-entitled cause, did
depose and say as follows:</p>
<p>(1) I am the Assistant Secretary of Labor. I am qualified on the 9th of
June, 1913.</p>
<p>(2) That question relates to the internal administration of the
Departmentand I regard it as calling for an answer that might be prejudicial
to the public interest. For this reason I decline to answer until instructed
otherwise by the Secretary of Labor</p>
<p>(3) Solicitorof the Department of Justice for the Department of Labor.</p>
<p>(4) Same response as to Question 2</p>
<p>(5) Same answer as to Questions 2 and 4.</p>
<p>(6) I am acquainted with a decision by Judge Dooling of the Federal
Court at San Franscisco which is the decision to which I suppose reference is
made by the question.</p>
<p>(7)Same response as to Question 2.</p>
<p>(8)Same response as to Question 2.</p>
<p>(9) In so far as that applies to immigration cases the response is the
same as the response to Question 2. Speaking generally, I am Acting Secretary
in the absence of the Secretary.</p>
<p>(10)Same response as to Question 2.</p>
<p>(11)Same response as to Question 2.</p>
<p>(12)Same response as to Question 2.</p>
<pb/>

<p>Answers of Mr. Post to Cross Interrogatories</p>
<p>(1) That question relates to the internal administration of the Department
and I regard it as calling for an answer that might be prejudicial to 
the public interest. For this reason I decline to answer until instructed
otherwise by the Secretary of Labor.</p>
<p>(2) Same response as to Cross Interrogatory 1.</p>
<p>(3) Same response as to Cross Interrogatory 1.</p>
<p>(4) Same response as to Cross Interrogatory 1.</p>
<p>(5) Same response as to Cross Interrogatory 1.</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 11th day of November, 1914.
Louis F. Post</p>
<p>Thomas G Lewis
Notary Public and Commissioner</p>
<p><add>Adjourned to Monday, November 16, 1914,
at three o'clock PM
Thomas G Lewis 
Commissioner</add></p>
<p>Monday, November 16, 1914: Adjourned to Monday, November 23rd, 1914,
at 3 pm, pending determination of a certifiateto the Supreme Court 
of the District of Columbia which set up the fact that the witness
Post had refused to answer interrogatories and cross interrogatories.
Thomas G Lewis
Commissioner</p>
<p>Monday, November 23, 1914: Adjourned to Friday, Nov. 27 at 3:30 p.m.
pending determination of the Court upon Certificate, Rule
and Return.
Thomas G Lewis
Commissioner.</p>
<p>Friday, November 27, 1914: Adjourned to Friday, December 4, 1914, at 3:30pm
Thomas G Lewis
Comissioner.</p>
<p>Personally appeared before me, Thomas G. Lewis, Notary Public
and Commissioner, pursuant to notice, Corry M. Stadden, who being produced
as witness to lawful age for and on behalfof the Petitioner,
Ching Hing, and being first duly sworn according to law, upon Interrogatories
and Cross Interrogatories, did depose and say as follows:</p>
<p>(1) Corry M. Stadden, attorney at law.</p>
<p>(2) Yes.</p>
<p>(3) I did.</p>
<p>(4) Louis F. Post, Assistant Secretary of Labor was present and on
duty in the Department of Labor on September 24th, 25th, and 26th,
1914. I am not certain whether Secretary Wilson was on duty on 
those dates or not, as I was more particular in satisfying myself
that Assistant Secretary Post was on duty, particularly on September 26th.</p>
<p>(5) I was notified on September 26th that Mr. J. B. Sensmore, as "Acting
Secretary" of Labor had affirmed the decision to deport Ching
Hing. The record will show.</p>
<p>(6) Assistant Secretary Post was on duty September 26. I visited
his office to satisfy myself that he was there on that date.</p>
<p>(7) Judge M. T. Dooling, in the U.S. District Court, sitting at San
Franciso, In re Quan Wy Chung, No. 15687, has so held.</p>
<p>(8) Quoting from a certified copy of the opinion In re Quan Wy
Chung, Judge Dooling said in part as follows:
"Whoever, therefore, challenges his right to act must
assume the burden of proving clearly, that his action was
not had in the 'Absence of the Secretary and Assistant Secretary'.
But however inconvenient it may be, if the Secretary
and Assistant are not absent, and particularly if both
are present, his performance of the duties of the Secretary
is unauthorized, either by the Statute, or the order of the
President. In the case at barit is practically conceded, and
conclusively established, that the appeal was not determined 
by the Acting Secretary in the absence of the Secretary and
<pb/>

Assistant Secretary, but that, on the contrary both were
present, and performing the duties of their office at the 
time the appeal was determined. The appellant were by law
to have their appeal heard and determined by him except as
above stated, and the determination of their appeal by another
not authorized, is neither a fair hearing, nor due 
process of law".</p>
<p>this opinion was filed by Judge Dooling with the Clerk of
his Court, October 23rd, 1914, as appears on the certified copy.</p>

<p>Answersof Mr. Stadden to Cross Interrogatories:</p>
<p>(1) I was not.But I satisfied myself that Assistant Secretary
Post was not considering the Ching Hing appeal, though on duty
in the Department.</p>
<p>(2) By seeing the word "approved" or "affirmed" and the initials
of Mr. Densmore, "J.B.D." on the memorandum prepared in the Bureau
of Immigration which recommended exclusion. I also knew personally
that Mr. Densmore was assuming to act upon this case as "Acting Secretary"
regardless of the fact that Assistant Secretary Post was 
on duty at that time.</p>
<p>Corry M. Stadden</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me,
Thomas G Lewis
Notary Public, D.C. and 
Commissioner.</p>

<p>Adjourned until further notice pending the order of the Court (Mr.
Justice Gould) upon the Rule to Show Cause, issued against the
witness, Louis F. Post, herein.
Thomas G Lewis
Commissioner.</p>

<p>June 10th, 1915: Further proceedings under this Commission hereby
suspended upon advice of Corry M. Stadden, cousel for Ching Hing
that he is informedthat the Petition of Habeas Corpus herein
has been dismissed. The Order of Mr. Justice Gould, of the Supreme
Court of the District of Columbia, commanding the witness Louis F.
Post to appear and answer question, was signed this day and a true
copy is appended hereto.
Thomas G Lewis
Commissioner.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>