<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>To the Honorable the Law Commissioners 
Court of St Louis County-</p>

<p>The petitioner of Robert 
Smith respectfully states and shows unto this 
Honorable Court, that George Bailey the person 
for whom relief is prayed is imprisoned and is 
restrained of his liberty by James A. Felps Esqr 
the jailor of St Louis County in the jail of 
said County; situate on the North East corner 
of Chestnut and Sixth streets in the City of 
St Louis; that all the facts concerning such 
<sic>improsionment</sic> and restraint are that on or 
about the 8th day of August inst A.D. 1856 the 
said George Bailey was arrested by one James C. 
Adams in the City of St Louis, upon the charge of 
being a runaway Slave, and as such was 
committed to the common jail of said County 
of St Louis by Peter N. Johnston Esqr a Justice of 
the Peace of said County, and the true cause 
of such <sic>imprisionment</sic> and restraint is the allege 
one that said Bailey is a runaway Slave, to the 
best knowledge and belief of your petitioner; that 
said Bailey is not imprisoned or restrained of his 
liberty as aforesaid for any of the causes which would prohibit him from being entitled to the writ of Habeas Corpus, as your petitioner is advised and believes; that the annexed paper marked "A" is a true copy of the order or process by which said Bailey is thus restrained and confined as your Petitioner is also informed and believes; that the said Adams <unclear>reo...</unclear> other Person to the knowledge or belief of your petitioner claims the said Bailey as a Slave, and that he was merely arrested and committed upon suspicion and that your petitioner knows

the said George Bailey to be a free man and has known him to be such for the last two years and more, and that such <sic>imprisionment</sic> and restraint is illegal, and that such illegality consists in restraining and confining the said George Bailey as a runaway Slave when he is not a Slave, but is a free man of color and that your petitioner makes his petition for and on the behalf of the said George Bailey.</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays a Writ of Habeas Corpus to be directed to the said James A. Felps commanding him to produce the said George Bailey and that he may be discharged from such <sic>imprisionement</sic> and restraint</p>

<p>R Smith</p>

