<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0150.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>George Hawkins v. The United States of America. Affidavit for Leave to Prosecute in Forma Pauperis</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J" xml:id="sjs">Salma Silva</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0150.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">George Hawkins v. The United States of America. Affidavit for Leave to Prosecute in Forma Pauperis</title>
<date when="1902-11-05">November 5, 1902</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1902-11">November 1902</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Hopkins, R. M. </term>
<term>Ayres, A. Reeves</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>McNeil's Island, Washington</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hawkins, George</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>The United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Fenton, James E.</persName>
<persName>Grigsby, Melvin</persName>
<persName>Allen, John B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Wood, Joseph K.</persName>
<persName>McGinn, John L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
<persName>Moyes, Arthur H.</persName>
<persName>Morro, William W.</persName>
<persName>Fuller, Melville W.</persName>
<persName>Moore, Alfred S.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>District of Washington, Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<ab>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT, IN AND FOR THE DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</ab>

<ab>In the Matter of the Application of
George Hawkins, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</ab>

<ab>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA,
STATE OF WASHINGTON, COUNTY OF KING.</ab>

<ab>SS:</ab>

<p>I, James E. Fenton, being duly sworn say; - That I am the
Attorney of record for the above named George Hawkins, and make this
affidavit for and in behalf of the said George Hawkins; that the said
George Hawkins is a citizen of the United States and is now confined and 
imprisoned in the United States Penitentiary at McNeil's Island, in the
District of Washington; that the said George Hawkins is the petitioner
named in the petition for a writ of habeas corpus in the above entitled
proceeding, filed with the Clerk of the above entitled court this 5th
day of November, A.D., 1902; that the said George Hawkins seeks and 
prays for an order of this court that a writ of habeas corpus may be
granted, directed to the Warden of the United States Penitentiary at
McNeil's Island, in the State of Washington, commanding him to have the 
body of the said George Hawkins before this Honorable Court at the time
and place therein to be specified, to do and receive what shall then
and there be considered by this Honorable Court concerning him, together
with the time and cause of his detention and the said writ, and that the
said George Hawkins may be restored to his liberty and discharged from 
custody; that affiant is the attorney of record for the said George
Hawkins, and the said petitioner prepared the said petition for a writ
of habeas corpus and has full knowledge of all the matter therein
stated, and believes that the said George Hawkins is entitled to the
redress sought to be obtained by the said petition, and has good cause
of action thereunder; that by reason of the poverty of the said George
Hawkins, he the said George Hawkins is unalbe to pay the costs of prosecuting
said proceedings for a writ of habeas corpus which he is about to
commence, or to give security for the same, and there is no person
interested in the said proceeding who is able to pay the security and</p>

<pb/>

<p>and costs of prosecuting the same;</p>

<p>WHEREFORE affiant prays that the said petitioner, George
Hawkins may have leave to prosecute his said petition for a writ of
habeas corpus, in form pauperis, pursuant to the statute in that case
made and provided, and that the officers of this Court shall issue,
serve all process and perform all duties in this cause, and that the
said petitioner have the same remedy as is provided by law in other
cases, without costs or fee of clerk or other officer of this court,
and without filing a bond to secure the same.</p>

<ab>James E Fenton</ab>

<ab>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 5th day of November, A.D., 1902.</ab>

<ab>R M Hopkins</ab>

<ab><del>Notary Public in and for the State of 
Washington, residing at Seattle.</del></ab>

<ab>Clerk of the U.S. District Court, 
District of Washington</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Tx</ab>

<ab>1047.</ab>

<ab><del>2364</del></ab>

<ab>UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</ab>

<ab>In the matter of the
Application of

GEORGE HAWKINS

For a writ of Habeas Corpus.</ab>

<ab>AFFIDAVIT FOR LEAVE TO PROSECUTE
IN FORMA PAUPERIS.</ab>

<ab>Filed Nov. 5 1902
A. Reeves Ayres
Clerk

RM Hopkins
Deputy Clerk</ab>

<ab>James E. Fenton,
Attorney for Plaintiff.</ab>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>