<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0376.012">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Junichi Yamamoto v. Luther Weedin. Memorandum Brief</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="ka">Salma J. Silva</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0376.012</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Junichi Yamamoto v. Luther Weedin. Memorandum Brief</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date/></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Kahl, Arthur J.</term>
<term>Samgoon, Owe</term>
<term>Yuen, Wong</term>
<term>Toguchi, Kuniyiro</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washingotn</term>
<term>Japan</term>
<term>Canada</term>
<term>Mexico</term>
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Yamamoto, Junichi</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Weedin, Luther</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Hellsell, Frank P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Gates</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Falkner, Judson J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Cushman, Edward E.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-10" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>No. 6617</p>
<p>MEMORANDUM BRIEF</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION
OF JUNICHI YAMAMOTO, FOR 
WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>

<p>The petitioner, Junichi Yamamoto, is a citizen of
the Empire of Japan and has been a resident of King County,
Washington since September 17, 1917. On the 10th day of
January, 1922 he was arrested by the respondant, United States
Commissioner of Immigration,at Seattle, Washington, on a tele-
graphic warrant sent from the Department of Labor at Washington.
In the warrant of arrest he is charged with the violation of Rule
11 of the Immigration Rules and that at the time of entry he was
likely to become a public charge. He was given a hearing before
one Arthur J. Kahl, an Immigrant Inspector at Seattle, Washing-
ton, and a complete copy of all of the testimony taken at his
hearing is attached to the petition and marked Exhibit A. From
the record it is apparent that the Government made no effor to
prove that at the time of hearing, or any time prior thereto,
the alien was likely to become a public charge. There is an
entire want of evidence to indicate that such is the fact. The
Government attempted to produce no evidence to show that the
petitioner was at any time likely to become a public charge, but
the evidence affirmatively shows that at the time of the hearing
the petitioner owned a Ford truck, upon which he had paid a sum
in excess of $800.00, and that he had loans outstanding in the 
sum of $500.00 and $120.00. In his petition he alleges that at
the time he arrived in the United States he had in his possession</p>

<pb/>

<p>the sum of 800 gold yen and that since his arrival he has sub
stantially paid for a Ford truck and has sent to his home in
Japan the sum of $1500.00. He is a young man, thirty-one years
of age, healthy and able-bodied in every way, and there is no
excuse or justification in the record for holding that at any
time he was likely to become a public charge.</p>

<p>The real reason he has been arrested and has been
ordered deported is that it appears from the record that he was 
born in Japan; that he came directly from Japan to the United 
States; that he landed at Seattle, Washington; that he reached
Seattle as an able-bodied seaman on the Steamship "Taiyo Maru"
on September 17, 1917; that he deserted as a seaman at Seattle,
Washington and has ever since been in the state; that he had no
passport from Japan; that he never tried to get a passport in
Japan and he didn't need one, because he was a part of the crew
and a seaman on board the "Taiyo Maru"' that at the time he left
the vessel in September, 1917 he did not see an Immigration
official.</p>

<p>Since there is a total want of any evidence to
indicate that the petitioner is likely to become a public charge,
it remains for us to determine whether he has obtained entry into
 the United States in violation of Rule 11 of the Immigration Rules.</p>

<p>JAPANESE LABOR.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court of the United States makes a
clean and well-defined distinction between a laborer seeking ad
mission to this country and an able-bodied seaman who comes to
this country on board a vessel engaged in foreign commerce. It
is not proper to call the petitioner a Japanese laborer within
the meaning of the Immigration rules. Our position is well sup-</p>

<p>-2-</p>

<pb/>

<p>ported by the case of Scharranberg vs. Dollar Steamship Company
245 U.S. 122, 62 L. ed. 189, where that court states that a
seaman is never called a laborer within the terms of the various
statutes concerning immigration.</p>

<p>But even should this court assume for the purposes
of this case that the petitioner was a Japanese laborer within
the meaning of the Immigration rules, still we confidently assert
that there is no statute of the United States by which the pe
titioner is among the excluded classes. It is a well known fact
that the United States Government has steadfastly declined to
enact any legislation which expressly is directed toward the
exclusion of Japanese labor. The laborers from Japan are treated
exactly in the same manner as is all alien labor, and in order to
avoid any appearance of discrimination against the citizens of
Japan the Government has declined to enact special legislation
affecting Japan.</p>

<p>However, it appears that there was a Gentleman's 
Agreement between the Japanese Government and the American Govern-
ment, whereby the Japanese Government denied passports to Japanese
laboreres, and absolutely the only reason that Japanese labor has
not come to this country is because of the refusal of the Japanese
Government to permit the same. In the absence of the Gentlemen's
Agreement there is nothing in our laws by which they could be
excluded.</p>

<p>The Japanese Government, however, permits its labor-
ers to come to Canada and to Mexico, and for that purpose grants
to them limited passports good only for that country. It appears
that these laborers holding limited passports were gaining
surreptitious entry into the United States by coming to Mexico
and Canada, and in order to protect the United States from the</p>

<p>-3-</p>

<pb/>

<p>entry of these laborers from adjoining countries, it was pro-
vided in the Immigration Act of February 20, 1907, and re-enacted
as the sixth proviso of Section 3 of the Immigration Act of 
February 5, 1917, as follows:</p>

<p>"That whenever the President shall be satisfied that
passports issued by any foreign government to its
citizens or subjects to go to any country other than
the United States, or to any insular possession of
the United States or to the Canal Zone, are being
used for the purpose of enabling the holder to come
to the continental territory of the United States
to the detriment of labor conditions therein, the
President shall refuse to permit such citizens or
subjects of the country issuing such passports to 
enter the continental territory of the United States
from such other country or from such insular pos-
session or from the Canal Zone."</p>

<p>The foregoing proviso is substantially the same in both the
Immigration Act of 1907 and in the Immigration Act of 1917.</p>

<p>It will be noticed that this proviso does not
grant to the President the right to exclude all Japanese labor,
but the privilege is granted to the President only to exclude
such Japanese labor or such alien labor who obtain passports from
their own country to countries other than the United States and
which <add>only applies</add> <del>implies</del> to them when such citizens or subjects attempt to
enter the United States, from <del>or</del> such other country to which the
limited passport is directed.</p>

<p>Pursuant to the authority granted in the Act of
February 20,1907, the President of the United States issued a
proclamation which referred expressly to the citizens of Japan.
This proclamation, dated March 14, 1907, after certain recitals,
provided that such citizens of Japan who have received passports
to go to Mexico, Canada or Hawaii, and come therefrom, be re-
fused to enter the continental territory of the United States.</p>

<p>The Japanese Government made objections to the
language contained in the foregoing proclamation and therefore</p>

<p>-4-</p>

<pb/>

<p>President Taft issued a new proclamation under date of February
24, 1913, which is set forth in full under Rule 11 of the
Department of Labor. That proclamation reads as follows:</p>

<p>"Whereas, by the act entitled 'An act to regulate
the immigration of aliens into the United States'
approved February 20, 1907, whenever the President
is satisfied that passports issued by any foreign
government to its citizens to go to any country other
than the United States or to any insular possession
of the United States or to the Canal Zone, are being
used for the purpose of enabling the holders to come
to the continental territory of the United
States from such country or from such insular pos-
session of from the Canal Zone;</p>

<p>"And whereas, upon sufficient evidence produced before
me by the Department of Commerce and Labor, I am
satisfied that passports issued by certain foreign
governments to their citizens or subjects who are
laborers, skilled or unskilled, to proceed to
countries or places other than the continental terri-
tory of the United States are being used for the pur-
pose of enabling the holders thereof to come to the
continental territory of the United States to the
detriment of labor conditions therein;</p>

<p>"I hereby order that such alien laborers, skilled or 
unskilled, be refused permission to enter the con-
tinental territory of the United States.</p>

<p>"It is further ordered that the Secretary of Commerce
and Labor be, and he hereby is, directed to take,
through the Bureau of Immigration and Naturalization,
such measures and to make and enforce such rules and
regulations as may be necessary to carry this order
into effect."</p>

<p>It cannot be too strongly emphasized that the 
proclamation of the President was not issued for the purpose of 
excluding all Japanese labor, but was issued for the sole pur-
pose of excluding that Japanese labor which obtains limited pass-
ports to other countries and abuses the use of such passports
by obtaining entry into the United States from such countries to
which they have been permitted to go by the Japanese Government.</p>

<p>-5-</p>

<pb/>

<p>In subdivision 3 of Rule 11 the Secretary of Labor
has provided:</p>

<p>"If such a laborer applies for admission and
presents no passport, it shall be presumed (1)
that when he departed from his own country he
did not possess a passport entitling him to come
to the continental territory of the United States,
and (2) that at the time he did possess a pass-
port limited to some country or place other than
the continental United States."</p>

<p>Of course, this rule was not intended to be ir-
rebuttable presumption, and the rule clearly indicates that the
President's proclamation was not enacted to exclude all Japanese
labor, but was simply enacted to cover a speical field where
special abuses had arisen. There can be no room for the opera-
tion of the presumption found in subdivision 3 in this case.
because the record conclusively shows that the petitioner had
no passport from the Japanese government of any kind, and did not
need one. He was designated as a part of the crew of the Japan-
ese vessel and came to this  country as an able-bodied seaman.
His name was on the crew list which was vised by the American
Consul in Japan. The petitioner came direct from Japan to the 
United States on board the vessel, and therefore does not in any
manner come within the provisions of the President's proclama-
tion or the ruels issued thereunder. The Immigrant Inspector
brought out himself the fact that the petitioner had no pass-
port of any kind, and it was furthermore shown that he did not 
need one.</p>

<p>We therefore assert confidently that the petitioner
is not present in the United States in violation of the Presi-
dent's proclamation or of the rules of the Department issued
thereunder. If he had presented himself to the Immigration
authorities at Seattle, Washington on September 17, 1917 it</p>

<p>-6-</p>

<pb/>

<p>would have been their duty to admit him.</p>

<p>In United States vs. Hemet, 156 Fed. 285, the 
United States District Court for Oregon, Wolverton, District
Judge, had for consideration the question of whether two
Japanese who arrived at Portland, Oregon as seamen on board
the French Barque "St. Louis", and who escaped from said vessel,
were unlawfully in the United States in violation of the Presi-
dent's proclamation. Judge Wolverton said that the President's
proclamation extended to and comprised such citizens of any
foreign government as shall have passports therefrom to any
country other than the United States and had used such passports
for the prupose of enabling the holders to come into the United
States; that neither the proviso in the Immigration law nor the
President's proclamation extended to all citizen of the govern-
ment issuing such passports, but only such citizens to whom
limited passports has been issued. The court held that the rules
of the Commissioner General went beyond the authority granted in
the Act; the the Commissioner had no authority to provide that
if a Japanese presents no passport the presumption shall be that
he possesses one of a limited character. The court said that the
Commissioner General might as well provide that if a Japanese
alien presents no passport is shall be presumed that he is an
idiot or a professional beggar. The court held that the two
Japanese seamen did not obtain entry into this country in vio-
lation of the President's proclamation.</p>

<p>OBTAINING ENTRY WITHOUT INSPECTION.</p>

<p>We believe that we have demonstrated that the
government is proceeding without warrant of law in attempting to
exclude the petitioner on the ground that he had obtained entry</p>

<p>-7-</p>

<pb/>

<p>into this country in violation of the President's proclamation.
The very worse that can be said against the petitioner is that
he violated the Immigration Law in failing at the time that he
left his vessel to present himself to the Immigration authorities
for inspection. Under Rule 22 of the Immigration Rules, adopted
May 1,1917, the various grounds upon which aliens can be de-
ported are classified, and the limitation in years within which
deportation may be had is expressly provided for each classifi-
cation. Under subdivision 1 (h) it is provided that any alien
who shall have entered without inspection may be deported within
three years after he obtains entry.</p>

<p>In Section 34 of the Immigration Act of February
5, 1917, it is provided as follows:</p>

<p>"That any alien seaman who shall land in a port 
of the United States contrary to the provisions
of this act shall be deemed to be unlawfully in
the United States, and shall, at any time within
three years thereafter, upon the warrant of the
Secretary of Labor, be taken into custody and
brought before a board of special inquiry for
examination as to his qualifications for ad-
mission to the United States, and if not ad-
mitted said alien seaman shall be deported at
the expense of the appropriation for this act as
provided in section twenty of this act."</p>

<p>It is provided in Section 36 of the same law that 
the owner or master of a vessel shall provide the Immigration
authorities with lists of all the seamen on board the vessel.
Rule 10 of the Immigration Rules of May 1, 1917, makes elaborate
provisions for the landing of alien seamen. In subdivision 1 of
Rule 10 seamen are defined, in subdivision 2 provision is made 
for the collection of a head tax upon those who are discharged
in a port of the United States. In subdivision 3 it is prov-
ided for the issuance to the seamen of an identification card
containing his photograph. It is provided that no seaman shall</p>

<p>-8-</p>

<pb/>

<p>be allowed to land without being registered and furnished with
such card. In subdivision 9 it is provided as follows:</p>

<p>"(a) Any alien who shall come to a United States port
as a seaman and land or remain in the United States
otherwise than in pursuance of and in accordance
with the provisions of this rule shall be arrested,
as provided in section 34, whenever and wherever found
in this country within three years from the date of
landing when his status changed from that of a sea-
man to that of an alien here resident. Such alien
then shall be brought before a board of special in-
quiry and subjected to a thorough examination under 
all provisions of the immigration law applicable to
the case of an alien seeking admision; such in-
vestigation, if any, as may be necessary to develop
evidence concerning him shall be conducted and he shall 
be subjected also to the medical examination required
in the cases of alien applicants for admission. If
rejected by the board he shall be allowed an appeal
to the department unless the rejection is upon a
ground with respect to which the law prohibits an
appeal; and in any event the record of the board of
special inquiry shall be transmitted to the bureau
for submission to the department, in order that a final
decision may be rendered if upon appeal and that a warrant
of deportation may be issued whether upon appeal or not.
Upon the issuance of the warrant the alien shall be de-
ported at the expense of the immigration appropriation."</p>

<p>It thus appears clearly that if an alien seaman
lands in a part of the United States contrary to the provisions
of the Immigration law he shall be arrested within three years
thereafter. This is expressly provided in Section 34, and also
expressly covered in subdivision 9 of rule 10. Furthermore the
seaman is granted the special treatment <del>instead</del> of being brought
before a board of special inquiry for examination as to his 
qualifications for admission to the United States. He is en-
titled to entirely different treatment than a person who is
arrested for deportation under Rule 22. A person other than a
seaman is entitled to a hearing before one Immigrant Inspector,
but a seaman is entitled to a hearing before a board of special
inquiry.</p>

<p>A board of special inquiry is a special tribunal</p>

<p>-9-</p>

<pb/>

<p>created by the Immigration Act, Section 17. Each board con-
sists of three members who are appointed by the Commissioner of
Immigration at the various ports of arrival. Such boards are
primarily designed to pass upon the qualifications of an alien
for admission. They do not pass upon ordinary deportation
matters. It therefore appears that the law contemplates that
a seaman who comes to this country on board of a foreign vessel
and obtains unlawful entry into this country is entitled to
different treatment than another alien who obtains unlawful en-
try into the country. In the case of a seaman <del>who</del> Le is entitled to
a hearing before a board of special inquiry, <add>and</add> if he can prove that
he is not within any excluded class, he is nevertheless entitled
to admission.</p>

<p>Now the petitioner has been denied all of the 
rights given to him by Section 34 of the Immigration Law, and
by Ruled 10 of the Immigration Rules. He is entitled to a
hearing before the special board of inquiry and in no event can
he be excluded when arrested more than three years after his
original entry into the United States. The petitioner in this
case has been in the United States continuously for four and one
half years, and therefore under no circumstances is subject to
deportation.</p>

<p>Even if this court should hold that the petitioner
is not entitled to the privileges of the time limitation pro-
vided for in Section 34 of the law, and should hold that he is
nevertheless subject to deportation under Section 19 of the
law, it still follows that he is only subject to deportation by
virtue of the fact that he has obtained entrance into this 
country without inspection and therefore he is entitled to the
protection of the three year statute of limitations contained</p>

<p>-10-</p>

<pb/>

<p>in Rule 22, subdivision 1 (h)</p>

<p>THE DECISION OF THE SECRETARY OF LABOR IS NOT FINAL
UPON QUESTION OF LAW.</p>

<p>Since there are no disputed facts in the record in 
this case, the validity of the deportation proceedings is entirely
a question of law. It has been repeatedly decided that the
decision of the Secretary of Labor upon questions of law is not
final or binding upon the courts, and <del>whether</del> where the Secretary of
Labor is proceeding in direction violation of the statute, or in
excess of his authority, a writ of habeas corpus will issue.
See Geigow vs. Uhl, 239 United States 3, 60 L.ed. 114.</p>

<p>Ex Parts Kuniyiro Toguchi, 238 Fed. 632, where Judge Neterer said:</p>

<p>"If petitioner is not within the prohibitory
clause of the Immigration Act, the Commissioner
of Immigration has no jurisdiction to detain and
deport him by issuance of concluding questions 
of law."</p>

<p>United States vs. Uhl, 211 Fed. 628</p>
<p>Backus vs. Owe Samgoon, 235 Fed. 846.</p>
<p>United States vs. Nakashima, 160 Fed. 844.Circuit
court of Appeals (9th)</p>
<p>Wong Yuen vs. Prentis, 234 Fed. 28.</p>

<p>Where the record before the examining inspector
shows an entire want of evidence that the alien is likely to
become a public charge, the courts grant a writ of habeas corpus
and discharge the petitioner. See United States vs. Howe,
235 Feb. 990, in which a girl twenty-two years old, an actress
and dancer by profession, with $35.00 in cash, in good health,
is held to be a person who is not apt to become a public charge</p>

<p>-11-</p>

<pb/>

<p>and is released on habeas corpus.</p>

<p>In Ex Parte Callow, 240 Fed. 212, the petitioner
worked as a fireman on a vessel, in harvest fields and traveling
from place to place getting what work he could do. He had an
interest in London which brought him a regular income of $150.00
a year, and had some money in a bank at Denver, but possessed
no property or baggage. The court said that no reasonable
inference could be drawn from these facts that would support the 
finding that he was likely to become a public charge.</p>

<p>In conclusion, we submit that the petitioner is
entitled to the three year statute of limitation granted him
by the special section of the statute, to-wit: Section 34, which
expressly covers the case; that having been here more than
three years, he is not subject to deportation upon any grounds
whatever, and that the warrant of deportation has been issued in
entire disregard of the petitioner's rights.</p>

<p>Respectfully submitted,</p>
<p>GATES &amp; HELSELL</p>

<p>-12-</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>