<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0150.004">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0150.004</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<ab>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, SS:</ab>

<ab>THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA,
To the Honorable the Judges of the District Court
of the United States for the District 
of Alaska, Second Division</ab>

<ab>GREETING:</ab>

<p>WHEREAS, lately in the District Court of the United 
States for the District of Alaska, Second Division
before you, or some of you, in a cause between the THE UNITED
STATES OF AMERICA, Plaintiff, and GEORGE HAWKINS, Defendant, a 
judgment was entered on the 22nd day of March, 1901, in favor of
the said plaintiff and against the said defendant, which said
judgment is of record in said cause in the office of the Clerk of
said District Court (to which record reference is hereby made 
and the same is hereby expressly made a part hereof)
as by the inspection of the transcript of the record
of the said District Court, which was brought into the United
States Circuit Court of Appeal for the Ninth Circuit by virtue
of a writ of error agreeably to the act of Congress in such
cases made and provided, fully and at large appears:</p>

<p>AND WHEREAS, on the 27th day of February in the year of 
our Lord one thousand, nine hundred and two, the said . cause 
came on to be heard before the said Circuit Court of Appeals,
on the said transcript of record and was argued by counsel:</p>

<p>ON CONSIDERATION WHEREOF, It is now hereby ordered and 
adjudged by this Court, that the judgment of the said District Court
in this cause be, and the same is hereby, reversed, and the cause
remanded for a new trial.</p>

<ab>(June 5th, 1902.)</ab>

<p>You, therefore, are hereby commanded that such further</p>

<pb/>

<p>Proceedings be had in said cause, in accordance with the opinion
and judgment of this court, and as according to right and justice
and the laws of the United States ought to be had, the said
judgment of said District Court notwithstanding.</p>

<p>WITNESS, the Honorable MELVILLE W. FULLER, Chief Justice 
of the United States, the 21st day of June, in the year of our
Lord one thousand, nine hundred and two.</p>


<ab>F. D. MONCKTON,
Clerk of the United States Circuit 
Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit</ab>

<ab>BY MEREDITH SAWYER
Deputy Clerk.</ab>

<p>Endorsed: 49 Crim. No.77. United States Circuit Court of Appeals
for the Ninth Circuit. George Hawkins vs. The United 
States. Mandate.
Filed in the Office of the Clerk of the U.S.Dist.
Court, Alaska, Second Division, at Nome, Alaska, Jul
31 1902 Geo. V. Berchsenius, Clerk, By H.C. Gordon
Deputy Clerk. Journal 2. Page 275.</p>

<pb/>






</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>