<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0187.022">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0187.022</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1914">1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-09">September 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Allen, Clay</term>
<term>Castner, B. P.</term>    
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Grayson, Marie Robina</term>
<term>Lakin, Edward M.</term>
<term>Lyen, J. L.</term>
<term>Merrick, Louis A.</term>
<term>Shakespeare, Noah</term>
<term>Stevenson, A. D.</term>
<term>White, Henry M.</term>

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Everett, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Marie Robina Grayson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Noah Shakespeare</persName>
<persName>Louis A. Merrick</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Clay Allen</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
    <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA. DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF 
WASHINGTON. NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the matter of the petition 
of Marie Robina Grayson, for 
a Writ of Habeas Corpus. 
PETITIONERS BOND ON APPEAL BY 
THE GOVERNMENT.
2780</p>

<p>KNOW ALL MEN BY THESE PRESENTS That  we Marie Robina Grayson, 
as principal, and J. L. Lyen and B. P. Castner, as sureties are held 
and firmly bound unto the United States of America, in the penal sum of 
$1000.00,for the payment whereof well and truly to be made in good and 
lawful money of the United States of America, we do bind ourselves,
and each of our heirs, executors, administrators and assigns jointly 
and severally firmly by these presents.</p>
<p>Sealed with our seals and dated this 24th day of August, 1914.</p>
<p>The condition of the above obligation is such that where heretofore
the above named principal, Marie Robina Grayson, duly filed her 
petition for the allowance of a Writ of Habeas Corpus, and thereupon
such Writ issued to Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration directed
and thereupon the said Henry M. White, made full return to said petition
whereupon a hearing upon the petition, return of the respondent and 
petitioners reply, to such return, was duly had in the above entitled
Court, and thereafter and on the 20th day of July, 1914, the above
entitled Court in the above cause did make and file its Order upon
such Writ of Habeas Corpus, discharging the above named principal, Marie
Robina Grayson and releasing her from the custody of the said Henry M. 
White, by whom theretofore she had been held, and thereafter the United
States did appeal from such Order and Judgment of this Court, in due 
form of law, to the United States Circuit Court of Appeals, for the 
Ninth Judicial Circuit, and this Court did make its order allowing 
such appeal, and directing that pending the said appeal and hearing, 
and determination thereof, the petitioner and principal Marie Robina 
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
Grayson should be enlarged upon executing a recognizance to the 
United States of America for her appearance to answer any Judgment in 
said matter given by the United States Circuit Court of Appeals for 
the Ninth Judicial Circuit.</p>
<p>NOW THEREFORE if the said Marie Robina Grayson shall appear,
answer to and abide and Judgment or Order made in said matter, by
the United States Circuit Court of Appeals for the Ninth Judicial 
Circuit, and shall render herself up in obedience to any Judgment or 
Order in said Circuit Court of Appeals in said matter, then this 
obligation to be null and void otherwise to be and remain of full force
and virtue.</p>
<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF We have hereunto set our hands and seals the 
day and year first above written.</p>

<ab>Mary Robina Grayson <lb/> 
J L Lyen <lb/>
B P Castern</ab>

<p>SIGNED SEALED AND DELIVERED 
IN THE PRESENCE OF</p>
<ab>A. D. Stevenson <lb/>
<unclear/>
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.SS.</ab>

<p>J.L. LYEN AND B. P. CASTNER first being duly 
sworn on their oaths do severally say, each for himself, and not one 
for the other, that they are the sureties named in and by whom the 
foregoing instrument was executed, that they are residents of the 
County of Snohomish, in the District aforesaid; that they are 
severally worth the sum of $1000.00named in the within bond, above their
just debts and liabilities, and exclusive of their property, exempt
from execution, in separate property; that they are free holders of 
and in District aforesaid, and citizens thereof; that they are 
neither an attorney, sheriff, clerk of any court, or other officer of 
any Court.</p>
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
<ab>J L Lyen <lb/>
A B Castner</ab>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 24th day of August, 1914.</p>
<ab>Noah Shakespeare <lb/>
Notary Public, Washington, residing at 
Everett.</ab>

<p><del>Ok Allen
US Atty</del></p>

<p>O.K. 
Allen
US Atty.</p>

<p>S &amp; Sworn Sept 2 1914</p>
<ab>Jeremiah Neterer <lb/>
Judge</ab>
<pb/>
<p>2780
2x</p>
<p>UNITED STATES OF 
AMERICA
DISTRICT COURT 
FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF 
WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>In Re. PETITION OF MARIE 
ROBINA GRAYSON FOR A WRIT OF 
HABEAS CORPUS
<del>Bankrupt</del></p>

<p>B S I 9 - 4 - <del>286</del> <add>286</add></p>

<p>PETITIONERS BOND ON APPEAL 
BY THE GOVERNMENT.</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. District Court, 
Western Dist. of Washington, 
NORTHERN DIVISION
SEP 2 - 1914</p>
<ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk, 
By EML Deputy</ab>

<p><add>NOAH SHAKESPEARE AND</add>
LOUIS A. MERRICK
Attorney for PETITIONER.
Everett, Washington</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>