<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.269.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title> In Re: Ex Parte - Turner Jackson Petitioner For A Writ of Habeas Corpus </title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Banse, AD" xml:id="ab">AD Banse</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.269.001</idno>
<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">  In Re: Ex Parte - Turner Jackson Petitioner For A Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="2022-06-07"></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington </repository>
<collection> RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle </collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName> Turner Jackson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName> C.B. Hopkins</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>C.H. Hanford</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> 
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>  

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs ="hc.case.wa.269.001"/>

<!-- <p>Reproduced at the National Archives at Seattle </p>-->



<p> No. 1325  </p> 
<p>In the   Circuit Court of the United States for Dirstrict of Washington Ninth Judicial Circuit Northern Division   </p>
<p>In  re. Ex Parte Turner Jackson vs. Petitioner. Assignment of Errors .</p>
<p>  Filled Sept 12, 1905 A Reeves, Ayres, Clerk. By A.N Moody, Deputy </p>


<pb/>

<p>  In The United States Ciruit Court, For the Ninth Juidicial Circuit, Western Division of the State of Washington, Northern Division.</p>


<p> In  re. Ex Parte Turner Jackson, Petitioner for Writ of Habeas Corpus, Charles B. Hopkins , U.S . Marshal, respondent.   Opinion, Filed Sept. 14, 1905. </p>


<p> Application by a United States prisoner for discharge by writ of Habeas Corpus, under the provisions of the not of Congress, entitled, " An <unclear> sot?</unclear> to regulate commitation for good conduct for United States prisoners." Approved June 21, 1902. 32 U.S. States, 397, State. 397; U.S. compiled statutes, 1901 supplement 446. Hearing on the petition, writ and return. Petition granted . </p>
<p>  Wm. H. Brinker, Richard Saxe Jones, J.B. Netcalfe.  For Petitioner.</p>
<p>  Jesse A Frye, U.S. District Attorney, For Respondent. </p>
<p> Hanford, District Judge: - The petitioner was brought from Alaska to the U.S. penitentiary, on McNeil's Island, and has been incarcerated there, on punishment for a crime of which he was convicted in the District Court of Alaska. The term of imprisonment fixed by the sentence of the court in ten years, and it is the petitioner's contention that he is entitled to credit for goof behavior to the extent of ten days for each month commencing on the first day of his arrival at the Penitentiary, as provided by an sot of Congress entitled, " An not to regulate commitation for good conduct for United States prisoners." Approved June 21, 1905, SE U.S. States P. 397 ; U.S. compiled Statutes, 1901, Sup, 440. The first section of said statute is clear, and not hard to understand. it provides " that each prisoner whom has ben or shall hereafter be convicted of any offence against the law of the United States,  XXXX whose reocrd of conduct shows that he has faithfully observed all the rules and has not been subjected to punishment, shall be entitled to a deduction from the term of his sentence to be estimated as follows, commencing on the first day of his arrival at the penitentiary, prsion, or jail,  xxxx upon a sentence of ten years or more, ten days for each month." it is a conceded fact that the petitioner's conduct as a prisoner has been good, and that he has earned all of the deduction on accoun tof good behavior which the laws of the United States allow to prisoners.  </p>
<p>  The respondent under a sense of duty reisists the petitioner's demand to be discharged from custody, on the grounds that the sentence in his case had been passed prior to the enactment of the statute above quoted, and therefore said statute is not applicable to his case, adn that under provisions of sections 6643-4 U.S.R.S, Compiled Statutes, 1901, pp. 3721-3722-3727, in force when the petitioner was convicted and sentenced, he is entitled to be credited on account of good conduct five  days for each month, and that the law does not allow any greater reduction in his favor. This contention is based upon the third section of the sot of Congress of 1902, which reads as follows: " That this sot shall take effect and be in force from and after thirty days from the date of its approval, and shall apply only to sentences imposed by courts subsequent to the time that this sot takes effect, as herein before provided. Prisoners serving under any sentence imposed prior to much time shall be entitled and receive the commutation heretobefore allowed under exing laws. Such existing laws are hereby respected on to all sentences imposed subsequent to the time when this sot takes effect.  </p>
<p> There is an irreconcillable conflict between the provision of the first and thrid sections, for, as already stated, in the first section is clear and its meaning unmistakable. The rule which gives for computation of time for good behavior is applicable to the cases of prisoners perviously convicted as well as those who afterwards shall be convicted, adn that the third section is equally explicit, in providing that the sot shall take effect and be in force from and after a future date, and that it shall apply only to sentences imposed subsequent to that date. Therefore, the right of petitioner to be discharged depends upon the determination of the question whether paramount effect shall be given to the first section or to the last section of the statute. The antogonism of the two sections is emphasized by the divergence in the opinions of the courts which have had occasion to continue the law. In the Watlers case, 128 Fed. Rep. 791, Judge Thomas, without discussing the question, held that the sot does not affect persons sentenced before its enactment. In Ferrar case, 133 Fed. Rep. 254, Judge Sheeler said: " If the first section did not expressly apply to each prisoner who has been convicted as well as to the those who should be, the third section did not expressly provide that the sot should only apply to subsequent sentences, he should be left within the first section."  </p>

<p> And then the learned judge proceeded to eliminate the antagonism of the two sections by serving the first and restricting the third as if it were a mere adjunct of the second section. The result of his decision, if soundm is to divide the statute into two parts, leaving the first section to stand by itself, as it it were a seperate and independent enactment, and the second and third sections constituting a detached and complete law</p>

<p> In view of the patent ambiguity of the statute said iteh conflicting opinions in regard to it, it in necessary to refer to the congressional record ro ascertain the purpose of Congress in enactign the law, and give effect to the legislative intent. I find that the Comittee on Judiciary of the House of Representatives made a report recommending the enactment of this law, saying : " Your committee believes that the legislation propsoed by the bill is useful and necessary." The committee also submitted as a part of its report the following letter written by the Attorney General: "Department of Justice, Washington, D.C. May 12, 1902."   </p>

<p>"Sir: Under the  present prostice with regard to the commutation for good conduct allowed United States prisoner, there is no uniformity whatever, and experience has shown the necessity for some modification of the statutes governing this subject. United States convicts confined in United States prisons, sas  each month of the term, without regard to its length. If confined in a state institution, however, which has a commutation system of its own, they are subject to the terms of that system. It thus happens that one class of United States convicts can earn but sixty days a year, even if the sentence is for ten years, while others, elsewhere confine, earn a much larger reduction.    </p> 


<p> In order to the correct this evil, and to place all United States prisoners on an equal footing in this respect, I will submit herewith draft of a bill for an act regulating commutation for good conduct in the case of United States prisoners. The table used has been compiled from the laws governing this matter in the state of Massachusetts, and is believed to be just and equitable. In the administration of the laws as they are at present a great deal of discontent and dissatisfaction is caused among United States prisoners, especially when transferred from a state institution, where liberal commutations are allowed, to a United States prison where they can be given but five days in each month, no matter how long their terms of sentence may be. It is hoped there will be no objection to the passage of the bill, as the necessity for the legislation is believed to be urgent. PC.C Knox, Attorney General.  </p>
<p> Hon. George W. Ray. Chairman Judiciairy Commitee, House of Representativcs."</p>

<p> From the foregoing it is apparent that Congress was prompted to enact this law by the recommendation of the Attorney General; that the evil intented to be remedied by the enactment was inequality in the time which  United States prionsers could eran by good behavior under the provisions of provicus laws, and that the object of the law was to prescibe a uniform rule. If convicts under sentence at the time when the sot became effective are denied its benefts, the evil intended to be remedied must continue until convicts previously sentenced for long terms who are imprisoned in United States penitentiaries and jails, and all those confined in state prisons in which the time allowance is less liberal than the rule described by this article, shall have discharged, and the object of the law cannot be accomplished for many years. For this reason it is in my opinion that the true intent of the legislative mind in the enactment of this law is expressed in the first section, and that the words of the third section limiting the application of the law to subsequent sentences are to be deemed, as an inadvertent expression, inconsistent with the object of the law. </p>
<p> The rule of construction which deems the latent expression of the legislative will in a statute as a repeal of all inconsistent laws previously laws previosuly enacted cannot be spilled in this instance for two reasons, viz: First: The limitation in the third section is inconsistent with the object of the law, because it  continues for an indefinite time inequality, which is the evil intened to be remedied. Second: There was in fact no difference in time  in the enactment of the first and third sections, the bill was not considered and voted upon section by section but was recomended in the report of the committee avobve referred to was adopted by the House of Representatives by unanimous consent, and then the bill as amended was passed to the House without debate, without opposition, and without a roll call, and it was afterwards gulped by the Senate without mastication; that is to say, it was passed as whole by unanimous consent, without a roll call, and immediately returned to the House without amendment, See Congressional Record, Volume 35.pp.  61347447.7453.    </p>

<p>  It is worthy of mention that immediately after the bill had been passed by unamimous consent in the Senate, Senator Hoar made the following extraordinary statement: </p>
<p>" With the leave of the Senator from California I should like to make one statement about the bill which has just been passed. I received a great many communications from different parts of the country saying that it ought to apply to cases of prisoners sentenced heretofore, and undoubtedly that would be quite desriable, bu there was verfy serious doubt in the minds of members of the committee of hte constitutional power of Congress to pass a bill of that sort which should apply to sentences heretofore imposed. Therefore the committee thought it unwise to include such a provision." </p>


<p> No person would seriously suggest the idea that prisoners have vested rights, to suffer punishment, which may not be abridged by the shortening of terms of imprisonment, without violating national constitution; and if a law abbreviating terms of imprisonment may be regarded as an infringment of the power to grant pardons, pertaining to the executive branch of the government, an objection on that ground would apply an well  to any statue affecting future convictions as to a law applicable to cases in which sentences had been previous to the enactment of the lae, the above quote remark must have been one of the pleasantries for which facetious Senator from Massachusetts was noted. At any rate, as the remark was not made until after the bill had been passed, it affords no grounds for supporting that either the Senate or House of Representatives intended that the first section should be understood otherwise than according to the sense of the words used in this  construction. </p>

<p> For the reasons above set forth, I direct that an order be entered granting the petition, and that the prisoner be discharged. C.H. Hanford, Judge. </p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>