<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>State of Missouri</p>

<p>To the Honorable the St Louis 
Law Commussioners <del>Criminal</del> Court of St. Louis</p>

<p>The petition of George Washington 
Kirk respectfully represents</p>

<p>That he is a free man of color, domiciled and 
residing in the state of Ohio, and has been free 
for the space of sixteen years, having with his father 
and his family been manumitted in Hamilton 
County State of Ohio on the 13th day of February AD 
1840, by his owner Exum Louis of Hind County 
in the State of Mississippi, as will appear by a certi-
fied copy of the record of manumission from the 
Superior Court of Cincinnati in the State of Ohio 
which is filed herewith.</p>

<p>He also filed herewith to prove his identity and 
that is and has been free, the affidavits of Casey 
Kirk, his father, of J.S. Engert, R.F. Engert, 
Henry F. <unclear>Tector</unclear> and James Richardson, good and 
lawful men residing in said City of Cincinnati</p>

<p>Your petitioner represents that he is confined 
in the common jail of St Louis County by James 
A Felps the keeper thereof, under authority 
he is informed of Thumer Maddox former Sher-
iff of said County of St Louis who committed him 
to said jail as a runaway slave and as your 
petitioner is informed has advertised that he will sell 
your petitioner as a runaway slave. He has asked and 
been refused a copy of his commitment</p>

<p>Your petitioner alleges that his imprisonment is 
illegal in this that your petitioner is a free man and 
not a slave, and that no person claimes him as 
owner by right or by law.</p>

<p>The Judge of the Criminal Court is now absent 
from this County as he is informed</p>

<p>And your petitioners will ever pray &amp;c</p>

<p>George Washington Kirk</p>
<p>By Whittelsey Atty</p>

<p>County of St Louis }</p>
<p>George Washington Kirk being 
sworn upon his oath says that the facts in the 
above petition stated are true</p>
<p>Geo his Washinton Kirk</p>
<p>X mark</p>

<p>Sworn to and subscribed 
before me Aug. 11 1856</p>


<p>Charle C Whittelsey attones for petitioner &amp; also 
in addition that no other application <del>has been</del> 
for the relief sought has been made to and refused 
by any other court or officer superior to this 
court</p>

<p>Cha C Whittelsey</p>



<p>In re 
Geo Washington Kirk</p>

<p>Petition for Habeas 
Corpus</p>

<p>Filed Aug 11th 1856</p>
<p>M <unclear></unclear></p>
<p><unclear></unclear></p>




