<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0224.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Lewis Johnson v. Defendant. Witness Testimony, Robert Tate.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0224.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Lewis Johnson v. Defendant. Witness Testimony, Robert Tate.</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-06">June 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Robert Tate</term> 
<term>J.K. Kennedy</term> 
<term>Lewis Johnston</term> 
<term>Curly</term> 
<term>Garnett</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>United States of America</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Lewis Johnson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-02" who="#AS">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>ROBERT TATE
821 Campbell Ave. 
called as a witness, being first
sworn, testified as follows:</p> 
<p>QUESTIONS by MR KENNEDY:</p> 
<p>50 Q. What is your occupation? A Porter and waiter.</p> 
<p>51 Q. Do you know Lewis Johnston? A Yes sir</p> 
<p>52 Q. How long have you known him? A. A little over a year</p> 
<p>53 Q. Do you remember the 4th of June? A. I really don't know
the date, but I remember Friday, Saturday morning. I paid no
attention to the date.</p> 
<p>54 Q. How many Saturdays ago? A. Pardon me, just a minute. I
paid no attention to the date.</p>
<p>55 Q. But how many weeks ago? Would you know how many Saturdays
have intervened since then? A. The Saturday before last.</p> 
<p>56 Q. That would be the 5th. Did you see Johnston on that date
A. He came to the house where I live between four and five in
the morning</p> 
<p>57 Q. Where do you live? A. 821 Campbell Avenue</p> 
<p>58 Q. And alone? A. Yes sir I room a lone but there are other
people in the house.</p> 
<p>59 Q. Now I want you to tell us in your own words, please, with
out any prompting what conversation you had with Johnston
in connection with this charge? A. He came to the house 
between 4 and 5 in the morning - I didn't notice the time 
so much either - but he came there really early in the morning
and knocked at the back door, and the lady of the house opened
the door and he asked her for "Bob"</p> 
<p>60 Q. You are "Bob", eh? A. Yes. He said "I want to see him on 
some very important business" So she opened the door and he came
in, and he was in the kitchen when I came down, and she called
to me that Mr Johnston wanted to see me on some very important
business; and I went out there and he had a bottle of Gin and
several packages of cigarettes; and he said he came to give
me the time of my life, that he was going to the States; and
I sat down and had a drink; and he said he had come into some
money.
<pb></pb> 
We sat there and drank awhile and he said "Bob will 
you go down-town today and get my shoes fixed and buy me some 
underwear" and I said "yes"; and he said "I will go and
catch Garnet before he goes to bed. I have get to get some 
money" he said "I wll have to go now because he is up at the
club all night" and he said "will you come with me" and I said 
"yes" so we left the house and went over to the Eagle Rooms
on Keefer Street, and he telephoned from there; and when 
he gets back to the telephone he finds he hasn't any nickel,
and he comes and calls me and I gave him a nickel.</p>  
<p>61. Q. To use for the telephone? A. Yes and I heard him say "bring
me a hundred dollars" so when he comes out he said "By George" 
he said "I ought to have asked for $130. He has got three
small ten dollar bills too" He come out and goes down towards
Garnett's club; being early in the morning the front door is
closed, and he went round the back way. I went round the
front on the corner of Gore and Keefer, and took a notion
to steal down that way, and as I did I saw him and Garnett
come from the back of the club to the barber's shop and
Garnett kneeled down in front of the safe and opened it
and handed Johnston something.</p> 
<p>62. Q. Something in the nature of bills, A. I don't know; he went 
in there and handed him something, and he came out, and met me
on Gore Avenue; and as we walked up Harris street he shewed
me two new fifty dollar bills of the Bank of Commerce. I 
remember looking at the numbers and saying"those are new
bills." 0156 something</p> 
<p>63. Q. And some other numbers? A. Yes those were the first numbers
0156 something, because I remember repeating the numbers; and 
then I said to him "new money, whe did you get that money
Johnston?" and he said "do you know I was in the Government 
service in the United States Army?" and I said "yes" and he
said "this is the service money from the Phillipine Islands" and
I have plenty more" and I said "alright"; and he goes back
<pb></pb> 
out to the house and starts drinking gin again; and by this 
time he produced a blue paper and said there was five dollar's 
worth of cocaine in it, and he started using this cocaine. 
Well he told several different stories, but never anything 
about stealing the money; about the Phillipines and service; 
and using that cocaine.</p> 
<p>64. Q. What other story did he tell except that he got it at the
Phillipines? A. I haven't got to that. So we just thought 
that was cocaine illusion and didn't pay any attention to it. 
We kind of just laughed at everything he said</p> 
<p>65. Q. Who is "we" A. The lady of the house. So in the meantime 
Sunday, that was Saturday, Saturday I goes out, I guess up 
town, he asked me to get him some underwear and get his shoes 
soled and heeled, and he hands me a fifty dollar bill; and I 
went up and got two suits of underwear and got his shoes 
fixed and came back to the house and gave him his change.
I started up-town again for something for myself, and he
said "by the way I want a Jaeger shirt. Will you get it for
me?" And I said "yes" and he gave me the other fifty dollar
bill. I said you have got change in your pocket John, why
don't you give me that change?" and he said "I am going to
the States and since this War is on these large bills are 
hard to change." So I took the bill and bought him a Jaeger
shirt; and I went back to the house and gave him the change.
And so he kept on drinking all that evening, and he goes up
town and came back along early Sunday morning; and he had been
drinking pretty hard; he said he had been to a dance or some-
thing and given everybody a good time.And this was the time
he commenced telling us about stealing the money. He was
drinking pretty hard and still using the cocaine which was
pretty nearly all gone, and I got after him about stealing the
money</p>  
<p>66 Q. He mentioned about stealing the money? A. No we asked him 
about where he got it; and the lady and I talked about it, 
we said "it looks suspicious this fellow spending a hundred 
<pb></pb> 
dollars so freely" and I took up a newspaper and I said "does 
he act as if he killed anybody?"</p> 
<p>67. Q. Who did you say that to? A. The lady of the house: She
said "I don't think so; he seems nervous about something, but
the chances are it is the dope he is using" and I took up a 
paper and said "man found with his head smashed in" What do 
you think of that" and looked at him, and he didn't shew any
signs of nervousness. And I looked at her and I laid the paper 
down and paid no attention to it; and I said "he hasn't killed
anybody because he couldn't be that calm about it" Then he
sat down and told us that he had gone into the Main Hotel
back to urinate and eeen a man lying there with his feet in
the water, seemingly drunk</p> 
<p>68. Q. Lying in the water? A. His feet were in the water of the
Urinal, and he reached down and struck his right-hand pocket 
and felt a purse in there. He put his life hands under his arms 
and as he done so he struck the purse in his pocket; and he
said he had five cents in his pocket, and walked out to the bar
and got a glass of beer.</p> 
<p>69. Q. Who had five cents? A. Johnston. And he went up to room 29
of the Lyle Rooms and hid the money in there, and he looked
and saw there were fifty dollar bills, and there was a little 
noise in the hall, and he started to throw the purse out of 
the window, but as the noise passed he looked again and saw 
a hundred dollar bill, and he looked and saw another one and
he counted seventeen one hundred dollar bills, two fifties
and three ten dollar bils I said you "you have told many a
story about that Johnston; the next thing you know you will
be killing some "ermans" He said that will be alright. 
I have got the money anyway" He said "I went and got Garnett
and told him I wanted him to do me a little favor, that I 
had made a little money and that I would give him seventyfive
or a hundred dollars if he could get it changed up into gold
for me. I don't want anything but gold." I didn't pay much 
attention. I didn't believe what he was saying. I knew some-
<pb></pb>
thing was wrong somewhere but I didn't know what it was, and
didn't believe what he was saying. That was after dinner
Sunday afternoon. So he goes out again Sunday evening; and 
in the morning he comes in - that is when he handed us a 
drink. I was sitting on the side of the bed and he had a 
bottle with about that much whiskey in it; and he gave us all
some, and I don't remember seeing Johnston any more till I
saw him over in Seattle.</p> 
<p>70 Q. How did you come to meet him in Seattle? A. I met him in 
a saloon.</p> 
<p>71 Q. Where? A. On the corner of King and 16th</p> 
<p>72 Q. That is in Seattle? A. Yes</p> 
<p>73 Q. How did you come tobe over there? A. I went over with the 
officers to locate him.</p> 
<p>74 Q. Had you known Johnston for some time before that? A. John-
ston about a year and a half</p> 
<p>75 Q. Did you ever know him to do anything, or have any money? 
A. No sir</p> 
<p>76 Q. Well did you know him not to do anything? That is did you
know he didn't work? A. I don't know anything he done. I 
don't know of any work he did.</p> 
<p>77 Q. Do you know if he had any money or not? A. He never had
any. He had stayed at the house the biggest part of the 
Winter with me and didn't pay any board or room.</p> 
<p>78 Q. At your place. A. Yes rooming with me</p> 
<p>79  Q. What reason did he give for not paying any board or room
A. He didn't have any money</p> 
<p>80 Q. That is what made you suspicious I presume in the first 
place when he came into all this money? A. Yes</p> 
<p>81 Q. Had he ever told you anything before about being in the
Phillipines or soldiering of any kind? A. Oh he told of 
several people he killed in the line of duty</p> 
<p>82 Q. Hadn't told you of any sum of money that was coming to
him? A. No</p> 
<p>83 Q. Did you happen to ask him what happened to all the rest of 
<pb></pb>
the money. All you had seen, you remember, was two fifty 
dollar bills. Allo told me that Garnett had it when I asked 
him about it. I asked him where it ws, and he said
"Garnett has it and will have changed it for me"</p>
<p>84 Q. Did Johnston say anything about being satisfied with
Garnett at all? A. He sent me out - he asked if I knew a
truthful man, and I said "I don't know of anybody but a 
messenger boy"; and he said "I will give him five dollars" - 
he was in the shoe-shop at this time</p>
<p>85 Q. Johnston was where - in the shoe-shop? A. Yes. He said 
he would give a man five dollar if he would find out if
Garnett was in a house on Alexander street, and if he was
to trail him until that afternoon and if he went near a 
train or boat just to get into a taxi and go immediately
and let him know.</p> 
<p>86 Q. When was it Johnstone told you that? A. That was 
between the....</p> 
<p>87 Q. Was that Saturday or Sunday? A. Saturday</p> 
<p>88 Q. What is his name? A. Curly. That is the only name
I know him by, down at that Home Messenger Office. I left 
out a part about Garnett. I sent for Garnett after I seen
it in the paper on Monday Night. That is when I believed 
that he stole this money when I saw in the paper about that
eighteen hundred dollars in the Main Hotel, on Monday
night</p> 
<p>90 Q. Of course Johnston had gone then? A. Yes</p> 
<p>91 Q. Do you know what happened to the pocket-book? A. He tore
it up</p> 
<p>92 Q. Who said so? A. Johnston said so, I asked him what he
done with it. I said there might have been valuable papers
in that pocket-book, that might be worth a thousand dollars
to a man, and he said "I tore it and threw it away"</p>  
<p>93 Q. Did he describe the pocket-book at all to you? NO sir</p>
<p>94 Q. I will show you a photograph which I shall put in as Exhibit
<pb></pb> 
"A" Do you recognise that photograph? A. That is Johnston</p> 
<p>95. Q. This is a photography of Lewis Johnston? A. Yes</p> 
<p>PHOTOGRAPH produced as Exhibit "A" </p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>