<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0222.009">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Francis Stephen Medcraf vs. Frank T. Hodge. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0222.009</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Francis Stephen Medcraf vs. Frank T. Hodge. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-09">September 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>










</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>San Francisco</term>    
<term>Canada</term>
<term>England</term>
<term>France</term>
<term>Greece</term>
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
<term>Texas</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>

</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Francis Stephen Medcraf</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Frank T. Hodge</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>George D. Emery</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-04" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON - 
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN RE. APPLICATION OF 
FRANCIS STEPHEN MEDCRAF 
FOR WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>
<p>3038
BRIEF FOR PETITIONER.</p>

<p>THE PETITIONER was convicted before REAH M. WHITEHEAD, a 
Justice of the Peace, of the crime of 'practicing dentistry' without
having a license so to do . Having been committed on such conviction
to the county jail, petitioner sues out the Writ, alleging that he
is restrained of his liberty, his property destroyed, and he is 
denied the equal protection of the laws, in violation of the Federal 
Constitution.</p>
<p>ARTICLE XIV. Sec. 1. CONSTITUTION OF U. S. (Amendments)</p>
<p>"- nor shall any state deprive any person of life, liberty
or property, without due process of law, nor deny to any 
person within its jurisdiction the equal protectino of the 
laws."</p>
<p>ARTICLE V. do do do</p>
<p>"No person - - - -shall be deprived of life, liberty or
property without due process of law."</p>
<p>ARTICLE 1. Sec. 12. CONSTITUTION OF WASHINGTON.</p>
<p>"No law shall be passed granting to any citizen, class of
citizens or corporation, other than municipal, privileges or 
immunities which, upon the swme terms, shall not belong 
equally to all citizens or corporations."</p>
<p>ARTICLE 1. Sec. 7. CONSTITUTION OF WASHINGTON.</p>
<p>"No person shall be disturbed in his private affairs, or his 
home invaded, without authority of law."</p>
<p>ARTICLE 1. Sec. 3. CONSTITUTION OF WASHINGTON.</p>
<p>"No person shall deprived of life, liberty or property
without due process of law."</p>
<p>The Gen. Laws of Washington for 1893 enacted a code which all
practioners of dentistry within the state should become licensed</p>
<p>This superseded the former enactments of 1888, and is Chap. LV
of the Laws of 1893. It provided for the examination by a competent 
Board to be appointed by the Governor, of all who desired to 
<pb/>
practice Dentistry. As a pre-requisite to such examination the 
applicant was required to present to the Board his or her diploma from 
some dental college in good standing and give satisfactory evidence
of his or her rightful possession of the same "Provided; That the
Board may admit to such examination such other persons of good moral
character
as shall give satisfactory evidence of having been 
engaged in the practice of dentistry ten years prior to the date of 
such examination."</p>
<p>A standard for such examinatino was provided and all persons 
satisfactory passing same were to be licensed.</p>
<p>The certificate or license was required to be recorded in the
County Auditors Office in each county where the license practiced.</p>

<p>This Act was amended and a substitute enacted in and by CHAP.
CLll of the Laws of 1901. (p 314-7)</p>
<p>"Sec. 4. Any person or person seeking to practice Dentistry in 
the State of Washington, or to own, operate or cause to be operated, 
or to run or manage a dental office or place for the practice of this Act 
shall file his or her name, together with an application for 
examination, with the Secretary of the State Board od Dental Examiners
and at the time of making such application shall pay to the 
Secretary of the Board a fee of $25.00, and to present him or herself
at the first regular meeting thereafter of said board to undergo
examination before that body. No person shall be eligible for such 
examination unless he or shee shall be of good moral character and
shall be present to said Board his or her diploma from some dental 
College in good standing and shall give satisfactory evidence of his
or her rightful possession of the saem; PROVIDED, This section 
shall not apply to persons engaged in the practice of dentistry 
at the time of the passage of this act who are bona fide citizens of 
the State of Washington. "</p>
<p>Provision is made for the issue of license to persons passing
such examination and for recording same and the practice of dentistry
without such license being duly issued and of record is made a 
misdemeanor punishable by fine of not less than $50. nor more than
$200.00 or by imprisonment in the County Jail for six months.</p>

<p>It appears that the Board of Dental Examiners employed one
Conover to go to petitioner's office and solicit him to perform some 
operation of dentistry upon him, in order that complaint might be made 
<pb/>
by Conover of such violation of the statute. This was done. On
such a complaint the warrant issued. Petitioner upon his trial 
before the Justice duly raised all the constitutional questions
set forth in his petition and they were overruled and his convistion
and sentence followed, Upon being committed under such sentence he 
sues out this Writ.</p>
<p>It appeared upon the trial and is shown by the petition 
that the petitioner served 5 years as an apprentice to a competent
and reputable dentist in London. that he has continuously practised
dentistry, in the employ of competent dentists for 8 years thereafter
and on his own account for 14 1/2 years since, in England, France,
Greece, Canada and for the past 7 1/2 years in the United States in
this city. That he has duly applied to the said Board for examination
and offerred to pay the fee required but because he had never 
attended any Dental College and could not produce a diploma from such 
College, he was refused any such examination and license.</p>

<p>It is insisted that the Dental Act of 1901 is void as being in 
conflict with both the Federal and State constitutions;</p>

<p>ARGUMENT.</p>
<p>THE POWER OF POLICE REGULATION of the practice of dentistry by the
State is not questioned, but this Act far transcends the powers of
the State in that particular. It is unreasonable; an unnecesaary 
restriction of and infringment upon the rigths of the individual; 
deprives him of his property unnecessarily and is violative of his 
constitutional rights. It constitutes unlawful discrimination.</p>
<p>The object of the law is the protection of the health and safety
of the public.</p>
<p>To this end, the qualifications of those who assume to practice
Dentistry are material and of importance. Reasonable tests and 
regulations to secure this and are lawful and if such interfere with 
the right to practice, they are still valid. But when they go beyond 
the line of reason and are no longer necessary nor regulative of the 
right to practice but unduly restrict that right in the individual,
<pb/>
they become in conflict with teh <del>Constitutional</del> <add>quotes</add> provisions of
the Federal Constitution and must fall.</p>
<p>If the applicant for examination is of good moral character and
has the knowledge and qualifing ability to practice dentistry, of 
what benefit is it to the public that he has or has not a diploma
from some dental college? How does the possession of such a paper 
protect the public, if the holder must pass the examination for the 
actual qualifying knowledge and ability? Why should the citizen wh o 
has come up the long road of practical experience, beginning with 
a 5-year apprentice ship and 22 1/2 years of actual and active 
practice, widely diversified and enriched with wide experience, and
who has constantly studied and kept apace with the best skill of the
day; why should  he be precluded from taking the examination test
while the boy or girl of no practical experience who holds the diploma
may enjoy that privalege?</p>
<p>It is an unfair and unnecessary restriction upon the right of every 
man to follow his profession for his livelihood.</p>
<p>True the Supreme Court of Washington has held that the provision
requiring the diploma is a reasonable. But such is not the 
opinion of the courts before whom such a question has come and is not
supported by any satisfactory reasoning. It is in no way binding 
upon the Federal Court nor any weight in construing the effect of 
the Federal Constitution upon the act in question. It is the 
peculiar province of the Federal Courts to interpret the Federal 
Constitution and in so doing they are not bound, even in conscience, by 
the opinions of the State courts.</p>

<p>Such a law (in effect) was before the Supreme Court of Hew Hamp.
and a conclusion quite opposite to that of the State of Washington
was reached.</p>
<p>STATE OF NEW HAMPSHIRE VS. PENNOYER 5 L. R. A. 709.</p>
    <p>The act there in question provided for the issue of 
    licenses to practice medicine to those who should ;</p>
    <p>either pass a satisfactory examination, or
<pb/>    
    present a diploma from some medical school etc.,</p>
<p>Those passing examination to pay a fee of $5.00 and those presenting
a diploma to pay $1.00 for the license.</p>
<p>Practice without being so licensed was made a misdemeanor and
punished by fine of $300 or less etc.</p>
    <p>"The provisions of the preceeding section (penal) shall not
    apply to persons who have resided and practiced their profession
    in the town or city of their present residence during all the
    time since January 1st, 1875, - - - "</p>
<p>This law too k effect in January 1879.</p>
<p>Parallel requirements.</p>
<p>Washington Act.</p>
<p>Persons who are engaged in the 
practice of dentistry at the 
time of the passage of this act
who are bona fide citizens of 
the State of Washington, are 
exempt from the penalties of the
act.</p>
<p>New Hampshire Act.</p>
<p>All physicians except those who 
practiced all the time between Jany. 1st,
1875 and Jany. 1st, 1879, and during 
that period did not remove from one 
town to another, are required to obtain
a license and pay therefore $5.00 or 
$1.00 according as it may be issued 
upon examination or upon diploma.</p>

<p>The Court said;</p>
    <p>"The law cannot discriminate in favor of one citizen to the
    detriment of another. The principle of equality pervades the entire
    Constitution. The Bill of Rights declares expressly that all
    government is 'instituted for the general good,' for the common 
    benefit, protection and security of the whole community, and not for 
    the private interests, or emolument of any one man, family, or class
    of men; that "every member of the community has a right to be 
    protected by it in the enjoyment of his life, liberty and property."</p>
    <p>"No one <add>citizen or</add> class of citizens can by law be charged with the
    performance of duties or be subjected to burdens not by law made 
    incumbent upon all other citizens in the same circumstances."</p>
        <p>Missouri vs Lewis 101 U.S. 22; 25 L. 989</p>
        <p>Barbier vs Connolly 113 U.S. 31: 28 L. 925</p>
        <p>Yick Wo. vs Hopkins 118 U.S. 356; 30 L. 220</p>
<p>The objection is that, "of those physicians who are declared
    by Statute, or under its provisions, are found, qualified to practice
    some are and others are not subjected to the burden of obtaining a 
    license. Exemptions from the burden is made to depend not on 
    integrity, education and medical skill, but upon a continuous dwelling
    in one place for (at) a certain time. It is an arbitrary 
    discrimination permitting some and forbidding others to carry on 
    their business without regard to their competency or to any material
    difference in their situation. The test is not merit but unchanged
    residence. For the right to continue the pursuit of his profession
    one physician is not, while another, his neighbor, whomay be his
    equal or superior in learning, experience and ability,is, 
    required to pay $5.00 . This is not the equality of the Constitution.</p>
    <p>The magnitude of the unequal burden is immaterial. If any inequality is
    permitted the discrimination might be made prohibitory, and a 
    monopoly of the busines given to the physicians who have resided
<pb/>
    in a town or city for a specified time."</p>
        <p>Citing State vs Express Co. 60 N. H. 219</p>
        <p>Mc Culloch vs Maryland 17 U. S. 4; 4 L.579
        606-7.</p>
<p><add>In <unclear/> - State v Hinman 18.Att. 194.</add></p>
<p>Note that under the present law, a man may be a bona fide citizen
of this State at the time of the passage of the Act and yet be 
practicing dentistry in some other state, and if such be true, he may 
practice here without either examination or license.</p>
<p>If he is a bona fide citizen of this state and is practicing here, 
he needs neither examination or license, according to this act.</p>
<p>It is no less an unconstitutional distinction to make the right
to examination depend entirely upon the applicant having a diploma
from some dental college. He must, under the act, possess such d
diploma to entitle him to be examined for license. His real
qualificaitons, obtained by long practice in this or any or other state or 
country, count for nothing. He may be the best dentist in the world
and yet, if he has not passed through a dental college, he cannot 
take the examination and, unless he resided and practiced here at 
the time of the passage of the act (or resided here and practiced else 
where) he cannot obtain a license.</p>
<p>The right to license is thus made to depend, not on actual
merit but upon the possession of a diploma or residence.</p>
<p>The right of the person to practice his profession is 
interfered with, not for the public benefit, nor by reasonable means, but 
for the benefit of the Dental practitioners who may be fortunate enoug
to have their diploma or to reside here at the time. Such is not a 
fair or reasonable requirement not is it the 'equality' which the
Constitution required.</p>
<p>Sec. 1977 Comp. Laws of U. S. guarantees equal rights under the 
law to all "persons" within the jurisdiction of the United Staets
and under the laws of every State. Such "persons" shall have the 
right "in every state and territory - - - to the full and equal 
benefit of all laws and proceedings for the security of persons and
property - - -"</p>
<p>The citizenship of the "person" is therefore of no consideration.</p>
<pb/>
<p>The Supreme Court of Washington has held a portion of this act to be
unconstitutional, and avoided so destroying the remainder only by a 
very forced construction of its provisions.</p>
<p>In STATE VS BROWN 37 Wash. 105. the Court says;</p>
    <p>"We feel that a court should be reluctant to pronounce 
    a statute invalid, except where its plain duty impels such action.
    Conceiving this to be such a case, we are led to declare that part 
    of the statute requiring an examination and license in order to 
    'own, run or manage' a dental office or department, void."</p>
<p>In the very same case the court cites abundant authority to 
sustain our contention here, saying; "The police power does not 
justify the withholding from one individual of a natural privilege
or right, in order that a corresponding advantage may be added to 
the rights or privileges of another. The restriction is permissible
only as a preventive of evil results reasonably to be expected 
without such limitation. Russell on Police Power pp 34.35 says; "To 
justify the State in thus interposing its authority, in behalf of 
the public, it must appear, first, that the interests of the public
generally, as distinguished from those of a particular class, 
require such interferance, and, second, that the means are reasonable
necessary for the accomplishment of the purposes, and not unduly 
oppressive upon individuals."</p>
<p>The test of those who assume to practice dentistry must 
necessarily be, not the possession of a diploma from some college, but 
"possession of the actual technical knowledge and skill peculiar to 
the study and practice of dentistry."</p>
<p>True, it may be proper to provide that the profession of such a 
diploma shall be satisfactory evidence of the possession of such 
knowledge and skill, but is it fair and lawful to exclude one who does
possess such knowledge and skill who has not such diploma? It is 
the 'knowledge and skill' which protects the public - not the means 
or place of acquiring it.</p>
<p>Common knowledge teaches that there are many excellen dentists 
in this country who have obtained their knowledge and skill by long
study and practice under competent dentists in their offices and not
in any dental college. The practice of apprenticeship of dental
students obtains in most states and in many foreign countries and in that
manner many of our best dentists obtained their technical training.</p>
<p>Does the public good require that all such shall be excluded from 
practice, or from examinations for license?</p>
<pb/>
<p>In State vs Clausen 65 Wash. 178, the Supreme Court again said;</p>
    <p></p>























</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>