<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0204.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Janet Mackay v. Henry M. White. Return and Answer of Respondent</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0204.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Janet Mackay v. Henry M. White. Return and Answer of Respondent</title>
<date when="1919-02-03">February 3, 1919</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1919-02">February 1919</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fisher, Thomas M.</term>
<term>Mackay, Valentine</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Mackay, Janet</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Moore, Ben L.</persName>
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2019-12" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="#hc.case.wa.0204.003"/>

<p>No. 4517</p>

<p>Return and Answer of Respondent, Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of JANET MACKAY, FORMERLY JANET ROY, FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>

<p>Comes now the respondent, herein, Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, and responding to the order to show cause heretofore entered by the court herein, and answering the petition of the above named applicant for a Writ of Habeas Corpus herein, respectfully certifies and shows to the court as follows:</p>

<p>That this respondent denies each and every allegation of the petition or complaint herein of the above named applicant, JANET MACKAY, formerly Janet Roy, except as hereinafter admitted.</p>
<p>And this respondent further certifies and respectfully shows to the court as follows:</p>

<p>1. That Henry M. White is now and at all of the times mentioned herein and in the petitioner's complaint has been United States Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington</p>

<p>2. That said petitioner JANET MACKAY, formerly Janet Roy, was duly and regularly arrested and detained under and by virtue of a warrant duly and regularly issued by the Acting Secretary of Labor on the 24th day of June, 1918, which said warrant is included withing and shown as a part of Exhibit "A" hereinafter referred to and hereto attached and made a part hereof; that the said JANET MACKAY, formerly Janet Roy, was thereafter duly and regularly detained in custody under and by virtue of said warrant of arrest until the issuance and service of the warrant of the Acting Secretary of Labor for the reportation of said JANET MACKAY, formerly Janet Roy. </p>

<p>3. That on, to-wit: the 8th day of July, 1918, the said JANET MACKAY, formerly Janet Roy, was examined by and had a hearing before the United States Immigration Inspector, Thomas M. Fisher, with relation to the matters and facts set forth in said warrant of arrest.</p>

<p>4. That the said applicant JANET MACKAY, formerly Janet Roy, had a fair hearing before said Immigration Inspector as aforesaid, and that upon the conclusion of said hearing, said Immigration Inspector duly made his findings <del>and rejected</del> in the case of the said JANET MACKAY, formerly Janet Roy, on the ground that she had entered the United States within three years preceding said hearing without the inspection required by law and that at the time of the entry of the said JANET MACKAY, formerly Janet Roy, she was an alien of the inadmissible class, in that she was a person who believed in or advocated the overthrow by force or violence of the government of the United States, or of all forms of law, or who disbelieved in or was opposed to organized government, and that she was a person likely to become a public charge.</p>

<p>5. That the record in said proceedings, including said record of examination before Inspector Fisher on said July 8th, 1918, was duly transmitted to the Secretary of Labor for action; that thereafter upon due consideration of said matter and of the proceedings therein, the findings and recommendation of said Inspector Fisher were duly and regularly approved, and on, to-wit: the 30th day of November, 1918, under said findings and approval thereof, warrant of deportation was duly and regularly issued by the Acting Secretary of Labor, which said warrant directed that the said JANET MACKAY, formerly Janet Roy,, be deported in accordance therewith; that ever since the said 30th day of November, 1918, the respondent, Henry M. White, as Commissioner aforesaid, held and detained and does now hold and detain said JANET MACKAY, formerly Janet Roy, under and by virtue of said warrant of deportation, which said warrant is set forth and included in Exhibit "A" hereto attached and made a part hereof.</p>

<p>6. That the said JANET MACKAY, formerly Janet Roy, has had a full and fair hearing as provided by law and that a record of the proceedings had with relation to the deportation of said JANET MACKAY, formerly Janet Roy, as aforesaid, including transcript of the testimony adduced in said proceedings and including the warrant of arrest and the warrant of deportation hereinabove mentioned, is set forth in Exhibit "A" hereto attached and by reference made a part hereof.</p>

<p>7. Respondent denies that he has any knowledge or information sufficient to form a belief as to whether the petitioner contracted a marriage with one Valentine Mackay on the 21st day of January, 1919, or at any other time, but respondent says that if the said petitioner did contract a marriage with, and become the lawfully wedded wife of said Mackay, the said marriage was contracted and the petitioner became such a wife of Mackay after the issuance and execution of the warrant described in the petition herein and after the petitioner was, by direction of the Secretary of Labor of the United States, ordered deported from the United States, and respondent denies that said Valentine Mackay is, and denies that at the time of the issuance and execution of said warrant said Valentine Mackay was, and denies that at any time since the issuence of said warrant said Valentine Mackay was, and denies that at any time since the issuance of said warrant said Valentine Mackay has been a citizen of the United States of America and denies that he has any knowledge or information sufficient to form a belief as to whether the petitioner was the lawful wife of said Valentine Mackay, and denies that the petitioner was and denies that at any time she had been a citizen of the United States.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE this respondent prays that said order to show cause be discharged; that the said application for writ of Habeas Corpus be denied, and that the said JANET MACKAY, formerly Janet Roy, be remanded to the custody of this respondent to be dealt with according to law and according to the terms and directions of said warrant of deportation.</p>

<p>John H Sargent</p>
<p>Acting Commissioner of Immigration.</p>

<p>Robt C Saunders</p>
<p>United States Attorney.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>