<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0365.020">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John Matthews v. Henry M. White. correspondents</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0365.020</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">John Matthews v. Henry M. White. correspondents</title>
<date when="1921-06">June 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-06">June 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Pierce, Ralph A.</term>
<term></term>
<term></term>
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Matthews, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>54904/149               June 30, 1921.

Mr. Ralph S. Pierce
c/o Seattle Central Labor Council,
Seattle, Washington.</p>

<p>Sir:</p>

<p>I beg to acknowledge the receipt of your letter of the 9th
instant, having relation to the case of Jack Matthews, an alien who
is now held in the United States Penitentiary at McNeil's Island,
Washington, and who has been ordered to e deported to Roumania, the
country of his nativity at the conclusion of his sentence. You advise
that Mr. Matthews first came to the United States in 1911, resided
here for nine years, then went to Canada and later to Alaska, where he
committed the offense for which he is now serving a prison term. You
also call attention to the difficulties which are likely to be encountered
in endeavoring to deport Matthews at the present time, particularly
in view of the passport requirements, and state that alien appears
to be a hard working man who would eventually develop into a good
citizen if given a proper opportunity.</p>

<p>The case of this alien was very carefully considered by the
Department before it directed that he be deported, and inasmuch as the
evidence in his case appears to be such as to quite clearly bring him
within the deportation provisions of the act, it seemingly will be
necessary to effect his deportation immediately that he is released from the
institution provided, of course, a passport for him can be obtained and
arrangments can be made for his ocean voyage and his passage from the
port of deportation into Roumania. If these arrangements can not be
made, consideration will, of course, be given to the matter of his
temporary release, as the Bureau would not like to see him held under custody
after his sentence has expired for no purpose other than that he might
be deported.</p>

<p>Respectfully,

Commissioner General</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>SEATTLE CENTRAL LABOR COUNCIL
"ONE FOR ALL AND ALL FOR ONE"
SEATTLE, WASH.</p>

<p>June 9, 1921</p>

<p>Department of Labor,
Bureau of Immigration,
Washington,
D.C.</p>

<p>FILE No.54904.-149</p>

<p>Gentlemen:</p>

<p>Jack Matthews is now held in the County Jail
of this city under order of deportation to Ukrainia.
This was entered under date of February 19, 1921.</p>

<p>The deportation has been ordered and upon the
ground that the alien had been convicted subsequent to the
passage of the Act of 1917 for the term of one year or more</p>

<p>for the crime of involving moral terpitude committed within
five years of his entry and that he was a person likely
to become a public charge at the time of his entry.</p>

<p>The facts as shows by the record are that Mr.
Matthews came to this continent in 1911, entered the US
at New York and shortly afterwards went to Canada. For
a great many years he worked continuously as a miner in
different sections of Canada and entered the United States
at Seattle from Victoria in August 1919 intending to remain
a few days in this District and then go to Alaska. He
shortly afterwards went to Alaska and while there, for reasons
not revealed by the record, caused to be sent thru the mails
an obscene picture. He was subsequently convicted of sending
obscene matter thru the mail and sentenced to serve a
sentence of one year at McNeil Island Penintentiary.</p>

<p>The record is not clear that his sentence was
for more than one year, the only thingbearing on that
question being an inquiry by the inspector thru the alien
that it was not a fact his sentence was for a year and a
day.</p>

<p>A few months prior to the expirarion of his
sentence he was granted a hearing before the Immigration
Inspectors. He did not have an attorney; the fact that
he did no request one was clearly because he had</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>neither friends nor acquaintances in this district, having
been here only one time and then only for a very few
days. There was found in the possession of the alien and
introduced in the record three very fine letters of
recommendation written by men for whom he had worked in Canada,
as a miner. In other words, the record shows that this
alien has only committed one crime and that is one which
any man might easily commit.</p>

<p>There is nothing in the record to show that he
has made a practice of distributing obscene literature nor
that he committed the particular act of which he has
convicted except thru carelessness and throughlessness.</p>

<p>In addition to the order is that he be deported
to Ukrainia and it is impossible, as the Department
knowns, to obtain a pasport to that country at this time.
This means that the aline will have to be detained either at
a local detention station or at Ellis Island for an undefinite
time. Local labor unions here have interested themselved
in his case because of the fact that he has affiliated
with the Miners Union in Canada. The man without funds
to take any action in the court challenging the order of
deportation and must appeal to the sense of justice in the Department.</p>

<p>The writer has interviewed the alien on several
occassions and is convinced that he is a hard working man
and who would eventually develop into a good citizen and the
Immigration authorities have stated to the writer that
he has always conducted himself in an orderly manner.</p>

<p>He has therefore requested that the Department take
one or two steps in this proceeding. First, release the
alien upon his personal recognizance until such time as
passports can be secured under guarantee that he will report
whenever wanted. Second, re-open the case and grant to the
alien a re-hearing permitting him to produce testimony and
proof as to his previous good character.</p>

<p>Respectfully submitted,</p>

<p>Ralph &amp; Pierce.</p>

<pb></pb>
 
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>