<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In the District Court of Washington Territory
and for the Fourth Judicial District holding terms
at Cheney.
In the matter of the application
of Willis D. Coyle for a writ of Habeas Corpus.
To the Honorable George Turner Judge
of said District Court
The petition of W. D. Coyle respectfully says
that he is unlawfully imprisoned, detained
confined and restrained of his liberty by E.T. Whitt-
ier in the Couty jail of Spokane County at 
Cheney in said County and Territory of Washington.
That the said imprisonment detention confinement 
and restraint are illegal and that the illegal
thereof constraint this to writ.
The said W.D. Coyle your petitioner was at the April
Term of the aforesaid court held at Cheney in Spo-
kane County Washington Territory in the year 1885
counted of the offense of assault and was by
grand sentement to imprisonmet in the
county jail for the term of sixty days and adjudged
to pay a fine of Two hundred dollars and cosrs
of writ.
That your honor failed to order yor petitioner
to jail until fine and costs where said
that a certified copy of said judgement or
sentence was defent to said E.P. Whittear where
is the lawfully qualified sheriff of said Spo-
kane county and by within thereof the said
E.P. Whittear took your petitionter is his charge
and confined him in the county jail.
That your petitioner has served and the term
of sixty days as sentenced by your honor and
that the said E.P. Whittear is now holding and
detaining your petitioner for the payment of
said fine and costs.
That this is the first application that has
been made for a writ of Heabras Corpus
wherefore your petitioner prays that a writ of 
Habeas Corpus may be granted due to 
the said E.F. Whittear commanding him to have
the body of the said W.D. Coyle before your Honor
at a time and place therein to be justified to do and
receive what shall then and there by by your
Honor considered and adjudged concerning him
together with the time and cause of this detention
and said writ and that he may be restored to
his liberty.
Wilson D. Coyle</p>
