<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0000.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1891">1891</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-09" who="#lkw">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,</p>
<p>NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>Opinion filed August 9, 1892.</p>

<p>In Re Friedrich:</p>

<p>Habeas Corpus. Application for writ, refused.</p>

<p>W. B. Tyler,</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner.</p>

<p>James A. Haight,</p>
<p>Asst. Atty. General, For the State</p>

<p>Hanford J. - </p>

<p>Albert Friedrich petitions for a writ of habeas 
corpus, on the following grounds: A valid indictment charging
him with the crime of murder in the first degree, was found by
a lawful Grand Jury and duly presented to the Superior Court
of the State of Washington for the County of King; after arraign-
ment and a plea of not guilty he was upon said indictment tried
in said Court with the result that the jury brought in a ver-
dict finding him "Guilty as charged in the indictment." He was 
thereupon sentenced to suffer the legal penalty for said crime
which is death. Upon a review of his case, the Supreme Court 
of the State considered the evidence insufficient to warrant
a conviction of the crime of murder in the first degree and on 
that ground reversed the judgment of the Superior Court, but
instead of setting the verdict aside, or ordering the Superior
Court to do so, the Supreme Court ordered that said verdict
stand and remanded the case to the Superior Court with instruc-
tions to enter a new judgment against the petitioner adjudging
him to be guilty of murder in the second degree and to proceed</p>

<pb/>

<p>thereon in accordance with law. In obedience to such instruc-
tions, the Superior Court did adjudge the petitioner to be
guilty of murder in the second degree and sentenced him there-
for to be punished by imprisonment at hard labor in the State
Penitentiary for a period of twenty years, and in pursuance of
that sentence he is now incarcerated in said penitentiary. The
Petitioner claims that this last judgment is not merely voidable
because erroneous or irregular, but that, upon the face of the
record it is manifestly void and therefore his present imprison-
ment is without due process of law and in violation of the
fourteenth amendment of the constitution of the United States.
The state has appeared by the Assistant Attorney General and
while admitting the facts above recited, resists the applica-
tion, denying that this court has any jurisdiction or authority
to order the release of the petitioner from custody; and deny-
ing the unlawfulness of his imprisonment.</p>

<p>No person charged with an offense against the laws of
this state can be punished for such offense unless he shall 
have been duly and legally convicted thereof in a Court of
competent jurisdiction; and no person indicted for an offense
can be convicted thereof otherwise than by confession of this
guilt in open Court, or by the verdict of a jury accepted and
recorded in open Court. 2 Hill's Code <unclear></unclear> 1369. 1364. In a case
wherein a person is accused of a crime like that of murder in th
the first degree, which necessarily includes other crimes of 
lesser magnitude, a question as to the grade of the offense or
degree of guilt must necessarily arise whenever the accused
shall have been found to have committed the guilty act charged.
This sub<del>p</del>ordinate question is one of mixed law and fact.
Obviously therefore it is for the jury to decide. An indict-
ment is sufficient to support a judgment for any grade of of-</p>

<p>2</p>

<pb/>

<p>fense necessarily included within the princip<add>a</add>l<del>e</del> crime charged.
The office of an indictment however, is to raise an issue, a
pleading which clearly and distinctly alleges all the facts
essential to constitute the lesser offenses included within
the highest, suffices to tender an issue as to each fact and
as to each offense, but a plea of guilty, or a verdict in a
cause, is, determinative and to be of any virtue or validity
must be certain and actually decisive of every question in
issue. A verdict which lacks the quality of certainty will
not support a judgment. (Hayne on New Trial and Appeal, page
706 <unclear></unclear> 235; Meeker vs Gardella 1 Wash. St. 148; Western Mill Co.
vs Blanchard ib. 234.) A verdict, or plea of guilty of murder in 
the first degree; and guilty of murder in the second degree;
and guilty of each lesser included crime, down to simple as-
sault, if such a thing can be imagined, could not serve to
guide, much less control the Court in rendering the final
judgment. The judgment in a case wherein such a verdict or plea
had been received, whether inflicting as punishment a merely 
nominal fine, imprisonment, or the dealth penalty, would not 
be founded upon the plea or finding of a jury, but upon the 
opinion of the Judge as to the facts of the case disclosed by
the evidence. Now, as shown by the above references to the
code, the laws of this state do not admit of a judgment in a 
criminal case adverse to the defendant, upon any such a basis.
A plea or verdict of guilty of a particular crime is in every
case a prerequisite an indispensable prerequisite to the
infliction of punishment under color of law, for any crime
cognizable in the Courts of record of this state.</p>

<p>The petitioner has not by a voluntary plea or confession
in open Court authorized the Superior Court to render any judg-
ment against him.</p>

<p>3</p>

<pb/>

<p>But one verdict has been returned, that is a general ver-
dict, the legal meaning and effect of which is to declare the 
petitioner guilty of the crime of murder in the first degree.
People vs Kennedy 39 N.Y. 245; State vs Matrassey, 47 Mo. 295;
Territory vs Timmerman 3 Washington Territory 445.</p>

<p>For that crime the law condemns the petitioner to suffer
death and does not authorize the Court to imprison him in a 
penitentiary or to subject him to any other punishment except
in an incidental way. The power to commute the punishment for
said crime to imprisonment, is committed to the Governor and is 
not vested in the Courts of this State.</p>

<p>There is therefore no law giving color of authority to
the Superior Court of King County, to sentence the petitioner
to be punished by imprisonment upon the verdict rendered by the
jury in his case.</p>

<p>The several propositions above stated are not directly
controverted by the Supreme Court in its opinion in this case.
The only authority claimed for the disposition of the case made
by its decision and judgment, is found in <unclear></unclear>1429 of Hill's Code
which provides that "The Supreme Court may affirm, reverse or 
modify any judgment or order appealed from, and may direct the
proper judgment or order to be entered, or direct a new trial
or further proceedings to be had." State vs Friedrich 29 Pacific
Reporter 1061. This law does not in terms, nor by implication
give any power not usually possessed by appellate tribunals.
Power to modify a judgment or to direct a proper judgment is 
given; and power to order a new trial of a cause whereby the 
verdict of a jury may be annulled is given. But to the word
judgment in this statute must be given its true legal and ac
curate definition. It does not stand as a synonym for the
word "verdict".</p>

<p>4</p>

<pb/>

<p>In the case of the commonwealth v Lockwood 109 Mass. the 
opinion ofthe Court by Mr. Justice Gray, gives an admirable
definition and shows the distinction between the terms "Con-
viction" and "Judgment". He says:- "The ordinary legal mean-
ing of "conviction", when used to designate a particular stage 
of a criminal prosecution triable by a jury, is the confession
of the accused in open Court, or the verdict returned against
him by the jury, which ascertains and publishes the fact of
his guilt; while "judgment" or "sentence" is the appropriate
word to denote the action of the court before which the trial
is had, declaring the consequences <add>to</add> the convict of the fact
thus ascertained". And the learned justice then proceeds by a 
logical and profound argument fortified by quatations from
Blackstone to prove the absolute truth and accuracy of this 
definition. The constitution of this state is radical in the
provisions it contains designed to retrain the Judges from
attempting to influence juries in the decision of questions of
fact. This should be taken into consideration in giving a 
construction to the statute and precludes the idea that the 
Legislature  could have intended to authorize the Court of modify
a verdict, even if the language used did not plainly limit the 
power of the Supreme Court, so that its determination of the
cause should only affect directly that part of the proceedings
which under a system of jursiprudence including jury trials,
is properly within the control of the Court.</p>

<p>These considerations lead me to the conclusion that the
imprisonment of the petitioner is without due process of law
and in violation of the fourteenth amendment of the Constitu-
tion of the United States. But on the other hand by his own
showing the petitioner is presumably guilty of the intentional</p>

<p>5</p>

<pb/>

<p>killing of a human being, with malice. <add>,</add> <add>t</add>The Supreme Court of 
the State, being of the opinion that the verdict of the jury
is to that extent sustained by the evidence, and by existing 
laws of this state, he is subject to punishment therefor, and 
not entitled to be set at liberty, nor to be by this Court
shielded from punishment. His imprisonment under the sentence
passed upon him, is no more unlawful than his discharge would
be. Inasmuch as the petitioner has been regularly tried and
sentenced in a Court having complete jurisdiction of the crime and
the prisoner <del>and the case,</del> whose error is not proceeding re-
gularly, in his case, under the general laws of the state can be
corrected upon a review of the case in the Supreme Court of
the United States by a writ of error, without doing injustice
to either the prisoner or the people, <del>in the final disposition 
of the case</del>, I do not consider that this Court ought to lean in
his favor in the exercise of discretionary powers, to the ex-
tent of delivering him from punishment for a crime whereof he
has been legally indicted and not acquitted.</p>

<p>The industry of counsel has been productive of the presen-
tation upon the argument of an array of authorities in which
the principles an rules, governing the case are set forth and
expounded. I will not prolong this opinion to the extent
necessary to review or comment upon them in detail. It is 
sufficient to say in general that <add>the authorities cited</add> in behalf of the petitioner,
<del>the authorities</del> fully sustain the proposition that any person 
who within the <add>t</add>Territorial limits of the jurisdiction of the
United States Government, is deprived of liberty, either without 
color of legal authority, or because of an act done in the
execution or attempted execution of a law of the United States,
or by the execution of a pretended law which is contrary to
the constitution of the United States, or of a valid law which</p>

<p>6</p>

<pb/>

<p>by application to his particular case becomes in its operation
and effect, in that instance violative of any constitutional
provision, or by an attempt to enforce a valid law by proceed-
ing otherwise than according to constitutional and lawful methods,
may invoke the power of a national Court to secure the equal 
protection of the laws; and his liberty, if he is not by the 
law of the land subject to further restraint. But no precedent
has been cited for the discharge from the custody of state of-
ficers, of a person lawfully indicted under a valid law for a 
crime which is bad in itself, without an acquittal upon a 
lawful trial, when there appears to be a lawfuly organized
Court having jurisdiction to try him and there is no impediment
to a lawful trial and determination of the case other than in-
formal and void proceedings of this Court. In Ex-parte <del>Men</del> Med-
ley 134 U.S. 160, the decision of the Supreme Court is to the 
effect that a convict in custody under a void judgment of a 
state Court and entitled to be released therefrom, should not
be set at liberty, if under any existing law of the state there
could be further proceedings in his case. I am unable to agree
with the petitioners counsel in the opinion expressed that 
the petitioner will be unable to obtain a writ of error from
the Supreme Court of the United States. While it is true that
the Supreme Court of the State has not as yet passed upon any 
federal question in the case, it may be required to do so.</p>

<p>The Supreme Court of the State, has already entertained two 
appeals in this case andhas reversed the judgments against him
given after two successive trials, and the law gives him the
right to appeal to that Court again and ask for a reveral of
the judgment of which he now complains, on the identical grounds
upon which he is in this Court asking for a writ of habeas cor-</p>

<p>7</p>

<pb/>

<p>pus. If the Court on consideration of such appeal should
adhere to the opinion which it has heretofore given, he will
then be clearly entitled to a writ of error from the Supreme
Court of the United States. Having that remedy it would not
be right to grant him a writ of habeas corpus.</p>

<p>Exparte Bigelow 113 U.S. 28; Exparte Wood, 140, U.S. 278;
Exparte Ulrich 43 Fed. Rep. 661.</p>

<p>The application for the writ is refused.</p>

<p>C. H. Hanford</p>
<p>Judge</p>

<p>8</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. H186</p>

<p>In the United States
Circuit Court
FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>

<p>In Re Friedrich</p>

<p>Opinion</p>

<p>Filed August 9 1892</p>

<p>W Reeves Ayres</p>
<p>Clerk.</p>

<p>By R. M. <unclear>Hafeknis</unclear></p>
<p>Deputy.</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>