<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0116.007"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Wiley v. Keokuk. Petition in Error Continue</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0116.007</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Wiley v. Keokuk. Petition in Error Continue</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1870-05">May 1870</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Keokuk, Moses</term>
<term>Wiley, Albert</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term/>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Wiley, Albert</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Keokuk, Moses</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Christian, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Last, First</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Kingman, C.F.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> 
<placeName>Douglas County, Kansas</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="sab">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0116.007"/> 

<p>On the 6th day of May AD 1869 the said plaintiff by his attorney appeared in open Court and dismissed his suit without prejudice as to the defendant Charles E Mix, Thomas Dorwin and W.P. Montgomery and continued the

<pb/>

case as to Thomas Murphy and the case against said Albert Wiley came on to be tried on the said petition of said plaintiff &amp; answer of the said defendant Albert Wiley. Whereupon a jury was called to try the issue in this case, and upon the trial of this action and in the course of the impannelling of the jury one Walter Willis was called as a juror and was challenged by the defendant counsel for cause. The cause of challenge given by the defendant counsel being that the said Walter Willis had served once already on a jury as a talesman on the trial of a cause in said court during the term thereof then being holden and the said Walter Willis on being challenged as aforesaid then and there stated in open court that he had so served as a talesman and which fact was then and there proven by the Record of the Court and admitted by the court and the

<pb/>

<fw>4</fw>

Counsel for the plaintiff. It also appeared that at the same term of said court and after said Walter Willis had served as a talesman as so aforesaid that said Willis had been duly summoned as a juror upon a special <unclear/> to fill a vacancy in the regular pannel of jurors for the term and that he was then in attendance as a regular juror. The court thereupon decided that the said Walter Willis was a competent juror to try said cause and overruled the challenge of defendant counsel of the said juror for the cause aforesaid, to which decision and ruling of the court the defendant by his counsel then and there duly excepted. at the time of said challenge by the defendant said defendant had not exhausted his peremptory challenge and that said Willis was after challenged peremptorily by defendant and did not sit as a juror.</p>

<p>A full jury was then imparrelled in said action to try said case in said District Court and were

<pb/>


duly sowrn to try said cause. and on the said 6th day of May AD 1869 said action came on for trial before said court and jury. Whereupon the plaintiff to maintain the issue on his part introduced the following testimony.</p>

<p>Wilson Shannon was sworn and testified as follows. The defendant Albert Wiley came to me and said that the Indians had counsel and that he wanted counsel in the case before the commission Montgomery. He wanted me to act as such attorney in the case. When I went to the office of the United States commissioner I found that the case was up for hearing. Captain Christian appeared for the Indians and I appeared at the instance of Wiley for the Wiley told me that he was acting as the agent of hte Sac &amp; Fox Indians and claimed that he was then acting as such agent.</p>

<p>William P. Montgomery was

<pb/>


sworn and testified as follows.</p>

<p>I was present at the examination of Keokuk and the other Indians before the commission. The examination was before me. there was something said about the Indians not giving bail and Wiley the defendant said "then they will have to go to jail" He might have said "send them to jail" Wiley had testified before Captain Christian came in. I did not discover any thing very remarkable about Wiley's manner. He may have been excited some what. Mr. Christian came in after the examination had proceeded some way and announced himself as attorney for the Indians under arrest and asked an interview with the Indians and called Keokuk out of the room. Mr. Dorwin (United States deputy Marshall) objected to Keokuk and the other Indians going with Mr Christian unless he accompanied them I think Mr Wiley also objected. I am not positive as to Mr Wiley

<pb/>

objecting. I told the Marshall to let Mr Christian have a private interview. he was permitted to have such interview. When Mr Christian with his clients the Indians came into the room after the interview mentioned I informed Mr Christian that Mr Wiley had been sworn and examined already and that he could ask any question he chose. I cannot now remember whether Mr Christian asked any question. my best recollection is that he based his defence on the legal question at issue and no witnesses were examined after Gov Shannon came in and after Mr Christian for the Indians came into the case, when I announced my decision that the Indians would be bound over to court there was a good deal of confusion in the room. Mr Christian and Mr Powers the interpreter advised the defendants (the Indians) not to give Bail. Mr Wiley said then they would have to go to jail or something to that

<pb/>

<fw>5</fw>

effect I issued no <gap/> then to send them to jail. I issued an order that the Marshall take charge of defendants the Indians and give them an opportunity to get bail if necessary allowing them to go to the Sue &amp; Fox Reserve. All the parties soon left my office I afterwards reduced the order I made to writing and delivered it to the Marshall Dorwin. During the progress of the examination of the Indians before me defendant (Wiley) bore an active part and was much in earnest:</p>

<p>Andrew Carnes was sworn and testified as follows. On the 23d day of November AD 1868 I was keeping the jail for sheriff Walker. I received Keokuk and the other Indians at the jail. There were at the time both white and colored prisoners at the jail. There was one confined for Burglary one for Robbery and some for city offences. The deputy Marshall brought the Indians to the jail about dark

<pb/>

and they remained there until 9 or 10 o'clock the next morning. The prisoners had their suppers and were locked up in the cells before the Indians came. I locked the Indians up in the hall of the jail and gave orders to the prisoners not to annoy or molest them. There was no obscene or offensive language or <unclear>Crud</unclear> talk by the other prisoners while the Indians were in jail and nothing that would offend them or wound their feelings. Mr Dorwin brought the Indians to the jail and took them away again. They were not in jail more than twelve hours</p>

<p>James Christian being sworn testified as follows. I was called upon on November 23d AD 1868 by these Indians to act as their counsel. I want to the office of Mr Montgomery and asked for a consultation with the Indians. Dorwin and Wiley objected to their going out unless they went with them and heard what was said. Mr Montgomery ordered

<pb/>

that they should have a chance to counsel with me. I did not see any one touch them except Dorwin, Wiley did not touch them. I instructed them not to give bail. Wiley then said I want them put in jail He insisted what they should go to jail. Wiley was very much excited I am the attorney for the plaintiff is this action.</p>

<p>Henry Jones being sworn testified as follows. There are about 700 Indians in our tribe (the Sac &amp; Fox) Keokuk in the chief He is the Government Chief our people think more of him than they do of a common Indian.</p>

<p>Keokuk plaintiff being sworn testified as follows. I was arrested about this time of day I was going to Washington on business I was going on my own business and expected to pay my own expenses, I am a chief of the Sac &amp; Fox Indians my business was to try to get the Indians to be like white men. I received pay from the government for my services as chief. I was going to Washington to see about

<pb/>

the trade and about other business for the Indians." The plaintiff than read as evidence In his part the following agreed statement of facts. It is agreed and admitted on the part of the plaintiff that Albert Wiley the defendant swore on the trial before W.P. Montgomery that he had verbal instructions from superintendant Thomas Murphy to arrest Keokuk and party should they attempt to go to Washington and it is admitted that if put upon the stand as a witness he would swear so again and it is admitted for the purposes of this trial that he has so sworn and if may to go to the jury. It is also admitted that the letters offered in evidence purporting to be from Charles E. Mix acting commission of Indian affairs &amp; from Thomas Murphy superintendent of Indians affairs are genuine and that they maybe read in evidence to the jury as though properly authenticated. It is also admitted that major

<pb/>

Albert Wiley read said letters or the purport of them to Keokuk a few days previous to his departure for Washington and told him that he would arrest him if he attempted to leave the Reserve and go to Washington and that in reply Keokuk told him that he had money to pay his own expenses that he did not ask the government to pay his expenses and that he was going. And that he did start for Washington on the 23d day of November 1868. It is admitted on the part of Albert Wiley that he came to Lawrence and made the affidavit on which Keokuk and his party were arrested. It is also admitted that he gave evidence on the trial <unclear></unclear> before W. P. Montgomery a I. Commission and Hon D M Valentine District judge and that he employed counsel to prosecute the same.</p>
<p>James Christian<lb/> 
Atty for Keokuk Plff</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
