<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0183.010.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Gwoo Shee Ah Look v. United States. Record.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0180.010</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Gwoo Shee Ah Look v. United States. Record.</title>
<date when="1914-04-14">April 14, 1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2647GwooSheeAhLook</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-04">April 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Bolster, N. W.</term>
<term>Clark, A. L.</term>
<term>Barbour, J. H.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Look, Gwoo Shee Ah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Frye, Jesse A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wilbur</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Spencer</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Clark, A. L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Allen, Clay K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, George P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<figure><ab>N.W. Bolster &amp; Co
Court Stenographies
707-08 Lowman Bldg
Please, Elliot 2B 
Seattle</ab></figure>
<p>In the United States District Court, Western District of
Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the matter of the application
for a writ of habeas corpus
for Gwoo Shee Ah Look } No. 2647.</p>
<p>This matter coming on for hearing on this 29th
day of April, 1914, at the hour of 10:00 o'clock a.m.
before the Honorable Jeremiah Neterer, Judge of the
above entitled court, the following proceedings were had:</p>
<pb/>
<figure><ab>N.W. Bolster &amp; Co
Court Stenographies
707-08 Lowman Bldg
Please, Elliot 2B
Seattle</ab></figure>
<ab>k2</ab>
<p>A.L. Clark, being first duly sworn, testifies
as follows:</p>
<p>Q (Mr. Wilbur) What is your name and occupation?</p>
<p>A A.L. Clark is my name and I am an attorney.</p>
<p>Q You are connected with the firm of Wilbur and Spencer
of Portland?</p>
<p>A I am.</p>
<p>Q And how long have you been practicing law?</p>
<p>A Eighteen years.</p>
<p>Q Were you called upon in the early part of November,
Mr. Clark, relative to looking after the interstate
of Gwoo Shee At Look, the petitioner in this case?</p>
<p>A I was</p>
<p>Q I wish you would state to the court the entire transaction
briefly, and as clearly as you can from the time
you first learned of it and particular of anuy talks
you may have had with Mr. Barbour.</p>
<p>The Court: The only thing I care to know about is what
relations you sustained to the Commissioner's office
in Portland, as to whether the office knew that you
were attorney for the woman.</p>
<p>A (by the witness) On the 5th day of November, some time
before noon, the matter was called to my attention and 
I went down to the police station where the women were
then confined, and Mr. Barbour was there. I first
applied to the policemen to ascertain if I could see the people.</p>
<p>The Court: What people -- what do you mean by "the people"?</p>
<p>A (Continuing) Well, this Chinese woman, and I was
<fw>1</fw>
<pb/>
k3
<figure><ab>N.W. Bolster &amp; Co
Court Stenographies
707-08 Lowman Bldg
Please, Elliot 2B 
Seattle</ab></figure>
referred to Mr. Barbour, and I went upstairs where
he was and enquired of him if he had this woman there,
and he said that he did, and I then inquired if I 
could see her and have a talk with her, and I told him 
that the firm of Wilbur and Spencer, in connection with
me, had been employed to look after her interest. He
said to me that he was just going through with them
and taking their statements and that no one could see
them at that time, and if I could come around some time
later on, or come to his office I could probably get
to see this woman. On the next day, I believe it was,
I went to his office in the Railway Exchange Building,
on the same mission, and he then told me that at that
time I could not see the woman. I was somewhat ignorant
of the manner of proceedings in the matter of this kind,
and he gave me a whole lot of information and told me
the way in which such examination were conducted, and
that they were conducted secretly until a certain point
when it was deemed proper by the Commissioner to advise
the  woman that she was entitled to an attorney, if she
so desired, and at that time I asked him if I could
see the woman, who then had been transferred to the
county jail, but was not permitted to do so. I think
from that time on, almost every day, probably not
every day, I either saw him in person or had a talk with
him on the 'phone -- we had numerous talks over the 'phone
relative to this woman. Before her statement had been
taken I called him up and made inquiries and he said 
"We will put you down as atttoneys and at the proper
time you will be permitted to come in and see the record".
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
k4
<figure><ab>N.W. Bolster &amp; Co
Court Stenographies
707-08 Lowman Bldg
Please, Elliot 2B 
Seattle</ab></figure>
After her statement had been taken, but before the
two policemen's statement, or testimony, had been taken
I was permitted to see her in the county jail on an
order from Mr. Barbour to the jailer directing the
jailer to permit me to toalk to the woman and to take
an interpreter in-, I went there -- I did not known whne 
the testimony of the two policemen was to be taken
and I did not know the names of any of the witnesses
until after their testimony had been taken, when Mr. 
Barbour handed to me the record which contained the
statementsof Gwoo Shee Ah Look and the two policemen.</p>
<p>Q You said that Mr. Barbour gave you this order to see
the woman?</p>
<p>A Yes sir</p>
<p>q After her statement had been taken?</p>
<p>A After her statement had been taken.</p>
<p>Q But before the testimony of the other witnesses.</p>
<p>A But before the testimony of the two policemen, because he
said at that time that he still had some other testimony
to take in this case, and that he had been quite
busy with some other matters and had not concluded yet,
but he had a couple of other witnesses, and when that
was taken the record would be complete.</p>
<p>Q And then the record here shows that this testimony
was taken, I believe, upon the 17th, of the policemen.</p>
<p>A Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q And when was the first opportunity that you had is any
way of seeing this record or knowing anything about what
was being taken?</p>
<p>A The first opportunity that I had was after all the
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
k5
<figure><ab>N.W. Bolster &amp; Co
Court Stenographies
707-08 Lowman Bldg
Please, Elliot 2B 
Seattle</ab></figure>
testimony was taken, when Mr. Barbour handed to me a
transcript of Gwoo Shee Ah Look's testimony, and a
transcript of the testimony of the two policemen.</p>
<p>Q And what did he say at that time?</p>
<p>A He handed the record to me; I think called me up on the
'phone and said "That you can prepare such -- present
such evidence as you now have by way of affidavits
and I will send them with my report to the Secretary
of Commerce and Labor".</p>
<p>Mr. Wilbur: That is all -- do you desire to ask any 
questions, Mr. Fishburn?</p>
<p>Mr. Fishburn: That is all.</p>
<p>Mr. Wilbur: Mr. Fishburn, would you care to put Mr.
Barbour on the stand?</p>
<p>Mr. Fishburn: I believe that is in substance the facts 
in the case; that is, I mean his statement there seems
to be in substance correct, but I will ask Mr. Barbour 
to take <add>the</add> stand a moment and ask him one question or
two.</p>
<fw>4</fw>
<ab>k6</ab>
<figure><ab>N.W. Bolster &amp; Co
Court Stenographies
707-08 Lowman Bldg
Please, Elliot 2B 
Seattle</ab></figure>
<p>J.H. Barbour, being first duly sworn, testifies 
as follows:</p>
<p>Mr. Fishburn: However, I believe this would waive my 
objection, and I don't want to do that -- you need 
not take the stand.</p>
<p>The Court: So far as I am concerned you can have it
in the record without waiving your objection, and we
will have his testimony in.</p>
<p>Mr. Fishburne: All right.</p>
<p>Mr. Wilbur: We will make absolutely no objection. We want
the court to understand the situation and we are perfectly 
willing that the record shall show that -- we will
make no objection.</p>
<p>The Court: You might just say that by offering this
evidence you do not desire to waive your objection.</p>
<p>Mr. Fishburn: In offering it I desire the record to show
that I do not desire to waive my objection. My objection
is that the record is the only thing that the court
has the right to examine even as to the question of
employing attorney.</p>
<p>Q I desire, Mr. Barbour, to ask you whether, before
taking the testimony of the policemen, there had been
any record made -- what, if any, record had been made
in your office as to the attorney there, before you
took the testimony of the policemen after you had
taken her testimony?</p>
<p>A There had been no formal entry or recongition of
the atttorney at any particular time whatsoever. Atttorneys 
for all these cases come into my office an hour after
<fw>5</fw>
k7
<figure><ab>N.W. Bolster &amp; Co
Court Stenographies
707-08 Lowman Bldg
Please, Elliot 2B 
Seattle</ab></figure>
the hearing take place, a ssuming to represent these
people; most of them being reputable atttorneys I naturally
would recongize their appearance in the case, but not
admit them in the case until such time as I see fit,
under the regulations. The recognition was not an
admission in this case, however.</p>
<p>Q How soon after the testimony was taken did you notify 
them of their rights to appear?</p>
<p>A I had had numerous talks with Mr. Clark, and as he states,
concerning his rights in the case and the limitation
on his rights, I told him that as soon as I had taken
the testimony of the woman and certain other evidence
he would be admitted to the case, as the regulations
provided. He understood that.</p>
<p>Q Did you tell him that he would have the right to cross
examine the witnesses?</p>
<p>A I never told him that, never.</p>
<p>Did you make that clear to him that --</p>
<p>A The matter of cross examining witnesses was never
mentioned by him no by me either. Mr. Clark, as he
states, was ignorant of this procedure and I enlightened
him along this line and I told him what his rights were,
and he accepted my word; he accepted my statement of 
it as being correct.</p>
<p>Q Am I understand the practice pursued in Portland, what
is that as to the presence of attorneys while the
Government is taking the testimony; what has been the
practice there?</p>
<p>Mr. Wilbur: I might make the formal objection that I think
that is governed by the rules and construction of the
<fw>6</fw>
k8
<figure><ab>N.W. Bolster &amp; Co
Court Stenographies
707-08 Lowman Bldg
Please, Elliot 2B 
Seattle</ab></figure>
law on the subject.</p>
<p>The Court: I don't think the custom in Portland would
govern.</p>
<p>Cross Examination</p>
<p>Q (Mr. Wilbur) Without going into the various questions
here; you heard Mr. Clark's testimony and his statement
here?</p>
<p>A Yes, sir.</p>
<p>Q And that statement, as you understand it, is substantially
correct?</p>
<p>A Well, I would not want to admit it all as being correct.
I admit Mr. Clark appeared at the police station on the
day of the arrest.</p>
<p>Q She was arrested on the 4th?</p>
<p>A Yes, sir, and I remember Mr. Clark appeared the same
day.</p>
<p>Q And Mr. Clark saw you frequently, didn't he, up to the
time?</p>
<p>A He called me up concerning it.</p>
<p>Q --up to the time that the record was finally completed
and turned over to him.</p>
<p>A Yes, he did</p>
<p>Q And, as a matter of fact, you refused Mr. Clark, didn't you,
the right to attend any of these examinations.</p>
<p>A Mr. Clark never demanded it as a right or a privilege.</p>
<p>Q Did you ever tell him that he had any right to come
there and appear as an attorney?</p>
<p>A I told Mr. Clark at the beginning, when he expressed
ignorance of the regulations, that he would be admitted
<fw>7</fw>
<pb/>
k9
<figure><ab>N.W. Bolster &amp; Co
Court Stenographies
707-08 Lowman Bldg
Please, Elliot 2B 
Seattle</ab></figure>
after I had taken the testimony of this alien and had
secured certain other evidence -- I would notify =him
and he would then be admitted in the case and have
access to the record and to that testimony, and would
be permissted to submit such evidence as he desired.</p>
<p>Q In other words, you practically told him, did you not,
that he would not be allowed to be present until after
that time.</p>
<p>A Until such time as I would designate.</p>
<p>Q Did you ever designate or indicate to him that he had
the right to attend any of these hearings -- you never did 
did you?</p>
<p>A What do you mean by "hearings"?</p>
<p>Q You just said you told him that he could come in whenever
you designated to him a time; now, as a matter of 
fact, you never did designate to him any time?</p>
<p>A I did.</p>
<p>Q When?</p>
<p>A By giving him a copyof the record.</p>
<p>Q And that was on what date?</p>
<p>A I don't recall</p>
<p>Q It was after you had taken the statements of the
policemen, wasn't it?</p>
<p>A Yes sir, it was.</p>
<p>Q And you had taken Gwoo Shee Ah Look's testimony, as
shown on the record, on the 10th?</p>
<p>A I believe so.</p>
<p>Q And the record is true, that the policemen's testimony
was taken on the 17th?</p>
<p>A Yes sir.</p>
<fw>8</fw>
<pb/>
<ab>k10</ab>
<figure><ab>N.W. Bolster &amp; Co
Court Stenographies
707-08 Lowman Bldg
Please, Elliot 2B 
Seattle</ab></figure>
<p>Q Did you, between the 10th and the 17th, indicate to
Mr. Clark in any way, shape, manner or form that
he could come in, and as the attorney for the woman
attend that hearing of the policemen when their
testimony was being taken.</p>
<p>A I did not.</p>
<p>Q Or by cross examination?</p>
<p>A I did not. Mr. Clark, if he so considers he was admitted,
was admitted for the purpose of bailing this woman
out. By reason of pressure of buisness I had been compelled
to hold this woman, and several others, in jail for a
week. It would have been necessary to have held them for
another week if I had kept Mr. Clark out of the case 
entirely until the statements of these policemen were
taken. I admitted him to the case for the purpose of
bailing this woman out, but for no other purpose,
until the statements of the police were taken.</p>
<p>Q That was after the hearing was concluded?</p>
<p>A No--</p>
<p>Q After the statement of the policemen?</p>
<p>A After the statement from the woman.</p>
<p>Q Now, you gave to Mr. Clark, didn't you, written
authority to see this woman between the 10th and and the
17th?</p>
<p>A Well, if she ws to be bailed out it would be natural 
he should see her.</p>
<p>Q Please answer my question, did you or did you not?</p>
<p>A Certainly, for the purpose of bailing her out.</p>
<p>Q Now, at the hearing, when the policemen's statements
were taken, this woman not present, was she?</p>
<fw>9</fw>
<pb/>
<ab>k11</ab>
<figure><ab>N.W. Bolster &amp; Co
Court Stenographies
707-08 Lowman Bldg
Please, Elliot 2B 
Seattle</ab></figure>
<p>A No sir; she don't speak the English language.</p>
<p>Q She was not present?</p>
<p>A She was not present.</p>
<p>Q Neither was Mr. Clark present?</p>
<p>A Mr. Clark was not present.</p>
<p>Q Nor was any member of our firm present?</p>
<p>A They were not present.</p>
<p>Q Nor was any member of our firm notified that this hearing
was going to be had of those policemen at that time?</p>
<p>A Not at this particular time or place or presence.</p>
<p>Q Neither was this woman notified that his hearing was
to go on at this time?</p>
<p>A The hearing of the officers?</p>
<p>Q The taking of the testimony of the two officers.</p>
<p>A This Chinese woman?</p>
<p>Q Yes.</p>
<p>A No sir, she was not notified.</p>
<p>Q It was taken without any invitation to her whatever?</p>
<p>A Exactly.</p>
<p>Q Or to any member of our firm?</p>
<p>A Yes.</p>
<p>Mr. Wilbur: That is all the testimony, may it please Your
Honor, that we desire to offer.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>