<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0187.026">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0187.026</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<date></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Grayson, Marie Robina</term>
<term>Grayson, William</term>    
<term>Kahoe, Margaret</term>    
<term>Pollock, Baron</term>    
<term>Shakespeare, Noah</term>
<term>Turner, Charles A.</term>

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>England</term>
<term>Bretagne, France</term>
<term>Salem, Oregon</term>
<term>St. Louis, Missouri</term>
<term>Everett, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Marie Robina Grayson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Noah Shakespeare</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
    <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>H250-94</p>
<p>UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE AND LABOR. IMMIGRATION SERVICE.</p>

<p>In re Marie Robina, 
alias Lena Mitchell. +
BRIEF ON BEHALF OF MARIE ROBINA.
n.g.</p>

<p>The testimony as taken before Immigration Inspector Turner, 
and returned to the Department s hows that Marie Robina, was 
born at Tridon Bretagne, France, twenty-nine years ago, and that 
she came to t he United States on the Steamship La Champagne, 
eleven years ago, and has ever since remained in the United States.</p>
<p>The testimony further s hows that up to the time of her 
arrival in the United States <add>Marie</add> Robina was not an immoral woman.
That after her arrival in the United States she married, in April 
of her marriage certificate, and thereafter she lived and cohabited
with her husband for the succeeding seven month.</p>
<p>The testimony shows that some nine years ago Robina became 
an immoral woman, and that was over two years after her arrival 
in the United States, and that since that time she has pursued 
intermittently the vocation of a sporting woman.</p>
<p>The testimony fur ther shows that the husband, whom she married, 
William Grayson, was a native born citizen of the United States, 
born in the City of St. Louis, Missouri, and the record of birth
introduced in evidence is returned by the Immigration Inspector.</p>
<p>As we understand t he Governments claim, it is under Section
three of the Act of February 20, 1907, as amended by the act of 
March 26, 1910, and we quote t herefrom, " Any alien who shall
be found an inmate of, or connected with the management of a house 
of prostitution, or practising prostitution after such alien 
shall have entered the United States, or who s hall receive, share
in, or derive benefit from any part of the earnings of any prostitute
or is employed by, in, or in connection with any house of prostitution,
or music, or dance hall, or other place of amusement, or 
resort, habitually frequented by prostitutes, or where prostitutes
gather, or who in any way assists, protects, or promises to 
protect, from arrest any prostitute s hall be deemed to be unlawfully 
within the United States, and shall be deported in the manner 
provided by Section 20, and 21 of this Act."</p>
<p>Sectin 20, referred to in Section 3 provides for deportation
at any time within t hree years after the arrival of t he alien
in this Country.</p>
<p>Section 21 provides for the deportation of such Alien at any 
time within three years after landing, and directs such removal 
by the Steamship Company upon whose boat the alien made his entry 
into this Country.</p>
<p>It will be noted that Section three provides for the deportation
of an alien.</p>
<p>If the person sought to be deported is not an alien, then the 
Statute has no application to such particular person.</p>
<p>One may effect an entry into t his country as an alien and 
thereafter the status of such personmay be c hanged in various ways.</p>
<p>If such status is c hanged before such person is taken into custody
under t his Act, the t he Act does not apply, and the penalty
denounced, to-wit, - deportation, cannot be enforced.</p>
<p>One of the methods of a change of status is in the case of a 
female, by marriage.</p>
<p>The respondent here prior to her entry into the Country was not a 
prostitute.</p>
<p>Two years ago, being an alien s he married an American Citizen.
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
For everyone born within t he territorial limits of t he United 
States is presumed to be a citizen, and ipao facto such marriage
Marie Robina took the citizenship of her husband, and thereafter
became and ever since has been and now is an American Citizen.</p>
<p>As to the fact of William Grayson's citizenship, there seems 
to be no controversy.</p>
<p>He was born within this country; if thereafter he expatriated 
himself it is a matter to be proved.</p>
<p>A given condition is presumed to continue until a change be shown.
Citizenship having been once s hown to exist is presumed to continue
and there has been no countervailing testimony offered, so that we 
start with the fact that William Grayson, the husband of the 
respondent was and is an American Citizen.</p>
<p>The fact of intermarriage between the respondent and William Grayson
is conclusively shown.</p>
<p>Then remains the question, what effect does that have upon the 
status of the wife, admittedly an alien at the time of marriage, 
but marrying in the United States, a citizen of the United States.</p>
<p>Respondents claim is t hat from the earliest times a woman
took the political status of her husband.</p>
<p>Her prior political condition, whatever it might be, became merged 
by marriage in that of her husband, and whether s he was in fact, 
at the time of her marriage, a citizen of a foreign Country, by 
the fact of such marriage her former citizenship was obliterated, 
and she became a citizen of the Country of w hich her husband was a 
citizen.</p>
<p>Historical examples of t his are found in the customs of the 
Teutonic Tribes, when they made raids, for t he purpose of 
procuring wives, upon other tribes, and being successful, the captured
wife took the status of her husband, and thereupon became a member 
of his tribe, and her allegiance to her native tribe was transferred 
to the tribe of her husband.</p>
<p>So it was under t he Jewish law.</p>
<p>So it was notably in the case of t he Sabineowmen, wehre, as it 
will be remembered the Romans being in need of wives sallied out 
and captured a number ofSabine women, and tookthem to wife, and 
thereupon t hose women, bore and theretofore having lived as Sabines
became thereafter Roman matrons, with all the rights and privileges
of Roman citizens, and solely by virtue of the marriage relation, 
and the political status of their husbands.</p>
<p>This Country derives its laws from England.</p>
<p>The common law of England is, at least as far as Federal 
jurisdiction goes, the law of this country.</p>
<p>Will it be doubted for a moment that under the English common law 
as it existed prior to the time of George III, and w hich common 
law became an integral part of the law of this Country, at least
within the Federal jurisdiction, that a French woman, marrying an 
English subject thereby lost her French nationality and acquired 
a British nationality.</p>
<p>The reason for such rule, which existed before the dawn of 
written history, existed down through the dark ages, and persisted
through the continuance of the common law in England, was this, 
a wifes' being became mergedd in t hat of the husband.</p>
<p>The husband, as the bible expresses it, was the head of the wife. 
There could be but one head.</p>
<p>The wifes' entire being, political and in all other respects, became 
that of the husband, by marriage.</p>
<p>Her former name became obliterated, her property rights, if she had 
any, passed ot her husband, her political status was obliterated, 
because where the husband is the head there could not be in the 
same head at the same time a condition of two different allegiances 
The allegiance of the male British subject was due to the British 
Crown.</p>
<p>The allegiance of the female French citizen was due in those times 
to the French crown.</p>
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
<p>By the fact of marriage the male and female became on in law.
The citizenship of one thereafter must be obliterated, and the 
common law, basing its rule upon the biblical rule, and for 
reasons which commend themselvers to any enlightened person,
decreed that the citizenship of the female was obliterated, adn 
she took the citizenship of her husband.</p>
<p>And there have been numerous holdings.</p>
<p>In Regina vs. Manning, 2nd Carr. &amp; Kir. 886 The English courts
held that a Swiss woman, married to an English subject was not 
entitled to be tried by a jury of aliens, because she was not an 
alien, taking the citizenship of her husband.</p>
<p>And in t hat case Chief Baron Pollock observes, -"The obvious, 
plain and natural inference **** appears to me to be that she 
should be considered exactly as if s he had been naturalized by 
the act of Parliament, or as if she had been a natural born subject."
Such will be conceded to have been the general rule in English
jurisprudence.</p>
<p>( The United States has also legislated uopn t his subject, and by 
the act of February 10, 1855, it is provided, -"Any woman who 
is now, or may hereinafter be married to a citizen of the United 
States, and might herself be lawfully naturalized, s hall be deemed 
a citizen."</p>
<p>Mr. Bishop in his treaties on the Laws of married women, 
 2 Bishop, Section 505, says,-"That by t he very act of marriage, 
citizenship is conferred on a woman, who by previous laws was 
capable of becoming naturalized. His citizenship conferred citizenship 
on her." )</p>
<p>And to the same effect is the holding of the Supreme Court of North 
Carolina, in Kane vs. McCarthy, 63 N.C. 299.</p>
<p>In the case of Leonard vs. Grant, 5 Fed. Rep. page 11, Judge
Deady discussing this precise question says, referring to some of 
the authorities that we have quoted before,-"While the language
in all of them is only consistent with a citizenship as enduring, 
and unqualified as if the wife had been actually naturalized upon 
her own formal application by the judgment of a competent Court."</p>
<p>The question might them possible arise as to what the meaning
of the language is, "and might herself be lawfully naturalized ", 
and upon that question we have the authority of Judge Deady, a Judge
of recognized ability, and in citing from his opinion, in the 
case last spoken of, it should be borne in mind that at t he time 
of the rendition of his opinion and the present time, (the requirements
of an alien as to naturalization were the same, to-wit, the 
applicant must be a free white person, or a person of African 
descent, or nativity.</p>
<p>The applicant must have resided within the United States five years, 
must have a good moral character, attached to the principles of 
the Constitution of the United States, and well disposed to the 
good order and happiness of the same, and must have renounced 
all titles or orders of nobility, if any applicant had. )</p>
<p>Quoting from Leonard vs. Grant, in Kelly vs. Owen, 7 Wallacem 
496, "the question did not appear to have been discussed, or considered 
but it was assumed that race was the only one of t hese qualifications
that it was necessary for the woman to possess at the tim e
of her marriage.</p>
<p>In other words, that as the law then stood, she "should be a free 
white person,"and not an alien enemy.</p>
<p>And it appeared affirmatively that one of the parties who was held 
to be a citizen, Margaret Kahoe, had not in the qualificationof 
respondents case, she was only two years in the United States, 
when s he was married, and only four years therein w hen her husband
became naturalized.</p>
<p>In Burton vs. Burton, 1st Keyes 359, the woman was never in 
the United States until after the death of her husband, and in 
neither case does it appear that there was any evidence that the 
women,held to be citizens by reason of their marriage with citizens, 
possessed the qualifications of good moral c haracter, attachment to 
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
the principles of the Constitution, and disposed to the good order 
and happiness of the United States.</p>
<p>( The reasonable inference is that notwithstanding the law 
of the Statute, "Might herself be lawfully naturalized", the 
Supreme Court considered that it was only necessary that the woman
should be a person of the class or race permitted to be naturalized
by existing laws, and that in respect to the qualifications arising 
out of her conduct, or opinions, being the wife of a citizen
she is to be regarded as qualified for citizenship, and therefore 
considered a citizen."</p>
<p>Kelly vs. Owen et al, 7 Wallace 496, Co-Operative Edition page 248, 
Book 19 the Supreme Court of the United Statesm speaking through 
Mr. Justice Field, say, "As we construe this act, (that is the 
act of1855) it confers the privilege of citizenship upon women 
married to citizens of the United States, if they are of the class
of person for whose naturalization the previous acts of Congress
provides. )</p>
<p>The terms, "married", or "who shall be married" do not refer in 
our judgment to the time when the ceremony of marriage, to a citizen, whether his 
citizenship existed at the passage of the act,or subsequently , 
or before or after the marriage, she becomes by that fact a 
citizenalso.</p>
<p>His citizenship when ever it exists confers under the act, citizenship
upon her.*** The terms "Who might lawfully be naturalized 
under the existing laws" only limits the application of the law 
to free white women."</p>
<p>It should be borne in mind that at the time of the marriage 
of respondent to Grayson she was not practising prostitution, and 
had not been for a month preceding the marriage.</p>
<p>By the marriage she gained t he status of an American Citizen.</p>
<p>In re Nickola, 184 Fed. 322.</p>
<p>In re Nickola, 173 Fed. Rep. 626.</p>
<p>Sprung vs. Morton, 182 Fed. Rep. 330.</p>
<p>United States vs. Cohen, 179 Fed. Rep. 834.</p>
<p>Hopkins cs. Fachant, 130 Fed. 839.</p>
<p>United States vs. Keller, 13 Fed. Rep. 82 (opinion by Mr. Justice 
Harland on Circuit).</p>
<p>Ware vs. Wisner, 50 Fed. Rep. 310.</p>
<p>Broadis vs. Broadis, 86 Fed. Rep. 951.</p>

<p>We have here then on this record the case of a women, who 
lawfully entered the Country, who at the time of entry and long 
thereafter was a law abiding moral woman, who thereafter married 
in this Country a citizen of this Country, and who at the time of 
marriage, for some time before, and for a considerable time there 
after remained a moral woman.</p>
<p>If she is to be deported it must be upon the ground that she 
unlawfully entered the Country, is an alien, and is practising 
prostitution.</p>
<p>It seems to us from the authorities cited that there can be no 
question but that her entry into the Country was lawful, that 
thereafter while living in this Country, in a law abiding manner, 
she married a citizen of this Country, and thereby she became a 
citizen of the United States, and of course that condition is 
presumed to continue.</p>
<p>The deportation statute applies only to aliens, it does not 
apply to citizens of this Country.</p>
<p>If citizens of this Country commit any breach of the laws of the 
Country, there is a tribunal provided for their trial, where they 
have a right to be heard in the manner provided by the Constitution 
before a Court composed of a Judge and a jury of their peers.</p>
<p>The Immigration acts are at best drastic, and it would appear 
that in order to bring one within such acts the showing must be 
clear and convincing, both of fact and of law.</p>
<fw>-4-</fw>
<pb/>
<p>The rights of American citizens will not be infringed upon by 
an executive department, but such rights will be left to the Courts 
to be determined and adjudged.</p>
<p>This woman may truthfully use a paraphrase of Cicero's 
remark "Civis Americana Sum".</p>
<p>Such claim would be truthful in law and in fact, and it should 
act in this case as a full and complete shield to her.</p>
<p>It is respectfully asked that Marie Robina be discharged.</p>

<ab>Noah Shakespeare <lb/>
Attorney for respondent Marie 
Robina.</ab>
<pb/>

<p><gap/></p>

<p><gap/></p>

<p><gap/></p>

<p>NOAH SHAKESPEARE
ATTORNEY AT LAW
EVERETT, WASHINGTON
PUGET PRESS EVERETT, WASH.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>