<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0472.001"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0472.001</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">September 14, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date>13 May 1897</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Pierce, John A.
Speck, Robert D.
Baldwin, Harris 
Hanford, C. H. 
Aspland, Lise C.
White, E. T.
Pomeroy, Frances A. 
Aspland, Andrew 
Aspland, Ella May 
Brown, Abel 
Wilkinson, M. A.  
Aspland, John H. 
White, E. T. 
Aspland, Jennie 
Switzer, W. D. 
Magnus, Franz
Sempee,John M. 
Sawyer, Mary
Spence, William C. 
Corbett, J. E. 
Eldridge, John 
Hair, N. C. 
Valentine, John E. 
Backus, C. F. 
Donovan, G. J.
Low, J. R. 
Thomas, C.
Monroe, W. A. 
Fenton, James E. 
</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Spokane County, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Webster, George</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Webster, George</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName> Del Cary Smith
Fenton, James E. </persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Pierce, John A.
Baldwin, Harris</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H. </persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Circuit Court of the United States, Ninth Judicial Circuit, District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>Spokane County, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0472.001"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES/, NINTH JUDICIAL CIRCUIT.</p>
<p>DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON. NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the application of
George Webster,</p>
<p>for</p>
<p>A Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>To the Hon. C. H. Hanford, Judge of the Circuit Court of the
United States, Ninth Judicial Circuit, District of Washington,
Northern Division.</p>
<p>The petition of George Webster respectfully shows to your
Honor:</p>
<p>First- That the said petitioner is now a prisoner imprisoned
and confined in the County Jail at Spokane, Spokane County, State
 of Washington, in the custody of Robert D. Speck, Sheriff of Spokane
County, State of Washington.</p>
<p>Second- That the cause or pretense of the restraint of the
said petitioner according to the best of his knowledge and belief
is, that on the 13th day of May, 1897, John A. Pierce as proecuting
attorney in and for the County of Spokane, State of Washington,
made and filed with the Clerk of the Superior Court of the State of
Washington, in and for Spokane County, an information, charging the
above named petitioner with the crime of murder in the first de-
gree, which said information is in writing in words and figures as
follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintiff,</p>
<p>v.</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Defendant.</p>
<p>Information for Murder
in the First Degree.</p>
<p>Whereas the hereinafter specified public offense has been com-
mitted by the said defendant George Webster, and whereas the said
defendant George Webster is not under indictment therefor; and whereas
the said defendant is in custody charged with having committed the
said public offense; and whereas the said court is in session, and 
no Grand Jury of, in or for said County is in session; now, there-
fore, John A. Pierce, Prosecuting attorney in and for the County of
Spokane, and State of Washington, and in the name and by the au-
thority of the State of Washington, by this Information informs
the said court and gives the said court to understand, know and
be informed that the said defendant George Webster is hereby charg-
ed with a public offense, to-wit; the crime of murder in the first
degree, committed as follows, to-wit; that on the sixth day of May,
A. D. 1897, and within three years before the filing of this In-
formation, at the County of Spokane and State of Washington, the
said defendant George Webster, then and there in the said County
and State being, then and there unlawfully, felioniously and pur-
posely, and of his deliberate and premeditated malice, killed Lise
C. Aspland, by then and there purposely, and of his deliberate and
premeditated malice, shooting and mortally wounding the said Lise C.
Appland with a gun, commonly called a revolver, which he, the said
George Webster, then and there held in his hand, contrary to the 
Statutes- in such case made and provided and against the peace and
dignity of the State of Washington.</p>
<p>JOHN A. PIERCE.
Prosecuting attorney and 
Informant.</p>
<p>By</p>
<p>HARRIS BALDWIN
Deputy Prosecuting Attorney</p>
<p>State of Washington )
) ss
County of Spokane. )</p>
<p>Harris Baldwin, being first duly sworn, upon his oath
deposes and says; that he is the duly appointed, qualified and act-
ting deputy prosecuting attorney in and for the County of Spo-
kane, State of Washington, and that all and singluar the several
statements, allegations, matters and things set out in the above
and foregoing information are true.</p>
<p> HARRIS BALDWIN</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 13th day of May, A. D. 1897.
E. T. WHITE</p>
<p>Notary Public for the State of
Washington, residing at Spokane
Washington.</p>
<p> (SEAL of Notary Public.)</p>
<p>Names of Witnesses known to the prosecuting attorney at
the time of filing this information:</p>
<p>Frances A. Pomeroy
Andrew Aspland
Ella May Aspland
Abel Brown
M. A. Wilkinson</p>
<p>John H. Aspland
E. T. White
Jennie Aspland
W. D. Switzer
Franz Magnus</p>
<p>John M. Sempee
Mary Sawyer
Wm. C. Spence
J. E. Corbett
John Eldridge</p>
<p>Second-a- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken
in said cause in said Superior Court that the said cause coming on
regularly for trial, one N. C. Hair, was called as a juror in said
cause upon being examined touching his qualifications to act
 as a jurir in said cause, answered that he was at said time the
client of John A. Pierce who was then the prosecuting attorney for 
Spokane County, Washington, and who was then representing the 
State of Washington in the said cause, and thereupon the said George
Webster by his attorneys, challenged the said juror N. C. Hair, for
implied bias on the ground that the relation of attorney and client
at said time existed between the sad juror and the said prosecut-
omg attorney/ and that the said juror N. C. Hair was, under the pro-
visions of Sec. 345 of Vol. 2 of Hills Code of the State of Washing-
ton, which is as follows; "Standing in the relation of guardi-
an and ward, attorney and client, master and servant, or landlord
and tenant, to the adverse party; or being a member of the family
of, or a partner in business with, or in the employment for wages
of the adverse party etc., "disqualified and incompetent to 
 </p>
<p>Second B- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken
in said cause in said Superior Court, that the said cause coming
on regularly for rial one John E. Valentine was called as a juror
to answer questions touching his qualifications to act as a juror
in said cause, and upon examination of the said juror John E. Val-
entine, touching his qualifications, he, the said huror testified
as follows;
</p>
<p>Q From what you read did you form an opinion as to the guilt of 
innocence of the defendant?
A Well, as is natural when a person reads anything of that kind 
he would have an opinion.
Q Have you that opinion now?
A Well, somewhat.
Q Is that such an opinion as would require evidence to remove or
change?
A Some. Yes sir.
Q Would it require strong evidence to change your opinion?
A Fairly good.
Q In that such an opinion as would require the evidence of at
least one witness to change?
A Yes sir.
Q Is that opinion that you have now, a fixed and decided opinion
from what you have reas?
A no.
Q Assuming what you have read to be true have you, then a fixed
and decided opinion?
A Yes sir. If it was true,
Q Welll, at any rate you now entertain an opinion that would re-
quire strong evidence to remove?
A Well, it would require some evidence, yes sir. Not particularly
strong evidence; it would require some evidence.
Q It would require some evidence of at least one witness?
A Yes sir.
Q To change your present opinion?
A Yes sir.
</p>
<p>(Statemet of Facts p. 195-196</p>
<p>That thereupon the said petitioner by his said attorneys chal-
lenged the said juror John E. Valentine, for cause on the ground
of actual bias, which said challenge of the said petitioner wasthen
and there denied by the said Superior Court, to which the said pe-
titioner duly excepted and an exception was allowed. And petitioner
alleged, that under the laws of the State of Washington in force
at the time of the trial of this cause, the said petitioner was en-
titled to exercise twelve peremptory challenges; and petitioner
further alleges, that upon the trial of said cause upon the said in-
foormation he, the said petitioner did exercse eleven peremptory
challenges, and did excuse eleven jurors peremptorily.</p>
<p>Third- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in 
said cause in the said Superior Court, of the State of Washington, in
and for the County of Spokane, that on the 14th day of May, A. D.
1897, the attorneys for the said petitioner made and filed with the
clerk of the said Superior Court a motion to quash and set aside
the said information, which said motion is in writing in words
and figures as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THESTATE OF WASHINGTON FOR SPOKANE COUNTY
</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintiff,</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Defendant.</p>
<p>Comes now the above named defendant by his attorneys
Del Cary Smith, and moves the court to quash and set aside the in-
formation 
filed herein and for grounds of said motion alleges;
</p>
<p>1- That the information filed herein is not verified as re-
quired by law.
</p>
<p>2- That it does not appear from said information or from any
of the record or proceedings in this cause, that the State of Wash-
ington is entitled to prosecute herein by information.</p>
<p>3- That as appears from the information in this cause, this
court has no jurisdiction of the person of the defendant, or of the
subject matter of this action.</p>
<p>4- That said information is not direct or certain as regards
either the party charged, the crime charged, or the particular cir-
cumstances of the crime charged.</p>
<p>5- That said information charges more than one crime and in
more than one form.</p>
<p>6- That the said act or omission charged as the crime in said
information is not clearly and distinctly setforth in ordinary and
concise language as required by law.</p>
<p>7- That the act or omission charged as the crime in said in-
formation is not stated with such a degree of certainty as to en-
able the court to pronounce judgment upon a conviction according to
the rights of the case.</p>
<p>8- That said information does not inform the said defendant of
the nature and cause of the accusation against him.</p>
<p>9- Tht it has never been judicially or otherwise established,
that there was or is probable cause to believe that the said defend-
ant ever committed the crime attempted to be alleged in the said
information, and as appears from the records in this cause, on file
with the clerk of this court, the said information was filed against
the said defendant without any probable cause first having been
established and shown.</p>
<p>10 That at a pretended preliminary examination held in this
cause, on the 12th day of May 1897, before Hon. C. F. Backus, a 
Justice of the Peace, the said defendant over the objections of his
counsel was denied the rights and protection guaranteed to him by
the laws and Constitution of the State of Washington, and that said
Justice, over the objections of defendant admitted all manner of
sham, irrelevant, incompetent, immaterial and hearsay testimony
against him.</p>
<p>11- That said information does not substantially comply with
the requirements of the criminal code of the State of Washington.</p>
<p>This motion is based upon the files and records herein.</p>
<p>Del Cary Smith,
Attorney for defendant.</p>
<p>No. 771
Filed May 14th, 1897, at 9:15 o'clock, A. M.</p>
<p>J. R. Low, Clerk</p>
<p>G. J. Donovan, Deputy.</p>
<p>Fourth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken
in t he said Superior Court, that the said motion of the said peti-
tioner to quash and set aside the said information came on regular-
ly for hearing before the Judge of the said Superior Court
and upon the argument thereof, the same was overruled, to which the
said petitioner then and there duly excepted, and an exception was 
allowed by the said Superior Court.</p>
<p>Fifth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in
said cause in the said Superior Court, that the at-
torneys for the said petitioner on the 25th day of May, A. D. 1897,
made and filed with the Clerk of the said Superior Court a demurrer
to the said information which said demurrer is in writing, in words
and figures as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON FOR SPOKANE COUNTY</p>
<p>The State of Washington</p>
<p>Plaintiff,</p>
<p>DEMURRER</p>
<p>v.</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Defendant.</p>
<p>Comes now the above defendant by his attorney
Del Cary Smith, and demurs to the information filed herein and for
grounds of demurrer alleges; 
</p>
<p>That said information does not substantially conform to the
requirements of the criminal code of the State of Washington.</p>
<p>2- That the facts charged in said information do not consti-
tute a crime or public offense.</p>
<p>3- That as appears from the record in this court in this cause,
this court has no jurisdiction of the person of the defendant or the 
subject matter of the action.</p>
<p>4- That said information does not inform the defendant of the
nature and cause of the accusation against him.</p>
<p>5- That it does not appear from said information or from any of
the records or proceedings in this cause, that the State of Wash-
ington is entitled to prosecure theis cause by information.</p>
<p>6- that as appears from all the records in this cause the in-
formation herein is void and the defendant is now deprived of his
liberty without due process of law.</p>
<p>7- That the said information is not direct and certain as re-
gards either the party charged, the crime charged, or the particular
circumstances of the crime charged.</p>
<p>8- That the act or omission charged as the crime in said infor-
mation is not clearly and distinctly setforth in ordinary and con-
cise language as required by law.</p>
<p>9- That the act or omission charged as the crime in said infor
mation is not stated with such a degree of certainty as to enable
the court to pronounce judgment upon a conviction according to the
rights of the case.</p>
<p>10- That said information charges more than one crime and in
more than one form.</p>
<p>11- That it has never been judicially or otherwise established
that there was or is probable cause to believe that the said defend-
ant ever committed the crime attempted to be alleged in the said
information, and as appears from the records in this cause, on file
with the clerk, the said information was filed against the said de-
fendant without any probable cause first having been established
and shown.</p>
<p>Del Cary Smith
Attorney for the defendant.</p>
<p>No. 771
Filed May 25th, 1897.</p>
<p>J. R. Low, Clerk,</p>
<p>By</p>
<p>W. A. Monroe, Deputy.</p>
<p>Sixth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in 
said cause in said Superior Court, that the said cause coming on
regularly to be heard upon the said demurrer, and the said Superior
Court having heard argument thereon, overruled the same to which
order overmling the same the said petitioner then and there duly
excepted, and the said exception was allowed by the said Superior
Court.</p>
<p>Seventh- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in
said cause in the said Superior Court, the jury which was im anell-
ed and sworn to try the said petitioner upon the said charge
in the said information, did, on the 25th day of September, A. D. 
1897, render and reutrn unto the said Superior Court their verdict
in said cause, which is in writing, in words and figures asfollows
to-wit;</p>
<p>Case No. 771</p>
<p>VERDICT OF THE GUILTY</p>
<p>We, the jury of the case of the State of Washigton, Plaintiff</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>George Webster</p>
<p>Defendant,</p>
<p>find the defendent George Webster, GUILTY as charged in the infor-
mation.</p>
<p>Spokane, Washingotn, Sept 25th, 1897.</p>
<p>C. Thomas,</p>
<p>Foreman.</p>
<p>No. 771
Filed May 25th, 1897.</p>
<p>J. R. Low, Clerk,</p>
<p>By</p>
<p>W. A. Monroe, Deputy.</p>
<p>Recorded Journal 41, page 449</p>
<p>Eighth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken
in said cause in said Superior Court, that on the 15th day of Nov-
ember, A. D. 1897, the attorneys for the said petitioner made and 
filed with the Clerk of the said Superiorb Court, a moti on in ar-
rest of judgement which said motion in arrest of judgment is in writ-
ing, in words and figures as follows, to-wit;</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, IN AND FOR THE 
COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintiff,</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Defendant.</p>
<p>Comes now the above named defendant by his attorney's Del Cary
Smith and James E. Fenton, and moves the court that judgment upon
the verdict herein be arrested and stayed, and that the information 
herein be dismissed, and that the defendant be dischaged from cus-
today and for grounds of said motion the defendant alleges;</p>
<p>1- That the facts (page 11)</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>