<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0241.035"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Typed Submission to Court</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>

<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0241.035</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Typed Submission to Court</title>
<date when="1885-07-22">July 22, 1885</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1885-07">July 1885</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Albright, Robert</term>
<term>Arnold, Emma</term>
<term>Campbell, Alex</term>
<term>Dolan</term>
<term>Downey, R.M.</term>
<term>Foster</term>
<term>Fulmer, Peter</term>
<term>Lockwood, William M.</term>
<term>Lowe, A.H.</term>
<term>Reich, George</term>
<term>Sherman, E.H.</term>
<term>Smith, Clara</term>
<term>Walker, Charles</term>
<term>Walker, Helen</term>
<term>Walker, M.A.</term>
<term>Whitem</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Port Townsend</term>
<term>Tacoma, Pierce County, Washington Territory</term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Walker, M.A.</persName>
<persName>Walker, Charles</persName>
<persName>Walker, Helen</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Campbell, A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court For The Western District of Washington Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="#sab">transcribed, encoded</change> 
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0241.035"/>

<p>there were other persons also present; found nothing that would affect deceased a general health; heart was in its normal condition; examined cut in base of skull; wound could have been made by force of blunt instrument; the wheel of the engine could not do it; there was nothing to show that Lockwood fell in a fit; the body was in an unnatural position; it would have been difficult to lay in that position; the position was unnatural; rigor mortis setting in is extremely exceptional in case of death like this.</p>
<p>On ss examined: A part of the back of the skull was carried away; it might have been carried away from the direction of the back; the body could not have been forced--into the position it was found in--by the train.</p>
<p>The court at 4:15 p. m. adjourned to 10 a. m. to-day.</p>

<p>July 22, 1885</p>

<p>There was some delay in calling the case owing to the non-arrival of witnesses; but at 10:30 o'clock Judge Campbell called the court to order.</p>
<p>The first witness called was Robert Albright, who testified that he was a clerk at the C. R. &amp; N. Co's office on the wharf, that he kept an official record of the arrivals of steamers, and that the official time of the arrival of the Olympian on Wednesday last was 9:55 p. m.</p>
<p>Cross-examined: Could not say whether the Olympian was behind time on Tuesday night or not, but have official record.</p>
<p>Dr. Reich was then called, but it was ascertained that he was out of town.</p>
<p>The court then took a recess till 1 o'clock.</p>
<p>At 1 o'clock the court reconvened.</p>
<p>Dr. Reich, the first witness called, testified as to the autopsy performed by him on the body of William M. Lockwood, on the night of July 17th and 18th, in the presence of the <unclear></unclear> and other witnesses, <unclear>describe the</unclear> wounds on the body, and illustrated what position the body must have had at the time of being run over; the position was an unnatural one; a body could be in such a position only in one of two cases; either the person laid down with deliberate intention of committing suicide, assuming studied position, or the dead body was placed there; there were so many injuries that he could not tell whether they were received before being run over or not; the engine could not have forced the body into the position as found, and if the man had fallen, the body could not have remained in such a position; the cramped position of the remains would exclude the theory of suicide; it was the voluntary position of either deceased, or was so placed by somebody else; if the head was struck by any part of the engine, there should be evidences of it; the force of the concussion would be sufficient to spatter the blood; no brain matter exuded from the head; portion of the <unclear></unclear> and scalp being gone, would have left evidence on the blunt instrument on that part of the engine striking; the engine would strike the feet first as the body lay, but quickly running over the feet it would probably not have any effect on the brain <unclear></unclear> upon how the speed of the <unclear></unclear> after striking, to make the brain <unclear></unclear> should think a lapse of a quarter of a second, after striking the fee till reaching the head, would convey to the brain a feeling; an engine goin at rate of ten miles an hour, the time elapsing after first striking body still reaching head might cause the brain to feel; the crushing of the feet would have the effect of numbing the nerves;</p>
<p>from appearance of wound on back of head, the blow which caused it must have come from below upwards; the braking of the neck was caused in the same manner; a gurgling noise cold be produced after death, and could be heard issuing from body; the man could not have fallen in a fit.</p>
<p>At this point a bag was produced in court, by the prosecution, which contained a quantity of bloody rags. They were emptied out of the bag on the table, and the doctor was called out to examine them.</p>
<p>The direct examination was resumed: Should say the rags had been soaked in blood and water, the blood being coagulated; these are blood stains on the sack; condition of cloths indicate they were used in clearing up, catching up or mopping up blood; water must have been mixed with the blood on rags.</p>
<p>Cross-examined: Did not see the body o the man on the rail; the wounds would indicate that right shoulder had lain on the rail, left foot over right, right foot alongside of and tilted over rail; he could not fall in such a position; it is improbable that he could have done so; it is impossible to have fallen and laid in the manner as he did; if he was drunk when run over, he could not raise his head; such a contused wound generally benumbs; if the engine struck his foot and he would raise his head, it is possible the ash pan on the engine would strike his head; there was an abnormal condition of the body in this case; the brain was congested; could not tell whether it was a case of apoplexy or not; the piece of skull was broken out through concussion; the neck was broken and the bones of neck were smashed; if struck on back of neck so as to mash bones, death would be instantaneous; clots of blood in brain could have been produced in head within half hour or an hour after death by being struck; the wounds on body could all have been made by train; blood must have been on object striking the head forcibly.</p>
<p>Re-cross: Blood would flow freely from drunken man, even on a cold night.</p>
<p>E.H. Sherman testified as to the finding of the sack of bloody rags, on Sunday afternoon, and also as to the arrest of the Walkers, he being with the deputy sheriff at the time of the arrest. He said the defendants at first refused admittance when the officers and he called at the house to arrest them; one of the  Walkers lit a lamp; one of them said: "Put out the light;" through a crack he saw that the party speaking seemed excited, reached for a gun, and drew back the hammer, then the light was put out; Deptuy Sheriff Lowe said he had a warrant for their arrest; they said that a man had been sharpening a knife there that day, and they were afraid some parties would harm them; they wanted us to call someone who knew us; told us to call Watchman Kelly; we did so; they said if McKay was there it would be all right; said he was; then they opened the door; they were arrested about 11 o'clock.</p>
<p>A.H. Lowe, deputy sheriff, in detailing the articulars of the arrest, corroborated Sherman's testimony. He said M.A. Walker was the man that had the</p>
<!-- newspaper cut off -->
<p>the bloody clothes; said he recognized them as those found by Mac Downey in a box at the side of the door at the parties outside were officers.</p>
<p>Mrs. Whitem was called and testified that she was at Walker's on the night of 15th to 16th of July; on Wednesday evening was at Mrs. Walker's; the parties present when I got there, between 6 and 8 o'clock, were Mrs. Walker, Charles Walker and Mrs. Foster, the mother of Mrs. Walker; a little girl, named Clara</p>
<p>Smith, went with me; Lockwood came in first; then came Mrs. Hunter, Miss Arnold, Mrs. Mrs. Dolan and Mr. Hunter came within an hour afterward; there was fiddling, waltzing and eating; staid till about one o'clock, and left before any of the rest did; this time is mill time; M.A. (am used to hearing him called Sila) Walker, was not there; I was there all evening, Hunter went out of the house into the yard at one time, while Mrs. Hunter and her sister were going to the spring after water; it was a pretty dark night; I came to Walker's on a different road from that which crosses the track; there are two roads; I came across an old log road to the Walker house; when I left I had a lit lantern; did not see Lockwood after I left the house; I left the party in the house; when I left the party were preparing to go, and Mrs. Dolan had on her wraps; none had started to go when I left; when near my home heard voices down on the railroad track, but could not recognize the voices; understood from Mrs. Walker that her husband went to Seattle on business; heard nothing that night about husband being away; I had a yellow shepherd dog with me; Mrs. Walker asked me the next morning if I knew that Billy Lockwood was dead; said he was killed by the cars; said no more about him, but told me her husband had got ome from Seattle shortly after we had left; heard no conversation on leaving for home between Mrs. Walker and Lockwood, about the latter's staying there over night; I had been invited to the party by Mrs. Walker, who said at that time they were going to have a party, and lemonade and beer, and also said at that time that her husband was going away, and that he might be back soon or in a month; this was on the morning before the party; never had any conversation with Mrs. Walker about Lockwood.</p>
<p>Cross-examined: Live on Twenty-third near E street; al present drank beer except Mrs. Foster, the little girl and myself; Hunter drank five or six times of beer; Lockwood drank about as much; the beer was in the house and in a ten-gallon keg; Mrs. Walker drank five or six glasses of beer; all drank about that much beer, except myself, Mrs. Foster and the girl; they drew the beer out in a tin pail; the pail was on the table; turned it form the pail into the glasses; Mrs. Walker passed the beer around; both Hunter and Lockwood were out of the house at various times, but not together; between 12 and 12:30 o'clock I prepared to go; suppose it took me about fifteen minutes to go home; got home in the neighborhood of 1 o'clock; heard talking on railroad track after reaching home; saw no light, but supposed it was the other party going home from Walker's.</p>
<p>R.M. Downey testified to the finding of the bloody clothes in the sack, and laying in a woodbox next to the door of the Walker house; he examined them to see what they were and put them back in the sack  He also testified to finding one bloody rag in the brush, about thirty-five feet from the house behind a log. On cross-examination he stated that he left the sack and rags in charge of the parties present at the time of the finding, and came after an officer.</p>
<p>Peter Fulmer corroborated Downey's testimony. He said he heard Downey call out, "We've struck it," when he found the rag in the brush, on the south side of the house.</p>

<p>Court adjourned</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
