<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0473.002"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla" xml:id="mg">Mikayla Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0473.003</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">September 2, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date>29 July 1899</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Denning, J. Henry
Mason, William
Miller, John F.
Nordstrom, Charles W.
Lewis, James Hamilton
Jacobs, Orange
Spencer, W. C.
McBride, W. P.
Ellanerth, P. C.
Hart, John B.
Calhoun, C. V.
Willard, Rufus S.
Marion, A. B.
Bories, Emil
McElroy, James F.
Ayres, A. Reeves 
Walthew, H. M.
Hanford, C. H.
Ashley, M
Moors, A. N.
Van de Vanter, A. T.
Van de Vanter, A. D.
McKenney, James H.
Owrigher, B.
</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington
Washington D.C.
Seattle, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Nordstrom, Charles W.</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>State of Washington</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>James Hamilton Lewis .</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>John F. Miller</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jacobs, Orange</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court Northern Division</orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.473.003"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->

<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON FOR KING COUNTY.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION OF
CHARLES W. NORDSTROM FOR RELIEF FROM
CONDITION OF INSANITY</p>

<p> State of Washington,</p>

<p>Plaintiff, No.</p>

<p>-vs- A F F I D A V I T.</p>

<p>Charles W. Nordstrom</p>

<p>Defendant.</p>

<p>State of Washington, )</p>

<p>: ss.</p>

<p>County of King. )</p>

<p> James Hamilton Lewis, being first duly sworn, on
oath deposes and says: That for record of the preceeding in the said
matter above named and for a record of the recitals of all the facts 
connected therewith, the following is a true and absolute statement
is a complete, full and true exemplification, exhibition, and
statement of the whole record of transaction in connection with the
proceeding. That all matter of every nature whatsoever that is now
or has been a part of any record or of any proceeding in so far as 
the same has been made known in anywise whatsoever is 
herin stated, provided, except only such record as the trnacript of 
the Clerk of the Superior Court of this County has disclosed anterior 
to the datte of this affidavit. That on the day of A.D. 1899,
at the City of Seattle, King County, Washington, Charles W. Nordstro,
was duly charged upon affidavit by J. Henry Denning, a legally
qualified dependent, and due suggestion and statement by motion based
upon said affidavit was also propertly made and duly filed, duly
reciting and regularly stated charged the said Nordstrom of being
non compos mentis ; that said Nordstrom was of insane mind and un-
able to appreciate his surroundings, had no knowledge sufficient to
conduct his affairs, or understand or appreciate the extent or
nature or consequence of any proceeding being had or taken against
or for him or in which he was interested. That this deponent, as 
counsel for the said Nordstrom, duly moved the Court for such proper
proceeding looking to the ascertainment of the mental state of the
said Nordstrom, based upon and supported by the said affidavit and
charge of insanity, also that such other course be had and taken by
which judgment appropriate to the proceeding and further proceedings
consistent with the facts elicited to be had. That thereupon the Court,
in the presece of the Counsel for the State, representing the County
of King, and appearing as opposing the motion for inquiry into the
lunacy of the said Nordstrom; and said Court stated that he would
name a Commission to examine into the subject at a future day named,
to-wit: the day of 18999; that thereupon this affiiant 
as counsel for defendant arose and stated to the Court that, in so
far as the selection of a Commission for a preliminary inquiry, the
commissioners being scinentific men, was concerned, affiant favoured 
proceedings to that extent, but must not be understood as consenting 
to the intimation given out that said Commission could take upon
themselves the right to pass upon the question, or to proceed for or 
against the defendant of their own volition as a court or trial
body That affiant felt it his duty to inform the Court then and
there that nothing could be done carrying with it the idea that 
affiant was waiving such rights as defedant would have, or was 
sitting in acquiescence to the course of proceeding without taking
the due course of informing the Court as to what he thought, as
counsel for the defendant and an advuser of the Court, was proper and
just in the premises, either as to the course of proceeding or the 
course of procedure.
</p>

<p>That on the day of , 1899, affiant being present 
as a friend of the defendant, Assistant Prosecuting Attorney, John B. 
Hart, being present representing the State, Hon. Orange Jacobs, the
presiding Judge in the presence of affiant and said Assistant
</p>

<p>Prosecuting Attorney, John B. Hart, stated that he had agreed
upon a Commission of physicians consisting of five gentlemen, being
medical men, to-wit: Drs. C.V. Calhoun, Rufus S. Willard, A.B. 
Marion, Emil Bories, and the phsician attendin in the Insane
Asylum at Steilacom; that he had concluded upon the commission 
without taking the suggestions of either the said Nordstrom or his
friend or any one in his behalf, or of the state or any one in its
behalf. Affiant then publicly state that he presumed that he would be given 
notice when the said commission would be returnable whereupon and at 
which time he assured he would be given opportunity to present what
 he thought and understood under the law were the rights of the
said Nordstrom; That affiant then and there understoof the court
specifically to say to the said Assistant Prosecuting Attorney that he 
should prepare such proper order naming the day of the citation and
serve the same upon affiant, and understood the said Assistant Pros-
ecuting Attorney to assert that he would do such; and this affiant 
then and there relying upon service of notice upon him of some kind
or in some form of the meeting of said commission by which he
would be given due opportunity of presenting the rights of the said
Nordstrom, and such other motion or suggestions as to affiant would 
appear right, just as proper in the premises. That subsequently,
to-wit, on the day of 1899, the said Hon. John B. Hart, 
Assistant Prosecuting Attorney in open court upon this affiant making public statement to the Court that
upon that statement of the Court, he had been led to believe that he 
was to have notice, by reason of said statements of the Court to the
said Assistant Prosecuting Attorney, she said Hon. John B. Hart stated
that he did not so understand the Court or that he did not hear the
Court make such statement, and affiant states that in this opinion of
the said Hon. John B. Hart, and the said Prosecuting Attorney's office
representing the state in opposing the proceeding, were sincere in
their statemet thaht they did not hear the court and did not so under-
stand the court, and affiant begs to state that he under no consider-
ation either directly or indirectly asserts that the said Assistant 
Prosecuting Attorney, Hon? John B. Hart, the Prosecuting Attorney or
any of his assistants or deputies, purpsely violated the order of the 
Court or attempted to evade any duty to the Court that was incum-
bent upon them. That from said date up to and including Saturday
morning 10 o'clock of the 6th day of May, 1899, when this affiant
made his oral protest against the proceedng which he had understoof
had transpired there had been in nowise whatsoever, directly or indi-
rectly, served upon the said Nordstrom, upon this said affiant, or
J. Henry Denning, or any other person whomsoever, any notice of any
proceeding, or the time fo any proceeding, or the occasion of any
action, or the presence, or the citing of any commission, or of any
proceeding whatsoever in anywise whatsoever connected with or con-
cerning or relating to, the commission or alleged inquiry into the
 condition of the said Nordstrom, or as to the proceedings or course of
any alleged commission or body of persons, or of any proceeding of
any nature whatsoever in anywise whatsoever. That affiant as a friend 
of the said Nordstro observed from the public press, the only form
of notice or information of any whatsoever; first appearing in 
the Seattle Daily Times the following article:</p>

<p>THE DOCTOR NAMED.</p>

<p>Judge Jacobs Appoints the Commission to</p>

<p>Examine into the Sanity of Nordstrom.</p>

<p>udge Jacobs to day announced the names of the members of the
medical commission appointed for the purpose of examining into the 
sanity of Charles W. Nordstrom, the condemned murderer of Willie Mason
The commission is composed of Dr. F. L. Godard, Superintendent of the
Western Washington Insane Hospital for the Insane; Dr. C.V. Calhoun,
Dr. A.N. Marion, Dr. Emil Bories and Dr. Rufus Willard.
Court were instructed to resent in </p>

<p> "We have made a very careful examination of the prisoner  and
taken the testimony of the sheriffs and other officers in whose
custody and under whose observation the said Charles W. Nordstrom 
has been since his incarceration, and we are of the unanimous 
opinion that he is now in such a condition of mind as to be able to
distinguish between right and wrong. And as far as we have been 
able to ascertain there has been no material change in his mental
condition since his conviction."</p>

<p>"G.V. Calhoun, Foreman,</p>

<p>F.L. Goddard,</p>

<p>Emil Bories</p>

<p>A.N. Marion</p>

<p>Rufus Willard"</p>

<p>Nordstrom, in charge of a deputy sheriff, sat inside the rail
when the fice commissioners, through their foreman, presented their
report. Through the reading he listened with attention and appeared 
to smile sardonically. Possibly it was only a nevous twitching of
the muscels of his face. He refused to talk to any one in the court
room or later in his cell down in the jail.
</p>

<p> the verdict of the commission was a suprise to many persons,
even those familiar with Nordstrom's case. While most of the latter
were not inclined to believe Nordstrom insane, they were equally
unprepared to announce him thoroughly sane, and it was the general
opinion among them that the commissioners would disagree or report
Nordstrom mentally unballaced. </p>

<p>The commissioner's verdict will be final with Judge Jacobs. as he
publicly stated that he would abide by the result of the examination
and sentence or not sentence the prisoner to death, according to
whether the commission reported him sane or insane.</p>

<p>That intermediate form the publication of one article to the 
other affiant nor the said Nordstrom or this affiant, or any person or
persons whomsoever acting in behalf of the said Nordstrom in any
capacity whatsoever, received any notice whatsoever of any proceeding,
or opportunity given in anywise whatsoever for the protection of the
rights, interest, or cause of the said Nordstrom, or to bebeheard by
witnesses or by counsel or by friend, or to be present to cross-examine
or opporunity to protext the rights of the said Nordstrom against
others whose interests are adverse to the claims of the said
Nordstrom or the clients of his friends. And the said Hon. Orange 
Jacobs, before whom this affiant made oral protest against the 
proceedings and the treatment of the said Nordstrom in the premises,
stated that he had chosen said commission and instructed them ti
investigate the question of the sanity of the said Nordstrom, by look-
ing exclusively and solely to the single standard of whether the 
said Nordstrom was able to distinguish right from wrong, and if so,
to report such fact to him. That he the said Judge prohibited the
commission from being visited or attended by any one representing
said Nordstrom either as counsel or friend, likewise prohibiting the 
attendance on said commission by any one representing the state in 
anywise whatsoever; affiant says that the said commission was authorized to take
such procedure as they thought proper and in such maner as they
chose, no person being allowed to suggest testmony in behalf of the 
said Nordstrom, nor to aypear and cross-examine, or to elicit before
the said commission either the prejudice, bias, competency, incom-
petency, qualification or disqualificatio of any witess or their 
interests who did so testify against the said Nordstrom and his 
claims. Affiant states that it was his opinion and understanding
gathered from the law and the doctrines therein announced that the
office of the commission was to inquire and possess themselves of cert-
tain facts and to qualify themselves as experts and that thereafter
they were to appeard at such proper time and under such proper circum-
stances to give their testimony either before the court in a judicial
inquiry or a jury in a hearing or trial and their opinion, which
opinio together with the testimony upon which it was based being 
also before the court or a jury, and there submitted to the ordinary
test permitted by the law, and ordinary cross-examination and inveti-
gation under the rules and standards justified by the law, and said
court or jury would have seached their conclusions under the ordin-
ary procedure upon an ordinary tried or ordinary hearing in which the
life or interests of a person were involved would have been conducted.
That whatever testimony was had by the commission and the nature of it
or the facts elicited, or the course of their procedure, or the con-
uct of their inquiry being in nowise reported or preserved or know,
it is impossible that the same could be the subject of review, or re-
vision, investgation, or correction by any Judge or of any appellate
court or tribunal, which according to the rights or interests of any
person interested or involved in said proceeding should have been
accessuble and of existence, affiant therefore is unable to state more fully the facts of
any inquiry whatsoever or any proceeding whatsoever conducted by
said commission or any part of the same, of which affiant will only
state his opinion that the said commission understood that their duty
was that, however, insane defendant might have appeared, however unfit
for the excecution or the due discharge of any obligation, however
wanting in moral senses and blunted intellegence, it was enough if
by the inquiry they could ascertain if he knew right from wrong on
any subject, that then and there such ascertain,ent ended their duty,
and that alone became the subject of their recommendation. That the
tests or course which said commission took in discharging their
instructions and duties in order to ascertain whether the defendant
knew right from wron, or what basis they used as a base of right, or 
what basis they used as a base of wrong, whether one recognized by the
law, or any recogized by modern science and the law, or whether one which
would have been permissible had it been submitted to a judicial tri-
bunal, and affiant is unable to state and is unable to inform the 
court because of the utter failture and complete abscence of all
record of the proceedings, and becase of the utter refusal neglect
of the said commission to make any any proceeding of record in anywise
whatsoever accessible to the said Nrdstrom or his friends or coun-
sel. That thereafter, to-wt, on the 5 day of May, 1899, the 
said commission assuing to act as such, returned into court a 
certain alleged finding, commonly called a verdict, of their judgment
as to the said Nordstrom, which is in words and language as follows.
to-wit:
To the Hon. Orange Jacobs, Judge of the Superior Court:
</p>

<p>Your commission, appointed to examine Charles W. Nordstrom, a
prisoner now confined in the county jail under sentence of death, and
report his mental condition to this honorable court, has performed
that duty and beg to report as follows:</p>

<p>We have made a very careful examination of the prisoner and
taken the testimony of the sherrifs and other officers in whose
custody and under whose observation the said Charles W. Nordstrom
has been since his incarceration, and we are of the unanimous
opinion that he is now is such a condition of mind as to be able to
distinhuish between right and wrong. And as far as we have been
able to ascertain there has been no material change in his mental
condition since his conviction.</p>

<p>G.V. Calhoun, Foreman,</p>

<p>F.L. Goddard,</p>

<p>Emil Bories,</p>

<p>A.N. Marion,</p>

<p>Rufus Willard.</p>

<p>That the said alleged verdict and judgment in nowise finds any
fact either of the sanity of insanity of the said Nordstrom, or any
other fact whatsoeverwhich can be recognized or is in conformity to the
law as a legal finding upon any issue which in law could be legally
recognized by any tribunal recognized by the law. That there has never
been at any time any hearing or inquiry upon the charge on non campos
mentis or insanity only made against or in behalf of the said 
Nordstrom in anywise whatsoever, and at this hour and at this time
said charge so duly made remains undisposed of without investigation
conclusion or judgment in anywise whatsoever.</p>

<p>That this affidavit is made in order that some record of the
proceeding while now on the memory of persons interested may be
preserved, to the end that the rights of the said Nordstrom may be 
duly protected by such proper legal course and procedure as under the
Constitution and laws of the United States and the State of Washing-
ton would be just in the premises. That affidavit particularly wishes
to impose upon the court, or any appellate court, that speaking as
the friend of said Nordstrom, he desires to conve unequivocally
the impression and information that the said Hon. Orange Jacobs in
whatsoever course or action he took in the premises was animated and
influenced by what he belives to be the highest sense of his duty and
was a justifyable proceeding, and one which he believed shuld be duly guarded by
the law and proper notice in the premiss as was incumbent upon
The State</p>

<p>That affiant states it to be his opinion and belief that the
mistake and injustices which has arisen to the said Nordstrom and
which has grown out of this proceeding as theu now exist have
been brought about by an unfortunate misunderstanding, in that the 
court presumed that the Prosecuting Attorney would give due notice
to the said Nordstrom and his friend and counsel in order that his
right as understood by him, would be duly urged at the proper time,
and that the said Prosecuting Attorney misunderstood, or not com-
prehending the court in that direction, failed to understand that
such was the desire of the court or that such was the duty of the
Prosecuting Attorney, and no notice whatsoever of any proceeding, what-
soever was given, and no notice of any proceeding whatsoever was
permitted or allowed or in anywise transpitred by which the said 
Nordstrom's interests could have been presented, guarded or protected.
That affiant would have ventured ti appear before the court had he
known at what time the commission itended to sit or have a hearing.
That affiant had lately returned from the East and had great press of 
business affairs upon him and did not have opportunity
or occassion to go at all hours to the cour house and ascertain by
investigation whether any proceedings have been taken or not, particu-
larly, is this true in view of affiant's natural expectation that
due and proper notice would be given the said Nordstrom or his friend
and counsel.</p>

<p>James Hamilton Lewis</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 10th day of May, A.D. 1899.</p>

<p>Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

<p>Exhibit "A"</p>

<p>IN THE BALANCE.</p>

<p>Murderer Nordstrom Before an Insanity
Commission</p>

<p>"Their Finding will Determine whether he shall Die
or go to the Asylum.</p>

<p>The commission appointed by Judge Jacobs for the purpose of 
determining whether or not Murderer Charles W. Nordstrom is insane
began its itttings this afternoon. The commission is composed of
Dr. F.L. Goddard, superintendent of that Western Washington Hospital
for the insane: Dr. A.N. Marion, Dr. G.V. Calhoun, Dr. Emil
Bories, Dr. Rufus Willard. Dr. Calhoun was appointed Foreman of the
commission.</p>

<p>Before the commission began its session Judge Jacobs delivered an
impressive charge to its members. He recited the authority under
the law by virtue of which the commission was appointed; defined
insanity as contemplated by the law as being a condition of mind un-
able to distinguish between right and wring, and charged the members
of the commission to investigate ever particle obtainable
evidence which would throw light on the question oe whether or not
Nordstrom has become insane since his confinement in the County Jail.</p>

<p>Judge Jacobs laid particular stress upon the responsibility
 that devolved upon the members of the commission, stating that the
destiny of the condemned man rested upon their finding in his case
The law, he saidm did not contemplate the excecution of an idiot or
maniac, but it was the duty of the commission to determine by every
scientific test known to the medical profession whether or not the
prisoner is in a state of mind to recognize his condition and his 
impending doom.</p>

<p>At a late hour this afternoon the commission had not yet bagan
to examine witnesses, the time being occupied in discussing a mode
of procedure. It is likely that one of the first witnesses will be
Ex-county Jailer Munroe, who was in charge of the County Jail at the 
time Nordstrom was first confined. He will testify to Nordstrom's
consition at that time.</p>

<p>The sessions of the commission will be held in Judge Jacobs'
private office in his chambers, and every one is denied admittance to
the room except the members of the commission and the prisoner.
Even the deputy sheriff must remain in the ante-room within call."</p>

<p>United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington.</p>


<fw type="footer"> &amp;</fw>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>