<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0222.009">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Francis Stephen Medcraf vs. Frank T. Hodge. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0222.009</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Francis Stephen Medcraf vs. Frank T. Hodge. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-09">September 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Brown</term>
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Emery, George D.</term>
<term>Lakin, Edward M.</term>
<term>Lamar</term>
<term>Marshall</term>   
<term>Morrow, J. J.</term>    
<term>Sawtelle</term>
<term>Van Fleet</term>    
<term>Whitehead, Reah M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>San Francisco</term>    
<term>Canada</term>
<term>England</term>
<term>France</term>
<term>Greece</term>
<term>New Hampshire</term>    
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
<term>Texas</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Francis Stephen Medcraf</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Frank T. Hodge</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>George D. Emery</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-04" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON - 
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN RE. APPLICATION OF 
FRANCIS STEPHEN MEDCRAF 
FOR WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>
<p>3038
BRIEF FOR PETITIONER.</p>

<p>THE PETITIONER was convicted before REAH M. WHITEHEAD, a 
Justice of the Peace, of the crime of 'practicing dentistry' without
having a license so to do . Having been committed on such conviction
to the county jail, petitioner sues out the Writ, alleging that he
is restrained of his liberty, his property destroyed, and he is 
denied the equal protection of the laws, in violation of the Federal 
Constitution.</p>
<p>ARTICLE XIV. Sec. 1. CONSTITUTION OF U. S. (Amendments)</p>
<p>"- nor shall any state deprive any person of life, liberty
or property, without due process of law, nor deny to any 
person within its jurisdiction the equal protectino of the 
laws."</p>
<p>ARTICLE V. do do do</p>
<p>"No person - - - -shall be deprived of life, liberty or
property without due process of law."</p>
<p>ARTICLE 1. Sec. 12. CONSTITUTION OF WASHINGTON.</p>
<p>"No law shall be passed granting to any citizen, class of
citizens or corporation, other than municipal, privileges or 
immunities which, upon the swme terms, shall not belong 
equally to all citizens or corporations."</p>
<p>ARTICLE 1. Sec. 7. CONSTITUTION OF WASHINGTON.</p>
<p>"No person shall be disturbed in his private affairs, or his 
home invaded, without authority of law."</p>
<p>ARTICLE 1. Sec. 3. CONSTITUTION OF WASHINGTON.</p>
<p>"No person shall deprived of life, liberty or property
without due process of law."</p>
<p>The Gen. Laws of Washington for 1893 enacted a code which all
practioners of dentistry within the state should become licensed</p>
<p>This superseded the former enactments of 1888, and is Chap. LV
of the Laws of 1893. It provided for the examination by a competent 
Board to be appointed by the Governor, of all who desired to 
<pb/>
practice Dentistry. As a pre-requisite to such examination the 
applicant was required to present to the Board his or her diploma from 
some dental college in good standing and give satisfactory evidence
of his or her rightful possession of the same "Provided; That the
Board may admit to such examination such other persons of good moral
character
as shall give satisfactory evidence of having been 
engaged in the practice of dentistry ten years prior to the date of 
such examination."</p>
<p>A standard for such examinatino was provided and all persons 
satisfactory passing same were to be licensed.</p>
<p>The certificate or license was required to be recorded in the
County Auditors Office in each county where the license practiced.</p>

<p>This Act was amended and a substitute enacted in and by CHAP.
CLll of the Laws of 1901. (p 314-7)</p>
<p>"Sec. 4. Any person or person seeking to practice Dentistry in 
the State of Washington, or to own, operate or cause to be operated, 
or to run or manage a dental office or place for the practice of this Act 
shall file his or her name, together with an application for 
examination, with the Secretary of the State Board od Dental Examiners
and at the time of making such application shall pay to the 
Secretary of the Board a fee of $25.00, and to present him or herself
at the first regular meeting thereafter of said board to undergo
examination before that body. No person shall be eligible for such 
examination unless he or shee shall be of good moral character and
shall be present to said Board his or her diploma from some dental 
College in good standing and shall give satisfactory evidence of his
or her rightful possession of the saem; PROVIDED, This section 
shall not apply to persons engaged in the practice of dentistry 
at the time of the passage of this act who are bona fide citizens of 
the State of Washington. "</p>
<p>Provision is made for the issue of license to persons passing
such examination and for recording same and the practice of dentistry
without such license being duly issued and of record is made a 
misdemeanor punishable by fine of not less than $50. nor more than
$200.00 or by imprisonment in the County Jail for six months.</p>

<p>It appears that the Board of Dental Examiners employed one
Conover to go to petitioner's office and solicit him to perform some 
operation of dentistry upon him, in order that complaint might be made 
<pb/>
by Conover of such violation of the statute. This was done. On
such a complaint the warrant issued. Petitioner upon his trial 
before the Justice duly raised all the constitutional questions
set forth in his petition and they were overruled and his convistion
and sentence followed, Upon being committed under such sentence he 
sues out this Writ.</p>
<p>It appeared upon the trial and is shown by the petition 
that the petitioner served 5 years as an apprentice to a competent
and reputable dentist in London. that he has continuously practised
dentistry, in the employ of competent dentists for 8 years thereafter
and on his own account for 14 1/2 years since, in England, France,
Greece, Canada and for the past 7 1/2 years in the United States in
this city. That he has duly applied to the said Board for examination
and offerred to pay the fee required but because he had never 
attended any Dental College and could not produce a diploma from such 
College, he was refused any such examination and license.</p>

<p>It is insisted that the Dental Act of 1901 is void as being in 
conflict with both the Federal and State constitutions;</p>

<p>ARGUMENT.</p>
<p>THE POWER OF POLICE REGULATION of the practice of dentistry by the
State is not questioned, but this Act far transcends the powers of
the State in that particular. It is unreasonable; an unnecesaary 
restriction of and infringment upon the rigths of the individual; 
deprives him of his property unnecessarily and is violative of his 
constitutional rights. It constitutes unlawful discrimination.</p>
<p>The object of the law is the protection of the health and safety
of the public.</p>
<p>To this end, the qualifications of those who assume to practice
Dentistry are material and of importance. Reasonable tests and 
regulations to secure this and are lawful and if such interfere with 
the right to practice, they are still valid. But when they go beyond 
the line of reason and are no longer necessary nor regulative of the 
right to practice but unduly restrict that right in the individual,
<pb/>
they become in conflict with teh <del>Constitutional</del> <add>quotes</add> provisions of
the Federal Constitution and must fall.</p>
<p>If the applicant for examination is of good moral character and
has the knowledge and qualifing ability to practice dentistry, of 
what benefit is it to the public that he has or has not a diploma
from some dental college? How does the possession of such a paper 
protect the public, if the holder must pass the examination for the 
actual qualifying knowledge and ability? Why should the citizen wh o 
has come up the long road of practical experience, beginning with 
a 5-year apprentice ship and 22 1/2 years of actual and active 
practice, widely diversified and enriched with wide experience, and
who has constantly studied and kept apace with the best skill of the
day; why should  he be precluded from taking the examination test
while the boy or girl of no practical experience who holds the diploma
may enjoy that privalege?</p>
<p>It is an unfair and unnecessary restriction upon the right of every 
man to follow his profession for his livelihood.</p>
<p>True the Supreme Court of Washington has held that the provision
requiring the diploma is a reasonable. But such is not the 
opinion of the courts before whom such a question has come and is not
supported by any satisfactory reasoning. It is in no way binding 
upon the Federal Court nor any weight in construing the effect of 
the Federal Constitution upon the act in question. It is the 
peculiar province of the Federal Courts to interpret the Federal 
Constitution and in so doing they are not bound, even in conscience, by 
the opinions of the State courts.</p>

<p>Such a law (in effect) was before the Supreme Court of Hew Hamp.
and a conclusion quite opposite to that of the State of Washington
was reached.</p>
<p>STATE OF NEW HAMPSHIRE VS. PENNOYER 5 L. R. A. 709.</p>
    <p>The act there in question provided for the issue of 
    licenses to practice medicine to those who should ;</p>
    <p>either pass a satisfactory examination, or
<pb/>    
    present a diploma from some medical school etc.,</p>
<p>Those passing examination to pay a fee of $5.00 and those presenting
a diploma to pay $1.00 for the license.</p>
<p>Practice without being so licensed was made a misdemeanor and
punished by fine of $300 or less etc.</p>
    <p>"The provisions of the preceeding section (penal) shall not
    apply to persons who have resided and practiced their profession
    in the town or city of their present residence during all the
    time since January 1st, 1875, - - - "</p>
<p>This law too k effect in January 1879.</p>
<p>Parallel requirements.</p>
<p>Washington Act.</p>
<p>Persons who are engaged in the 
practice of dentistry at the 
time of the passage of this act
who are bona fide citizens of 
the State of Washington, are 
exempt from the penalties of the
act.</p>
<p>New Hampshire Act.</p>
<p>All physicians except those who 
practiced all the time between Jany. 1st,
1875 and Jany. 1st, 1879, and during 
that period did not remove from one 
town to another, are required to obtain
a license and pay therefore $5.00 or 
$1.00 according as it may be issued 
upon examination or upon diploma.</p>

<p>The Court said;</p>
    <p>"The law cannot discriminate in favor of one citizen to the
    detriment of another. The principle of equality pervades the entire
    Constitution. The Bill of Rights declares expressly that all
    government is 'instituted for the general good,' for the common 
    benefit, protection and security of the whole community, and not for 
    the private interests, or emolument of any one man, family, or class
    of men; that "every member of the community has a right to be 
    protected by it in the enjoyment of his life, liberty and property."</p>
    <p>"No one <add>citizen or</add> class of citizens can by law be charged with the
    performance of duties or be subjected to burdens not by law made 
    incumbent upon all other citizens in the same circumstances."</p>
        <p>Missouri vs Lewis 101 U.S. 22; 25 L. 989</p>
        <p>Barbier vs Connolly 113 U.S. 31: 28 L. 925</p>
        <p>Yick Wo. vs Hopkins 118 U.S. 356; 30 L. 220</p>
<p>The objection is that, "of those physicians who are declared
    by Statute, or under its provisions, are found, qualified to practice
    some are and others are not subjected to the burden of obtaining a 
    license. Exemptions from the burden is made to depend not on 
    integrity, education and medical skill, but upon a continuous dwelling
    in one place for (at) a certain time. It is an arbitrary 
    discrimination permitting some and forbidding others to carry on 
    their business without regard to their competency or to any material
    difference in their situation. The test is not merit but unchanged
    residence. For the right to continue the pursuit of his profession
    one physician is not, while another, his neighbor, whomay be his
    equal or superior in learning, experience and ability,is, 
    required to pay $5.00 . This is not the equality of the Constitution.</p>
    <p>The magnitude of the unequal burden is immaterial. If any inequality is
    permitted the discrimination might be made prohibitory, and a 
    monopoly of the busines given to the physicians who have resided
<pb/>
    in a town or city for a specified time."</p>
        <p>Citing State vs Express Co. 60 N. H. 219</p>
        <p>Mc Culloch vs Maryland 17 U. S. 4; 4 L.579
        606-7.</p>
<p><add>In <unclear/> - State v Hinman 18.Att. 194.</add></p>
<p>Note that under the present law, a man may be a bona fide citizen
of this State at the time of the passage of the Act and yet be 
practicing dentistry in some other state, and if such be true, he may 
practice here without either examination or license.</p>
<p>If he is a bona fide citizen of this state and is practicing here, 
he needs neither examination or license, according to this act.</p>
<p>It is no less an unconstitutional distinction to make the right
to examination depend entirely upon the applicant having a diploma
from some dental college. He must, under the act, possess such d
diploma to entitle him to be examined for license. His real
qualificaitons, obtained by long practice in this or any or other state or 
country, count for nothing. He may be the best dentist in the world
and yet, if he has not passed through a dental college, he cannot 
take the examination and, unless he resided and practiced here at 
the time of the passage of the act (or resided here and practiced else 
where) he cannot obtain a license.</p>
<p>The right to license is thus made to depend, not on actual
merit but upon the possession of a diploma or residence.</p>
<p>The right of the person to practice his profession is 
interfered with, not for the public benefit, nor by reasonable means, but 
for the benefit of the Dental practitioners who may be fortunate enoug
to have their diploma or to reside here at the time. Such is not a 
fair or reasonable requirement not is it the 'equality' which the
Constitution required.</p>
<p>Sec. 1977 Comp. Laws of U. S. guarantees equal rights under the 
law to all "persons" within the jurisdiction of the United Staets
and under the laws of every State. Such "persons" shall have the 
right "in every state and territory - - - to the full and equal 
benefit of all laws and proceedings for the security of persons and
property - - -"</p>
<p>The citizenship of the "person" is therefore of no consideration.</p>
<pb/>
<p>The Supreme Court of Washington has held a portion of this act to be
unconstitutional, and avoided so destroying the remainder only by a 
very forced construction of its provisions.</p>
<p>In STATE VS BROWN 37 Wash. 105. the Court says;</p>
    <p>"We feel that a court should be reluctant to pronounce 
    a statute invalid, except where its plain duty impels such action.
    Conceiving this to be such a case, we are led to declare that part 
    of the statute requiring an examination and license in order to 
    'own, run or manage' a dental office or department, void."</p>
<p>In the very same case the court cites abundant authority to 
sustain our contention here, saying; "The police power does not 
justify the withholding from one individual of a natural privilege
or right, in order that a corresponding advantage may be added to 
the rights or privileges of another. The restriction is permissible
only as a preventive of evil results reasonably to be expected 
without such limitation. Russell on Police Power pp 34.35 says; "To 
justify the State in thus interposing its authority, in behalf of 
the public, it must appear, first, that the interests of the public
generally, as distinguished from those of a particular class, 
require such interferance, and, second, that the means are reasonable
necessary for the accomplishment of the purposes, and not unduly 
oppressive upon individuals."</p>
<p>The test of those who assume to practice dentistry must 
necessarily be, not the possession of a diploma from some college, but 
"possession of the actual technical knowledge and skill peculiar to 
the study and practice of dentistry."</p>
<p>True, it may be proper to provide that the profession of such a 
diploma shall be satisfactory evidence of the possession of such 
knowledge and skill, but is it fair and lawful to exclude one who does
possess such knowledge and skill who has not such diploma? It is 
the 'knowledge and skill' which protects the public - not the means 
or place of acquiring it.</p>
<p>Common knowledge teaches that there are many excellen dentists 
in this country who have obtained their knowledge and skill by long
study and practice under competent dentists in their offices and not
in any dental college. The practice of apprenticeship of dental
students obtains in most states and in many foreign countries and in that
manner many of our best dentists obtained their technical training.</p>
<p>Does the public good require that all such shall be excluded from 
practice, or from examinations for license?</p>
<pb/>
<p>In State vs Clausen 65 Wash. 178, the Supreme Court again said;</p>
    <p>"It  is not meant to be asserted that this power (police)
    is above the Consitution, or that everything done in the name
    of the police power is lawfully done. It is meant only to be 
    asserted that a law which interferes with personal and property
    rights is valid only when it tends reasonably to correct some 
    existing evil or promote some interest of the State, and is not in 
    violation of any direct and positive mandate of the constitution.
    The clause of the constitution now under consideration was intended
    to prevent the arbitrary exercise of power, or undue, unjust, 
    and capricious interferances with personal rights; not to prevent
    those reasonable regulations that all must submit to as a condition
    of remaining a member of society. In other words, the test of a police
    regulation, when measured by this clause of the constitution, 
    is reasonableness,as contradistinguished from arbitrary or 
    capricious action."</p>
<p>Measured by this test, the statute in question clearly 
violates the constitutional provision. It is both unreasonable, 
unnecessary, capricious and unjust to that large class of dentists who 
have gained their knowledge and skill without the aid of a college
education. Do petitioners apprenticeship in one of the best
offices in England and 22 1/2 years constant practice since, count for 
nothing? Is he to be forbidden to demonstrate to the Board his 
knowledge and skill because he did not obtain them from some 
dental college? Or because he did not live in the state at the time 
of the passage of the act?</p>
<p>But the Supreme Court of Washington, in State R1.Thompson vs
State Board 48 Wash. 291-3, has passed upon this contention and 
held adversely to the petitioner. In that case the qualification 
of the Relator was admitted, save as to possession of a diploma, 
and the court refused to compel the Board to grant him examinatino
holding the statute valid. No reasons are given but the case is 
based on the decision in State vs. Thompson 36 Wash. 377, the court
saying;</p>
    <p>"The statute makes the same requirements of all applicants for 
    examination. No favored or preferred classes are created or 
    recognized. The requirement of both diploma and examination as a test
    of knowledge and skill is not such an unreasonable or arbitrary one 
    as to invalidate the statute. The right to determine what requirements
    must be met by an applicant is within the exclusive province of 
    the legislature."</p>
<p>If this be true, what force has the constitutional provision?
If the legislature determine upon an unreasonable and infair test 
which is an arbitrary interferance with the right of the individual, 
how is he to obtain protection in his right?</p>
<pb/>
<p>In State vs. Thompson 36 Wash. 380, the court bases its decision 
upon Ex part Whitely 77 Pac. 879. That case is ruled by Dent vs
West Virginia 129 U. S. 124; 32 L ed. 623.</p>
<p>Examination of the federal case will show that the statute of 
West Virginia under consideration and which was sustained, provided 
that license should be issued to three classes;</p>
    <p>(a) Those possessing diplomas from some suitable school;</p>
    <p>(b) Those who had resided and practiced in the state for 10 
    years last past;</p>
    <p>(c) Those who should pass a satisfactory examinatin before 
    the Board.</p>
<p>The possession of a diploma was made one ground of the issue of a 
license without examinatino;</p>
<p>The fact of practicing for ten years before the passage of the act 
was made another ground for issuing the license;</p>
<p>The possession of the requisite knowledge and skill as shown by a 
satisfactory examination before the board, was the third ground.
It was not made a pre-requisite to examination that the applicant 
should hold a diploma from some dental college.</p>
<p>Upon this foundation, the Supreme Court rests its decision in 
the Thompson case. The authority relied on is exactly contrary to 
its own conclusions.</p>
<p>Not a single reason is given by the State court to support its 
conclusion that the requirement of a diploma is reasonable. It is 
without a supporting case and without a single valid reason.</p>
<p>There is not and never was, in the State of Washington, any 
Dental College or any College of Medicine or other school which 
can or ever did grant any such diploma as the act requires. How is
such a diploma to be obtained? What does a main gain by getting it,
that will be of benefit to teh public, more than he has gained by
an apprenticeship of five and a continuted practice of 22 years?</p>
<p>What requirement is made of the man who was actually practicing 
dentistry and a citizen of this state when the act was passed?</p>
<p>As the court aptly remarked in the Dent case supra;</p>
    <p>"In this country the requirement (constitutional provision) is 
    intended to have a similar effect against legislative power, that is
    to secure the citizen against any arbitrary deprivation of his rights
<pb/>    
    whether relating to his life, his liberty or his property."</p>
<p>The correct rule was stated by the Missouri Supreme Court in 
STATE VS SMITH, 33 L. R. A. (NS) 187, thus;</p>
    <p>"If, under the guise of the police power, the legislature 
    unreasonably and capriciously restrains one's liberty or 
    property, the Court may interpose the Constitution and declare the
    law void."</p>
<p>So in STATE VS FISHER 52 Mo. 174, the same court said;</p>
    <p>A law which unnecessarily and oppressively restrains a 
    citizen from engaging in any trafic or disposing of his property as he
    may see fit, though passed under the specious pretext of a 
    preservative of the health of the inhabitants, would be void."</p>

<p>The profession of Dental Surgery, like that of law or medicine,
is a profitable employment, to the public as well as to the 
practitioners; The only elements of danger arising from the practice of 
them lies in the admission of incompetent persons into them.</p>
<p>"Any prohibition which extends further than to prevent the admission
of incompetent men will be constitutional."</p>
    <p>Tiedman on Police Power. Sec. 87</p>
<p>The provision in question does extend further. It absolutely 
excludes the man, no matter competen, that can not produce a 
diploma from some dental college - outside the State, for there is
none in the State. Qualifications do not matter. The DIPLOMA is 
the essential.</p>
    <p>"There is no easier nor more tempting opportunity for the practice 
    of tyranny than in the police control of occupations. Good and
    bad motives often combine to accomplish this kind of tyranny. The
    zeal of the reformer as well as cupidity and self-interest must alike
    be guarded against. Both are apt to prompt the employment of means 
    to attain the end desired, which the constitution prohibits."</p>
    <p>Tiedman on Police Powers Sec. 102.</p>
    <p>"- - - if the business is not inherently harmful, the prosecution
    of it cannot rightfully be prohibited to one who will conduct the 
    business in a proper and circumspect manner. Such an one would be
    "deprived of his liberty" without due prosess of law."</p>
    <p>Ibid. Sec. 102.</p>
<p>IT SHOULD REQUIRE NO CONSIDERATION to discover that the act in 
question discriminates against those who lack a college education
and in favor of those who are not so lacking. That the actual
possession of all the benefits which such an education would confer
is no excuse for the failure to attend such a college. It is not 
merit, but the evidence of it which separates the 'classes'.</p>
<pb/>
<p>Such discrimination is unjust and is in defiance of the 
constitutional rights of the individual.</p>
<p>In Raich vs Truax et al. 219 Fed. 273, such an infringment was 
relieved against. The state had passed an act forbidding any 
employer of labor to employ less than 80 % of qualified electors
in his work. The requirement also extended to native-born 
citizens as being the qualified ones to be employed to the extent 
specified. Upon injunction being brought to restrain the enforcement 
of this act the U. S.District Court, JJ. Morrow, Van Fleet and 
Sawtelle held;</p>
    <p>"We think the act in question denies to complainant the equal
    protection of the laws, and is therefore in violation of the 14th
    amendment to the Constitution of the U. S., and is void."</p>
<p>Quoting from the decision of the U. S. C.C. of Appeals in Tiburcio</p>
<p>Parrott, the court said; "In our country, hostile and 
discriminating legislation by a state against persons of any class - - - - 
in whatever form it may be expressed, is forbidden by the 14th amendment
of the Constitution."</p>
    <p>In Re Ah Chong (c.C.) 2 Fed. 733.</p>
<p>The underlying principle of discrimination is pointed out by the
U. S. C. C. A. of Penn. in Fraser vs McConway 82 Fed. 257, where a 
license tax was imposed upon unnaturalized foreign born persons who 
might be em ployed within the State. The court says;</p>
    <p>"The tax is of an unusual character and is directed against and 
    confined to a particular class of persons. - - The act is hostile
    to and discriminates against such persons. It interposes to teh 
    pursuit by them of their lawful avocations, obstacles to which others
    under like circumstances are not subjected. It imposes upon those
    persons burdens which are not laid upon others in the same calling
    and condition.</p>
<p>The case of Yick Wo. vs. Hopkins, 118 U. S. 356 ; 30 L.ed. 220, is 
a text upon the case at bar.</p>
<p>Under an ordinance of the city of San Francisco, chinese 
laundries were prevented from obtaining license by the arbitrary
authority conferred upon the Board. The ordinance was held to be void 
as conflicting with the 14th amendment of the Fed. Constitution.</p>
<p>The case as a whole is instructive and is the leading authority
upon the question involved here.</p>
<pb/>
<p>There are many cases wherein the United States Supreme Court has
maintained the rights of the individual as against unjust 
discrimination under the guise of police regulation. but non perhaps so
pointed or so recent as the case of 
SMITH VS TEXAS "233 U. S. 630; 58 L. ed. 1129.</p>
<p>The state of Texas passed a law forbidding the employment of 
any person as conductor of a freight train unless he should have 
previously acted as brakeman or freight conductor for two years.</p>
<p>One who had served several years as an engineer was employed
as such freight conductor and was arrested therefor under the act in 
question. His conviction was sustained by the state courts and 
affirmed by the Supreme Court of the State. On error to the U. S.
Supreme Court these convictions were set aside and the act was held 
void as an unreasonable infringement upon the right of the individual.
The briefs of counsel are full and the citation of cases is
very great and the decision of the highest importance and closely in
point here.</p>
<p>Justice Lamar in delivering the opinion of the Court said;</p>
<p>"- - None of the cases sustains the proposition that under the power 
to sustain the public safety, a privileged class can be created and
be then given a monopoly of the right to work in a special or favored
position. Such a statute would shut the door without a hearing
upon many persons and classes of persons who were competent to serve,
and would deprive them of the liberty to work in a calling they 
were qualified to fill with safety to the public and benefit to
themselves.- - - The act prescribes no other qualification for 
appointment as conductor than that for two years the applicant should
have been a brakeman on a freight train, but affords no opportunity
to others to prove their fitness. It thus absolutely excludes the 
whole body of the public , including many railroad men, from the 
right to secure employment as conductor on a freight train. FOr it 
is noted that under the statute, not only the general public, but 
also four classes of railroad men, familiar with the movement and 
operation of trains, and having the same kind of experience as a 
brakeman, are given no chance to show their competency, but are
arbitrarily denied the right to act as conductors. The statute 
excludes firemen and engineers of all trains and all brakemen and 
conductors of passesger trains. But no reason is suggested why a 
brakeman on a passenger train should be denied the right to serve
in a position that the brakeman on a freight train is permitted to 
fill. Both have the same class of work to do, both acquire the 
same familiarity with rules, signals, and methods of moving and 
distributing cars, and if the training of one qualifies him to serve
as conductor, the like training of the other should not exclude him 
from the right to earn his living in the same occupation." - - - -</p>
<p>"So that the case distinctly raises the question as to whether 
a statute, in permitting certain competent men to serve, can law
down a test which absolutely prohibits other competent men from 
entering the same private employment. It would seem that to ask
the question is to answer it,-and the answer in no way denies the 
right of the 
<pb/>
right of the State to require examinations to test the fitness 
and capacity of brakemen, firemen, engineers and conductors to 
enter upon a service frought with so much risk to themselves and 
to the public.</p>
<p>But all men are entitled to the equal protection of the law in 
their right to work for the support of themselves and families. 
A statute which permits the brakman to act, because he is presumptively
competent, and prohibits the employment of engineers and others
who can affirmatively prove that they are likewise competent, is 
not confined to securing the public safety, but denies to many the 
liberty of contract granted to brakemen, and operates to establish
rules of promotion in a private employment.</p>
<p>"Life, liberty and property, and the equal protection of the law
grouped together in the Constitution, are so related that the 
deprivation of any one of those separate and independent rights may 
lessen or extinguish the value of the other three. In so far as 
a man is deprived of their right to labor, his liberty is restricted, 
his capacity to earn wages and acquire property is lessened, and 
he is denied the protection which the law affords those who are 
permitted to work. LIBERTY means more than freedom from servitude, 
and the constitutional guaranty is an assurance that the citizen 
shall be protected in the right to use his powers of mind and body 
in any lawful calling."</p>
<p>"If the service is public, the state may prescribe qualifications
and require an examination to test the fitness of any person to 
engage in or remain in the public calling. - - - - But as the public
interest is the basis of such legislation, the testa and prohibition
should be enacted with reference to that object, and so as
not unduly to 'interfere with private business or impose unusual or
unnecessary restrictions upon lawful occupations'."</p>
<p>In LAWTON VS STEELE, 152 U. S. 187; 38 L.ed. 388, Justice Brown in 
delivering the opinion of the court, said;</p>
<p>"To justify the State in thus interposing its authority in 
behalf of the public, it must appear, first, that the interests of 
the public generally, as distinguished from those of a particular
class, require such interferance; and, second, that the means are 
reasonably necessary for the accomplishment of the purpose, and not 
unduly oppressive upon individuals. The legislature may not, under
the guise of protecting the public interests, arbitrarily interfere
with private business, or impose unusual and unecessary restrictions
upon lawful occupations. In other words, its determination as 
to what is a proper exercise of its police powers, is not final or 
conclusive, but is subject to the supervision of the Courts."</p>    
<p>After citing numerous cases the court continues;</p>
<p>"In all these cases the acts were held to be invalid as involving
an unnecessary invasion of the rights of property and a practical
inhibition of certain occupations harmless in themselves and which
might be carried on without detriment to the public interest."</p>
<p>The principles for which we contend have been announced time
and again in the many cases before the Supreme Court of the U. S. a 
and almost as often in the highest tribunals of every state.</p>
<p>The exercise of the police power must be necessary and its methods 
reasonable in their provisions and must not unnecessarily nor
arbitrarily interfere with the inherent rights of the citizen. When 
they go beyond these limits they are in conflict with the 
<pb/>
Constitution and have no validity.</p>
<p>It is matter of common knowledge that the dental society of
the State has long been most influential in its efforts to drive out
competition in that business and prevent the incoming of dentists
from other states, thus keeping the field for themselves. The law
of 1888 and that of 1893 were both fair and reasonable in their 
provisions and afforded more ample protection to the public. The sole
purpose of the act of 1901 was to keep out dentists from other states 
and make it impossible for those who had gained their knowledge 
and skill by the long, had road of experience, and who had been
unable to take the benefits of a college course, from practicing.</p>
<p>By this means it was expected to keep out a large class of 
qualified practicioners and such has been its effect.</p>
<p>There can be no valid reason given why the 80 boys and girls who 
recently graduated from the Pacific Coast Dental College in Portland
should be allowed to stand for examination to practice of Washington
and such men as the petitioner be excluded from that test. His 
skill and experience and his moral character are unquestioned. He 
has devoted his life to the acquirement of that knowledge and skill 
in the true channels from which it should be drawn. The right to 
earn his livelihood thereby is equal to any mans. He is entitled 
to the same consideration as every other person within the 
jurisdiction of the United States and the possession of a diploma from 
some dental college cluld add nothing to his qualifications to serve
the public and in no way protects the public health.</p>
<p>The following U. S. Supreme Court decisions will be found in line 
with our contention.</p>
    <p>Lochner vs New York 198 U. S. 52; 49 L. ed. 940</p>
    <p>Hennington vs State of Georgia 163 U. S. 300; 41 L. ed. 169</p>
    <p>Ohio Oil Co. vs Indiana 177 U. S. 185; 44 L. ed. 728-9</p>
    <p>Voight vs. Wright 141 U. S. 62; 35 L. ed. 640</p>
    <p>State of Minn. vs Barber 136 U.S. 313; 34 L. ed. 457-8</p>
    <p>Mugler vs. Kansas City 123 U.S. 623; L. ed. 211</p>
<p>It is sometimes said that the legislature is the exclusive judge
of the conditions to be imposed for the protection of the public 
health and safety. But these provisions must, under the constitution,
be reasonable in their nature and not unnecessarily trench
<pb/>
upon the rights of the individual.</p>    
<p>In the language of Chief Justice Marshall in Marbury vs. Madison 
1 Cranch 137 ; 2 L. ed. 60;</p>
    <p>"The powers of the legislature are defined and limited, and 
    that tose limites may not be mistaken or forgotten, the Constitution
    is written. To what purpose are powers limited, and to what purpose 
    is that limitation committed to writing if those limits may at any 
    time be passed by those intended to be restrained? The distinction 
    between government with limitedand unlimited lowers is abolished
    if those limits do not confine the persons on whom they are imposed
    and if acts and acts allowed are of equal obligation.?"</p>
<p>To require the petitioner to expatriate himself and go to some 
other state to study for three years in some dental college to learn
exactly what he already knows and has acquired by long years of 
arduous labor and study, is so unreasonable as to appear almost
ridiculous.</p>
<p>To say that mere residence and practice at the time of the 
passage of the act of 1901 dispenses with all other qualification
is equally absurd.</p>
<p>To create a class of college students and provide that no one 
else shall have the right to prove by examination his qualifications 
of knowledge and skill to practice his life-long profession, seems
so far from the justice and integrity of constitutional liberty as
to need no comment upon its invalidity.</p>
<p>It appears that the petitioner has duly applied for a license
and tendered the required fee and offerred to subject himself to 
the examination by the Board, only to be refused for want of the 
all-important diploma.</p>
<p>That he is fully skilled and qualified to serve the public in
his chosen profession, to a far greated extent than a mere college 
graduate can be. That he practiced his profession for 9 years 
before the objectionable law was passed and ever since. That he is 
of good moral character and a man of family.</p>
<p>Is he not entitled to the protection of the Federal Constitution
or is the Board of Dental Examiners and its parent the State dental
Siciety supreme and above the Constitution?</p>
<pb/>
<p>While htere are undoubtedly cases which sustain similar
enactments, they will be only found to be those of state courts and on
inspection will be discovered to be without reason or authority for 
their support and in no sense binding upon the Federal courts in 
construing the Constitutional question.</p>

<p>Jurisdiction</p>
<p>The Writ lies to discharge a prisoner from a conviction by 
a Justice of the Peace.</p>
    <p>In Re Albert White 43 Fed. 913</p>
    <p>Royall vs Royall 117 U. S. 241; 29 L. ed. 868</p>

<p>Respectfully submitted</p>
<ab>Geo. D. Emery
Atty. for Petitioner</ab>

<pb/>

    <p>ORIGINAL 
        No. <gap/></p>
    <p>In the District Court
        of the United States for 
        the Western District of Washington
        Northern Division</p>
    
    <p>Service of within <gap/> 
        this <gap/> day of <gap/> 191
        and receipt of a copy thereof, admitted,</p>
    <ab><gap/>
        Attorneys for <gap/></ab>

    <p>FILED IN THE 
        U. S. District Court, 
        Western District of Washington,
        NORTHERN DIVISION
        SEP241915</p>
    <ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk,
        By Ed M Lakin Deputy</ab>
    <p>2x</p>
    
    <p>Geo. D. Emery
        Attorney for </p>
        <p>Telephone:
        Elliottt 4606
        419 Central Building
        SEATTLE, WASH.</p>
    <p>At which office they consent that service of all
        subsequent papers, except writs and processes, 
        may be made upon them.</p>
    <p>BULL BROS. "JUST PRINTERS"</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>