<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0434.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John Bowler and Edward McCrinkle v. James H. Bennett. Final Mittimus, Exhibit A</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0434.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">John Bowler and Edward McCrinkle v. James H. Bennett. Exhibit A</title>
<date when="1888-06-26">June 26, 1888</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1888-06-26">June 26, 1888</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Emery, Charles D.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Bowler, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McCrinkle, Edward</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Bennett, James H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court for the Third Judicial District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>King County</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>FINAL MITTIMUS
No. 107</p>

<p>"Exhibit A"</p>

<p>United States of America,
Territory of Washington,    } ss.
City of Seattle</p>

<p>The President of the United States of America to the Marshal of said Territory,
and to the Keeper of the Jail of King County, in the Territory
of Washington, Greeting:</p>

<p>Whereas, John Bowler
has been arrested upon the aoth of James H. Bennet
for having, on or about the 26th day of June A.D. 1888, at
Seattle in the Territory aforesaid
having duly taken an oath before C.D. Emery ( he the said C.D. Emery
being then and there a United States Commissioner duly commissioned acting
sworn and qualified to administer oaths) that he woud testify declare
and depose truly in a certain action then and there pending before the
said commissioner wherein the United States was plaintiff and he the said
James H. Bennett was defendant, did then and there wilfully corruptly
feloniously and contrary to such oath, wilfully under oath state and testify
that he the said James H. Bennett did on the 15th. day of June A.D.
1888 at the harbor of San Francisco in the State of California, with brass
knuckles, make an assault in and upon him the said John Bowler, and him
the said John Bowler, with said brass knucles did then and there beat
and wound, the said statement by the said John Bowler then and there testified
to being then and there a material matter in and upon the said
hearing and which he the said John Bowler then and there believed and
knew to be untrue.</p>

<p>and has been examined by me, Charles D. Emery a Commissioner of the United States for said Territory
of Washington, upon the aforesaid charge <add>and the said charge appearing to be sustained</add> and has been required to give bail in the sum of 200
Dollars for his appearance before the
District Court for the 3d Judicial District of said Territory <add>Seattle</add> on the first day of the next regular term
thereof, which requisition he has failed to comply with:</p>

<p>There are therefore, to Command you, In the name and by the authority aforesaid, to receive the said
John Bowler prisoner of the
United States of America, into your custody, to remain in confinement until he be discharged by due course of law.</p>

<p>Given under my hand and seal in the City and Territory aforesaid, this
27 day of June A.D. 1888</p>

<p>C.D. Emery
U.S. Commissioner</p>

<p>(Seal)</p>

<pb></pb>
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>