<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0357.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Wu Kao v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0357.005</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Wu Kao v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ</title>
<date when="1920-11-16">November 16, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-11">November 1920</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Young, D. L.</term>
<term>Fong, Chin</term>
<term>Tung, Quong</term>
<term>Huan, Lei Chen</term>
<term>Monroe, H. A.</term>
<term>Mangels, G. H.</term>
<term>Wilcox, Eugene</term>
<term>Plumb, T. J.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Monteray, California</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Angel Island, California</term>
<term>Canton, China</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Kato, Gin</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Reynolds</persName>
<persName>Ballinger</persName>
<persName>Huston</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division.</p>

<p>No. 5652</p>
<p>Petition for Writ.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Wu Kao (Ng Go) for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE JEREMIAH NETERER, Judge of said Court.</p>

<p>The Petition of Wu Kao (Ng Go) shows the court as follows:</p>

<p>1.</p>

<p>That he is restrained of his liberty by Henry M. White, Esq. as Commissioner of Immigration at the Port of Seattle, Washington, and is within the custody of said Commissioner at Seattle, in King County, State of Washington, and within the jurisdiction of this court.</p>

<p>2.</p>

<p>The cause or pretense of said restraint, according to the best knowledge and belief of the petitioner, is that petitioner is a Chinese person claimed by said Commissioner not to be entitled to remain in the United States, and said Commissioner holds said petitioner for deportation to the Republic of China and intends so to deport him on or about November 19, 1920.</p>

<p>3.</p>

<p>That said restraint is illegal and the illegality thereof arises from and consists in the facts hereinafter set forth, to-wit:</p>

<p>(a) Your petitioner is of Chinese blood and was born in the Empire (now Republic) of China. He is not, and never has been, a laborer; but until the age of 19 years was a student, and thereafter was a merchant until about the year</p>

<p>Page One</p>

<pb/>

<p>1915 when he became assistant to the Collector of Internal Revenue in Sunning City, China, his authority extending over the Province of Quong Tung in which said Sunning City is situated.</p>

<p>(b) That in the year 1918 petitioner was appointed by the Military Governor of said Province of Quong Tung as his commissioner to come to the United States for the investigation of certain industrial conditions in the United States and petitioner, in good faith, came to the United States on said mission, accompanied by a secretary, and when so coming was in the employ of said Military Governor for the purposes aforesaid at a salary of $300.00 per month, Chinese money, and his expenses; and your petitioner came to the United States and entered the same as hereinafter set forth in good faith, intending to perform his duties as such investigator as he might be directed by said Military Governor.</p>

<p>(c) That upon leaving China there was placed in his hands a certificate from the Secretary of Foreign Affairs at Canton, China, by direction of said Military Governor of said Quong Tong Province, dated the 8th month, 9th day, Republic 7,. Said certificate stated that your petitioner would be accompanied by his secretary and bore a photograph which was a good likeness of your petitioner and contained upon its back an endorsement made at the American Consulate General, at Canton, China, August 12, 1918, by C. D. Minehardt, Vice Consul in Charge, in the following languge:</p>

<p>"American Consulate General, Canton, China, August 12, 1918. This is to certify that this passport has been issued by Mr. Loh Cheng, Commissioner of Foreign Affairs, Canton, to Mr. Wu Kao (Ng Go) who is to proceed to the United States under Commission from His Excellency</p>

<p>Page Two</p>

<pb/>

<p>Mo Yung Hsin, Military Governor of the Quong Tung Province, to investigate matters pertaining to industry. Mr. Wu Kao is accompanied by his secretary, Mr. Lei Chen Huan (Lui Chun Wan).</p>
<p>(Signed) C. D. Meinhardt, Vice Consul in Charge." (No fee prescribed)</p>

<p>Said endorsement bore the seal of said American Consulate General, at Canton, China.</p>

<p>(D) Your petitioner with said certificate in his possession proceeded to the United States and arrived at the Port of Seattle in the United States in the month of October, 1918, accompanied by his said secretary and upon his arrival the Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, referred the Department of Labor of the United States the question of the admission of your petitioner and was directed by said Department of Labor to parole your petitioner, in care of the Chinese Consul at Seattle, pending determination through official channels as to his official standing. That it having been ascertained on inquiry of the Chinese Minister to the United States that your petitioner is not an accredited official of the Chinese Government but that said legation has no objection to his admission into the United States, such proceedings were had that the Bureau of Immigration of the Department of Labor in the month of December, 1918, directed the temporary admission of petitioner and his said secretary for the period of one year, provided a bond in the sum of $1000.00 was filed in behalf of each of them. That thereafter your petitioner filed a bond with said department, a copy of which is hereto attached, marked exhibit "A" and is hereby referred to and made a part hereof. And thereupon your petitioner was admitted to the United States and has since remained therein.</p>

<p>Page Three</p>

<pb/>

<p>(e) That thereafter your petitioner proceeded to the city of San Francisco where his friends, who had indemnified the Bonding Company for making said bond, resided for the purpose of waiting instructions from said Military Governor, which instructions petitioner says he did not thereafter receive, nor did your petitioner receive from said Military Governor any remittances on account of his salary or expenses. That said indemnitors were unwilling that petitioner should leave the vicinity of said San Francisco without specific orders therefor from said Military Governor and therefore, in the month of January, 1919, your petitioner purchased an interest in the firm of Wing Chong Company, a firm of merchants doing business at New Monterey, California, and entered actively upon the transaction of the business of said firm. That for more than one year last past, to-wit: since the month of January, 1919, your petitioner has been and he still is a merchant and member of the firm aforesaid and as such merchant he has bought and sold and does still buy and sell merchandise at a fixed place of business in said New Monterey, California. That he is acting as salesman in said business, which said labor was and is necessary to the conduct thereof; but he has not since he has entered the United States, performed any other manual or other labor whatever.</p>

<p>(f) That more than one year after your petitioner so became a merchant he made application to the Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, for the release of his said bond with a view to your petitioners remaining permanently in the United States as a merchant residing therein.</p>

<p>Page Four.</p>

<pb/>

<p>That said application was accompanied by his affidavit and the affidavits of two white witnesses and by the affidavit of the manager of said Wing Chong Company fully setting forth and disclosing the mercantile status of your petitioner as hereinbefore set forth. That said application was, by said Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, referred to one Plumb, an Immigrant Inspector attached to the office of the Chinese Inspector in charge, at Angel Island, California, for investigation. That said Plumb on February 18, 1920 duly examined your petitioner and said two white witnesses and said manager of said mercantile establishment, under oath, and thereupon made report of his said examination in words and figures as follows:</p>

<p>Feb. 18, 1920.</p>

<p>"Commissioner of Immigration, Through Chinese Inspector in Charge, Angel Island, Calif.</p>

<p>In re Wu Kao, alias Ng Go, No.</p>
<p>12016/1712 (36038/5-3, "Kashima Maru," Oct. 23, 1918.)</p>

<p>Statements having been taken from the manager of the Wing Chong Co. at New Monterey, from the applicant and two white witnesses. There is a good agreement in these statements on all essential points, the only unfaborable feature being that the applicant answered, "I dont know" or "the bookkeeper can tell you," to several questions regarding the business on the firm. However, as the applicant is a salesman in the store, it is perhaps natural that he should not know definitely regarding general matters such as the value of the building, amount of liberty bonds purchased and cash on hand, etc. On matters referring to his particular duties he is in agreement with the manager; also as to names, duties he is in agreement with the manager; also as to names, duties and interests of the active members. The two white witnesses seem to have excellent opportunity to observe the applicant as each calls practically every day at the store. They state they usually find the applicant present and that they have personal dealing with him. The firm occupies one of the best stores in Chinatown at New Monterey. They have a large stock of goods on hand and the store has every appearance of being a bona fide mercantile establishment with none of the prohibited features. The manager exhibited copy of the lease for the property on which the store buildings is located which shows that a yearly rental of $90 is paid for the lot only, it being stated that the firm owns the building. He also exhibited an insurance policy covering the said building executed by the Aetna Ins. Co. of Hartford, in the</p>

<p>Page Five</p>

<pb/>

<p>sum of $5000.</p>

<p>I believe that the evidence presented reasonably establishes the mercantile status of the applicant Ng Go, for at least one year last past and that it should be conceded.</p>

<p>T. J. Plumb"</p>

<p>(g) Your petitioner states that said two white witnesses were reputable white persons, David Berwick, a United States letter carrier of New Monterey, California, and Eugene Wilcox, employed as night watchman for the Great Western Packing Co. at its premises across the street from said mercantile establishment. That the testimony of both of said witnesses and the testimony of the manager of said mercantile establishment and the testimony of your petitioner each established the fact that your petitioner was a bona fide merchant as aforesaid and had been for more than one year last past, and that said testimony established said fact to the satisfaction of said Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle; that nevertheless said Commissioner on June 9, 1920 made report of the history of said case to the Commissioner of Immigration at Washington, D.C. wherein he states that "the report submitted by inspector Plumb is to the effect that Wu Kao has been connected with a mercantile concern at New Monterey, California for the last past year," and submitted the application of petitioner to remain in the United States <add>with</add> unfavorable recommendation, upon the sole ground that petitioner was not a bona fide government official at the time of his admission to they country (United States).</p>

<p>That in response thereto the Assistant Secretary of the Department of Labor in writing directed the Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, to require petitioner's bondsmen to produce him at the station of the Commissioner</p>

<p>Page Six</p>

<p>at Seattle and to direct petitioner, if he desired to prosecute his claim, to be taken before a board of special inquiry as an applicant for admission as of the status which he, the petitioner, had when he arrived in 1918, thereby ignoring your petitioner's mercantile status as hereinbefore set forth.</p>

<p>(h) That pursuant to said direction of the Assistant Secretary of Labor your petitioner was taken before a board of special inquiry composed of H. A. Monroe, Chairman, G. H. Mangels, Inspector, and Edith M. Easter, Member and Stenographer, they being connected with the office and employees thereof and was orally examined by them and in said examination the facts concerning the mercantile status aforesaid of petitioners were stated by petitioner to said board, together with the facts aforesaid concerning petitioner's admission to the United States and thereupon said board rendered its opinion, in writing, as follows, to-wit:</p>

<p>"The applicant, accompanied by an alleged secretary, Lei Chen Huan, arrived at this port October 23, 1918, on the ex S/S "Kashima Maru" holding some sort of a commission from the military governor of Quong Tung province, China, to investigate industrial conditions in this country. Not being in possession of the certificate required by Section 6 of the Act of 1884, the application was submitted to the Department with request for appropriate instructions. The Department at first directed that the applicant and his secretary be paroled to the local Chinese Consul, if the Consul was willing to assume responsibility, but this the Consul was reluctant to do; the applicants were paroled nevertheless. Later the Department directed that final action be taken and the record forwarded for review. This was done, both applicants being denied admission. On review the Department directed the landing of the two under a $1000 bond each for one year under Subdivision 5 of Rule 5 of the Chinese Regulations. At the end of the year it was found that the applicant had made no attempt whatever to investigate industrial conditions in this country, but had gone to Monteray, California, and there engaged in the mercantile business. Toward the end of the year specified in the bond the applicant petitioned the Government to permit him to remain in the country as a domiciled exempt. This</p>

<p>Page Seven</p>

<pb/>

<p>application was denied by the Department July 9, 1920, No. 54549/498, and the instructions issued that demand be made on the surety company for delivery of the applicant at this station, and that on his arrival if he desired to prosecute his claim to admission he be taken before a Board of Special Inquiry and examined for admission as of the status which he had when he arrived in 1918. This has now been done.</p>

<p>Want of good faith appears clearly in this application. In the first place the applicant did not obtain the certificate required by Section 6 of the Act of 1884, but did seek admission on a commission issued by the military governor of Quong Tung province, which commission set forth that the person to whom it was issued was coming to the United States to investigate industrial conditions. The fact that on arrival in this country no attempt was made to investigate industrial conditions, but that the applicant instead bought an interest in a store in Monteray, and became a local merchant satisfies me that his coming here was not in good faith. This conclusion is made all the stronger because of the fact that his secretary has left for parts unknown and has forfeited his $1000 bond. Under the circumstances I move the rejection of the applicant.</p>

<p>(Inspector Mangels) I second the motion.</p>
<p>(Miss Easter) I make it unanimous.</p>

<p>(Chairman to Applicant) You have been denied admission because this Board finds that on arrival you were not in possession of the certificate required by Section 6 of the Act of 1884. The Board further finds that your coming was not in good faith, even though the military governor's commission had been acceptable as meeting the requirements of the Chinese Exclusion Law, because no attempt has been made by you to carry out the directions of your alleged commission. Do you understand why you have been denied admission?</p>

<p>A. I understand.</p>

<p>(Chairman) You may communicate with the Chinese Consul, your own counsel, Mr. Edsell, and friends if you desire. You understand you have these rights, do you?</p>

<p>A. I understand.</p>

<p>Q. You are further informed that if finally returned to China the steamship company bringing you over is required to return you as of the same class in which you came."</p>

<p>(i) That your petitioner, throught his representatives, Messrs. Edsell &amp; Dye, prior to said hearing, addressed to said Commissioner of Immigration an argument in the nature of a brief which was before said board of inquiry at the time of said hearing, a copy of said argument is hereto attached marked exhibit "B" and is hereby referred to and made a part hereof.</p>

<p>That notwithstanding the jurisdiction of said</p>

<p>Page Eight.</p>

<pb/>

<p>board to deport your petitioner was thus directly challenged upon his behalf, said board ignored said challenge and assumed jurisdiction to hear said matter and order the deportation of your petitioner.</p>

<p>(j) That thereupon your petitioner duly prosecuted his appeal to the United States Commissioner of Labor from said order of said board and the same being heard by the Assistant Secretary of Labor, said appeal was dismissed. In the course of the decision of said Assistant Secretary he stated as follows:</p>

<p>"Since the alien's stay in this country has not been under circumstances either actually or apparently entitling him to residential rights, it would seem that he can not plead an exempt status acquired here, in lieu of an exempt status acquired in China and duly certified before his arrival here. His permanent admission would seem to depend upon his possession of a Section 6 certificate. As he has had no such certificate it follows that his appeal must be dismissed, and he be excluded unless the case of Chin Fong, decided by the Supreme Court in May, 1920, which is cited as conclusive in alien's behalf, is foundto control."</p>

<p>The said Assistant Secretary attempted to distinguish said Chin Fong case by the following observations:</p>

<p>"But Chin Fong's residence had been upon pretense and under color of a residence right whereas this alien's is of record as a temporary privilege only * * * but this alien was coming to this country for the first time, was denied admission as an exempt, but was admitted temporarily for a specific purpose * * * and instead of returning at the expiration of his privileged entry, he made application to have the temporary admission made permanent, not upon proof that it should have been made permanent originally during his temporary stay in this country."</p>

<p>(k) And your petitioner shows the court from the facts hereinbefore set forth that for more than one year prior to his hearing before said board he was, ever since has been and is now, a merchant domiciled in the United States and is entitled to remain therein and that said board of inquiry had not, nor has said Commissioner of Immigration</p>

<p>Page Nine</p>

<p>at Seattle, nor has the Department or the Secretary of Labor or any other executive officer within the United States any right or jurisdiction to consider or adjudicate upon the right of your petitioner to remain in the United States; but that such inquiry, if prosecuted, must be instituted in some district court of the United States or before some commissioner of such court and not elsewhere; and your petitioner shows the court, upon the foregoing facts, that said investigation and determination by said board and by said Assistant Secretary of Labor were wrongful, unfair and oppressive in this: That the same was taken without jurisdiction and that said board of inquiry and said Assistant Secretary of Labor ignored and refused to accord to your petitioner the rights accruing to him by reason of his mercantile status aforesaid, though satisfied that in fact your petitioner has such mercantile status; and in this:</p>

<p>That said board and said Assistant Secretary wrongfully adjudicated upon the rights of your petitioner as of October 23, 1918, which your petitioner contends was a false and irrelevant issue, and in this: That said board and said Assistant Secretary were wrongfully influenced in arriving at thier concusion that your petitioner had not entered the United States in good faith by considering the conduct of a person other than your petitioner and over whom your petitioner had and has no control, and by considering their opinion concerning other applicants who had theretofore arrived at said port of Seattle bearing credentials similar to those presented by your petitioner, said persons being persons for whose status petitioner was not responsible and</p>

<p>Page Ten</p>

<p>over whose actions and conduct he had and has no control. That for all of the foregoing reasons the detention of your petitioner in custody, as aforesaid, is illegal and your petitioner is entitled to be discharged therefrom.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE your petitioner prays that a Writ of Habeas Corpus may issue herein, directed to said Henry M. White as United States Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, requiring him to produce your petitioner in this court at such time and place as the judge of this court shall direct, to do and receive what shall be ordered concerning him and that upon the hearing of said writ and on the return thereof your petitioner be discharged from custody.</p>

<p>(Signature in Chinese) (Wu Kao)</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>

<p>Reynolds Ballinger and Hutson</p>
<p>Attorneys for Petitioner.</p>

<p>United States of America,</p>
<p>Western District of Washington,</p>

<p>ss.</p>

<p>WU KAO (Ng Go) being first duly sworn on oath deposes and says that he is the petitioner in the above entitled cause and that the facts and allegations contained in the foregoing petition are true as he verily believes.</p>

<p>(Signature in Chinese) (Wu Kao)</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 16th day of Nov. 1920/</p>

<p>D.L. Young</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

<p>Page Eleven</p>

<pb/>

<p>Original</p>

<p>No.5652</p>

<p>In the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Wu Kao (Ng Go) for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Petition</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Nov 16 1920</p>

<p>F. M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<p>Reynolds, Ballinger &amp; Hutson</p>

<p>Attorneys for Petitioner</p>
<p>1503 Hoge Bldg.</p>
<p>Seattle</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>