<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0224.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Lewis Johnson v. John M Boyle, United States Marshal. Witness Testimony, Frankie Russell.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0224.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Lewis Johnson v. John M Boyle, United States Marshal. Witness Testimony, Frankie Russell.</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-06">June 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Frankie Russell</term> 
<term>Lewis Johnston</term> 
<term>Lewis Johnson</term> 
<term>Robert Tate</term>
<term>Garnett</term>
<term>J.K. Kennedy</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Canada</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Lewis Johnson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>John M. Boyle</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Hammond and Hammond</persName> 
<persName>George R. Tennant</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Winter S. Martin</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court, For the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-02" who="#AS">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>MISS FRANKIE RUSSELL,
821 Campbell Ave.</p>
<p>called as a witness, being first
sworn, testified as follows:</p> 
<p>96 Q. You live in the same house, or rather the last witness
lives in the same house you do? A. Yes </p> 
<p>97 Q. Do you know Lewis Johnston? A. Yes</p> 
<p>98 Q. How long have you known him? A. I have known him about six 
months.</p> 
<p>99 Q. Will you tell us shortly what happened on Saturday, that
would be the 4th of June and from then on as far as
you personally know about it? A. Johnston came to our house 
between 4 and 5 in the morning and knocked on the door. I
told him first we were in bed; he said it was important, that
he wanted to see Mr. Tate. I opened the door and let him in
and called Mr. Tate; and him and Mr Tate were talking and my-
self. He had a bottle of gin with him and some fancy
cigarettes and a bottle of cream, and he said that the reason he
said it was important he thought we would not let him in.
We drank there for awhile, and he asked Mr. Tate if he would
go up-town to get him some underwear and shoes. Mr Tate 
said he would. He wanted Mr. Tate to go up-town with him. 
He said "what is the object of going up-town so early in
the morning?" and he said "I have to see Garnett before
Garnett goes to bed." The rest he knows. He came back 
to the house and he drank a considerable bit, and when I 
saw this money I asked him where this money came from.</p> 

<p>100 Q. What money? A. Two fifty dollar bills. And he said he
<pb></pb> 
got it from the American Government for work in the Phillipines
He gave Mr Tate one fifty dollar bill to go up-town and buy
him a shirt and buy some underwear - no some underwear and a pair
of shoes. Later on in the afternoon Mr. Tate was going up-town
after some beer and he gave him another one of those fifty 
dollar bills; and Mr Tate said "why you have change" and he
said "Yes but I want this one changed as I am going over to 
the other side and it is more convenient to take it in smaller
denominations."</p> 
<p>101 Q. Now will you get it right down to the time when he began to
make explanations about where he got that money? A. It was
about Sunday afternoon he had a big package of cocaine and 
we allowed that he was full of cocaine and didn't know what
he was talking about. On Sunday afternoon all of a sudden 
he straightened up. He would not drink any more and he acted
as if he was worried, and I said to Mr Tate "maybe he has done
something wrong; maybe he killed somebody for that money" And
he talked about he had more money, he said he had lots of 
monye, when left our place he said he was going to leave
town; and he told us that he had eighteen hundred dollars;
told us that he made it off a man that was drunk in the 
Main Hotel bar. The man was asleep in the lavatory. He
went to raise him and he felt the purse in his pocket, and
said there were two fifty dollar bills, three ten dollar
bills, and seventeen one hundred dollar bills that the man
had in his pocket. On Monday I told him, I said "if you 
have done anything.....</p> 
<p>102 Q. Monday? He was still in town on Monday? A. Yes this was 
early in the morning. I said "if you have done anything
crooked for that, I don't want you to get ourseleves in wrong" He
said "you talk as if you would be a snitch" I said "I don't
call that snitching. I am protecting ourselves." about three
o'clock in the morning we had a nice sleeping draught 
and woke up between four and five Monday afternoon.</p> 
<p>103 Q. Given to who? A. Me and Mr Tate</p>
<p>104 Q. Just in what form was the sleeping draught given? A. He 
said he was going up-town and asked us if we would have
anything before he went, and took a glass off the stand 
and filled the glass with whiskey out of his hip and gave T-
ate a drink and me out of the same glass, and he said he
wouldn't drink his without water; and he walked into the 
kitchen and that is the last I saw of Johnston.</p>   
<p>104 Q. He didn't drink out of the glass? A. He took the same glass</p>
<p>105 Q. After you had drunk it? A. Yes</p> 
<p>106 COURT: You don't know whether he drank it? A. I don't think
he drank it.</p> 
<p>107 Q. What happened to you? A. Both of us went to sleep in the
same room and when we woke up it was between four and five
in the afternoon.</p>
<p>108 Q. That is you had slept right from between three and
four in the early morning till between four and five in the
afternoon? About fourteen hours A. Yes</p> 
<p>109 Q. Did you drink heavily yourself? A. No not very</p> 
<p>110 Q. Had you been drinking much that night? A. Not that after
noon.</p> 
<p>111 Q. And Tate tells us he doesn't drink much himself? A. No
he doesn't drink</p> 
<p>112 Q. Now is that a photograph of Johnston, Lewis Johnston? A. Yes</p>
<p>113 Q. You recognise him by that, do? A. Yes</p> 
<p>MR KENNEDY: This photograph has already been put in as Exhibit "A#</p>
<p>Your worship</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>