<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0215.048">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chung Him and Seid Yam v. Henry M. White. Record of Hearing</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0215.048</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Chung Him and Seid Yam v. Henry M. White. Record of Hearing</title>
<date when="1920-06-21">June 21, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-06">June 1920</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Lee, H. A.</term>
<term>Strench, W. G.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Ketchikan, Alaska</term>
<term>China</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Him, Chung</persName>
<persName>Yam, Seid</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Corrigan, John L.</persName>
<persName>Winston, Will H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>U.S. Department of Labor</p>
<p>Immigration Service</p>

<p>Ketchikan, Alaska, June 21, 1920.</p>

<p>William G. Strench,</p>
<p>Inspector in Charge</p>
<p>Examiner and Reporter.</p>

<p>In the matter of the arrest of CHUNG HIM</p>
<p>Departmental warrant #54821/147 dated June 3, 1920.</p>

<p>Hearing held at Federal Jail, Ketchikan, Alaska.</p>
<p>Will H. Winston, Attorney for alien, present.</p>
<p>H. A. Lee, Interpreter in Chinese.</p>

<p>The alien is informed that he has been taken into custody as directed in the above-described warrant, charging him with being in the United States in violation of law in that he has been found employed by, in, or in connection with a house of prostitution, and that the purpose of this hearing is to afford him an opportunity to show cause, if any there be, why he should not be deported to the country of which he is a citizen. He and his attorney were given an opportunity to inspect the warrant and the evidence upon which it was issued.</p>

<p>Copy of Departmental warrant is attached to this record, marked "Exhibit A".</p>

<p>Interpreter and alien duly sworn:</p>

<p>Q Inspector Strench to alien: Is Mr. Winston your attorney? A Yes.</p>

<p>Q What is your correct name? A CHUNG HIM.</p>

<p>Q Have you ever been known by any other name or names? A Charley.</p>

<p>Q Any other Chinese name? A No; that is all.</p>

<p>Q How old are you? A 65.</p>

<p>Where were you born? A Canton Province, Sunning District, village of Chung Poon.</p>

<p>Q When did you first come to the United States? A I came to the United States the 8th year of Quong Sui.</p>

<p>Q How many times have you been back to China since then? A One trip.</p>

<p>Q How many years ago? A The 18th year of Quong Sui.</p>

<p>Q Have you a wife in China? A Yes, her name is Lee She; she lives in Chung Poon village.</p>

<p>Q You are still a citizen of China? A Yes.</p>

<p>Q How long had you been working in this house of prostitution? A A little bit over two months.</p>

<p>Q You were cooking there? A Yes, sir.</p>

<p>Q Were you not aware of the fact that the Alaska law provides that any male person who shall act as an employee or servant in any house or place of prostitution shall be deemed guilty of a felony and that upon conviction of such charge shall be imprisoned in a penitentiary for not less than 2 years nor more than five years? A I did not know.</p>

<pb/>

<p>If I had known it I would not have gone there to work. Why didn't they publish it so that the Chinamen would know something about it.</p>

<p>Q How long have you been in Ketchikan? A About one year and two months.</p>

<p>Q How many different times have you worked in houses of prostitution? A Only this time.</p>

<p>Q What other work have you done around here? A I worked in Louie's laundry.</p>

<p>Q Ever arrested before? A No.</p>

<p>Q Have you any relatives in the United States? A No relatives.</p>

<p>Q Where is your certificate of residence now? A Portland with Suey Lok Hin Society.</p>

<p>Mr. Winston:</p>

<p>Q Ever since you have lived in Ketchikan, haven't Chinese and Japanese boys been working down the line? A Yes, ever since I have been here I have known that Chinese and Japanese worked in those places.</p>

<p>Q You know that that district is operating openly and publicly? A Yes, it is run openly.</p>

<p>Q Have you ever known of any Chinese or Japanese to be arrested for working there? A No.</p>

<p>Q Did you know that it was against the law to work there? A I did not know.</p>

<p>Q Did you not work there openly and everybody knew you were working there? A Yes, the white people knew I was working there.</p>

<p>Q What were you doing? A Cooking.</p>

<p>Q Have you ever been arrested? A Ever since I have been in the United States I never was arrested.</p>

<p>Summary and recommendation.</p>

<p>Chung Him is a Chinese subject, 65 years old, who according to his statements, has been in the United States for many years, and made but one trip to China which was some years ago.</p>

<p>He admits that he was employed in a house of prostitution and recommendation is respectfully submitted that an order of deportation be entered.</p>

<p>W. G. Strench</p>

<p>Examining Inspector</p>
<p>Reporter.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>