<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0149.001.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Lee Fong v. John Sullivan. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0149.001.xml</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Lee Fong v. John Sullivan. Petition</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">February 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Tonka Bajlo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Edward E. Cushman</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, IN AND FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON. 
NORTHERN DIVISION.

In the Matter of the application
of Lee Fong for a writ of 
Habeas Corpus

1036

To the Hon. C.H.Hanford, Judge of the above entitled Court. 
The petition and complaint of Lee Fong respectfully shows; That he is of chinese
birth and a resident of the City of Seattle in said District of Washington, where
for seven (7) years last past he has been engaged in the occupation and business of
a laundryman; that in the month of June last past, he leased the premises No.1410 east
Fir Street, in the City of Seattle,State of Washington, for the purpose of coverting
the same into a laundry, and therein carrying on the business of a laundry; that
upon a building permit being issued by the proper authorized building inspector, in
said City of Seattle, to whom had been submitted for inspection, and who approved of
the specifications prepared for the conversion of said premises into a laundry, he
incurred an expenditure of upwards of six hundred dollars ($600.) in making the
necessary changes, additions and improvements in and on said premises required for
the purpose of conducting said laundry business, all of which was done in accordance
with said specifications for said laundry, approved and authorized as aforesaid by
said building inspector in said City of Seattle. That after he had made said expenditures
upon said authority, a petition from certain persons was addressed to
the common Council of the City of Seattle, praying that said body should refuse its
consent to, and prohibit the establishment of a laundry, designated in said
petition as a "Chinese laundry", on said premises; that said Council, in compliance 
with said petition granted the prayer thereof and witheld its consent
to this petitioner to establish or carry on his proposed laundry upon said premises

1

<pb/>

and that this petitioner had no hearing before said Council or their committee 
having said petition in charge; that the said Laundry has been so constructed and arranged
as to be in a good sanatory condition, of which the health officer in said
City of Seattle has delivered a certificate; and that all proper precautions were
taken by the petitioner in the preparation of said premises for his laundry
business, for the protection of property <add>from</add> injury or destruction by fire.

That notwithstanding the premises, your petitioner has been arrested upon a complaint,
a copy of which is hereto attached, and made a part hereof, and that he is
now unlawfully imprisoned, detained, confined and restrained of his liberty by
John Sullivan, Chief of Police of said City of Seattle, at and in the City Jail of said
City. That the said imprisonment, detention, confinement and restraint is illegal,
and that the illegality thereof consists in this, to-wit; That said arrest and 
imprisonment &amp; Sections six (6) and seven (7) of ordinance NO.710, of the City of
Seattle, for the alleged violation of which this petitioner has been arrested,
and is now imprisoned and restrained of his liberty as aforesaid, are in violation 
of, and in conflict with the constitution of the United States, and especially
of the fifth (5th) and fourteenth (14th) amendments thereto; And also that said
arrest and imprisonment is in violation of the treaty made and existing between
the Government of the United States, and that of the Empire of China, the chief objection
and opposition to the petitioner's laundry being that it is to be conducted
by a chinaman, and that said ordinance which petitioner is charged with having violated,
and the whole thereof, isnull and void.

WHEREFORE, your petitioner prays that a writ of Habeas
Corpus may be granted directed to the said John Sullivan, Chief of police of the City
of Seattle, commanding him to have the body of the said Lee Fong before your Honor at
a time and place therein to be specified, to do and receive what shall then and
there be considered right by your Honor concerning him, together with the time
and cause of his said detention and said writ.

Done on the 2nd day of September 1902

Lee Fong

<pb/>

State of Washington,
County of King.

ss.

Before me, a Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing in
Seattle, said State, and duly qualified and commissioned, personally came Lee Fong
the petitioner above named, being first duly sworn according to Law, did depose and
say that he has had read to him the foregoing petition, knows the contents thereof
and believe the same to be true

Lee Fong

Subscribed and sworn to before me this 2nd day of September, 1902.

Frank B. <unclear>Westl</unclear>
Notary Public in and for the State of Washington,
residing in Seattle in said State.

<pb/>

EXHIBIT

Copy of Complaint.

The City of Seattle,
VS.
Lee Fong.

CRIMINAL COMPLAINT.

F.E. Bryant being sworn says; That on the twenty nineth (29) day of
August 1902, said Lee Fong did commit a mis-demeanor as follows, to-wit-
By carrying on a public laundry without any permit from City council, said Lee
Fong did wilfully and unlawfully at number 1410 Fir Street, said City of Seattle,
establish, maintain and carry on a laundry within the corporate limits of said
City of Seattle, and at said place, without first obtaining the consent of the
City of Council of said City, the said laundry not being located in a building
constructed either of brick, stone nor covered with a metal roof, all of which
is contrary to ordinance No. 710, sections 6 and 7 of the City of Seattle
entitled "An ordinance regulating the establishment and maintenance of public 
laundries and pulic was houses within the limits of the City of Seattle,
approved February the sixth (6th,) 1886."

F. E. Bryant
Sworn August 30th, 1902.

<pb/>

EXHIBIT "B"

SEATTLE, JULY 14TH, 1902.

To the City Council of the City of Seattle,Washington.

Whereas, the building at No.1410 East Fir Street is being remodeled, and by
additions and extensions is being fitted up for a Chinese Wash house or Laundry,
and said building is not constructed either of Brick or Stone, nor is there any sewer
connection, and it is dangerously near private residences,

THEREFORE, your petitioners, legal voters, tax payers or residents in the immediate
vicinity respectfully and earnestly protest against having a Chinese
Laundry established on the lot owned by Mr J. R. Miller at No. 1410 East Fir Street,
and we ask you Honorable Body not to give your permit for the proposed Laundry, 
which we believe to be a menace to health, property valuation and fire protection,
as in duty bound we will ever pray

Mrs W. T. Monroe 1404 East Fir Street, and other.

INDORSED.

Remonstrance against location of a Chinese Laundry at No. 1410 East Fir Street.
Filed July 14, 1902, By G.K. Coryell, Deputy City Comptroller.
Referred July 14. 1902 to H' &amp; S' N Com.
Reported July 21, 1902. Report adopted July 21, 1902.

Report that the Council refuse to grant the permit necessary.

J. E. Crighton, Chairman.
Mullin.
Murphy.
Rude.
J.C. Redward.

<pb/>

Tx

No. 2333

In the United States
District Court
FOR THE DISTRICT OF Washington
Northern Division

In the Matter of the
Petition and Complaint of

Lee Fong

for a writ of 
Habeas Corpus

Petition

FILED IN THE
U. S. DISTRICT COURT,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.

SEP 2 1902

R. M. HOPKINS, Clerk

A. N. Moore
Deputy

J. M. Wiestling
Attorney for Petitioner

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>