<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0180.017.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Reply Brief.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0180.017</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Reply Brief.</title>
<date when="1914-02-01">Feburary 1, 1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2628AlbertYoung&amp;KamasaburoSugiura</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-02">Feburary 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Denamore, J. B.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fisher, Thomas M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>DeBruler, Ellis</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Umeda, K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Ito, K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Saito, Hana</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Deadrich, Bertha</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Martin</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Okajima</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Thayer</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Nakada</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Young, Albert H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sugiuro, Kamasaburo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Myers, H. A. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>McClellan, R. W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Johnstone, Walter L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, G. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States, for the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division</p>
<p>In the matter of the Petition of
Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo
Sugiura, alias B.K. Sugiura,
aliens, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus | #2628
Petitioners' reply brief</p>
<p>Argument</p>
<p>We shall take but little issue with counsel for the Government,
upon the "RULE" and the "REASONS FOR THE RULE", bu which the
Court is limited in this sort of proceeding, to the one question of
whether or not the petitioners had a fair and legal hearing; and if
so, whether there is, in the record, any evidence to sustain the
charge.</p>
<p>While such hearing need not be in accordance with every 
rule of criminal proceedure, yet there are a few fundamental rules,
which a sense of propriety and common justice would dictate as necessary;</p>
<p>(a) There must be some definite and specific offense charged, 
bringing the alien within the excluded class, in order that he may
have an opportunity to meet it upon the Government warrant to show
cause why he should not be deported;</p>
<p>(b) There must be a hearing on that specific charge:</p>
<p>(c) There must be some evidence adduced which amounts to legal
evidence, tending to prove this specific charge;</p>
<p>(d) There must be a finding by the proper authorities, which
finding, in order to be legitimate and sufficient, must be based on
and fairly deducible from this evidence. A finding which is clearly
arbitrary, that is not fairly deducible from such evidence, that is
based, rather, upon the opinion of some Inspector or other official, 
<fw>1</fw>
<pb/>
to the exclusion or in disregard of the evidence or one which is 
arrived at by reason of extraneous circumstances arising subsequent
to such hearing, or upon findings based upon some alleged offense
other than the one charged in the orginial Warrant, cannot be sustained
as a fair and legal hearing; and if such is the case here, it
is the duty of the Court to sustain the Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>Our contention here is that the petitioners did not have a 
fair and legal hearing for the following reasons:</p>
<p>1. The Warrant of Arrest, which reads as follows:
"Warrant - Arrest of Aliens
That the said aliens are unlawfully within the
United States in that they have been found assisting,
protecting, or promising to protect from arrest, a
prostitute or prostitutes."
does not definitely charge them with any specific act amount to a
violation of the Immigration Act.</p>
<p>2. The Warrant for Deportation, which reads as follows:
"Warrant - Deportation of Alien
That the said aliens are unlawfully within the
United States, in that they have been found assisting
a prostitute and protecting or promising to protect
from arrest, a prostitute, and may be deported
in accordance therewith."
does not find them guilty of any specific act amounting to a violation
of the Act.</p>
<p>3. There was and if absolutely no evidence in the record what-ever,
which can be regarded as legal evidence, tending to prove them
guilty of the violation attempted to be charged.</p>
<p>4. The postion now taken by counsel for the Government in
his Brief, and which was announced by him for the first time at the
hearing on this Habeas Corpus, and which is evidently based upon the
letter of opinion of Mr. J.B. Denamore, Solicitor, appended to and
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
as a part of his Brief, not only takes us by surprise, but is clearly
a subsequent idea, and is an adroit and desperate effort, after failing
on the first, to convict petitioners in some other offense than 
that in the original Warrant, upon which the hearing was had.</p>
<p>In United States v. Sibray, 178 Fed. pp. 148 and 149,l the 
Court says:</p>
<p>"I am constrained to hold that the charge is not sufficiently
specific. It is not required that the warrant of
arrest should have the formality and particularity of an
indictment, but it should give to the alien sufficient information
of the specific act or acts which bring him within
the excluded classes, so that he can offer testimony in refutation
of the charge at the hearing directed to be had by 
the warrant of arrest in pursuance of the act of Congress
and the rules of the department. What woman is he charged
with importing and for what immoral purpose? Was he convicted
of or did he admit the commission of a crime? Was
it a felony or other crime or misdemeanor involving moral
turpitude? If either, which was it? By paragraph "b",
Rule 35, as has been seen, a fully statement of the facts
must be the basis of the warrant. It is contemplated therefore,
that facts, and not conclusions, must be set forth in
the warrant.</p>
<p>The hearing provided for should be according to established
precedent, because that is contemplated by the act
and regualtions.</p>
<p>There is no finding that any particular felony, crime, 
or misdemanor prior to entry was admitted.</p>
<p>I have gone over the testimony taken by the inspector,
and do not find any evidence that the relator was convicted
of or admits the commission of any offense which can be
embraced within the general language of the warrants."</p>
<p>Then can be no doubt, from an inspection of the record,
that the said hearing on the Warrant of Arrest was solely and only
upon the theory that petitioners had rendered assistance and protection
to some prostitute in avoiding arrest. There never was any other
idea or charge, either inferentially or otherwise, and no other evidence
adduced, than on this one ground. The very letter of information 
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
of Thos. M. Fisher, Inspector (see record) recommending this
arrest clearly shows this one idea and intention; he says:</p>
<p>"In the view of the facts above mentioned, it would seem to
me that noth of these parties are subject to deportation,
on the ground that they assisted a prostitute and promised
to protect her from arrest."</p>
<p>The charge in the Warrant of Arrest and in the Warrant of Deportation
and all the evidence adduced thereon, clearly indicate this one
charge of assisting a prostitute from arrest (see also,k letter of 
Ellis de Bruler, Commissioner of Immigration, to the Commissioner
General, dated November 11, 1913, on thee lower third of page 2 thereof),
which reads as follows:</p>
<p>He thus refers to the evidence of Ito and Umeda on this point only.</p>
<p>The announcement of counsel for the Government at the hearing
of the Habeas Corpus, coming, as it did, frankly and voluntarily,
that he had carefully searched through the record in the Immigration
proceeding in this case, and failed to find an evidence upon which
the Warrant for Deportation could properly be based upon said ground 
of assisting from arrest, was not a surprise to us, because, we likewise,
were unable to find any such evidence. But the subsequent announcement
of councel, raising for the first time in this Habeas Corpus
proceeding, the question of construction or meaning of the words,
"who in any way assists", as used in the Immigration Act and Warrant
of Arrest and for Deportation, claiming that said words were not to
be construed with the rest of the setence in which they are used,
but that Congress really meant and intended to carve out another offense,
and provide against the same, than that of assisting from
arrest, came as a complete surprise to us, and is clearly an effort
<fw>4</fw>
<pb/>
now to bolster up a failing cause, and catch the aliens upon some
other charge still more indefinite than the first, and upon which
they have not had a hearing.</p>
<p>If this is not a demonstration of arbitrary power and of
findings upon charges never made and never proven, we can hardly conceive
how it may more strongly appear.</p>
<p>This, however, being now the announced postition of the
Government in this case, we take it that our attention and Brief
need be directed only to the question of construction and meaning of
said words.</p>
<p>At the very outset it seems to us the Government's contention
in this second position is less tenable than in the first, for
the reason that said words "any assistance" necessarily must be limited
to any assistance of a prostitute in connection with her avocation.
Mr.Denamore's said opinion concedes this much. Surely no Court could
ever construe the meaning of Congress so as to subject an alien to
deportation for assisting a fallen woman to reform, or to some more
noble purpose.</p>
<p>We think that Congress did not intend to carve out or set
apart a separate and distinct offense in the Immigration Act, by the
use of the words, "who in any way assists"; but that the same were to
be construed as a part and connected with and expressed in the rest
of the sentence where they occur.</p>
<p>36 Cyc, page 1118 (g), Associate Words, says:
"In accordance with the maxim, "noscitur a sociis", the
meaning of a word used in a statute must be construed in
connection with the words with which it is associated."</p>
<p>We think a careful reading of the entire section of the
Immigration Act sustains our contention. Had there not already been
a provision in the upper portion of this <del>clause</del> <add>same statute</add> providing for other
<fw>5</fw>
<pb/>
assistance of prostitutes there might be some remote probability that
Congress intended the meaning ascribed by counsel. But in reading
the entire section, the Court will see that their interpretation is
far-fetched, and is a repetition of provisions already made. In the
following words above:</p>
<p>"Any Alien ++++ who in any way assists a prostitute
in the conduct of her avocation",etc.</p>
<p>Mr. Denamore says that the use of these words in connection
with the rest of the sentence makes "bad English".
But we claim that to use them in the sense counsel contends, would
not only make "bad English" but would be bad law, and bad punctuation,
and worse than allo, would be indefinite and absolutely meaningless,
in failing to say what sort of assistance should render the alien
liable.</p>
<p>The Court, in the case of People vs. Chicago, 152 Ill. pp.
546-552 (38 N. E. p.746), cited by counsel, says:</p>
<p>"When  the literal enforcement of a statute would result
in great inconvience and consequent injustice, and lead to
consequences which are absurd, and which the legislature
could not have contemplated, the Courts are bound to presume
that such consequences are not intended, and adopt a construction
which will promote the ends of justice, and avoid the 
absurdity."</p>
<fw>6</fw>
<pb/>
<p>Could anything be more absurd or unjust than to say that
Congress intended to punish an lien with deportation, or condemn him
as unworthy to remain in this country who "in any way assists" a 
prostitute to reform, or to get legitimate employment, or if he should
find her destitute, or sick, or injured in the streets, and should
aid her, etc?</p>
<p>In other words, even if the Court feels constrained to
adopt the Government's view of the meaning of the aforesaid words,
it cannot find any other reasonable meaning then that it was meant
to prevent any assistance of a prostitute in the conduct or her avocation.
And if this construction is now, at this late date, to be 
injected, then we contend with still greater earnestness, that the
aliens have been denied a fair hearing upon this point for the following
reasons:</p>
<p>1. This construction of the Statute has arisen entirely since the
said hearing, and the petitioners have had no hearing or day in Court
whatsoever, upon it;</p>
<p>2. If the Warrant for Arrest did not intend to charge them with
assisting a prostitute to avoid arrest, then what did it intend to 
charge?</p>
<p>3. There was no specific charge in the Warrant of any other assistance,
and the view now taken by counsel shows it;</p>
<p>4. If there was specific charge, then there could have been no 
specific finding in the Warrant for Deportation;</p>
<p>5. And if no specific charge, the evidence is all to no definite
purpose and cannot be said to apply to anything. This is not a case
where the pleadings may be amended to conform to the evidence. Hence,
it is the same thing as no evidence.</p>
<p>The Government totally failed in establishing any evidence
upon the theory that the aliens assisted or protected a prostitute
<fw>7</fw>
<pb/>
from arrest, which counsel voluntarily admitted in open Court. Therefore,
we will not pursue this branch of the case further.</p>
<p>And assuming, for the sake of the argument only, that the
Act should be construed as counsel contends, let us ask: where is
there any evidence in the record in this case, that Young and Sugiura
gave any assistance to the woman, Hana Saito, even in the way of her
avocation as a prostitute? In her affidavit she herself says that
she considered herself under arrest by Young and Sgiura. In this
affidavit she says that she is testifying substantially as she did
at the trial in the Federal Court. And yet, it appears by Young's
statement (see page 7 of the record, and statement of Bertha Deadrich
her affidavit, page 2,) that Hana testified in said first trial that
when Young and Sugiura came to Tacoma to get her, they never told her
anything about their being officers, but that she, knowing that she
had run away from Frisco, naturally supposed they were officers; but
that at any rate, she voluntarily came with them; she also says in
this affidavit that Young and Sugiura told her on the boat they were
going to take her back to the house in Frisco where she had formerly 
practiced prostitution. While the statements of Young and Miss Deadrich
and Attorney Martin all show that she testified at the trial
that she had no talk whatever with Young and Sugiura going down on
the boat.</p>
<p>We cite these inconsistencies in evidence in order to show
that while they have amounted to some evidence upon a charge of
white slavery, of which Young and Sugiura were acquitted, hyet they
do not amount to any evidence upon the charge in this Immigration
proceeding.</p>
<p>The affidavit of Washio, upon which the Government bases its
prinicipal defense in this Habeas Corpus, and which they especially
set out in paragraph IV, of theier affirmative defense, though by an 
<fw>8</fw>
<pb/>
admitted perjurer, and though bearing animosity against Young and
Sugiura, admits that he came to Seattle in search of the woman, iwht
a lie upon his lips about her being his wife; that he represented to
the hotel-man with whom he stopped, to Young and Sugiura, to Okajima,
anohter interpreter, and to Mr. Thayer, the detective, and others, 
that the woman was his wife, and that he had come to Seattle to get
her. By ingratiating himself in Sugiura's confidence with recollections
of old neighborhood and family ties back in Japan, it is not
strange that Young and Sugiura believed him and were willing to assist 
him in the effort, as they thought, to regain his wife. On the
last half of page of Washio's testimony, he testified as follows:</p>
<p>"Q How lond did you and Hana live together in San Francisco
before she ran away from you? A About five months from January 
to about May, about four months, the 7th of May.
Q Was that when she away the 7th of May? A Yes.
Q It was your intention to make her your wife at that time
wasn't it? A Yes.
Q And you wrote back to Japan to the father for permission
to marry her didn't you? A Yes.
Q It wasn't your intention to put her into prostitution
then when you came up here?: A My intention was to take her
back and live with me as my wife but not put her in a house of
prostitution.
Q And you hired Sugiura and Young to help you get her with
that idea and that intention didn't you? A I asked them to bring
her to Seattle.
Q Where did you and Hana live together in San Francisco before
she ran away? A At 1020 Stockton Street."</p>
<p>While he intimates that he did tell Sugiura that she had formerly
been a prostitute, yet all the evidence in the case tends to show
that whatever she had been she was now reformed and it was Washio's
intention, as well as her willingness, that she should go back to
Frisco and live with him as his wife.</p>
<p>The testimony of Ito and Umeda show it was not Young and
Sugiura who protected Hana from arrest, but another man, named
Nakada, and they, as well as Hana, show that Young and Sugiura's
<fw>9</fw>
<pb/>
efforts with regard to the woman ended when they landed at the dock
in San Francsico, because Ito and his wife took charge of Hana and
she went with them, voluntarily to the house, 10120 Stockton Street,
where she had formerly lived, and that Young and Sugiura merely followed
along with the party, and Hana never saw them afterwards. This 
likewise, is the testimony of the other witness, Umeda.</p>
<p>An entire perusal of all the evidence in the record, so far
as any of legal value or applicability goes, fails absolutely to show
any act or effort on the part of Young and Sugiura, either to protect
the woman from arrest, or to render her any other assistance, than a 
respectful aid which they were giving to Washio and her as his reputed
wife.</p>
<p>Brief</p>
<p>Federal Courts will, On Habeas Corpus, look into the deportation
recorded to determine whether or not there is any evidence therein
to sustain the charge upon which the persons are sought to be
deported.</p>
<p>U.S. vs. Williams 200 Fed. 541-2
(same) 189 " 917
Frick vs. Lewis 195 " 696
U.S. vs. Martin 193 " 797-8
Exparte Saraceno 182 " 957
Exparte Patterson 166 " 539
U.S. vs. Sibrary 176 " 149 <add>Supra</add>
Bouve's Exclusion &amp; Expulsion of Aliens pp. 519-545</p>
<p>In the caseof Frick vs. Lewis, 195 Federal, 696, the Court
says:</p>
<p>"The court believed that there was no evidence tending to
support any of the charges, except the one concerning the woman.
Where there is nothing to support a charge, we agree that the department
cannot rightfully issue a warrant to deport; for that would be
a clear abuse of power."</p>
<p>In the case of ex parte Saraceno, 182 Ferderal, 957, the
Court says:</p>
<p>"If there was any evidence competent or otherwise to sustain
this finding, the Court, though of a different opinion, should
not distrub it. But it is impossible to avoid the conclusion that
the real ground for the order is that the immigration authorities
think the alien an undesirable citizen, which is a class not excluded
by the immigration law. The proof, as we have seen, is that the
alien is not without funds, is young, healthy, following the trade
<fw>10</fw>
by which he has supported himself and his family for years in this
country, and is going to his brother, who has lived here for years
following the trade of tailor."</p>
<p>In the case of ex parte Patterson, 166 Federal, 539, the
Court says:</p>
<p>"A preliminary question has been suggested which must first
be considered: Has this Court authority in a habeas corpus case to
examine the record of the proceedings before the immigrant inspector
for the purpose of ascertaining whether the Assistant Secretary of
Commerce and Labor, in issuing his warrant for deportation, acted
with respect fo a matter over which he had jurisdiction? It is of
couse well settled by abundant authority that the writ of habeas
corpus cannot be employed to perform the function of a writ of error
or an appeal. There are, however, several recent decisions of the
Supreme Court holding that the courts of the United States have
jurisdiction to grant relief to a party aggrieved by any action by
the head or one of the subordinate officals of a department, when
the evidence adduced before such official, and upon which he assumes
to act, is wholly uncontradicted, and above beyond any room for dispute
or doubt that the case in any view is beyond the statutes, and
not covered or provided for by them. Gonzales v. Williams, 192
U.S. 1; 24 Sup. Ct. 177; 48 L. Ed. 317; American School of Magnetic
Healing b. McAnnulty, 187 U.S. 94, 23 Sup. Ct. 33; 47 L. Ed. 90.
Upon the authority of these cases - and many others might be cited
there can be no room for question that this court has authority to
examine the record and the evidence upon which the Assistant Secretary
of Commerce and Labor predicated his authority to issue his
warrant for the deportation of the petitioner, for the sole purpose
of ascertaining whether the evidence before that official, and upon
which he assumed to act, showed beyond any room for dispute or doubt
that this case is beyond the purview of the immigration statutes of
the United States, and not covered or provided for by them."</p>
<p>Persons sought to <add>be</add> deported are entitled to a full, fair
hearing:</p>
<p>Chin Yow vs. U. S. 208 U. S. 11.
Ex parte Long Lock, 173 Fed. 208.</p>
<p>The charge contained in the warrant of arrest and warrant of
deportation must be reasonably specific:
U. S. vs. Sibray, 178 Fed. 146.
(see page 3 of this Brief)</p>
<ab>Respectfully submitted,
R.W. McClelland
H.A.P. Myers
Attorneys for Petitioners</ab>
<fw>11</fw>
<pb/>
<p>No 2628</p>
<p>In the 
District Court
of the United States
for the Western District
of Washington
Northern Division</p>
<p>In the matter of the Petition
of Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo
Sugiura, alias B.K. Sugiura,
aliens, for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Petitioners' Reply Brief</p>
<p>R.W. McClellan, H.A.P.
Myers, and
Walter L. Johnstone
Attorney for Petitioners</p>
<p>Leary Building
Empire Building, City</p>
<p>J.L. MacDonald Company No. 183</p>
<p>Service of within Brief
and receipt of copy admitted this 
2d day of
Feburary 1914
G.P. Fishburne assistant
Attorney for U.S.</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>