<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0154.001"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0154.001</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">October 14, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date></term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Clifford, Peter A.
Long (Clifford, Williams), Grace E.
Clifford, Alice B.
Burt. J.  J.
White, W. H. 
DeLang, James
Hanford, C. H.
Ayres, A. Reeves
Matthew, H. M.
Herice, Deevnay 
Fuller, Melville W.  
Hopkins, C. B.
Stringer, John
Heade, Matthew H.
Tallman, Boyd J.
Humphreys, William P.
Allison, William B.
Norris, George E.
Huxston, R. I.
Koepfli, C. A.
Brewster, J. M.
</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Georgetown, King County, Washington
San Francisco, San Francisco County, California
Seattle, King County, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Clifford, Peter A.</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Long (Williams, Clifford), Grace E.
Williams, Herbert O.</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>White, W. H.
Burt, J. J. 
Steiner, G. E.
Sweeney
</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>
Humphreys, William P.</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.
Tallman, Boyd J.</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0154.001"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL CIRCUIT,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>PETER A. CLIFFORD,
PETITIONER,
vs.
HERBERT O. WILLIAMS and
GRACE E. WILLIAMS,
Respondents.</p>
<p>Petition for Writ of 
Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>To the Honorable the Circuit Court
of the United States for the District of Washington, Northern
Division:-</p>
<p>The petition of Peter A. Clifford respectfully shows:</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>That at all the times herein stated he was and now is a citizen
and resident of the State of California, and that respon-
dents are and for more than eight months last past have been
citizens and residents of the State of Washington, in the 
County of King.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>That on the 17th day of October, A. D. 1899, one Grace E.
Long was a citizen and resident of the State of California, and
on that day your petitioner and the said Grace E. Long, at the
City and County of San Francisco, in the said State of Califor-
nia, intermarried, and bacame husband and wife, and the said
Grace E. Long thereby became Grace E. Clifford.</p>
<p>III.</p>
<p>That thereafter your petitioner and his said wife lived
together in the City and County of San Francisco, State of Cal-
ifornia until about the 7th day of March, A. D. 1901, and
that on or about the said last named day the said Grace E. Clif-
ford deserted and abandoned your petitioner without any just cause
and without his consent.
</p>
<p>IV.</p>
<p>That during the marriage of your petitioner and the said
Grace E. Clifford, there was born to them, as the issue of said
marriage, a female child, now living, and of the age of four
years, named Alice B. Clifford.</p>
<p>V.</p>
<p>That on the 24th day of March, A. D. 1902, the said Grace E.
Cliffored commenced an action in the Superior Court in and for
the City and County of San Francisco, State of California, for
an absolute divorce from your petitioner, and therein prayed
for the custody of said child of said mariage, and your petit-
ioner appeared in said action and filed his answer, and also a
cross-complaint for a divorce from said Grace E. Clifford there-
in, and in said cross-complaint prayed that the custody of said
child should be awarded to him by said Court.</p>
<p>VI.</p>
<p>That thereafter such proceedings were had in such action
and cross-action that the judgment of said court was given, made and
entered therein, denying a divorce to said Grace E. Clifford and
granting a divorce to your petitioner, and awarding the custody
of said child to said Grace E. Clifford until the further order
of the court; and providing that your petitioner should be al-
lowed to see said child once a week and to take the same out
with him once in every two weeks.</p>
<p>VII.</p>
<p>That at the time of the commencement of said action and from
thenoe on down and including the time of the entry of said judg-
ment, your petitioner, thhe said Grace E. Clifford, and said 
child were all citizens and bona fide residents of the said City
and County of San Francisco, in said State of California, and
actually present therein, and your petitioner and the said Grace
E. Clifford had been such citizens and residents of said City
and County continuously since the date of their said marriage,
and said child had been such citizen and resident continuously
since the date of her birth, and within the jurisdiction of said
Superior Court in said acion and cross-section, and said Superior
Court was then and yet is a court of record and of superior jur-
isdiction.</p>
<p>VIII.</p>
<p>That after the date of entry of said judgment by said
Superior Court, the said Grace E. Clifford continued to reside
in said City and County of San Francisco until some time in 
September, A. D. 1903, the exact time being unknown to your
petitioner, and that during said moth she secretly and surrepti-
tiously and without the permission of said Superior Court,
and in contempt thereof, and without the knowledge or consent
of your petitioner, took said child out of the State of Califor-
nia.</p>
<p>IX.</p>
<p>That on the 27th day of November, A. D. 1903, your petition-
er fled in said Superior Court a verified petition in said ac-
tion and cross-action for a modification of the judgment there-
in by taking away from the custody of the said Grace E. Clifford
the said child and awarding the custody thereof to your petit-
ioner, and such proceedings were thereupon had that an order was
made and entered therein modifying and changing said judgment
and taking the custody of said child from said Grace E. Clifford
 and awarding the same to your petitioner until the further order
of the said Superior Court, and said order ever since has been
and still is standing and not set aside, and in full force and
effect, and under the laws of the State of California, at the 
time of the commencement of said action, and at the time of the 
entry of said judgment, and at the time of the making of the
said order, said child was a ward of said Court and under the 
control thereof; and it is provided by the laws of the said
State that said Court could at any tme after the entry of said
judgment make any order with or without notice modifyig said
judgmet as to the custody of said child.</p>
<p>X.</p>
<p>That since the said judgment of divorce, the said Grace E.
Clifford and one Herbert O. Williams above named, intermarried
in said State of California, and became and ever since have
been and now are husband and wife and evrer since their
said marriage have had in the State of California and elsewhere
and now at the town of Georgetown, in said County of King,
saod child in their custody and posession.</p>
<p>XI.</p>
<p>That on the 19th day of January, 1904, at the said town of
Georgetown, your petitioner presented to the said Herbet O.
Williams and also to the said Grace E. Williams, a copy of the
record and proceedings of the said Superior Court of said City
and County of San Francisco, in said acion and cross-section,
certified under and in pursuance of an Act of the Congress of
the United Sates in such case made and provided, and demanded
from them and eachof them the immediate delivery of the said
child to him, said petitioner, but they refused and still do 
refuse to give up said child, and said child ever since has been
and now is imprisoned and restrained of her liberty by them at 
said town of Georgettown, and that according to the best of your
petitioner's knowledge and belief, the cause of pretense of the
aforesaid confinement or restraint of the said child, Alice B.
Clifford, is that under the said judgment of said Superior Court
of said City and County of San Francisco, the custody of said
child was given to said Grace E. Clifford, now Grace E. Williams,
umtil further order of the Court, and that after she took said
child beyond the limits of said State of California, as afore-
saod, said Superior Court lost all jurisdiction to make any fur-
ther order in said action and cross-section in regard to any mod-
ification of said judgment as to the custody of said child, and
that she had the right to take said child beyond the jurisdic-
tion of the State of California without first obtaining therefor
the permission of said Court, and that after said child was
taken into said State of Washington said Herbet O. Williams
and without the knowledge or consent of said Superior Court of
said City and County of San Francisco, and without giving any
notice thereof, undertook, under the laws of the said State of
Washington, to adpot said child as husband and wife, as theor
own. And your petitioner further states that he believes and
therefore alleges, ad he is advised by counsel W. H. White, Esq.,
residing at the City of Seattle, State of Washington, and J. J. 
Burt, Esq., residing at the City and County of San Francisco,
State of California, that the said imprisonment of the said
child, Alice B, Clifford, is illegal, and that the illegality
consists in this, to-wit:-
</p>
<p>That said Superior Court of the said City and County of San
Francisco had jurisdiction under the laws of the State of Calif-
ornia, to award the custody of said child upon the fact here-
onbefore alleged until the further order of that Court, and to
thereinafter change and modify the judgment as to the custody
of said child with or without notice to any or either of the 
parties to said action, and that the said Grace E. Williams and 
Herbert O. Williams had no, nor had either of them any, right or 
power under the laws of California, to remove said child from
the State of California or change its placee of residence there-
from to any other place without the permission of said Superior
Court of said City and County of San Francisco, and that under
Art. IV, Sec 1 of the Constitution of the United States, and
Section 905 Revised statutes if the United States enacted i
pursuance thereof, full faith and credit must be given in the
State of Washington to the acts and proceedings of said Super-
ior Court of the City and County of San Francisco, and all per-
sons and courts must recognize the petitioner's right to the
custody of said child under said order in said State of Washing-
ton; as wel as under the laws of commity existing between
said State of Washington and said State of California; and that
also under the laws of Washington said attempted adpotion was
illegal and void, for the reason thar there is no provision
in the laws of Washington authorizing any person to adopt hi
or her own legitimate child by birth, and that under the laws of
the State of Washington there is no provision allowing or permit-
ing a woman who has married again to consent to or permir
the adoption of any child which she may have had by her first
husband and from whom she has been divorced, and that the con
sent given by Grace E. Williams for the adoption of said 
child and said adoption proceedings was given to its adoption
by herself and the said Herbert O. Williams, and not to the said
Herbert O. Williams, with whom she was at the time living as her
husband, alone. </p>
<p>XIII.</p>
<p>And your petitioner further states that there is danger
that the said Herbet O. Willliams and the said Grace E. Wil-
liams will take or send the said child out of the jurisdiction
of this court, from the fact that they secret;y, and without
the permission of the saodd Court in the City and County of
</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford
Petitioner.</p>
<p>W H White
J. J. Burt,
Co Counsil.</p>
<p>ting a woman when she has married again to consent to or permit
the adoption of any child which she have had by her first
husband and from whom she has been divorced, and that the con
sent given by said Grace E. Williams for the adoption of said
child and said adoption proceedings was given to its adoption
by herself and the said Herbet O. Williams, and not to the said
Herbert O. Williams, with whom she was at the time living as her
husband, alone.</p>
<p>XII.</p>
<p>And your petitioner further states that there is danger
that the said Herbet O. Williams and the said Grace E. Wil-
liams will take or send the said child out of the jurisdiction
of this court, from the fact that they secretly, and without 
the permission of the said Court in the City and County of 
San Fracisco, and in contempt thereof, took said child be-
yond the limits of the State of California. </p>
<p>WHEREFORE, your Petitioner set up and claims, upon the fore-
going facts set out in this petition, under the said Article
IV., Section I, of the Constiution of the United States and
Section 905 of the Revised Statutes of the United States, the
right to the immediate custody of said child Alice B. Clifford
to be taken back, and restored, to the jurisdiction of the
Superior Court of City and County of San Francisco, State 
of California, and prays a writ of habeas corps directed to
the said Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams commanding them to bring up the
body of the said child, Alice B. Clifford, to abide such order
as your Honor may make, and that also a warrant issue to the
marshal of the Untied States for this District commanding him
to take said child into his cusotdy and to hold the same in his
custody until the final determination of this petition.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford
Petitioner.</p>
<p>W H White
Attorney for Peitioner
J. J. Burt
Of Counsil.</p>
<p>State of California, )
)ss.
City and County of San Francisco )
</p>
<p>Peter A, Clifford,  being first duly sworn, on his oath
deposes and says:</p>
<p>I am the petitioner in the above entitled cause; I
have read the foregoing petition, know the contents thereof,
and verily believe the same to be true.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 3rd day of June, A. D. 1904
James DeLang
Commissioner for Washington
in San Francisco, California.</p>
<p>Upon reading and filing the foregoing petition, verified by
the petitioner, whereby it appears that Alice B. Clifford is
illegally imprisionmented restrained of her liberty by Herbert
O. Williams and Grace E. Williams at the town of Georgetown,
County of King, State of Washington, and stating wherein the il-
legality consists, from which it appears to me that a writ of
habeas corpus should issue;</p>
<p>IT IS ORDERED: That a writ of habeas corpus issue out of
and under the seal of the above named Circuit Court, directed to
the said Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams, commanding
them and each of them to have the body of Alice B. Clifford be-
fore me on the 9th day of June A. D. 1904, at the hour
of ten o'clock A. M., at the Court room of the said Court
in the City of Seattle, State of Washington, to do and receive
what shall then and there be considered concerning the said
Alice B. Cliffordm together with the time and cause of her de-
tention, and that they have then and there the said writ.</p>
<p>It further appearing that there is good reason to believe
that said Alice B. Clifford will be carried out of and beyond
the jurisdiction of said Court, it is ordered that a warrant
issue out of and under the seal of said court to the marshal of
said District commanding him to take the said Alice B. Clifford
and to hold her in custody until the determination of said pe-
tition.</p>
<p>Dated, June 7th 1904.</p>
<p>C. H. Hanford
Judge.</p>
<p>No. 1204 Tx
IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED
STATES, FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASH-
INGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>PETER A. CLIFFORD,
Petitioner,</p>
<p>vs.
HERBERT O. WILLIAMS and
GRACE E. WILLIAMS,
Respondents.</p>
<p>PETITION FOR WRIT OF HABEAS
CORPUS.
Order</p>
<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JUN 7 1904
A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk
H. M. Matthew
Deputy.</p>
<p>W. H White
ATTORNEY- AT- LAW
SAVINGS UNION BUILDING
530 California Street, SAN FRANSISCO, CAL.
J. J. Burt;
Co Counsil.</p>
<p>United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington.
</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford
Petitioner
vs.
HO. Williams et al.
No. 1204
Appearance</p>
<p>To the Clerk of the above Entitled Court:
You will please enter our appearance as attorneys
for Petitioner
in the above entitled cause
W. H. White
J. J. Burt
NOTICE.- Attorneys will please endorse their own Filings. Rule 47.</p>
<p>GoB 8-103.
No. 1204 Tx
United States Circuit Court
District of Washington.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford
Petitioner
vs.
HO. Williams et al.
Appearance
Filed FILED IN THE 
U. S. Circuit Court, 190
JUN 7 1904 Clerk
A. Reeves Ayres, Clerk.
HM Matthew
Deputy Clerk</p>
<p>W. H. White
JJ Burt.
Petitioner
order on petitioner.</p>
<p>United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington.
Peter A. Clifford
vs.
Herbert O Williams 
et. al</p>
<p>No. 1204
Appearance</p>
<p>To the Clerk of the above Entitled Court:
You will please enter Our appearance as attorneys
for Referendants
in the above entitled cause
Sweeney <unclear></unclear>
NOTICE.- Attorneys will please endorse their own Filings. Rule 47.</p>
<p>GOB 8-108
10 pd
Tx
no. 1204
United States Circuit Court
District of Washington.
</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford
Pet
vs.
Herert O. Williams
Ref
Appearance
Filed FILED IN THE 
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON. 
190
JUN 9 1904 Clerk
A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk
HM Matthew
Deputy Deputy Clerk
Sweeney <unclear></unclear>
Attys
For Ref</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES , NINTH JUDICIAL 
CIRCUIT, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.
</p>
<p>Peter A, Clifford,
Petitioner
vs.
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>
<p>The President of the United States of America to Herbet O.
Williams and Grace E. Williams, G r e e t i n g :
</p>
<p>We command you that you have the body of Alice B. Clifford,
now held by you in illegal custody and detention, as it is said,
together with the time and cause of such detention, by whatso-
ever name the said Alice B. Clifford shall be called before the
above named Court, at the 
court room of said court in the City of Seattle, County of King,
State of Washington, on the 9th day of June 1904, at 10
o'clock A. M. of said day, to do and receive what shall then
and there be considered and determined concerning the said Alice
B. Clifford, and that you have then and there this writ.</p>
<p>WITNESS the HONORABLE Melville W. Fuller, Chief Justice of
the United States, this 7th day of June, A. D. 1904.
A. Revees Ayres
Clerk.
By HM Matthew
Deputy Clerk.</p>
<p>Form No. 282. RETURN ON SERVICE OF WRIT.
United States of America, )
DISTRICT OF WASH) ss.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that I served the annexed Writ of Habeas
Corpus on the therein-named Grace E. Williams
by handing to and leaving a true and correct copy thereof with Grace E. Williams
personally
at Georgetown in said District on the 8 day of
June , A. D. 190</p>
<p>Marshals for
service 6.00
1.50
7.50
Service 
Expenses</p>
<p>C. B, HOPKINS,
U. S. Marshal.</p>
<p>By John Stringer 
Deputy.</p>
<p>DISTRICT OF Wash ) ss:</p>
<p>I hereby certify that I served the annexed writ. of. Habeas
Corpus on the therein-named Herbert O. Williams
By delivering to and leaving with his
wife Grace E. Williams at his usual place
of abode She being a resident therein
and a person of suitable age and decision
at Georgetown in said District on the 8 day of
June, A. D. 190X
C. B, HOPKINS,
U. S. Marshal.
By John Stringer
Deputy.</p>
<p>No., 1204 Tx
</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED
STATES, FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASH-
INGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>PETER A. CLIFFORD,
Petitioner</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>HERBERT O. WILLIAMS,
GRACE E. WILLIAMS
Respondents.</p>
<p>WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>
<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. Circuit Court
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JUN 9 1904
A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk
HM Matthew
Deputy.</p>
<p>W. H White
ATTORNEY- AT- LAW
SAVINGS UNION BUILDING
530 California Street, SAN FRANSISCO, CAL.
J. J. Burt;
Co Counsil.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, NINTH JUDICIAL
CIRCUIT, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs.
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
W A R R A N T.</p>
<p>To C. B. HOPKINS, Marshal of the United States for the Dis-
trict of Washington, Northern Division:</p>
<p>WHEREAS, Peter A. Clifford as applied to me for a warrant to
take Alice B. Clifford, alleged to be in the custody of Herbert
O. Williams and Grace E. Williams; and</p>
<p>WHEREAS, it appears from the proof before me on such applica-
tion that the said Alice B. Clifford is held in illegal custody
by the said Herbert O. Williams and Grace E Williams, and that
there is good reason to believe that she will be carried out
of the jurisdiction of this Court before she can be relieved by
a writ of habeas corpus, and this warrant having been ordered
to issue by the Honorable the above named 
Court.</p>
<p>THESE ARE THEREFORE TO COMMAND YOU, in the name of the Pres-
ident of the United States of America, that you forthwith take
the said Alice B. Clifford and bring her before the Honorable
above named Court, at the Court room there-
of, in the City of Seattle, State of Washington, on the 9th 
day of June 1904, at Ten o'clock A M. of said day
to be dealt with according to law.</p>
<p>WITNESS Melville W. Fuller, Chief Justice of the United 
States, the 7th day of June 1904.</p>
<p>A. Reeves Ayres Clerk.
By, HM Matthew
Deputy Clerk.</p>
<p>W H White
Attorney for Petitioner.
J. J. Burt,
Co Counsil.</p>
<p>United States of America, )
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON. ) ss.</p>
<p>I, C. B. Hopkin U. S. Marshal for the District of Washington, do hereby
certify that I received the within Warrant on the 7 day of June 1904 and in
pursuance thereof have the said Alice B. Clifford, before
this Honorable Court as eviction
I am commanded this 9 day of June 1904</p>
<p>CB Hopkins U. S. Marshal,
By John Stringer Deputy.</p>
<p>No. 1204. Tx</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED
STATES, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTH-
ERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>PETER A. CLIFFORD,
Petitioner,
vs.
HERBERT O. WILLIAMS and
GRACE E. WILLIAMS,
Respondents.
W A R R A N T.</p>
<p>FILED IN THE
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JUN 9 1904
A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk.
HM Matthew 
Deputy</p>
<p>W. H. White
ATTORNEY-AT-LAW
SAVINGS UNION BUILDING
530 California Street, SAN FRANCISCO, CAL.
J. J. Burt,
Co Counsil.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL DISTRICT
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION </p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams.
Respondents.</p>
<p>No. 1804.
APPLICATION FOR CONTINUANCE.</p>
<p>Comes now the respondents, Herbet O. Williams and Grace
E. Williams, by Sweeneyy and Steiner, their attorneys and moved the
Court for a continuance herein from the 9th day of June, 1904, at
the hour of ten o'clock, for the period of ten days or until such
time as this Honorable Court may deem just and proper.</p>
<p>This motion is based upon the affidavits of G. E. Steiner
and respondents, Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams.</p>
<p>Sweeney <unclear></unclear> </p>
<p>No. 1204. Tx
</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE 
UNITED STATES.
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner
vs.
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams.
Respondents.
Motion for continuance.</p>
<p>FILED IN THE
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JUN 9 1904
A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk.
HM Matthew
Deputy</p>
<p>Sweeney and Steiner,
Attorneys for Respondents.
Haller Buiding, Seattle, Wn. </p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL DISTRICT
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION. </p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs
Herbert O. Williams, and
Grace E. Williams.
Respondents.
No. 1204.
 A F F I D A V I T.
</p>
<p>United States of America )
District of Washington, ) SS.
Northern Division. )</p>
<p>Herbert O. Williams, being first duly sworn on oath, de-
poses and says:</p>
<p>That he is a resident of King County, State of Washington;
one of the respondents in the above entitled action, and the husband
of respondent, Grace E. Williams.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL DISTRICT
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs
Herbert O. Williams, and 
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
United States of America
District of Washington, )SS.
Northern Division.</p>
<p>No. 1204.
A F F I D A V I T .</p>
<p>Herbert O. Williams, being first duly sworn on oath, de-
poses and says:</p>
<p>That he is a resident of King County, State of Washington;
one of the respondents in the above entitled action, and the husband
of respondent, Grace E. Williams.</p>
<p>That the petition herein was served upon respondents by
leaving a copy thereof at the residence of respondents with saiid
Grace E. Williams, in Georgetown, Washington, on the 8th day of
June, 1904, at about the hour of ;</p>
<p>The deponent is a carpenter by occupation and was working
at his trade in Seattle, Washington on the 8th. day of June, 1904,
and knew nothing of the service of said papers until informed by his
counsel, Sweeney and Steiner, on the evening of the 8th. day of June,
1904, at about the house of P. M. ; that he had previously had no 
intimation or notice of the commencements of this action; that he has
submitted the facts of the case to his counsel and is advised and
believes that he has a complete defense to said writ; that said writ
is maade returnable on the 8th, day of June, 1904, at the hour of ten
o'clock A.M., and that it has been imposaible in the time between the
service of said writ and the return thereof prepare respondent's
defense; that he has used due dilligence in an effort to prepare his
return to said writ on the day and hour designated by this Honorable
Court; and he has found it impossible in so short a space of time to
prepare a proper return to said writ; that if the petition herein
is heard on its merits on the 9th. day of June, 1904, at the hour of
ten o'clock, depondent will be deprived of an opportunity to properly
inform this Court of the facts in this cause.</p>
<p>Herbert O. Williams
Subscribed and sworn to before me this 9 day of June, 1904.</p>
<p>G. E. Steiner
Notary Public in and for the
State of Washingtion, residing at
Seattle.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL DISTRICT
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs
Herbert O. Williams, and 
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
United States of America
District of Washington, )SS.
Northern Division.</p>
<p>No. 1204.
A F F I D A V I T .</p>
<p>Grace E. Williams, being first duly sworn on oath, deponses
and says:</p>
<p>That she is a resident in King County, Washington, the wife
of the respondent, Herbert O. Williams, and one of the respondents
herein.</p>
<p>That the petition and writ herein were served upon her at
her residence in Georgetown, on the 8th, day of June, 1904, at about
the hour of A.M.;</p>
<p>That respondent, Herbert O. Williams, her husband, is a
carpenter by trade and was, at the time of service of said papers was
made, at work on a building in Seattle; that deponent had no communi-
cation with said Herbert O. Williams by telephone or otherwise and
it was impossible to inform him of the service of said papers; that
deponent requested the Marshall serving said papers, to inform re-
spondents' counsel, Sweeney and Steiner of said service; that at about
the hour of A.M., G.E. Steiner, one of our attorneys, called at
deponent's residence in response to the notice given by said marshall
and secured papers; that deponent has been diligent in the
preparation of her defense to this writ and that she is advised by
her counsel and believes that it will be impossible to prepare an
adequate return to said writ within the time limited by this Honorable
Court.
Grace E. Williams
 </p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 9 day of June, 1904.</p>
<p>G. E. Steiner
Notary Public in and for the
State of Washingtion, residing at
Seattle.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL DISTRICT
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs
Herbert O. Williams, and 
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
United States of America
District of Washington, )SS.
Northern Division.</p>
<p>No. 1204.
A F F I D A V I T .</p>
<p>G.E. Steiner, being first duly sworn on oath, deposes and says:</p>
<p>That he is one of the attorneys for respondents herein
and is conversant with the facts in this cause.</p>
<p>That the petition and writ issued herein were served upon
respondents at the family residence at Georgetown, Washington, on
the 9th. day of June, 1904, at about the hour of A.M. That deponent
was informed of this fact by the Deputy United States
Marshall who had made said service. Whereupon, deponent proceeded
at once to the residence of said respondents to obtain said papers
with a view to preparing a return thereon. That deponent then
discovered that said writ was made returnable at ten o'clock on
the day after the service thereof or at ten o'clock June 9, 1904. </p>
<p>That it is impossible to prepare an adequate return to
said writ within the time allotted respondents' attorneys, and if
this writ is heard o its merits on the day and hour designated for
the return thereof, if will work a great hardship upon respondents
and respondents' attorneys and deeat the ends of justice, in that
said attorneys will not be prepared to adequately present the case
to this Honorable Court.</p>
<p>G. E. Steiner
Subscribed and sworn to before me this 9 day of June, 1904.
Matthew H. Heade
Notary Public in and for the State 
of Washington, residing in Seattle.</p>
<p>No. 1204.
IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE
UNITED STATES,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.
NORTHERN DIVISION.
Peter A. Clifford, 
Petitioner,
vs.
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
FILED IN THE U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JUN 9 1904
A. Reeves Ayres, Clerk
HM Matthew 
Deputy</p>
<p>Affidavits of G. E. Steiner;
Herbert O. Williams and 
Grace E. Williams</p>
<p>Sweeney and Steiner,
Attorneys for Respondents.
Haller Building, Seattle, Wash.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, NINTH JUDICIAL CIRCUIT,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN
DIVISION.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
Vs
Herbert O. Williams and 
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
No.
R e p l y . </p>
<p>Comes now the Petitioner herein and replying to the answer
of the respondents herein, replies as follows:</p>
<p>Said Petitioner denies that by any reason of the writ of habeas
corpus in Number 41787, or of any proceedings, or of any adjudica-
tion of the Superior Court of the County of King, State of
Washington, or of any Judges thereof, referred to in the answer of
respondents, or by reason of any thingtherein, or any proceedings
between the parties hereot, or any other persons or parties, he is 
estopped from further questioning any right or rights claimed by 
said respondents, or either of them, as to the custody of said
child, Alice B. Clifford.</p>
<p>And in further reply said Petitioner avers and alleges:</p>
<p>That upon the hearing of said proceeding in said Superior
Court and before the Honorable Boyd J. Tallman, the Judge before
whom said hearing of said habeas corpus proceeding was had, said
Petitioner presented and put in evidence a copy of the judicial
records and proceedings of the Superior Court of the City
and in the notion granting the divorce referred to in his petition herein
County of San Francisco, State of California, 
authentioated a provided i Section 905 of the Revised Statutes 
of the United States, and claimed the right to the custody of
said child upon the ground that is was being imprisoned and
detained by respondents, and each of them, in violation of Article
exemplified and
IV, Section 1 of the United States and Section 905 of the Revised
Statutes of the United States, and demanded that in pursuance of
said provision of said Constitution and said provision of said
Revised Statutes if the United States, full faith and credit to
said records of said Superior Court of California should be given
by said Court of Washington and the respondents herein, and that
said child should be released from the imprisionment and detention
by said respondents, and each of them, and delivered into the
custody of your Petitioner, to be by him taken back to the juris-
diction of said Court of California; but said Superior Court of
 Washington refused, and it appears upon the face of the records and
proceedings of said Superior Court of Washington, in said habeas
corpus proceedings therein, that said Court refused, to give any
faith or credit to the records or proceedings of the said Court of
California; and your Petitioner sets up and claims under said
Article IV, Section 1, of the Constitution of the United States,
and said Section 905 of the Revised Statutes of the United States,
that said record and proceedings of said Superior Court of Wash-
ington in the application therein for a writ of habeas corpus should
be disregarded by this Court and held to be of no force or effect
whatever.
 </p>
<p>Further replying to the answer of the respondents herein, as
to the adoption of said child by proceedings in Number 5262 of
said Superior Court of the State of Washington, said Petitioner
avers and alleges that by reason of the facts set out in his
petition herein, said child at the time said adoption proceedings
were commended and had, and ever since, has been, a resident of and
at all of said time had and yet has her domicile in the State of
California, and that the facts of such residence and domicile and
her being a ward of said Superior Court of California and subject
to the control and jurisdiction thereof, were made to appear before
the said Superior Court of Washington when said proceedings for
the adoption of said child were taken and had therein, and said
domicile and said wardship of said child appear upon the face of
the records and proceedings of said Superior Court of said State of
Washington in the matter of the adoption of said child, which
consist of a petition by the respondents herein to be allowed to
adopt said child, a copy of which is hereto attached marked
"Exhibit A" and made a part hereof, a written consent to the
adoption of said child, a copt of which is hereto attached, marked
"Exhibit B" and made a part hereof, and an order for the adoption
of said child, a copy of which is attached to the answer of the
respondents herein marked "Exhibit E", and which is hereby
referred to and made a part hereof, and of them alone; but
nevertheless the said Court of Washington refused to give any
faith or credit to the said records or proceedings of said Court
of California, and made and entered said order allowing said
adoption of said child; and your Petitioner hereby sets up and
claims that under said Article IV, Section 1 of the Constitution
of the United States and Section 905 of the Revised Statutes
thereof, said order allowing said adoption is void, and of no
force or effect.</p>
<p>And further replying as to the now pending in the
Superior Court of the State of Washington in and for the County of
King to set aside said order of adoption, said Petitioner alleges
that said proceeding is nothing more than to have expunged from
the records of that Court an order claimed by said Petitioner to 
be void and of no affect, and presents to reason why this appli-
cation should be denied, abated or continued</p>
<p>And further replying to Exhibit C of respondents' answer,
reffered to and adopted by them as a portion of their answer 
herein, said petitioner denies, as alleged in Parahraph IX thereof,
that no notice whatever was served upon them, or either of them, or
that they, or either of them, received no information as to the
change of the decree of the Court of California as to this custody
of said child; and on the contrary alleges that eight days' notice of the 
motion to modify the decree was given and served upon William P.
Humphreys. Esq., who was and yet is the attorney of record for
Grace E. Williams in the action wherein said decree was made and
entered.</p>
<p>Futher replying to Paragraoh I of the affirmative defense of respondents' Exhibit C
adopted as a portion of their answer herein, said Petitioner
alleges and avers that all of thematters and things therein set up
and alleged were set upp ad alleged in the complaints in actions
brought by Grace E. Williams, as Grace E. Clifford, against your
Petitioner in the said Court of California, wherein your Petitioner
was granted a divore from her, and all of such matters and things
were adjudged and decreed by said Court against her and in favor
of your Petitioner, and are barred by the judgments therein, one
which is the judgment granting said divorce; and further
replying as to the matters and things set out in said paragraph,
said Petitioner avers and alleges that they are beyond the jurisdiction of
this Court upon this application, and are solely and exclusively
within the jurisdiction of said Superior Court of California.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, Petitioner objects to the consideration by this
Court of any of the matters or things set out in this answer of
the respondents herein, and respondents are notified hereby that
upon the calling of this matter for hearing herein Petitioner will
move the Court for judgment upon the pleadings herein, and for the
granting of the prayer of his Petition herein; and in the case of the
Court's refusal to grant said motion Petitioner will then offer
evidence in support of his Petition herein, and of this Reply.
W H White
J. J. Burt
Attorneys for Petitioner.</p>
<p>State of Washington, )
County of King. ) ss.</p>
<p>J. J. Burt, being duly sworn, says; That he is one of the
attorneys for the Petitioner in the above entitled matter or
proceeding; that he has read the foregoing reply of the Petitioner
therein and knows the contents thereof, and that he verily believes
the same to be true. </p>
<p>Deponent further says that the reason he makes this affidavit
is that said Petitioner is absent from the State of Washington, and
in the State of California, and also that deponent is better in-
formed as to the facts stated in said reply than is the said
Petitioner.</p>
<p>J J Burt</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 15th day of June, A. D. 1904.</p>
<p>William B Allison
Notary Public in and for the State of
Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>
<p>Exhibit A</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, FOR KING COUNTY.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Adoption of Alice B. Clifford, an infant, by
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams, his wife,</p>
<p>No.
Petition.</p>
<p>To the Hon. Boyd J. Tallman, one of the Judges of the above
entitled court:</p>
<p>The petition of Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams,
his wife, respectfully shows;</p>
<p>1. That petitioners Herbert O. Williams and Grace E.
Williams are and ever since the 15th day of August, 1903, have
been husband and wife, and are residents of Seattle, King County,
Washington.</p>
<p>a. That your petitioners desire to adopt as their own an
infant female child named Alice B. Clifford, and to change the
name of said child to Alice B. Williams.</p>
<p>3. That the parents of said child, Peter A. Clifford and
his then wife, Grace E. Williams, were divorced by decree of the
Superior Court of San Francisco County, California, on the 20th
day of May, 1908, and that said decree by its terms awarded the
carem custody and control of said infant to its mother Grace E.
Clifford, now Grace E. Williams.</p>
<p>4. That said Peter A. Clifford and his then wife, Grace E.
Clifford, have ever since the issuanceof said decree, and for a
long time prior thereto, lived separate and apart, during all
of which time said infant, Alice B. Clifford, has been and now is
in the care, custody and control of its said mother, Grace E.
Williams.</p>
<p>5. That said Grace E. Williams and said infant, Alice B.
Clifford are residents of King County, Washington.</p>
<p>6. That your petitioners are persons of good oral
characterm industrious habits, and good prospects in life, of the
ages of 31 years and 32 years respectively, are amply able to 
provide a suitable home for said child, and are in every respect
fit and proper persons to be entrusted with the moral ad other
character of said child, and to make a reasonable provision for
its future usefulness and happiness in life. </p>
<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioners pray that by order of this court
said infant, Alice B. Clifford, shall from and after the date of
such order be deemed to all legal intent are purposes the child
of your petitioners, Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams,
and that said child be rendered capable of inheriting the estate
of your petitioners and each of them, and that the name of said
child be changed to Alice B. Williams.</p>
<p>Herbert O. Williams
Grace E. Williams</p>
<p>Sweeney and Steiner,
Attorneys for petitioners.</p>
<p>State of Washington
County of King.</p>
<p>Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams being first duly
sworn on oath say, each for himself, that they are the peti-
tioners above named, and that they have read the foregoing
petition, know the contents thereof, and that the same is true.</p>
<p>Herbert O. Williams
Grace E. Williams</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 18th day of Nov. 1903.
G. E. Steiner,
Notary Public in and for the State of Washington,
residing at Seattle.</p>
<p>Exhibit B</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Adoption of Alice B. Clifford, an infant, by
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams, his wife,</p>
<p>No.
Consent to Adoption.</p>
<p>State of Washington
County of King.</p>
<p>I, Grace E. Willia,s being first duly sworn say: That I am
the mother of Alice B. Clifford, the infant child mentioned in
foregoing petition of Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams,
his wife; that I was divorced from Peter A. Clifford, the father
of said child, in San Francisco County, California, on or about
the 20th day of May, 1902, and that the court in granting the
divorce awarded the care, custody and control of said
child; that I hereby consent to the adoption of said child, Alice
B. Clifford, by Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams, the
foregoing petitioners, and that the name of said child be changed
to Alice B. Williams.</p>
<p>Grace E. Williams</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 12th day of Nov. 1903.
G. E. Steiner
Notary Public in and for the State of Washington,
residing at Seattle.</p>
<p>ORIGINAL.
No. 1204 Tx</p>
<p>In the United States
C I R C U I T Court
FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN Division</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford, 
Petitioner,
vs.
Herbert O. Williams and 
Grace E. Williams, 
Respondents.</p>
<p>R E P L Y . </p>
<p>FILED IN THE
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. of WASHINGTON.
JUN 15 1904
A. REEVES AYRES Clerk
HM Matthew
Deputy
W. H. White and
J. J. Burt,
Attorneys for Petitioner</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL CIRCUIT,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner. 
vs
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.</p>
<p>No.
A N S W E R .</p>
<p>Come now the respondents by their attorneys Sweeney and
Steiner and answering petitioner's petition for habeas corpus allege:</p>
<p>That on or about the 20th. day of January, 1904, petitioner,
Peter A. Clifford filed in for the Superior Court of the State of Wash-
ington, for King County in the cause numbered 41727, entitled
"Peter A. Clifford, petitioner, vs Herbert O. Williams and Grace
E. Williams, respondents", praying for a writ of habeas corpis
to bring the body of Alice B. Clifford before said Superior Court
to abide such order as said Court may direct, a copy of which said 
petition is hereto attached marked "Exhibit A", and hereby reffered
to and made a part hereof; that thereupon in response to said petition
a writ of heabeas corpus was issued returnable before the Honorab;e
George E. Norris, one of the judges in the above entitled court.
which said writ is hereto attached and marked "Exhibit B" and is
hereby referred to and made a part hereof; that respondents there-
upon appeared in said action and filed their answer or return to
said petition which said answer or return is hereto attached and
marked "Exhibit C" and is hereby referred to and made a part hereof;
that in obedience to said writ, the body of said Alice B. Clifford
was produced on the 22nd day of Janurary, 1904, before the said Court, where upon the said cause was
referred to by his Honor, George E. Norris to the Honorable Boyd J.
Tallman, also one of the judges of the aforesaid Superior Court, and
continued to January 25, 1904, at which time and place the body of
said Alice B. Clifford was produced before his Honor, Boyd J. Tallan
and a full and complete hearing had on said petition. That
at said hearing, evidence was introduced by the petitioner and re-
spondents and the cause argued at length by counsel for petitioner
and respondents, and at the conclusion of said hearing, the Court,
being fully advised in the premises, made an order sustaining the validity of the decree of adoption; dissolving said
writ of habeas corpus and demanding said infant, Alice B. Clifford to the care,
custody and control of respondents, which said order is hereto at-
tached, marked "Exhibit D" and is hereby referred to and made a
part hereof; that the parties in said cause number 41727 were
identical with the parties in this cause; that the subject matter
in controversy was identical; that the facts at issue in said cause
number 41727 and in this case are identical and that no new facts
have since arisen; that the petition in said cause umber 41727 and 
in this cause are identical with the exception of slight and imma-
terial variations; that the subject matter at issue in this cause
has been and the facts involved were fully and finally adjudicated
in said cause number 41727, by his Honor, Boyd J. Tallman, Judge of
the Superior Court, State of Washington, for King County, and the
status of said infant, Alice B. Clifford was thereby fixed and es
tablished, and the custody of said infant awarded to respondents
herein.</p>
<p>That by reason of said writ of habeas corpus in number
41727 and the proceedings had therein. and the full and final ad-
judication thereof petitioner is estopped from further questioninh
respondents rigt to the custody of said infant, Alice B. Clifford
by reason of said former adjudication.</p>
<p>That respondents claim the rightful custody of the said
infant, Alice B. Clifford by reason of the aforesaid adjudication.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, respondents pray that the writ of habeas corpus
issued herein may be dissolved and the said infant, Alice B. Clifford
be remanded to the custody of respondents.</p>
<p>Further answering the petitioner's petition herein re-
spondents allege:</p>
<p>That on or about the 12th, day of November, 1903, respondenta
petitioned the Superior Court of the State of Washington, for King
County, in cause number 5262, entitled "In the matter of the adoption
of Alice B. Clifford, an infant, by Herbert O. Williams and Grace
E. Williams, his wife, "for permission to adopt said child, Alice B.
Clifford as their own. That thereafter, such proceedings were had
that a decree of adoption was entered by said Supreme Court adjudging
thatfrom and after said date, said infant, Alice B. Clifford should
to all legal intents and purposes, be the child of petitioners
respondents herein the same as if she had been born to them in
lawful wedlock, and that the name of said child be changed to Alice
B. Williams, a copy of which decree is hereto attached and marked
"Exhibit E", which decree is hereby referred to and made a 
part hereof, and by virtue of which respondents have the custody 
of said infant now known as Alice B. Williams, and claim to be her
rightful custodians.</p>
<p>Respondents further allege that petitioner did on or about
the 5th, day of June, 1904, file a petition in said cause number 5262,
praying that the decree of adoption therein made and entered be
set aside and held for naught, which said petition is now pending in 
said Superior Court.</p>
<p>Further answering the petitioner's petition herein re-
spondents hereby refer to and make a part hereof their said answer
in said cause number 41727, attached hereto and marked "Exhibit C",
as fully and completely as if said answer was here repeated.</p>
<p>Wherefore, having fully answered petitioner's petition,
respondents pray that the writ of habeas corpus heretofore issued
herein be dissolved and said infant, be remanded to the custody of
respondents and that said respondents be awarded their coats here-
in.</p>
<p>Sweeney Steiner
Attorneys for respondents</p>
<p>United States of America, )
District of Washington, ) SS.
Northern Division. )</p>
<p>Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams being first duly
sworn on oath, depose and say: that they are the respondents in the
above entitled cause; that they have read the foregoing answer, know
the contents thereof and the same is true. </p>
<p>Herbert O. Williams
Grace E. Williams
Subscribed and sworn to before me this 10 day of June, 1904.
G. E. Steiner
Resides in Seattle, WA the Notary Public, residing Seattle Wash</p>
<p> IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTO, IN AND FOR THE
COUNTY OF KING</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs
Herbert O. Wiliams, and
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents</p>
<p>Exhibit A
No. 41727
PETITION FOR WRIT OF
HABEAS CORPUS</p>
<p>To the Honorable George E. Morris, one of the judges of the
Superior Court of the State of Washington, in and for the County of
King.</p>
<p>The Petition of Peter A. Clifford respectfully shows:-</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>That at all of the times herein stated he was and now is 
a citizen and resident of the State of California, and that
defendants are and for more than three months last past have been
citizens and residents of the State of Washington, in the County
of King.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>That on the 17th, day of October, A.D.1899, one Grace E. Long
was a citizen and resident of the State of California and on that
day your petitioner and the said Grace E. Long, at the City and
County of San Francisco, in the said State of California, intermar-
ried and became husband and wife, and the said Grace E. Long thereby
became Grace E. Clifford.</p>
<p>III.</p>
<p>That thereafter your petitioner and his said wife lived
together as such husband and wife in the City and County of San 
Francisco, State of California until about the 7th day of March A. D.
1901, and that on or about the said last named day the said Grace E.
Clifford deserted and abandoned your petitioner without any just cause
and without his consent.</p>
<p>IV.</p>
<p> That during the marriage of your petitioner and the said
Grace E. Clifford, there was born to them, as the issue of said marriage,
a female child, now living, and of the age of three years and six months, named Alice
B. Clifford.</p>
<p>V.</p>
<p>That on the 24th. day of March, A.D.1902, the said Grace E. 
Clifford commenced an action in the Superior Court in and for the
City and County of San Francisco, State of California, for an absolute
divorce from your petitioner, and therein prayed for the custody of
said child of said marriage, and your petitioner appeared in said
action and filed his answer, and also a cross-complaint for a divorce
from the said Grace E. Clifford therein, and in said cross-complaint orayed
that the custody of said child should be awarded to him by said Court.</p>
<p>VI.</p>
<p>That thereafter such proceedings were had in such action and
cross-action that the judgment of said Court was given, made and
entered therein, denying a divorce to said Grace E. Clifford and
granting a divorce to your petitioner, and awarding the custody of
said child to Grace E. Clifford until further order of the 
Court; and providing that your petitioner should be allowed to see
said child once a week and to take the same out with him once in every
two weeks.</p>
<p>VII.</p>
<p>That at the time of the commencement of said action and from
thence on down and including the time of the entry of said judgment,
your petitioner, the said Grace E. Clifford and said child were all
citizens and bona fide residents of said City and County of San Fran-
cisco, in said State of California, and actually present therein,
and your petitioner and the said Grace E. Clifford had been such
citizens and residents of said City and County continuously since the
date of their said marriage, and said child had been such citizen
and resident continuously since the date of her birth, and within
the jurisdiction of said Superior Court was then and yet is a Court of record
and of superior jurisdiciton.</p>
<p>VIII.</p>
<p>That aftet the date of entry of said judgment by said
Superior Court, the said Grace E. Clifford continued to reside in
said City and County of San Fransisco until sometime in September,
A.D.1903, the exact time being unknown to your petitioner, and that
during said month she secretly and surreptitiously and without the
permission of said Superior Court, and in contempt thereof, and with-
out the knowledge or consent of your petitioner, took said child
out of the State of California.</p>
<p>IX.</p>
<p>That on the 27th day of November, A.D. 1903, you petitioner
filed in the Superior Court a verified petition on said action
and cross-action for a modification of the judgment therein by taking
away from the custody of said Grace E. Clifford the said child and
awarding the custody thereof to your petitioner, and such proceedings
were thereupon made had that an order was made and entered therein
modifying and changing said judgment and taking the custody of said
child from said Grace E. Clifford and awarding the same to your
petitioner until the further order of the said Superior Court, and
said order ever since has been and still is standing and not set aside
and in full force and effect, and under the laws of the State of
California, at the time of the commencement of said action and at
the time of the entry of said judgment, and at the time of the making
of said order, said child was a ward of said Court and under the
control thereof; and it is provided by the laws of the said State
that said Court could be at any time after the entry of said judg-
ment make any order with or without notice modifying said judgment
as to make the custody of said child.</p>
<p>X.</p>
<p>That since the judgment of divorce, the said Grace E.
Clifford and one Herbert O. Williams above named, intermarried in
said State of California, and became and ever since have been and
now are husband and wife, and ever since their said marriage have
had in the State of California and elsewhere and now have at the town
of Georgetown in said County of King, said child in their custody 
and possession.</p>
<p>XI.</p>
<p>That on the 19th, day of January, 1904 at the said town of
Georgetown, your petitioner presented to the said Herbert O.
O. Williams and the said Grace E. Williams a copy of the record and
proceedings of the said Superior Court of said City and County of
San Francisco, in said action and cross-action, certified under and
in pursuance of an act of the Congress of the United States, in such
case made and provided and demanded from them and each of them
immediate delivery of said child to him, said petitioner, but they
refused and still do refuse to give up said child, and said child
ever since has been and now is imprisoned and restrained of her
liberty by them at said town of Georgetown, and that according to
the best of your petitioner's knowledge and belief, the cause or pre-
tense of the aforesaid confinement or restraint of the said Alice
B. Clifford is that under the said judgment of said Superior Court
of said City and County of San Francisco, the custody of said child
was given to the said Grace E. Clifford now Grace E. Williams. until
futher order of that Court, and that after she, secretly and
surreptituously took said child beyond the limits of said State of
California, as aforesaid, said Superior Court lost all jurisdiction
to make any further order in said action or cross-action, in regard
to, in modification of said judgment, as to the custody of said child,
and that after said child was brought into the said State of Washing-
ton, said Herbert O. Williams, with the consent of said Grace E.
Williams, and without the knowledge or consent of said Superior Court
of said City and County of San Francisco, undertook, under the laws
of the said State of Washington, to adopt said child as his own. And
your petitioner further states that he is advised by counsel W. H.
White, Esq., resding at the City of Seattle, State of Washington, and
J. J. Burt, Esq.,
residing at the City and County of San Francisco, State of California,
that the said imprisonment of the said child, Alice B. Clifford, is 
illegal and that the illegality consists in this, towit:-</p>
<p>That said Superior Court of the said City and County of
San Francisco had jurisdiction to award the custody of said child,
upon the facts herein before alleged, until further order of the
Court, and to thereafter change or modify thhe judgment as to the 
custody of saaid child, with or without notice to any or either of
the parties to said action, and that under Article 4, Section I,
of the Constitution of the United States, full faith and credit must
be given in the State of Washingto to the acts and proceedings of
said Superior Court of the City and County of San Francisco, and all
persons and Courts must recognize the petitioner's right to the
custody of said child under said order, in said State of Washington,
as well as under the laws of the country existing between said State
of California and said State of Washington. And your petitioner
further states that there is danger that the said Herbert O. Williams
and the ssaid Grace E. Williams will take or send the said child out
of this State, from the fact that they secretly and without the per-
mission of the said Superior Court of the City and County of San
Francisco and in contempt thereof, took said child beyond the limits
of the State of California.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, your Petitioner prays a writ of habeas corpus to
bring up the body of said child, Alice B. Clifford, to abide such
order as your Honor may direct, and that also a warrant issue immedi-
ately to take said child.</p>
<p>(sgd.) Peter A. Clifford</p>
<p>(sgd.) W. H. White.
Attorney for Peitioner.</p>
<p>(sgd.) J. J. Burt,
of, Counsel.</p>
<p>State of Washington, )
)SS.
County of King. )</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford, being duly sworn, says: That he is the
Petitioner above named; that he has read the foregoing, his petition,
and knows the contents thereof, and that the same is, and that the
facts therein stated are true of his ow knowledge.</p>
<p>(sgd.) Peter A. Clifford.</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 19th day of January, A.D. 1904.</p>
<p>(sgd.) R. I. Huxston.
A Notary Public in and for the
State of Washington, residing
at Seattle.</p>
<p>Ex. A Con</p>
<p>Upon the reading and filing of the foregoing Petition verified
by the Petitioner, whereby it appears that Alice B. Clifford is
illegally imprisoned and restrained of her liberty by Herbert O.
Williams and Grace E. Williams, at the town of Georgetown, in the
County of King, State of Washington, and stating wherein the illegality
consists, from which is appears to me that a writ of habeas corpus 
should issue :+</p>
<p>It is ordered that a writ of habeas corpus issue out of and
under the deal of the Superior Court of the State of Washington, in
and for the County of King, directed to the said Herbert O. William
and Grace E. Williams, commanding them and each of them to have the
body of Alice B. Clifford before me May 33, 1904 at 1:30 of such day
in the Court room of said Court to do and receive what shall then
and there be considered concerning the said Alice B. Clifford, to-
gether with the time and cause of her detention, and that they have
then and there the said writ.</p>
<p>It further appearing that there is good reason to believe that
said Alice B. Clifford, will be carried out of and beyond the juris-
diction of said Court, it ordered that a warrant issue out of and
under the seal of said Court to the Sheriff of King County, com-
manding him to take the said Alice B. Clifford and to hold her in
custody until the determination of said Petition.</p>
<p>Dated, January 20, 1904.</p>
<p>(sgd.) Geo. E. Morris,
Judge.</p>
<p>"Exhibit B"</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OFmWASHINGTON, FOR KING COUNTY.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs.
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.</p>
<p>No.
Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>The people of the state of Washington, to Herbert O.
Williams and Grace E. Williams, Greeting.</p>
<p>We command you that you have the body of Alice B. Clifford now
held by you in illegal custody and detention, by whatsoever name the
said Alice B. Clifford shall be called, before the Hon. George E. Mor-
ris, one of the judges of the above named court, at the court room of
said court and department three thereof, in the City of Seattle, Count
of King, State of Washington, on the 22nd day of January, 1904, at
1:30 o'clock P. M. of said day, to do and receive what shall then and
there be considered and determined concerning the said Alice B. Clif-
ford, and that you have then and there this writ.</p>
 <p>Witness the Hon. Geoorge E. Morris, one of the judges of the
 Superior Court of the state of Washington, in and for the County of
 King.</p>
 <p>C. A. Koepli,
 (Signed.) Clerk.</p>
 <p>(Seal.) by J. M. Brewster,
 Deputy.</p>
 <p>Exhibit "C"</p>
 <p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, FOR KING COUNTY.</p>
 <p>Peter A. Clifford,
 Petitioner,
 vs.
 Herbert O. Williams and
 Grace E. Williams, his wife,
 Respondents.</p>
 <p>No. 41727.
 Answer.</p>
 <p>Come now the respondents herein by their attorneys Sweeney 
 and Steiner, and answer the petitioner's petition as follows:</p>
 <p>I.</p>
 <p>Respondents admit the allegations of the first paragraph of
 said petition.</p>
 <p>II.</p>
 <p>Respondents admit the allegations of the second paragraph of 
 said petition.</p>
 <p>III.</p>
 <p>Answering the third paragraph of said petition, respondents 
 admit that respondent Grace E. Williams and petitioner lived together
 as husband and wife in the city and county of San Francisco until
 about the 7th day of March, 1901, and deny each and every other alle-
 gation in said paragraph.</p>
 <p>IV.</p>
 <p>Respondents admit the allegations of the fourth paragraph of
 said petition.</p>
 <p>V.</p>
 <p>Respondents admit the allegations of the fifth paragraph of
 said petition.</p>
 <p>VI.</p>
 <p>Answering paragraph six of said petition, respondents admit
 that the care, custody and control of the child Alice B. Clifford was
 awarded to the respondent Grace E. Williams, then Grace E. Clifford.
 </p>
 <p>VII.</p>
 <p>Respondents admit the allegations of paragraph seven of said
 petition.</p>
 <p>VIII.</p>
 <p>Answering paragraph eight of said petition, respondents admit
 that they left the state of California and came to King County, Wash-
 ington, but deny that the departure was secretly, surreptitiously,
 or without the permission of the Superior Court of the County of San
 Francisco.</p>
 <p>IX.</p>
 <p>Answering paragraph nine of said petition, respondents have
 no information sufficient to form a belief as to the truth or falsity
 of the allegations therein contained, and therefore deny the same, and
 and further allege that at the time said decree is alleged to havecbeen
 amended respondent Grace E. Williams and Alice B. Clifford (now Alice
 B. Williams) were not redients of nor in the State of California but
 were residents of King County, Washington. That no notice whatever was
 served upon respondents or either of them now did they or either of
 them receive any information concerning an attempted change of the decree
 awarding said child to respondent, Grace E. Williams.</p>
 <p>X.</p>
 <p>Respondents admit the allegations of paragraph 10 of said 
 petition.</p>
 <p>XI.</p>
 <p>Answering paragraph eleven of said petition, respondents admit
 that they refused to deliver said child to petitioner, and denynthe
 allegations concerning which respondents have knowledge; and respondents
 have no information sufficient to form a belief as to the truth or
 falsity of the remaining allegations, and therefore deny the same.
 </p>
 <p>For a separate and affirmative defense to petitioner's petition,
 respondents allege:</p>
 <p>I.</p>
 <p>That respondent, Grace E. Williams, then Grace. E. Long, and 
 petitioner, Peter A. Clifford, then residents of San Francisco, Cali-
 fornia, were married in San Francisco, California, on or about the 17th,
 day of October, 1899; that very soon after said marriage, petitioner
 came home in a state of hopeless intoxication; that at frequent inter-
 vals thereafter, petitioner came home drunk, at which times he was 
 abusive to respondent, and caused her great pain and distress, so that
 it became impossible to longer endure his conduct, whereupon on or
 about July, 1900, said respondent left petitioner, and returned
 to her mother's home. That on or about the 5th day of August, 1900,
 after repeated promises on the part of petitioner to resume the duties
 and obligations of a husband toward said respondent, said respondent
 returned to petitioner with a view to living with him again as his 
 wife. That very soon thereafter, petitioner became abusive, commenced
 drinking and neglecting said respondent, and failed to provide for her
 comfort, and respondent, who was then an expectant mother, ws sore
 distressed; that their child, Alice B. Clifford, was born on October
 14, 1900; that thereafter petitioner refused to provide for respondent's
 comfort, or to provide her with medical attendance and neglected her
 so that on or about the day of March, 1901, said respondent was
 compelled to and did leave said petitioner and returned again to
 hermother's home, where she was provided with medical attendance and
 other comforts necessary to herself and child, That during the time
 petitioner and said respondent lived together, petitioner wholly
 failed to provide her with clothing which during all of said time was
 furnished her by her mother. That in April, 1902, said respondent
 brought an action for divorce from petitioner which resulted in a
 decree of the Superior Court of San Francisco County, California,
 dissolving the bonds of matrimony theretofore existing between said
 respondent and petitioner and awarding the sole care of custody and
 control of their infant child, Alice B. Clifford, to said respondent,
 its mother, a copy of which said decree is hereto attached marked
 "Exhibit A" and is hereby referred to and made a part of this answer.</p>
 <p>That thereafterm in or about the 15th, day of August, 1903,
 said respondent and Herbert O. Williams were intermarried in San Fran-
cisco, California, and ever since have been and now are husband and
wife. That on or about the 24th, day of September, 1903, respondents
left the State of California and came to Seattle, King County, Washington,
to make iit possible for Herbert O. Williams to enter to employ of 
his brother, Charles L. Williams, who was then and is now a prominent
contractor and builder in the City of Seattle. That since coming to
Seattle, said Herbert O. Williams has been in his brother's employ as
a carpenter and has been earning and does now earn the sun of three
dollars ($3.00) per day.</p>
<p>That thereafter, said respondents became desirous of
adopting said Alice B. Clifford as their ow child, and thereupon on
or about the 12th day of November, 1903, respondents petitioned the
Superior Court of King County, Washington, in cause Number 5262,
entitled "In the matter of the adoption of Alice B. Clifford, and infant,
by Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams, his wife, "for permission
to adopt said child, Alice B. Clifford, as their own. That thereafter,
such proceedings were had the a decree of adoption was entered bu
said Superior Court of King County, Washington, adjudging that from and
after said date, said infant, Alice B. Clifford should to all legal in-
tents and purposes be the child of the petitioners, respondents herein,
Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams, the same as if she had
been born to them in lawful wedlock, and that the name of said child
be changed to Alice B. Williams, a copy of which decree is hereto at-
tached and marked "exhibit B", which is hereby referred to and made
a part of this answer by virtue of which, said respondents claim the
rightful posession of said infant, Alice B. Wiliams.</p>
<p>Respondents further allege that they are amply able to 
provide a suitable home for said child and to make reasonable provision
for its future usefulness and happiness in life.</p>
<p>That respondents left the State of California not for the
purpose of evading the order of nor in contempt of any Court nor did
they leave secretly nor surreptitiously, but they came to  the State of
Washington in good faith in view of better business opportunities as
aforesaid in Seattle and for the purpose of becoming bona fide citizens
of the State of Washington. That respondents now are and expect to
remain citizens of the State of Washington.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, respondents pray that the writ of habeas corpus
issued herein may be dissolved, and that said child, Alice B. Williams,
be released from the custody of the Sheriff of King County, and returned
to the custody and keeping of respondents, Grace E. Williams and
Herbert O. Williams, and for their costs and disbursements n this
behalf expended.</p>
<p>(sgd.) Sweeney and Steiner
Atttys. for Resp.</p>
<p>State of Washington )
) SS.
County of King. )</p>
<p>Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams, being
first duly sworn, on oath depose and say: That they are the respondents
above named; that they have read the foregoing answer, know the contents
thereof, and the statements therein made are true.</p>
<p>(sgd.) H. O. Williams.
(sgd.) Grace E. Williams.</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 22nd, day of January, 1904.</p>
<p>(sgd.) G. E. Steiner.
Notary Public in and for the
State of Washington, residing
at Seattle.</p>
<p>"Exhibit D"</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, FOR KING COUNTY.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
 Petitioner,
 vs.
 Herbert O. Williams and
 Grace E. Williams, his wife,
 Respondents.</p>
<p>No.</p>
<p>O R D E R .</p>
<p>Whereas, a writ of habeas corpus was on the 20th, day of
January, 1904, issued herein upon the petition of Peter A. Clifford,
in behalf of Alice B. Williams, designated in said petition as Alice
B. Clifford, directed to Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams,
respondents herein, and</p>
<p>Whereas, on the 22nd, day of January, 1904, the said Herbert
O. Williams and Grace E. Williams, in obedience to said writ of
habeas corpus, produced the body of said Alice B. Williams before
this Court, and made answer and return to said petition, and
</p>
<p>Whereas, a hearing on said petition and return was continued
on the 25th day of January, 1904, at which time petitioner appeared
in person and by his attorneys, W. H. White and Bert, and
respondets appeared in person and by their attorneys, Sweeney and
Steiner, and evidence having been introduced and argument of counsel
heard, and the Court being fully advised in the premises, finds as
follows:-</p>
<p>I. That on the 17th, day of October, 1899, respondent Grace E.
Williams, then Grace E. Long, and petitioner Peter A. Clifford, in-
termarried in San Francisco, California.</p>
<p>2. That to said Peter A. Clifford and his then wife, Grace E.
Clifford, a female child was born on the 14th. day of October, 190,
which child is now living, named Alice B. Clifford, the same being
the child in controversey in this cause.</p>
<p>3. that on the 20th, day of May, 1902, a decree was entered in
the Superior Court of the State of California, in and for the City
and County of San Francisco, in cause numbered 30,124, entitled,
"Grace E. Clifford, plaintiff, vs. Peter A. Clifford, Defendant",
dissolving the bonds of matrimony then and theretofore existing between said Grace E.
Clifford and Peter A. Clifford, and awarding the sole charge, con-
trol and custody of said Alice B. Clifford to respondent, Grace E.
Williams.</p>
<p>4. That subsequent to said divorce, and on or about August 15,
1903, respondents, Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams, then
Grace E. Clifford, intermarried in the State of California, and
thereafter on or about the 20th day of September, 1903, said respon-
dents together with said infant, Alice B. Clifford, removed from
the State of California to the State of Washington, and thereupon
became bone fide residents of King County, Washington. </p>
<p>5. That said Alice B. Williams, then Alice B. Clifford, was in 
the care, custody and control of respondent, Grace E. Williams at the
time of her marriage with said Herbert O. Williams, and was brought
with said respondents to King County, Washington, and has since been
in the custody of resided with said respondets.</p>
<p>That on or about the 12h day of November, 190, respondents,
Herbert O. Williams, petitioned the Superior Court of King County,
Washington, in the cause numbered 5262, entitled "In the matter of
the adoption of Alice B. Clifford, an infant, by Herbert O. Williams
and Grace E. Williams, his wife," for permission to adopt said child
under the laws of the State of Washington.</p>
<p>7. That thereupon such proceedings were had that a decree was
entered in said causem adjudging from and after said date said
child, Alice B. Clifford should to all legal intents and purposes
be the child of petitioners in said suit, Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams his wife, the same as if the child had been born
to them in lawful wedlock, and that the name of said child be changed
to Alice B. Williams.</p>
<p>8. That subsequent to said adoption, and on the 15th, day of
December, 1903, the petitioner applied to the Superior Court of the
State of California in and for the City of San Francisco,
for an order amending the decree granted in the aforesaid divorce
proceeding, and awarding the custody of the said infant Alice B.
Clifford to petitioner, which order was then and there granted; that
respondents had no notice of the application for said order, and
were at that time, together with said infant, residents of King
County, Washington.</p>
<p>9. That the Superior Court of King County, Washington, had
jurisdiction over the parties and the subject matter in the adop-
tion proceedings mentioned in paragrapg six of these findings, and
that said proceedings were in every respect regular and in accord-
ance with the statutes of the state of Washington.</p>
<p>The court further finds that the respondents Herbert O. Williams
and Grace E. Wiliams are fit and proper persons to have the care,
custody and control of said infant Alice B. Williams, and the best
interests of said infant require that she remain in the care, cus-
today and control of said respondents.</p>
<p>It is therefore ORDERED, tha the said infant Alice B. Williams
be and she is hereby remanded to the care, custody and control of
respondents Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams; that they
retain the care, custody and control of said infant; that the writ
of habeas corpus heretofore issued herein be dissolved, and that
respondents recover from petitioner their costs in this behalf ex-
pended.</p>
<p>It is further ordered that the bond heretofore given in this cause
be cancelled, and the bondsman released from all liability,
and that the cash bond, if any, in the hands of the sheriff of King
County be returned to said bondsmen.</p>
<p>Done in open court this 29th day of January, 1904.</p>
<p>(Signed) Boyd J. Tallman,
Judge.</p>
<p>page 62</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>