<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0490.013">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ng Kwack Kang v. King County. Points and Authorities</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Daoud, Mariam M." xml:id="mmd">Mariam M. Daoud</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0490.013</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ng Kwack Kang v. King County. Brief of United States</title>
<date when="1915-12-20">December 20th, 1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno>Case No 3157</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1916-01">January 1916</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>White, Henry M.</term>
<term>Kum, Ng</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Kang, Ng Kwack</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, Adam</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay</persName>
<persName>Moodie, Albert</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
<person role="clerk">
<persName>Crosby, Frank L.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>King County</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#mmd">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0490.013"/>

<p>
In the United States District Court, In and for the Western District
of Washington, Northern Division.

In the matter of the application of 
Ng Kwack Kang, for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus.

No. 3157
Points and Authorities

This case not only involves the right of a child of a 
native born <add>Chinese</add> citizen to enter into the United States, but involves
the larger question of parentage. If the petitioner is the son of 
Ng Kum, then he is the heir of Ng Kum, and as such heir he is entitled 
to the right of inheritance, which, if the ruling of the
Secretary of Labor and Commerce shpuld be upheld, would, not only 
deprive the petitioner of the right of entry into the United States,
but would deprive the petitioner of the rights of succession and inheritance
as the heir of Ng Kum.

It is conceded upon a question of citizenship alone that a
decision of the Secretary of Labor and Commerce is final,
unless there appears to be an abuse of discretion. But the petitioner in 
this case contends that the decision of a ministerial officer as to
his parentage, is not final, and that he has a right to a judicial 
hearing, to determine the question of his parentage. The petitioner
seeks to review the findings of the Commissioner of Immigration, not
alone upon the question of citizenship and abuse of discretion, but
upon the question of his parentage, For your petitioner to be, by 
a ruling of a ministerial officer, unjustly deprived of the right 
of succession and inheritance, would be to deprive him of his property 
without due process of law.

The petitioner in this case seeks admission into the United 
States, not as an American born citizen of the United States, but as
the son of his father, which has been legally adjudged an American b
orn citizen. (See Exhibit B, Ng Kwack Kang) For the United States 
Government to take this young boy before executive officers, and
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
in what might be in every sense of the word, termed " a star chamber
proceeding"; without being confronted by witnesses, with no opportunity
for cross-examination, without the aid of counsel, and upon 
the unsworn and ex parte statements and conclusions of what appears
biased and prejudiced officials - to be by them, upon conjecture and 
doubt officially declared that he is not the son of his father, and
to deny him the right of entry into the United States, the opportunity
and advantaged of education, and last, but not least, the loving
care of his father, and to say that such a determination is final,
and that the applicant cannot have his parentage judicially determined
would be a monstrous and <add>an</add> iniquitious proceeding, contrary to 
all the rules of fair play.

Parentage has never been determined by ministerial officers
.. is not now determied by ministerial officers.. and will never
be finally determined by ministerial officers.

It will be noted from the examination of Ng Kum set forth
in "Exhibit B", November 17th, 1910, that Ng Kum gave the following
testimony:
Q. What are your names?
A. NG KUM, given name - NG HONG FAN, marriage name - no others.
Q. When were you married?
A. When I was twenty years old to Chin She, natural, 29
Back Wut Village, Sn, living now and since I married her
in Gong Ben Sn, China.
Q. Have you any children?
A. One son, NG KG Kwock Teun, 10, born 8/15, forgot year. No
daughters.
This testimony was given at a time when there could have 
been no motive for making a false statement.
At this point it might be well to consider the nativity 
of Ng Kum. In the record the following question appears to be 
propounded by the inspector:
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
Q. Is that your cert. of disch. and your photo thereon?
A. Yes. (indicating cert. of disch. in name of NG Kum, 
dated April 11, 1901, by Wm. V.S. Woodward, U.S. Comr.
No. Dist. of N.Y. On Cert. is also added "Release pursuant
to an Order of Honorable Alfred C. Coxe, U.S.
District Judge." Report of H.E. Owen, Assistant U.S. 
Attorney, dated November 15th 1910, and shows that
cert. is genuine and evidence forwarded by N.Y. inspector,
shows issue was nativity.)

Upon the completion of the testimony, the following note
appears:
Inspector's note: "From the completed record I am of the
opinion that the applicant's nativity is res adjudicata,
and he is therefore admitted.
    
(Exhibit "B" - case Ng Kwack Kang, Immigration Service Number 32828)
    
From the original record on appeal in case of NG <choice><sic>KWOCK</sic><corr>KWACK</corr></choice> KANG
File Number 54005/86, in the memorandum of the Acting Secretary, in
re APPEAL of NG <choice><sic>KWOCK</sic><corr>KWACK</corr></choice> KANG, aged 16, the following appears:
"1. Reason claimed as ground for admission:
That applicant is the son of a native.
2. Reason for exclusion at the port:
That alleged relationship has not been established.
3. Issue: Relationship.
4. Substance of record in support of admission:
Harmonious portions of record.
5. Substance of record opposed to admission:
Lack of satisfactory evidence of status of
alleged father and discrepancies indicating
doubt as to bona fides of claimed relationship.

Applicant applies for admission to Seattle as the son of
an American-born Chinese who resides <choice><sic>is</sic><corr>in</corr></choice> Boston. The identifying
witness lives in New York. This record, therefore, has been 
transmitted from Seattle to Boston and New York for examination
of the respective witnesses and, upon its return to Seattle,
the applicant was reexamined. As a result, there have been 
developed between his testimony and that of the other witnesses 
discrepancies of so material and positive a nature that there 
is serious doubt as to the bona fides of the relationship said
to exist between the alleged father and himself. The report
of the Acting Inspector in Charge at New York (pp26-29) also
raises the question of the competency of the evidence submitted
by the alleged father to establish his American nativity."

Q. Us the petitioner's status, parentage and relationship to 
be thus established by a ministerial officer upon doubt, conjecture
and surmise, if there exists <add>only</add> a doubt in the mind of this executive
</p>
<pb></pb>
    
<p>
officer as to the bona fides of the realtionship existing between
this petitioner and his father? Is this petitioner to be, not only 
deprived of the right of entry into the United States, but to be 
deprived of the right of succession and precluded from enjoying a 
father's loving care?
If there exists a doubt, even if it be a serious doubt
as to the bona fides of the realtionship between this applicant and
his father, that doubt should be resolved in favor of the applicant, 
and not against him.
The discrepeancies referred to are pointed out under the
captions "A", "B", "C", "D"  and "E". Considering the discrepancies 
pointed out under caption "D";

"The applicant and his alleged father disagreed concerning
the names and families of the occupants of most of the houses 
in their native village concerning whom they were questioned,
although they agree positively about their next door neighbors,
i.e., the families living to the right and left of them in
their row and opposite their house in the rows on either side.
This would indicate that they have prepared their testimony 
especially regarding their next door neighbors and had failed to 
do so concerning the other occupants of the village in China."
        
NG KUM was born in San Francisco, California, and not in 
China. The Honorable Secretary reasons that because the father and son 
agreed upon their next door neighbors that they were lying, and because 
they did not agree as to the names of the other families living 
in their native village, they were not father and son.

The discrepancies pointed out by the Immigration Official 
set forth in this memorandum, evidences an honest case rather than 
otherwise.

William C. Prout in his argument to the COmmissioner
General of Immigration, ably said:
"After making due allowance for the boy's youth and inexperience, 
and bearing in mind that being so young and so far 
from home in a country so strange in every detail, he udoubtedly 
was very much frightened and confused, so that in some things 
his testimony is not altogether correct. But, bearing these 
various reasons for confusion in mind, it must be admitted that 
the evidence given by him is substantially the same as that
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
given by his father. Of course, there are minor discrepancies, 
as there are bound to be in every case, but on the points which 
the boy could be reasonably expected to be clear his testimony 
leaves no room for criticism. A boy 17 years of age cannot
be expected to remember as clearly and testify as exactly as 
an adult, and a Chinese boy of that age is entitled to a wider 
latitude than would be an American boy.

As to family relations, family history and the various
intimate details of family life, the boy's testimony is precise
and apparently true. In some details he differs from the testimony
of his father, but upon further consideration it would 
appear that these details where they do not allow if a misunderstanding 
because of being a matter of opinion, the boy is 
correct. An example of this is  the conflict of the testimony of 
the father and son as to the burial place of NG GOON. The boy 
testified that he is buried in Mah Gee Hill in China. The 
father testified that he is not certain as to his burial place 
and so far as he knows he is buried in New York. The boy is
quite certain on this point and it is very likely that the Chinese 
Burial Society sent the bones of NG GOON to China for burial 
without the knowledge of NG KUM, the father.

The boy was probably warned or instructed before leaving
China not to give too much information and this probably explains
his statements that so far as he knew and the inhabitants of the
Hong Hing village were all members of the NG family, while the
father testifies that they included members of the MOY, CHUEY,
LEE, CHIN and NG families. This discrepancy evidences an honest
case rather than otherwise, since on such a simple and important 
matter the father and son would be in accord if the case were 
a dishonest one, and one which had been prepared in advance.

There are other matters of lesser importance in the testimony
upon which the boy and his father do not agree, but these 
are matters which rest almost altogether in the memory of the 
witness and consequently a difference between their testimony 
can readily be accounted for. They both agree that there are
ten or eleven rows in the village; that there are from twenty 
to thirty houses in the village, the boy describes the ownership
of the various houses correctly and describes the village
correctly, or at least the testimony of father and son on these
points is in accord in the more important particulars. The
HONG PING, his own village, in the village hall. The father 
gives as a reason that the boy did not attend school in HONG PING
that the school building was decayed. It is entirely possible 
that the boy did attend school for a time in HONG MEE, that 
village being but from a quarter to a half mile distant from
HONG PING, but it is entirely possible and on the evidence seems
to be the case, that the village hall in HONG PING had been repaired
and possible enlarged, as the boy and father both give 
the same location for the school house in HONG PING.

The father talks of a village known as SHEK KOW WAI, and
the boy appears to be unfamiliar with this village. This would
seem to be hard to explain, since SHEK KOW WAI is supposed to
between HONG PING and HONG MEE, but the father testified that it 
is "practically" between HONG PING and HONG MEE, thus making it
likely that it sets out to one side and it is also quite probable
that the boy knew the village under some other name.
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
The only other discrepancy in the testimony that amounts
to anything is the testimony as to the physical condition of 
applicant's paternal grandmother. The father testified that
his mother was humpbacked and the boy in the first instance
testified that she had physical defects, but then stated 
that he understood the question to refer to his own mother
instead of his father's mother. Even though this were true, 
this is not at all serious since in our language the word
humpbacked is frequently used to denote the stoop which comes
with old age and the witness might have used this word intending 
to mean that rather than any congenital defect.

Appended to this appeal is a drawing of the town of HONG
PING, made by NG KUM, the applicant's father. If the Honorable 
Commissioner General remains in doubt as to the relationship
of applicant to NG KUM, applicant respectfully suggests that 
he be given a chance to make a similar drawing, or to fill in a 
blank duplicate of the same, in order that it may be compared 
with this original.

From the reasons for denying the application given, it
does not appear that the American citizenship of the father is
in question, since the finding does not specifically so state,
therefore applicant has not touched upon this phase of the 
case in this appeal, and from the record in the case it appears
that the father has been duly adjudicated an American citizen
by a court of competent jurisdiction, behind whose verdict no
inquiry can be made in this proceeding."

Immigration officers cannot act arbitrarily in refusing 
to believe persons sought to be deported, or his witnesses.
U.S. vs Lee Chung, 206 Fed. 367;
In re, Gin Wong Lee, 91 Fed. 240;
Wong Chung vs. U.S., 179 Fed. 182;
94 C .C.A., 198;
U.S. vs Leung S an, et al, 144 Fed. 72.

The burden of proof is on the Immigration officials.
U.S. ex rel, Castro vs. Williams, 203 Fed. 155.
It is not sufficient to raise a doubt. 
U.S. vs. Hong Lin, 214 Fed. 456.
One cannot be deported on insufficient or illegal evidence,
ex parte, Yah Ucaina, 199 Fed. 885.

In determining whether aliens are entitled to admission, 
the Immigration authorities act in an administrative and not a judicial 
capacity, and must follow definite standards, and apply general rules.
U.S. vs. Uhl, 203 Fed., 152.
Congress has seen fit to base the final decision as to the 
rights of aliens to enter the country in the Department of Commerce
</p>
<pb></pb>
    
<p>
and Labor, but that Department is governed by certain rules and regulations,
which must be strictly construed in conformity with the
eternal principles of justice and right.
        
It is fundamental in American jurisprudence that every
person is entitled to a fair trial by an impartial tribunal.
U.S. vs. Redfern, 180 Fed. 500;
In the case of U.S. vs. Williams, 185 Fed., 598, 599, District 
Judge Holt, after stating the usual procedure in deportation proceedings, says:

"It is, of course, obvious that such a method of procedure 
disregards almost every fundamental principle established in
England and this contry for the protection of persons charged
with an offense. The person arrested does not necessarily know 
who instigated the prosecution. He is held in seclusion, and is 
not permitted to consult counseel until he has been privately
examined under oath. The whole proceeding is usually substantially 
in control of one of the inspectors, who acts in it as informer, 
arresting officer, inquisitor, and judge. The Secretary who issues 
the Order of arrest and the Order of deportation is an administrative 
officer who sits hundreds of miles away, and never hears or 
sees the person proceeded against or the witnesses. Aliens, if
arrested, are at least entitled to the rights which such a system
accords them; and, if they are deprived of <choice><sic>anu</sic><corr>any</corr></choice> such right, the
proceeding is clearly irregular, and any order of deportation
issued is invalid."

The petitioner's full rights, provided for in relation 
to the Chinese Exclusion Law, have been violated. He was denied the
right to have his appeal heard and determined by the Secretary of 
Labor and Commerce, as provided by law. W.B. Wilson is the Secretary
of Labor, and Louis Post is his only Assistant Secretary of Labor.
The petitioner appealed to the Secretary of Labor from the decision
denying him the right to enter and remain in the United States. The 
applicant's appeal, under the law, should have been heard by the
Secretary of Labor, unless he was unable to act, then his Assistant 
Secretary should have heard and determined the matter. The applicant's
appeal was heard and determined, not by the Secretary of Labor, but
the appeal and the Order affirming the findings of the Commissioner 
of Immigration of Seattle was heard, determined and approved by one,
Alfred Hampton, without designing any name or authority vested in
</p>
<pb></pb>
    
<p>
Albert Hampton, or that the Secretary of Labor was absent, or unable 
to act. The findings were approved only by Louis Post, Assistant 
Secretary, page 31 of the Treaty Law and Rules governing the Admission
of Chinese, approved January 24th, 1914, it is provided:

"That every case where an alien is excluded from admission 
into the United States under any law or treaty now existing 
or hereafter made, the decision of the appropriate Immigration
Officials, if adverse to the admission of such alien,
shall be final, unless reversed on appeal to the Secretary 
Of Labor."

Applicant appeaked to the Secretary of Labor, and under
the law had a right to have his appeal determined by the Secretary
of Labor. The findings and judgement of Alfred Hampton, approved
by Louis Post, the Assistant Secretary of Labor, was not in strict
compliance with the law. Suppose in a proceeding like the case at
bar, the matter should be referred to the Court Commissioner for determination.
It might be that the Court Commissioner was perfectly 
capable to pass on the issues involved, but if he were to do so, 
and the Judge should approve his findings, no one would question 
the illegality of the proceeding. The methods of procedure in 
immigration matters disregard almost every fundamental principle of 
law. The person arrested does not necessarily know who instigated
the prosecution. He is held in seclusion, and is not permitted to
consult counsel until he is privately examined under oath. The 
whole proceeding is usually substantially controlled by one of the 
inspectors, who acts as informer, arresting officer, inquisitor 
and judge. The Secretary who issues the Order of arrest, and the 
Order of deportation is an administrative officer who sits undereds
of miles away, and never heards or sees the person proceeded against, 
or the witnesses. Aliens, if arrested, are entitled to the rights 
which such a system accords them, and if they are deprived of any 
such right, the proceeding is clearly irregular, and any Order of 
Deportation issued is invalid.
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
The Immigration system accorded the applicant the right to appeal
to the Secretary of Commerce and Labor, and it accorded him a right
to have his appeal heard, determined and adjudged by the Secretary
of Labor. This was denied him; the proceedings, therefore, were irreular,
and the Order of Deportation is invalid. The Immigration 
Officers must strictly follow the rules, which rules must not be 
inconsistent with the established law.

U.S> vs. Williams, 185 Fed. 598;
Roux vs. Com. of Immigration, 203 Fed. 413;
Manges vs Whitfield, 209 Fed., 675, affirmed
222 Fed. 745;
Ex parte Lam Pui, 217 Fed. 456;
Ex parte Lan Fuk Tak, 217 Fed., 468.

It is most respectfully urged that the discrepancies pointed
out by the Commissioner are but minor discrepancies, which are of a 
less material nature than usually occur in actions before a court.
The testimony as a whole, fairly and justly reviewed, unqualifiedly
establishes the parentage of this petitioner.

It is admitted that this court cannot review the findings 
if there be legal evidence to support such findings, but there is no
evidence in this action to support the findings of the Immigration
Commissioner, and the evidence is overwhelmingly in favor of the
petitioner, and is sufficient to establish his parentage in any
judicial proceeding. The decision of the Immigration Commissioner
is arbitrary, unjust and not supported by any evidence. There is
no evidence in the records to sustain the exclusion and deportation
order, and your petitioner most respectfully contends that he was 
denied a full and fair hearing on the charged which threatened his 
deportation, which was contrary to law.

A full and fair hearing on the charges which threatens his
deportation and an absence of all abuse of discretion and arbitrary
action by the inspector, or other executive officer, are indispensable
to the lawful deportation of an alien. Where, by the abuse of
</p>
<pb></pb>
    
<p>
the discretion or the arbitrary action of the inspector or other
executive officer, or without a full and fair hearing, and alien
is deprived of his liberty, or is about to be deported, the power is
conferred, and the duty is imposed upon the Courts of the United 
States to issue a writ of habeas corpus and relieve him.

The Japanese Immigration Case, 189 U.S., 86, 100, 101; 47 Law Ed. 721;
Chin Yow vs. U.S., 208 U.S., 8, 10, 12, 13; 52 Law Ed., 369; Low Wah
Suey vs Backus, 225 U.S. 460; 56 Law Ed., 1165.

The record shows that the petitioner was denied the right
to face the witnesses whose testimony was taken by the United States
Government. The record shows that he was denied the right of cross-examination
of the witnesses who gave testimony for, and in behalf 
of the Government. The petitioner, the record shows, was denied the
right to face the witnesses who gave testimony for and in behalf of
the government. Testimony may, no doubt, be taken in the form of
affidavits, or otherwise, preliminary to, and as a basis for, an 
application for warrants of arrest of specified aliens when the Immigration 
Officers are credibly informed, or have good reasons to be believe
that such aliens are unlawfully within the United Srares, but
is the testimony so taken upon the preliminary hearing, even when 
lawfully taken, admisible against the aliens upon the hearing required
to be given them after warrants for their arrest have been
issued, to determine whether or not they shall be deported? It is
incumbent upon the Government to establish competent evidence
that the petitioner in this case is not the son of NG KUM. True, the
proceeding for this purpose may be summary, and before an <choice><sic>esecutive</sic><corr>executive</corr></choice>
or other authorized official of the Government; but it must be a
lawful proceeding and established by competent evidence, and the
petitioner afforded a fair hearing, and an opportunity to discredit
or disprove the evidence adduces against him. Such an opportunity
requires that he have the benefit of counsel at every stage of the
proceedings after his arrest, with the right to cross-examine witnesses,
whose testimony is to be used against him before the Bureau
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
of Immigration in determining whther or not he should be deported.

"The right of cross-examination is one of the principal,
as it is one of the surest, tests which the law affords for the
ascertainment of the truth in all disputed matters of fact; and
it is indispensable in all judicial proceedings in this country,
civil or criminal, that ex parte testimony, even though given
under the solemnity of, a legal oath or affirmation that it is
true, taken in the absence of and without opportunity at some
stage of the proceedings to the party to whom it is proposed to
be used to cross-examine the witnesses giving such testimony,
cannot rightly be used against him."

1 Greefleaf Ev. (16th Ed.) 447; 2 Wigmore on Evidence, 1361 &amp; 1365.
In U.S. vs Williams, 185 Fed. 598, 604;/ U.S. vs. Williams,
D.C., 193 Fed. 231, the court states;

"Indispensable requisites of a fair hearing according to 
these funamantal principles are that the course of proceedings
shall be appropriate to the case and just to the party affected.
That the party shall be notified of the nature of the charge
against him in time to meet it; that he shall have such an
opportunity to be heard that he may, if he chooses, cross-examine
the witnesses against him; that he may have time and
opportunity, after all the evidence against him is produced and 
known to him, to produce evidence and witnesses to refute it;
that the decision shall be governed by and based upon the evidence
at the hearing, and that only; and that the decision shall not
be without substantial evidence taken at the hearing, to
support it.

In re Rosser, 101 Fed. 562; 41 C.C.A. 497; in re Wood and 
Henderson, 210 U.S. 246, 254; 52 Law Ed. 1046; Interstate Commerce 
Commission vs Louisville &amp; Nashville Ry. Co., 227 U.S. 88, 91
and 93; 57 Law Ed. 431; ex parte Patkos D.C. 212 Fed. 275-278.

That is not a fair hearing in which the inspector chooses
or vontrols the witnesses or prevents the accused from procuring
witnesses or evidence or counsel he desires.

China Yow vs. U.s., 208 U.s. 11; 52 Law Ed. 369; U.S. vs.
Sibray, C.C., 178 Fed. 144; U.S. vs. Williams, D.C., 185 Fed.
598; Roux vs. Commissioner of Immigration, 203 Fed. 413; 212 C. 
C. A., 523."

In the case of Lam Fuk Tak, 217 Fed. 468, 469, the court
said:

"It is apparent that many of what we are accustomed to regard
as the essential safeguards of individual liberty were ignored.
The prisoner was not allowed to see any of the witnesses
against him while they were testifying, nor to cross-examine them; 
and he had no power to make them testify afterwards. All the oral
testimony against the prisoner (except his own) was taken behind
his back, and, if not secretly, at least without notive to him
or to his counsel, although the latter was well known to the
officers, and had seasonably demanded the right to be present at
the taking of the testimony and to cross-examine the witnesses.
The petitioner was denied the assistance of counsel both before and
while giving his testimony at, the first so-called 'hearing'
before the officers, and also at the second 'hearing'.
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
Statements of fact not under oath, made by persons not
connected with the prisoner or with the Immigration Department,
and never present at any hearing, were used against him.

The proceedings plainly were not of a judicial character,
they cannot be supported, it seems to me, as legitimate administrative
proceeding, because the officers did not endeavor
themselves to ascertain the truth about the matter. Tan Tun vs.
Ednell, supra., U.S. v. Sprung, 187 Fed. 903, 907, 110 C.C., 
37 (dissenting opinion, by Pritchard, J.); Bouve on Aliens, p.
518. They evidently became convinced that in investigating
Hop Lee's Laundry they had stumbled upon an organized and far
reaching plot to enter Chinatown fraudulently into the United
States. They believed that his petitioner was among the
persons whose admission had been so procured. They, thereupon
instituted proceedings against him endeavored by every legal
means in their power to secure his deportation. They did not 
act in bad faith; I do not doubt that they honestly believed
the prisoner to be unlawfully here. I think, however, that the
immigration records show that they were endeavoring to make
out a case,r ather than to act in a fair or judicial manner
toward the alien. I see no other explanation of their refusal 
to allow him the assistance of counsel, their ommission to 
notify his counsel of the taking of testimony in Pennsylvania,
their uncritical acceptance and use of the testimony of Hop Lee,
taken in proceedings to which this prisoner was not a party,
and under circumstances which, as these experienced officers
must have known, rendered it of <choice><sic>littlr</sic><corr>little</corr></choice> or no value, the extremely
partisan character of the Mallett and Rodgers reports, 
andd also, perhaps, the lack of any proper effort to obtain for
these proceedings information from the San Francisco officers
concerning the admission thre and the testimony of the witnesses
on which the petitioner was admitted, though this was to
some extent done in a different proceeding, the record of which
was submitted to the Secretary, and it may have been the duty
of the petitioner to get more complete evidence from San Francisco,
if necessary for his case.

Why were the ordinary safegaurds against injustice refused
or ignored? Why was no notice given to the petitioner's counsel
that the testimony of the Pennsylvania witnesses was to be 
taken? Why was Hop Lee not examined in the proceedings against 
this petitioner and offered for cross-examination? Why was the
petitioner denied the right of counsel before the first hearing,
and at any 'hearing', until the government's case against him
had been completed? These seem to me to be vital questions in 
considering the fairness of the proceedings; and no answers to
them have been suggested by the respindent, except that the
officers were not legally obliged to do more than they did,
which is the attitude of a prosecutor, rather than of a judge,
or of a fair adminstrative officer, in a case like the present.

It is true that the right to counsel secured by the 
Constitution (Amendemnet 6, Sec. 1) related only to criminal
prosecutions; but it is equally true that that provision was
inserted in the Constitution because the assistance of counsel
was recognized as essential to any fair trial of a case against 
a prisoner. See, too, Amendment 14. To make the defendant's
substantial rights in a matter involving personal liberty
depend on whether the proceeding be called 'criminal' or 'civil'
seems to be unsound. Indeed, historically the right to counsel
in civil cases and upon charges of misdemeanors antedates such
right in cases of felony and treason. Cooley, Constitutional
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
Limitations, p. 475. 'The presence, advice, and assistance of 
counsel,' is said by Story to be necessarily included in 'due 
process of law.' Story on Constitution, p. 668. Without undertaking
to say that a prisoner has an absolute right to counsel
before administrative boards, not composed of lawyers, or that
the denial of counsel would in every case prevent such proceedings
from being fair, I am of opinion that, under such circumstances
as are disclosed in this case, where counsel for a
prisoner seasonably requests the privilege of conferring with 
him before the trial and of being prsent during the taking of
the evidence, the refusal of that request puts upon the officiall
so cating a great burden of explanation and of scrupulous regard
for the prisoners rights which in this case is not met.
Ex parte Lam Pui (D.C.) 217 Fed. 456

And while it is true that the administrative boards are 
generally speaking, entitled ot make their own rules of evidence, 
and to consider any evidence which to their minds is probative 
value, there are, nevertheless, certain fundamental principles
which can hardly be diregarded, consistently with fair treatment 
to the prisoner, and which were not observed in this instance. 
Moreover, he had had a trial in San Francisco, which 
had resulted in his favor. He was poor, and was under great 
difficulty in retrying that issue at a point 3,000 miles away.
This seems to me one more circumstance which called upon the 
officers to be scrupulously careful and fair in their investigations.

It does not seem to me that the opportunity here given
to present evidence and to argue the case rendered the proceedings
fair, or in accordance with due process of law. They are
to be viewed as a whole, and, so viewed, they present, to my
mind, a plain violation of the fundamantal principles of fair
play by the Immigration inspectors. I find and rule that the
proceedings before them were substantially - - and on account of 
their mistaken attitude towards the matter I think intentionally -
unfair to the alien. The Acting Secretary, instead of disaffirming
the illegal confuct of his subordinates, approved it and 
based his decision on it. In this case the petitioner belongs to 
a race little favored by our law. But it has been held that
immigration tribunals have authority to determine finally, with 
no appeal to the law courts or to a jury, questions of citizenship; 
and the next case of this chatacyer may be one of an 
American citizen endeavoring to protect himself against exile
by administrative order made in this way. U.S. v. Ju Toy, 198
U.S. 253, 25 Sup. Ct. 644, 49 L. Ed. 1040; Tang Tun Case, Supra,

Without considering the other points urged on behalf of
the petitioner, I am of opinion that he had not a fair hearing 
before the immigration authorities."

We respectfully submit that under the law and the evidence
the petitioner did not have a fair and impartial hearing; that the
evidence is sufficient to establish the fact that NG KWACK KANG
is the son of NG KUM, a native born American citizen.
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
Wherefore, your petitioner respectfully prays that the
findings of the Immigration Department be reversed, and the Order of
Deportation heretofore made, be set aside, and that your petitioner 
be admitted into the United States, as the son of NG KUM.

Respectfully submitted,

<signatures>Beeler &amp; Sullivan</signatures>
Attorneys for petitioner, 
NG KWACK KANG
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
Copy of within Points &amp; authorities
recieved and due service of same acknowledge this 
20th day of Dec 1915
Clay Allen
Attorney for Respondents

No. 3157
Original
In the <add>U.S.</add>
<del>Superior</del><add>District</add> Court
<del>State of Washington
King County</del>
In and for the Western
District of Washington, 
Northern Division.

Plaintiff
vs.
In the matter of the application of Ng Kwack Kang
for a Writ of habeas corpus

Defendant

Points and Authorities

Beeler &amp; Sullivan
Lawyers
510-11 White Building
Seattle, Wash.
</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>