<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the Circuit Court of the United States Ninth Circuit</p>

<p>Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus of Tom Sing</p>

<p>Filed in the U.S. Circuit Court, Dist. of Washington. OCT 7 1904, A Reeves Ayres, Clerk. A.N. Moore Dep.</p>

<p>Sanders and Sanders, Attys for Petitioner</p>

<pb/>

<p>In the Circuit Court of the United States, Ninth Circuit</p>

<p>To the Honorable William B. Gilbert, Judge of the Circuit Court of the Ninth Circuit</p>

<p>Ham Hung Wah, by Tom Sing, his Guardian in this behalf respectfully shows, That he the said
       Ham Hung Wah is now unlawfully detained, confined and restrained of his liberty by Thomas M.
       Fisher, Chinese Inspector at Port Townsend in the State of Washington in the said Ninth Circuit.</p>

<p>That the said detention, confinement and restraint are illegal in this that Your Petitioner Ham Hung Wah
       is a native born citizen of the United States, having been born of parents domiciled in the United States
       and subject to the jurisdiction thereof at three hundred and four (304) Wyoming Street in the City of Butte,
       Silver Bow County, State of Montana, in said Circuit, in 1893. That his parents were then permanently
       domiciled in the United States as alien residents therein, not appointed, employed or engaged in any
       diplomatic or other service of any foreign Prince, Potentate, Republic or Government but that the said
       Tom Sing who is Father of him the said Ham Hung Wah was then a laborer residing in the United States
       and China and the laws in such case made and provided and having the Laborer's Cerfificate therein
       required was and is entitled to be and remian lawfully within the United States.</p>

<p>That the said Ham Hung Wah in the year 1900 at the request of his grand  parents was sent to China for the
       purpose of visiting them and entering a Chinese school where he remained until 1904 when he returned to
       his native country as well might and where he is entitled to all the rights and privileges of all other American
       citizens and your petitioner says that his Father Tom Sing with his wife he lay since birth have resided in Utah
       and Montana continously and now reside at Boseman, Montana. </p>

<pb/>

<p>And your petitioner further says that upon his return from China in 1904, to Port Townsend in the State of Washington
       he was arrested and detained by the Chinese Inspector in Charge at said Port Townsend in the said State of Washington
       in said Circuit under some pretense of right or authority so to do by virtue of some law of the United States and is now so
       held, Imprisoned, detained and confined unlawfully by him the said Thomas M. Fisher who is now such Chinses Inspector
       in Charge and acting as such and who assumes by virtue of some pretended authority for the United States to have the
       right not only to so detain and imprison him without bail or mainprise and forcibly and against the will of your petitioner to
       deport him from the United States to the Chinese Empire as being an alien Chinese person seeking unlawfully to land in
       the United States whereas in truth and in fact said Chinese Inspector has no such right or authority because your petitioner
       says he was born in the United States, is subject to the jurisdiction therof and is a citizen of the same and entitled upon a
       Writ of Habeas Corpus or otherwise to have his said citizenship judicially determined by due process of law and not arbitrarily
       by executive or ministerial officers. </p>

<p>And your petitioner says that he is not advised as to what particular inquisition has been made or upon what evidence the said
       Thomas M. Fisher has arrived at his conclusion that your petitioner was unlawfully seeking to enter the United States nor has he
       had any opportunity to hear the testimony of or cross examine any witnesses upon that subject nor ahs nay hearing been accorded
       him before any competent tribunal to establish to its satisfactio his citizenship of and right to enter the United States and the said
       Thomas M. Fisher is threatening to and will unless restrained by the issuance of the Writ of Habeas Corpus or some other appropriate
       remedy deport your petitioner from his native land without giving him an opportunity to establish before a competent tribunal his lawful
       right to enter and remain therein.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Your petitioner says taht he was informed by the said Chinese Inspector or his assistants that his right to enter the Unted States
       was denied and his application therefor rejected and that he had two days in which to appeal that he was more than eight hundred
       miles from his home, was detained by the said Inspector, that he telegraphed to his Father at Bozeman, Montana the fact of his
       rejection but did not receive an answer to his despatch in time to avall himself of such right to apeal within the two days designated
       and his effort to appeal came too late.</p>

<p>That he a was a child twelve years old, without parents, guardian or lawyer by reason whereof his desire to show his right to enter
       the United States before said Executive officers, came to naught.</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus may be granted, directed to Thomas M. Fisher, Chinese Inspector in
       charge at Port Townsend in the State of Washington, as aforesaid, commanding him to have the body of said Ham Hung Wah
       before your Honor at a time and place, therein to be specified or before a Judge holding the Circuit Court of the United States
       for the District of Montana, at Helena, in said District, to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by the judge
       hearing the same, concerning said Ham Hung Wah, together with the time and cause of his detention, and said writ, and that he,
       the said Ham Hung Wah may be restored to his liberty.</p>

<p>Dated this 3rd day of Octboer, 1904</p>

<p>Tom Sing</p>

<p>United States of America, District of Montana</p>

<p>Tom Sing, father of the foregoing Ham Hung Wah, and his natural guardian, upon his corporal cath doth
       say and swoar: That he has heard read the foregoing petition, of Ham Hung Wah by this affiant, as his guardian, and knows the con</p>

<pb/>

<p>tents thereof, and that upon his information and belief so much of the <unclear></unclear>sets forth the unlawful detention and restraint of his
       liberty by Thomas M. Fisher, and so much of the same as sets forth the length of time said Han Hung Wah resided in China, and so much of
       the same as states the law applicable to the rights of th said Ham Hung Wah, and so much of the same as states the intent to deport him the
       said Ham Hung Wah, isture; and as to the other matters set forht in the said petition, the same is true of his own knowledge, and that, if an
       opportunity shall be afforded, he will be able, by indubitable proof from Anglo-Saxon and Chinese witnesses, to establish to the satisfaction
       of the court the right of the said Ham Hung Wah to enter and remain in the United States. And furhter sayeth not.</p>

<p>Tom Sing</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this third day of October, 1904.</p>

<p>A.D. McPhurson, U.S. Commisioners</p>

<pb/>

<p>United States of America, District of Washington</p>

<p>Ham Hung Wah, petitioner in the foregoing matter, being first duly sworn, on his oath deposed and says: That so much of said petition as sets
       forth the detention, confinement and restraint of his liberty, and that he was sent from the United States to China in the year 1900, and remained
       there until 1904, and so much thereof as relates to his arrest and detention by the Chinese Inspector at Port Townsend, Washington: and so much
       thereof as sets forth his ignorance of any trial or testimony had</p>

<pb/>

<p>against this petitioenr, and that he has had no hearing before any court, and that he is threatened to be deported from the United States, and that his
       right to enter the same has been denied, and his application rejected, and that he had two days within which to appeal, and that he was distant from his
       home, and that he telegraphed to his father the fact of his rejection, and did not receive an answer to his dispatch in time to avail himself of such right of
       appeal, is true, of his own knowledge, and that as to the other matters and things set forth in said petition, the same is true to his best knowledge,
       information and belief; and if an opportunity shall be afforded, your petitioner, he believes he will be able to establish by competent, credible and conclusive
       proof his citizenship of the United States, and his right to enter therein, and remain without let or hindrance from any ministerial or executive officer or any
       other authority or person whatsoever. And further sayeth not.</p>

<p><unclear>foreign signature</unclear></p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this Second day of October, 1904.</p>

<p><unclear>notary signature</unclear></p>

<p>Notary Public in and For the State of Washington. Residing at Port Townsend</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>