<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0366.500"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Brief Opposing Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0366.500</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Extradition.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">September 2, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date>29 July 1899</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Denning, J. Henry</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>grace</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName></placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022" who="AS">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0366.500"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>IN THE DISTRICT OF THE UNITED STATES
WESTERN DISTRICT NORTHERN DIVISION</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE EXTRADITION
of 
FLETCHER DECKER.) ( )</p> 
<p>No.</p> 
<p>B R I E F
opposing petition for
WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS</p> 
<p>The proceedings before the commissioner were pursuant
to the Extradition Treaties between U.S. and Great Britian 
of 1842 and 1889. For these treaties, see Malloy's Treaties,
Vol.1, page 655 and 740.</p> 
<p>The present hearing being one on Habeas Corpus before
the District Court, the first inquiry is as to the scope of
review of the District Court: on a habeas corpus hearing:</p> 
<p>POWER OF DISTRICT COURT OF HABEAS CORPUS PROCEEDINGS TO REVIEW
PROCEEDINGS OF THE COMMISSIONER IS LIMITED TO DETERMINING
WHETHER THERE WAS ANY LEGAL EVIDENCE UPON WHICH COMMISSIONER
COULD EXERCISE HIS JUDGMENT AND WHETHER ANY PROBABLE CAUSE
EXISTED FOR COMMISSIONER BELIEVING PRIONER GUILTY.</p> 
<p>In re Count De Touluse Lautrec, 102 Fed 879.
Matter of Wahl, 15 Blatch. 334.
Matter of Wiegand, 14 Blatch. 370.
Ex p. Van Aernam 3 Blatch 160.
Ex p. Van Hoven, 4 Dill 415.
Terlinden vs Ames 184 U.S. 270.
Bryant v. U.S. 167 U.S. 104.
Ornelas vs. Ruiz 161 U.S 502.
Fong Yue Ting vs U.S. 149 U.S. 698.
In re Cortes, 136 U.S. 330.
Benson vs. McMahon, 127 U.S. 457.
Sternaman vs. Peck 80 Fed. 883.
In re Fowler 4 Fed. 303.
In re Veremaitre, 3 Am. L. J. N. S, 438
28 Fed. Cases No. 16,915.
In re McDonell, 11 Blatch. 170,
16 Fed. Cas. No. 8772.
In re Kaine, 10 N.Y. Leg. Obs. 257,
14 Fed. Cas. 7598.
In re Stupp 12 Blatch. 501.
Matter of Vandervelpen 14 Blatch. 137.
In re Krojanker, 44 Fed. 482.
In re Behrendt 22 Fed. 699.</p> 
<p>Fed Case 16409</p>  
<pb></pb> 
<p>In re Wadge 16 Fed. 332
Grin vs Shine 187 U.S. 191
In re Herskovitz 136 Fed. 713.
Ex parte Charlton 185 Fed. 880.
Powell vs U.S. 206 Fed. 400. 
Ex parte Schorer 197 Fed. 78.</p> 
<p>In re Herskovitz, 136 Fed. 713.</p>
<p>On petition for Habeas Corpus after proceedings
before the Commissioner.</p> 
<p>"By section 5270, already referred to, concurrent
jurisdiction is given to the serveral officers
named in the statute to issue warrants, hear exam-
inations, and to commit in extradition proceedings.
This, the, is a collateral attack upon the judg-
ment of a concurrent court. It is too well settled
to require the citation of authority that the writ
of habeas corpus cannot be used as a method or fe-
viewing proceedings as if upon error, and that judg-
ments or findings of courts of competent jurisdic-
tion cannot be set aside or avoided by this pro-
cedure because of error. Under the provisions of
the statute the commissioner had full jurisdiction
of the subject-matter, and there is no question
but what he had jurisdiction of the person of the
petitioner. I think the disclosures made at the
examination have, however, cured any defect in the
complaint."</p>
<p>Powell vs. U.S. 206 Fed. 400</p> 
<p>Defense attempted to prove absence from the foreign
country at the time of the offense charged by the way
of alibi, and alleged as error the refusal of the
commissioner to entertain the defense.</p> 
<p>"The commissioner also said orally upon the hearing,
and in his return to the writ issued from the Dis-
trict Court, that he did not disregard the testi-
mony tending to show an alib, but gave it due con-
sideration and did not believe it, and from the
whole testimony drew the conclusion that there was
probable cause to believe Powell guilty."</p> 
<p>Ex parte Charlton 185 Fed. 880.</p> 
<p>"The duty of the committing magistrate is confined 
to determining: First, whether such warrant or cer-
tificate has been issued; second, whether the of-
fense charged against the accused is extraditable un-
der the treaty; third, whether the person brought be-
fore him is the one accused of such crime; and, four-
th, whether there is probably cause for holding the
accused for trial, the evidence in that respect to
be such as, according to the law of the state in
which the accused is apprehended, would be sufficient
to commit him for trial."</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>Sternam vs Peck  80 Fed. 883.</p>
<p>"A writ of habeas corpus cannot perform the office
of a writ of error in reviewing the proceedings in
extradition before an officer authorized to enter-
tain such proceddings. It is efficent only to
reach error which is fatal to the jurisdiction of
the officer over the person of the accused, or
over the subject-matter of the accusation......
.....The evidence was not very satisfactory, and
was far from being convincing. Nevertheless, the
facts and circumstances proved authorized conflict-
ing presumptions and probabilities as to her guilt 
or innocence, and it was the province of the com-
missioner to determine theri import, and whether
they were such as to justify him in exercising
his power to commit her to custody pending the
action of the department of state."</p> 
<p>In re Stupp. 12 Blatch. 501</p> 
<p>The court issuing the writ of habeas corpus
"is not to inquire whether the legal evidence of
facts before the commissioner was sufficient or in-
sufficient to warrant his conclusion; nor, if there
was legal and competent evidence of facts before the
commissioner, for him to consider in making up his
decsion as to the criminality of the accused, is the
court, on habeas corpus, to hold the proceedings il
legal, and to discharge the prisoner, because some
other evidence was introduced which was not legal
or competent, but was held to be so by the commis-
ioner, and was considered by him on the question of
fact, or, because the court, on a consideration of
all the evidence which the commissioner considered,
would have come to a different conclusion, or be-
cause the court on an exclusion of such of the
evidence as it may think was not legal or competent,
would come on the rest of the evidence, to a dif-
erent conclusion of facts from that at which the
commissioner arrived."</p> 
<p>Grin vs Shine. 187 U.S. 181.</p> 
<p>the sufficiency of the evidence cannotbe reviewed
on habeas corpus.</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>Ex parte Schorer 197 Fed. 67.</p> 
<p>The court, after discussing the lack of proof of
intent, said:</p> 
<p>"It is always possible to conceive that the accused
might be an innocent victim of circumstances; but,
if an extradition commissioner has drawn the per-
missable inferences of guilt, it is beyond the prov-
ince of the court on habeas corpus to reject them.
We may note that the testimony given by the accused
before the commissioner, although it consisted of
denials, called for nothing more than the exercise
of the commissioner's discretion in believing it or
disbelieving it. It could not render incompetent
the other testimony, and whether it was worthy of
belief, whether the accused fairly met the incul-
pasing circumstances with which he was confronted,
was within the peculiar province of the commissioner
to determine; and such determination is not review-
able on habeas corpus."</p> 
<pb></pb>
</div1> 
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>