<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0218.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Gussie Goldman Woods v. Henry M. White, Petition For a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0218.005</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Gussie Goldman Woods v. Henry M. White, Petition For a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</title>
<date when="1915-02-15">February 15, 1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-02">February 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Gussie Goldman Woods</term>
<term>HW C. Billingsley</term>
<term>George Vanderveer</term>
<term>Cummings</term>
<term>Henry M. White</term>
<term>Albert H. Joy</term>
<term>Thomas W. Lynch</term>
<term>Fredrick L. Woods</term>
<term>J. B. Densmore</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</term>
<term>State of Washington</term>
<term>Groveland, California</term>
<term>Skagway, Alaska</term>
<term>Empire of Russia</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Gussie Goldman Woods</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>George Vanderveer</persName>
<persName>Cummings</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Clay Allen</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Edward H. Cushman</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington, Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc>
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#AS">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, 
FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTION, 
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION 
OF GUSSIE GOLDMAN WOODS, ALIAS 
GUSSIE GOLDMAN, for a WRIT OF 
HABEAS CORPUS</p>

<p>No. 2960 
PETITION FOR A WRIT OF 
HABEAS CORPUS</p>

<p>To The Honorable The Judges of the above entitled
court:</p>
<p>Now comes Gussie Goldman Woods, the petitioner above
named, by Vanderveer &amp; Cummings, her attorneys, and represents
and shows to Your Honors as follows:</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>That she is a citizen of the United States of America,
over the age of twenty-one years, a resident and citizen of
the State of Washington and the district and division of the
above entitled court above specified; that she is native
of the Russian Empire and came to the United States of America
in the year 1903 where she has since resided.</p> 
<p>II.</p>
<p>That your petitioner intermarried with one Fred L.
Woods in the City of Seattle, Washington, on the 23d day of
November, 1914, and at all times thereafter has been, and still
is, the lawful wife of the said Fred L. Woods; that at the
time of said marriage of your petitioner and said Fred L. 
Woods in the said City of Seattle, State of Washington, in the
United States of America,the said Fred L. was a natural 
born citizen of the United States of America having been born
in the town of Groveland in the State of California, on 
September 12, 1884, and that he has never renounced his allegi-
<pb></pb>
ance to the United States of America.</p>
<p>III.</p>
<p>That on or about the 13th day of October, 1914, your
petitioner was taken into custody of Skagway, Alaska, by one
Albert H. Joy, Immigrant Inspector of the United States, 
upon a warrant issued by one J.B. Densmore, Acting Secretary 
of Labor of the United States, charging your petitioner with
being an alien in the United States of America and with being 
a prostitute, and that she was such at the time of her entry 
into the United States, and that she has entered the United States
for the purpose of prostitution. That thereafter, a hearing
was had before the said Albert H. Joy on the 15th day of
October, 1914, and said cause was transferred for further hear-
ing to Seattle, Washington, where a hearing upon such charge
was held before Thos. W. Lynch, Examining Inspector, and there-
after your petitioner was taken into custody and is now in cus-
tody of Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration, under and
by virtue of a warrant issued by the Secretary of the Depart-
ment of Labor of the United States of America directing that
your petitioner be deported from the United States of America
and transported to the Empire of Russia for the reason as
stated in said warrant, that your petitioner is an alien in 
the United States and had been found practicing prostitution
in the United States of America.</p>

<p>IV.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further avers that she is restrained 
of her liberty by the said Henry M. White, as such Commissioner
of Immigration, under a claim that she is a subject to deporta-
tion for a violation of the laws of the United States in that
being an alien she was found practicing prostitution in the
United States of America.</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>V.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further avers that she is held in
custody under and by virtue of a claim that she has violated
the laws of the United States of America, and she is being held
in such custody within the district and division aforesaid.</p>

<p>VI.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further avers that she is unable to
attach hereto a copy of the process under which she is held
in custody and restrained of her liberty for the reason that
she has no such copy in her possession, and for the reason that 
she has not been furnished with such copy.</p>

<p>VII.</p>
<p>Your petitioner, however, avers that she is being now
restrained of her liberty and held in the custody of Henry M.
White, Commissioner of Immigration, under a pretense of a law
of the United States of America.</p>

<p>VIII.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further avers that at the said hear-
ing before the said Thos. W. Lynch, Examining Inspector, it
appeared conclusively and without contradiction that your
petitioner at all times since her said marriage with the said
Fred L. Woods has been a resident of the United States of
America and a citizen thereof, and that the said warrant of
the Secretary of Labor is invalid and of no force and effect
in law for the reason that your petitioner is not an alien.</p>

<p>IX.</p>
<p>Your petitioner now complains that she is unlawfully 
restrained of her liberty by the said Henry M. White under the
pretense that she has violated a law of the United States of
America, which pretense and claim is unfounded in fact and is
to the said Henry M. White and to the Secretary of Labor of 
the United States well known.</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>X.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further avers that in her confinement
by the said Henry M. White her rights as an American citizen
are infringed and she is deprived of her liberty without any
warrant of law and that such restraint is illegal and invalid</p>

<p>XI.</p>
<p>Your petitioner furthers avers that in the hearing
before the officers of the Immigration Service of the United 
States, she was denied the right to cross-examine witnesses,
to meet the witnesses face to face, and that your petitioner
in such hearing before the officers of the Immigration Service
of the United States was denied a fair and impartial hearing,
and that there was no testimony taken before the said Albert 
H. Joy or Thos. W Lynch tending to show, or which did show,
that your petitioner was at any time subsequent to her said in-
termarriage with said Fred L. Woods an alien to the United
States of America</p>

<p>WHEREFORE your petitioner prays that she may be allow-
ed the writ of right, a Writ of Habeas Corpus to The Honorable 
Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration, directing, com-
anding and requiring the said Henry M. White to produce be-
fore Your Honors at a time and place to be specified, the
body of your petitioner, together with the cause alleged for her
detention by the said Henry M. White, and that she further be
awarded a Writ of Certiorari to the Honorable Henry M. White,
Commissioner of Immigration, commanding and requiring the said
Commissioner to certify unto this court all and singular the
proceedings had before said Albert H. Joy and Thos. W. Lynch,
as such Immigration Inspectors, respecting the matter of the 
deportations of your petitioner, and that upon the return to
such Writ of Habeas Corpus and the return to such Writ of
<pb></pb>
Certiorari such order be made therein by Your Honors as upon 
due consideration is consonant with law under and pursuant to
the Constitution of the United States of America and as in
duty bound your petitioner will ever pray.</p>
<p>GUSSIE GOLDMAN WOODS,</p>
<p>Petitioner,</p>
<p>VANDERVEER &amp; CUMMINGS,</p>
<p>Attorneys for Petitioner.</p>

<pb></pb>
<p>WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON :
NORTHER DIVISION : SS</p>

<p>GUSSIE GOLDMAN WOODS, being first duly sworn, upon
oath deposes and says: That she is the petitioner named in
and by whom the foregoing petition is subscribed; that she
knows the contents thereof, and that all the matters and things
in said petition set forth are true.</p>
<p>Gussie Goldman Woods</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 15th day of February A.D. 1915.</p>
<p>HW C. Billingsley</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

<pb></pb>
<p>ORIGINAL. 2960</p>
<p>Cause No.</p>
<p>DISTRICT COURT
OF THE UNITED STATES FOR
THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE 
APPLICATION OF GUSSIE
GOLDMAN WOODS etc. FOR 
WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS</p>

<p>PETITION FOR WRIT OF
HABEAS CORPUS.</p>

<p>VANDERVEER &amp; CUMMINGS</p>
<p>Solicitors and Counsel for PETITIONER</p>
<p>Hoge Building</p>
<p>SEATTLE - WASHINGTON</p>
<p>RAINER PRINTING COMPANY, INC.</p>

<p>FILED IN THE
U.S. District Court, 
Western Dist. of Washington, 
NORTHERN DIVISION
FEB 17 1915 
FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk
By Emy Deputy</p>

<ab></ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>