<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0205.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Bartholomeo Massulo v. Henry M. White. Assignment of Error</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0205.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Bartholomeo Massulo v. Henry M. White. Assignment of Error</title>
<date when="1919-11-04">April 11, 1919</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1919-04">April 1919</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Massulo, Bartholomeo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Moore, Ben L.</persName>
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2019-12" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="#hc.case.wa.0205.002"/>

<p>No. <gap></gap></p>

<p>In the <gap></gap> Court of the United STates for the <gap></gap> District of Washington</p>
<p><gap></gap> Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Apr 11 1919</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<p>Service of within assignment of error and receipt of copy admitted this 11th day of April 1919</p>
<p>Robert C. Saunders</p>
<p>Attorney for United States</p>

<p>No. 4523</p>
<p>Assignment of Error</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of BARTHOLOMEO MASSULO, for a writ of habeas corpus.</p>

<p>Now comes the complainant in the above entitled cause and files the following assignment of error upon which he will rely upon his prosecution of the appeal in the above entitled cause from the order made by this Honorable Court on the 3rd day of March, 1919.</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That the order and warrant of deportation made and entered by the Secretary of Labor of the United States or by the General Commissioner of Immigration under his direction and affirmed by the District Court on the 3rd day of March, 1919, is void for want of jurisdiction on the part of the said Secretary of Labor or General Commissioner of Immigration to enter such order.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>That there is no evidence to sustain the findings of said Commissioner or Secretary; that the complainant was at the time of his entry into the United States a person likely to become a public charge.</p>

<p>III.</p>

<p>That there is no evidence to sustain the finding of said Commissioner or Secretary that the complainant was at the time of his entry or since that time, found advocating and teaching anarchy and the overthrow, by force or violence, of the Government of the United States and of all forms of law and the assasination of public officials.</p>

<p>IV.</p>

<p>That the court erred in denying the application of the complainant for a writ of habeas corpus and in sustaining the order of deportation made by said Secretary of Labor.</p>

<p>V.</p>

<p>That said Commissioner and Secretary in entering the order of deportation herein and the said Court in sustaining said order deprived the complainant of his liberty without due process of law and denied him his rights under the provisions of the Fifth Article of the Amendment of the Constitution of the United States.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, the appellant prays that said order be reversed, annulled and held for naught, and for such other relief as may be proper in the premises.</p>

<p>Ralph S Pierce</p>
<p>Attorney for Appellant.</p>



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>