<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0183.014.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Gwoo Shee Ah Look v. United States. Petition.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0183.013</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Gwoo Shee Ah Look vs. United States. Petition.</title>
<date when="1914-01-12">January 12, 1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2647GwooSheeAhLook</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-01">January 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Lakin, Edward M.</term>
<term>Lung, Wong Sing</term>
<term>Barbour, J. H.</term>
<term>Bonham, R. P.</term>
<term>Harms, L. A.</term>
<term>Wise, J. M.</term>
<term>Chew, Lau Wing</term>
<term>Line, Sue Key</term>
<term>Ark, Wong</term>
<term>Shee, Wong</term>
<term>Huston, D. L.</term>
<term>Batholemew, Walter</term>
<term>Spever, S. C.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
<term>China</term>
<term>Multnomah County, Oregon</term>
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Look, Gwoo Shee Ah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Frye, Jesse A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wilbur</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Spencer</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Clark, A. L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, George P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>2647
In the District Court of the United States
For the Western District of Washington
Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the matterof the Application for
a Writ of Habeas Corpus for Gwoo Shee
Ah Look.</p>
<p>To the Hon. Jeremiah Neterer, Judge of said Court:</p>
<p>Your petitionr, Wong Sing Lung, respectfully shows to
the Court that he <add>is</add> an alien by birth but has been domiciled
within the United States for many years, and that Gwoo Shee 
Ah Look, who has been termed Ah Sing, alias Gwoo Shee, alias
Gwoo Ah Look, by the United States to China by the 
Secretary of Commerce and Labor of the United States and
that said Secretary of Commerce and Labor has issued his
warrant directed to R.P. Bonham, Acting Inspector of Immigration
Service at Portland, Oregon, for the deportation of said Gwoo 
Shee Ah Look;</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that he is informed and
believes, and therefore says that the said R.P. Bonham as
Acting Insepctor of Immigration Service of Portland, Oregon,
has caused the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look to be removed from
Portland, Oregon, to the City of Seattle, State of Washington,
where she is now held by some person, the name of whom and the
place of which is unknown to your petitioner; that the said
Gwoo Shee Ah Look is unlawfully restrained, imprisoned and
detained of her liberty by the said R.P. Bonham and ther
persons, the name of whom is unknown to your petitioner
<fw>-1-</fw>
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<pb/>
and that the said R.P. Bonham clandestinely, secretly, and
without authority of law removed the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look from
the county jail of the County of Multnomah and State of Oregon,
and clandestinely and secretly detained her and has refused upon
the application of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look, as well as that of
her husband, Wong Sing Lung, to let it be known where she is
detained.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that he, together with
his representative, who is the representative of Gwoo Shee Ah
Look, has applied to the said R.P. Bonham, Acting Inspector 
of Immigration Service at Portland, Oregon, and requested the
said R.P. Bonham to advise or tell them the whereabouts of the
said Gwoo Shee Ah Look, but that the said R.P. Bonham has 
frauduently refused to let it be known where she or the
person in whose custody he has placed the said Gwoo Shee
Ah Look is located;</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that the said Gwoo Shee Ah
Look is an alien and by birth a Chinese and that she arrived
in this country at the port of San Francisco on the Steamer
Siberia, during the year 1907, since which time she has been
continously domiciled within the Untied States, and your
petitioner further shows that the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look is
now unlawfully imprisioned, detained, confined, and restrained
by certain persons under the authority of the said R.P. Bonham,
and the said Secretary of Commerce and Labor, the name of whom 
is unknown to your petitioner;</p>
<p>That the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look came to the State of 
Oregon during the early part of October, 1913, and that shortly
after her arrival in said State she was arrested and charged by
the immigration authorities under the provisions of a statute
of the United States with being unlawfully within the United
<fw>-2-</fw>
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<pb/>
States, in that since her arrival and domicile within the 
United States she had been found practicing prostitution and
that she was a prostitute;</p>
<p>That a hearing was had before the United States
Commissioner at the City of Portland, Oregon, who thereafter made
his report to the Secretary of Commerce and Labor, and that
acting upon the evidence taken by said Commissioner at the City
of Portland, and which was forwarded to the Secretary of Commerce
and Labor, the said Secretary of Commerce and Labor has ordered
said Gwoo Shee Ah Look's deportation to China and found "That
the said alien is a prostitute and has been found practicing prostitution
subsequent to her entry into the United States."</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that said Gwoo Shee Ah Look
is being held by the said R.H. Bonham, Acting Inspector of 
Immigration Service at Portland, Oregon, or by someone to whom
the said R.P. Bonham has turned the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look over
to for deportation, as directed by the said warrant of the said
Secretary of Commerce and Labor for deportation to her native
country, China, and that they are about to and will deport her
to her native country,</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that the said imprisonment,
detention, confinement, and restraint and order fo deportation are
illegal, and that the illegality thereof consists in this, that
there was no evidence before said Commissioner or Secretary of
Commerce and Labor authorizing the order for said Gwoo Shee Ah 
Look's deportation;</p>
<p>That the only evidence there was before either the Commissioner
of the Secretary of Commerce and Labor on behalf of the
Government was the testimony of L.A. Harms, who is a Sergeant of
Police of the City of Portland, and whose testimony, so far as the
virtue of said Gwoo Shee Ah Look is concerned, is substantially as
<fw>-3-</fw>
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<pb/>
follows:-</p>
<p>"Q When and where did you first see this woman?" (Gwoo Shee
Ah Look)</p>
<p>"A About three weeks ago, about two weeks before her
arrest was made, upstairs, second floor, in a building
on the southwest corner of Fourth and Flanders Streets,
this city.</p>
<p>"Q Under what circumstances did you see her at that time?</p>
<p>"A We were investigating that place, knowing that there were
Chinese prostitutes up there, about two or three weeks
before the arrest was made; we were up there three or 
four times; Officer Wise and myself."</p>
<p>"Q State briefly what you saw on the occasion of these two
investigations, so far as your observation is limited
to this woman.</p>
<p>"A In the first place, we had information from different
sources that there were Chinese prostitutes up there.
We watched the place on several different occasions and
saw Chinese going up there in the rooms that the women
were in. We went up there and talked to the women the
best we could. At different times we found different 
men in this woman's room. Finally, about 4:30 in the
morning November 4th, we went up with the purpose of
making her arrest and we found a Chinese in bed with her.</p>
<p>"Q In your capacity, experience, and observation as a police
officer in the Chinese quarter on North Fourth Street,
Portland, what have you found to be the reputation of
the place out of which this womna was arrested?</p>
<p>"A It has the reputation of being a bawdyhouse where prostitutes
ply their trade."</p>
<fw>-4-</fw>
<p>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</p>
<pb/>
<p>And the testimony of J.M. Wise, who is a police officerof
the City of Portland, whose testimony so far as the virtue
of said Gwoo Shee Ah Look is concerned, is substaintially as 
follows:-</p>
<p>"Q When, where and under what circumstances did you first see
or meet this woman?" (Gwoo Shee Ah Look)</p>
<p>"A Along about the 20th of October, this year, in room 17 of
a building on the southwest corner of Fourth and Flanders
Street, this city."(Portland)</p>
<p>"Q Under what circumstances did you first see her?</p>
<p>A Investifating the place, gaining evidence as to this
place being a house of prostitution and as to this woman
being a prostitute.</p>
<p>"Q Did you arrest this woman?</p>
<p>"A Yes, on the 4th day of November, about 4:30 in the morning"</p>
<p>That there was no other testimony on behalf of the
Governmnet of questions or character from which prostitution
is hsown or which shows that Gwoo Shee Ah Look is a prostitute
in the record of this case.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further says that said Gwoo Shee Ah Look 
is not a prostitute and that said Gwoo Shee Ah Look
has not practiced prostitution within the United States,
or at any other place;</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that said Gwoo Shee
Ah Look come to this country in company with her husband,
Lau Wing Chew, who she married in China, according to the
Chinese custom, that after her arrival within the United
States said Lau Wing Chew deserted said Gwoo Shee Ah lOok
and that thereafter she was married to your petitioner,
Wong Sing Lung, at Oroville, California, some time during
<fw>-5-</fw>
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland, Oregon</ab></figure>
<pb/>
the year 1912, since which time she has lived with your
petitioner Wong Sing Lung, as hiswife;</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that the evidence
before the said Commissioner and the Secretary of Commerce
and Labor showed in substance that said Gwoo Shee Ah Look
came to the State of Oregon on the 8th day of October, 1913,
with her husband; that they resided at a hotel in the City 
of Portland form that time until the 15th day of October, 
1913, when said Gwoo Shee Ah Look went to live with a 
respectable Chinese family, where she remained until
the first day of November, 1913, at which time, she, together
with her husband, rented a room at the place where said Gwoo
Shee Ah Look was arrested.</p>
<p>Your petitoner futher shows that the affidavits in 
behalf of said Gwoo Shee Ah Look showed in substance that she
had not been in the room or at the place where she was
arrested until the first day of November, 1913, when she 
moved there with her husband;</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that the facts as above
detailed were shown in the affidavits of Wong Sing Lung, Sue
Key Line, Wong Shee, Wong Ark, D. L. Huston and Walter
Bartholemew, all of which were filed with the Commissioner
in the City of Portland, attached to the record, and before
the said Secretary of Commerce and Labor;</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that the sole and only
testimony upon which the said Secretary of Commerce and Labor 
has ordered the deportation of said Gwoo Shee Ah Look was the
testimony of said two policemen, the substance of which has
been set out herein, and that their testimony that they saw
her at the place of her arrest prior to the first day of
November, 1913, is untrue and a case of mistakedn identity.</p>
<fw>-6-</fw>
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland, Oregon</ab></figure>
<pb/>
<p>Wherefore, your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus 
may be grantedf, directed to the person who unlawfully restrains
the liberty of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look, the name of whom is
unknown to your petitioner, commanding him to have the body
of said Gwoo Shee Ah Look before your Honor at the time and 
place hereafter to be specified, to do and recieve what shall
then and there be considered by your Honor concerning her,
together with the time and cause of her detention and said
writ and that she may be restored to her liberty.</p>
<ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
A.L. Clark &amp; Jesse A Frye
Attorneys</ab>
<ab>Dated January 12th 1914.</ab>
<p>United States of America,
State of Oregon,
County of Multnomah } ss.</p>
<p>I, Wong Sing Lung, being first
duly sworn according to law, say that I am the husband of
Gwoo Shee Ah Look, the person who is unlawfully restrained of
her liberty; that I am informed and believe and therefore say
that my said wife, Gwoo Shee Ah Look, is detained and restrained
by some person upon the authority of R.P. Bonham, Acting Inspector
of Immigration Service at Portland, Oregon, upon a warrant for
her deportation to China, the name of the person having the
custody of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look being unknown to me; that
the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look was clandestinely, secretly and 
fraudulently removed from the City of Portland, State of Oregon, 
to the City of Seattle, State of Washington, where she is now
unlawfully restrained of her liberty; that the said R.P. Bonham,
on the 12th day of January 1914, was requested by the attorney
of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look and myself to advise of the
present whereabouts of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look, which request
was summarily refused by the said R.P. Bonham, which makes it
<fw>-7-</fw>
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<pb/>
impossible for Gwoo Shee Ah Look to verify this petition and
for this reason I am verifying this petition; that I have had
the same read to me and know the contents thereof to be true.</p>
<ab>Wong Sing Lung</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to beforeme this 12th day of
January 1914.</p>
<ab>SC Spever
Notary Public State of Oregon.</ab>
<fw>-8-</fw>
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<pb/>
<p>2x No. 2647</p>
<p>In teh District Court of the
United States for the
District of <del>Oregon</del> <add>Washington</add></p>
<p>In the matter of the
application for a
writ of Habeas Corpus
for Gwoo Shee Ah Look</p>
<p>Filed in the
U.S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington,
Northern Division
Jan 13 1914
Frank L. Crosby, Clerk,
By EML Deputy.</p>
<p>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys for <gap reason="blank"/></p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>