<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0241.037"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Typed Submission</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>

<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0241.037</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Typed Submission</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1885-07">July 1885</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Arnold</term>
<term>Dolan</term>
<term>Dolan</term>
<term>Hunter, W.E.</term>
<term>Kirkbride, J.W.</term>
<term>Kelly, J.W.</term>
<term>Lockwood, H.B.</term>
<term>Thompson</term>
<term>Vail, William</term>
<term>Walker, Charles</term>
<term>Walker, Helen</term>
<term>Walker, M.A.</term>
<term>Winslow</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Port Townsend</term>
<term>Tacoma, Pierce County, Washington Territory</term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Walker, M.A.</persName>
<persName>Walker, Charles</persName>
<persName>Walker, Helen</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Campbell, A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court For The Western District of Washington Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="#sab">transcribed, encoded</change> 
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0241.037"/>

<p>Exhibit "A"</p>

<p>The justice having opened court, the names of the witnesses were called out, and as the persons came in they were sent to the witness; room. H. B. Lockwood, a brother of <unclear></unclear> M. Lockwood, deceased, <unclear></unclear> a seat near the prosecuting attorney.</p>
<p>The first witness called was A.H. Thompson, who was sworn, and in answer to interrogatories of the prosecuting attorney, testified as follows:</p>
<p>I live in Tacoma, and have resided here since last August; am night yardmaster; between 2 and 3 o'clock on the morning of the 16th, I was on a train between the wharf and the top of the hill; after 2 o'clock we were going up the grade, with a car of live stock for the slaughterhouse; I was sitting in the engine cab, on the fireman's side, which is on this side of track; saw an object moving on left of track, and moving away from a black object; I thought the latter was an overcoat; I kept my eyes on the object, until, when the fireman opened the firebox door, the fire blinded me and prevented me from seeing; the engine was about thirty feet distant form the object when it disappeared from my view; when we struck the object I felt it, and called the engineer to stop; this was 2:30; when the engine stopped I got off first and ran back; I knew it must have been a dog or something we ran over; as I neared the place I saw a dog leaving; I found a man on the track: the body was laying face down, on the inside of the track, close to the rail. the engine and car had run over feet and shoulders; the head was close to the rail, with the face turned to the center of the track; the feet were crossed, the left foot was over the rail, the right on the inside; did not examine his feet; the body looked like that of a man lately killed; the eyes were <unclear></unclear> there was a hole in the forehead, from which no blood  was coming out; looked at the man with a <unclear>tanern</unclear>, and knew he was a man I had seen about town; saw no marks except those described; a gargling noise came from the body; I saw light and called out to the person with the light; he said he was Kelly; told him we had run over a man, but did not know his name; Kelly came up; the body lay in the same position after being run over, as I saw it before; heard no noise we were going south at the time, up grade, the engine pulling the car; I looked over the engine afterwards, but found  to signs of blood or hair; the distance from ash pan to wheel of engine is about six inches; I did not examine the car until yesterday, [Sunday], when I found blood on all the wheels; the brakebeam on the engine is higher than the steps and could have passed over the body without touching it; had the clothes on the body caught it would have been mangled; the coatflap was turned up a little; the engine must have struck the foot first; the body did not bleed freely; was going to take the body, but the others who had come up objected; did not examine body very closely, and did not put hands on it; sent a man down after coroner, or a constable; appeared to me as though the man had been alive when struck, though I saw no twitching of the muscles; the man might have raised his head and might have been struck by a bolt, and his forehead might have struck a spike; we took the car down to the slaughter house unloaded it and when we got back the body was on the outside and other side of the track; there is a roadway across the track, about thirty-five yards from where the body lay.</p>
<p>Cross examined: The switch engine, with light at both ends, <unclear>was</unclear> backing up with car of live stock, going at the rate of eight or nine miles an hour; there is a good roadbed there; track is level between ties, and is in a out and on a curve; the cut is about 115 feet deep; can see about 90 feet ahead on lower side of curve; saw a small gray dog moving away from object; did not see any movement by the object as the track; the train ran about 80 feet beyond the body before it stopped; there as not much of a grade at this point; did not see the arm bleeding; saw blood on the tie; the wound in the forehead was like a dent, the skin was not broken, and wound not bleeding; there was blood on</p>

<p>Exhibit "A"</p>
<p>1601</p>

<p>the face; a piece of the skull lay on the side of the track ; he might have raised his head, put it back again, and a spike might have struck his forehead.</p>
<p>Re-direct: Think head lay on a tie; saw blood on right and left of rails where the shoulder and the feet would be; couldn't fall when Olympian arrived; had no occasion for remembering; the wound on forehead was between the eyes, V-shaped; did not examine it closely; such a hole would be made by a rock between the ties; it could not have been made only by a spike; the skin of forehead wound was not broken; did not examine wound in back of head.</p>
<p>Re-cross: The forehead wound was of a shape as would be the head of a railroad spike.</p>
<p>William Vail, being sworn, corroborated the testimony of first witness as to the train;s running up the hill, and the</p>
<p>location of the body; he was on the upside of the engine; could not see as far as Thompson, from up-side; heard Thompson call out "Hold her! hold her!" reversed his engine; felt the wheels rise and drop, but heard no noise; this was at 2:30 a.m. on Tuesday; after Thompson got off the engine, he waited awhile, about 1 1/2 minutes, and then went down the track, where he saw the body; he heard no noise come from the body; supposed the man was dead; the face was down and turned towards center of track; two feet were on rail; the wheels passed diagonally over the feet, cleared the body and then again ran on the arm and shoulder; the ashpan on the engine could not have struck him, and if he made no struggle, everything but the wheels would be clear of the body; he thought they ought to send for the coroner; he saw blood at the place; knew the dead man by sight; the night was dark and slightly foggy, and could not see object on track from his place on the engine; supposed they had run over the man and killed him; went back to his engine and took car up to slaughter house, being gone over and hour; did not wait long at body; would have heard noise if man made any.</p>
<p>Walter Osgood sworn: I live in Tacoma; am fireman on yard engine since the 7th of last November; was firing on the morning of July 16; between 2 and 3 o'clock was on hill between wharf and slaughter house; our train ran over a man; was firing at time, heard Thompson call, "hold her!" and saw Vail throw her over; I thought we had struck something; when engine stopped yardmaster and brakeman went back; I went down and saw a man on the track; knew him by sight; he was named Lockwood; he was lying on his cheek, his face toward center of track, head against the rial; did not touch body; supposed him to be dead; we put a man there to watch, and sent the brakeman for the coroner; looked at the body with the lantern; saw gash on forehead, it was bleeding; heard no noise; body did not move; the man was perfectly dead; it was two or three minutes after we stopped that I got off engine; the body was not bleeding freely; heard no noise when we passed over body; could see further ahead on my side than the engineer could on his; the engine could pass over the prostrate body, the car might not; Vail, Thompson, Kirkbride and Winslow were on the train.</p>
<p>Cross-examined Was never before on a train running over a man.</p>
<p>J. W. Kirkbride sworn: I am a brakeman and have been sin e the 1st of June; between 2 and 3 o'clock on morning of 16th, went from wharf to stockyard, train struck the body about 2:30; was on the car lying down, when I heard engine stop; knew the engine was reversed by the sound of escaping steam; put on the brake; heard Thompson say, "Billy, you ran over something;" said man was run over;</p>

<p>looked at the body not more than five minutes after it was struck. [He here described the position of the body.] Saw a piece of skull on ground; the head was between the ties; saw no movement of body nor did I touch it; appeared to be dead; head was against the rail, saw no mark on face until at <unclear></unclear> then saw gash, which seemd cut to bone; the skin was broken, a timber under tank frame of engine was low down, but do not know whether it would touch body or not; the clothing on body was not torn, and body was covered with dust; heard no noise when we struck the body and felt no jar.</p>
<p>Cross-examined: A piece of the skull was knocked off; piece half as big as my hand. [Witness illustrated about where the piece of skull was gone on the head.] If the man had raised his head it is likely he would have been struck where piece of skull was off.</p>
<p>Jay W. Kelly sworn: Live in Tacoma; am a nightwatchman at pumping station of water works; heard train stop about 2:30 a. m. on morning of 16th; somebody called to him and said there was a man on the track; went up and saw man on track; face of body was down; saw that the feet were mangled; saw a hole in the head of body, and supposed it to have been cut by the flange of the wheel; saw blood on the left cheek; did not touch the body; saw the trainmen, but did not know the party who came up there afterwards; Mr. Walker's folks told me who it was that was killed; I heard voices at the Walker house; called twice, but they did not hear me call at first; I said a dead man was on the track and described the dog that was there; they said it must be Lockwood's dog' M. A. Walker, his wife and brother came down on track; said that was Lockwood; they thought the man's folks ought to know about it; after I was called I got to the place within five minutes; the Walker's were dressed when they came to the track; Mrs. Walker took hold of Lockwood's hand or wrist; I said "I wouldn't touch it;" she said it would do no harm; I said I suppose it will not; I saw no movement of body; was there from five to ten minutes after train stopped; the Walker house is a few yards to northwest of place where body was found; place where body lay is southeast of house; there is a medium curved track; I could not tell what the voices were saying in the house; the two Walkers came on the track about the same time; think the married man was first if any one; the trainmen asked me to stay by the body while they sent after coroner, and I did so until he came about three-quarters of an hour later; feet of body must have been on the rail; did not notice head nor notice body bleeding.</p>
<p>Cross-examined: The place where the body lay was a few yards from the Walkers' house; I called twice, " Mr. Walker"; could see house from where I stood; I said, "there is a man on the track and a dog here"; I described dog; they said it must be Lockwood's; think the married man came down the bank first; a man would naturally have to one down the bank fast, as it is steep.</p>
<p>At this juncture, 12:20 p. m., the court took a recess for one hour.</p>
<p>W. E. Hunter, sworn, testified as follows: Live in Tacoma; have been a resident for two years; am a painter; acquainted a short time with defendants; have met them three times; was at the Walker house on night of 15th and 16th of July; want there on Wednesday, July 15; went there with Mr. Dolan, Mrs. Dolan, Miss Arnold, Mrs. Hunter (my wife) and myself; found </p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
