<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0228.003"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Edward Krause v. Robert W. McClelland. Judge Response to Petition for Habeas Corpus</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0228.003</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Edward Krause v. Robert W. McClelland. Judge Response to Petition for Habeas Corpus.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1915">1915</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-11"></date>23 November 1915</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Edward Krause</term>
<term>J. Grattan O'Bryan</term>
<term>Clay Allen</term>
<term>Jeremiah Neterer</term>
<term>Robert W. McClelland</term>
<term>Cornelius Hanford</term>
<term>Marshall Harlan</term>
<term>Frank L. Crosby</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Territory of Alaska</term>
<term>Juneau, Alaska</term>
<term>District of Columbia</term><!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Edward Krause</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Robert W. McClelland</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>F. Grattan O'Bryan</persName>
<persName>Kazis Krauczunas</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>William Christie</persName>
<persName>Winter S. Martin</persName>
<persName>Clay Allen</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court, Western District of Washington</orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022" who="AS">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>
</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0228.003"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p> 
<p>---oOo---</p> 
<p>In the Matter of the Petition
of EDWARD KRAUSE for a Writ
of Habeas Corpus.</p> 
<p>)()()(</p>
<p>No. 3166
Filed November 23, 1915.</p> 
<p>---oOo---</p> 
<p>J. Grattan O'Bryan, Seattle, Washington,
Kazis Krauczunas, Seattle, Washington, )) For Petitioner.</p> 
<p>Clay ALLEN, United States Attorney,
Winter S. Martin, Assistant United
States Attorney;
Seattle, Washington. )) For Respondent.</p> 
<p>NETERER, JUDGE:</p>
<p>The petitioner alleges that he is restrained of his
liberty by the United States Marshal, who holds him under an
order of removal to the United States District Court for the
Territory of Alaska;
that he was arrested upon a warrant
issued by Robert W. McClelland, United States Commissioner
for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division
upon complaint filed by the United States Distriсt Attorney
charging the petitioner with the commission of a crime with-
in the territory of Alaska in violation of Seation 1907 of
the Compiled Laws of Territory of Alaska, Codified and
Arranged by Act of Congress of August 84, 1912:that a pre-
liminary hearing was had and petitioner bound over by the
Commissioner to the grand jury at Juneau, Alaska; and further
alleges that if a crime was committed that it was not an
offense against the laws of the United States, but an offense
against the laws of the territory of Alaska.</p>
<p>On presentation of the petition an order was issued</p>
<pb></pb> 
<p>and the United States Marshal thereby directed to produce
the petitioner before the court for such disposition as may
be directed. Obedient to this order, the petitioner is pro-
duced in court.</p> 
<p>The issue presented is whether the petitioner shall
be removed to the district court of Alaska pursuant to the
provisions of Section 1014 of the Revised Statutes. Much
was said upon the argument on both sides as to the applica-
tion of the provisions of this section to the offense charg-
ed, and several citations given by the respective parties
claiming support for the positions assumed.</p> 
<p>An examination of the complaint upon which the
warrant was issued and the several provisions of the laws of
the territory of Alaska, together with the general extradi-
tion laws enacted by Congress, and expression of the courts
upon similar issues, I think clarifies the situation.</p>
<p>It is urged that Judge Hanford held a fugitive from
Alaska to be removable under the provision of this section.
This holding it was alleged was in the case of Tiberg v.
Warren<add>which was appealed to the circuit court and is reported in</add>192 Fed. 458; but an examination of the case shows
that this question was not an issue, the emphasis upon the
suggestion is placed upon the argument in the brief of the
United States District Attorney before the Circuit Court of
Appeals, in which reference was made to the application of
this section. The issue in that case was the right to extra-
dite under the provisions of Section 5278 Revised Statutes.
If Judge Hanford in that case said that an offender under
the Alaska Criminal Code, being present in this district
could be removed under Section 1014, supra., it was purely
obiter dictum.</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>It is fundamental that the United States courts as
such, can only entertain jurisdiction of offenses against
the United States. If the offense charged is not an offense
against the United States, this court would not have juris-
diction to try the petitioner if it had been committed with-
in this district, and that, I think, is the criterion by
which this issue must be determined. The question is not,
Has the district court of Alaska jurisdiction?, for that
court acts in a dual capacity, one in administering the laws
of the United States, and the other in administering the
local laws of the territory. The Supreme Court of the
United States, in the case of Coquitlam, 163 U.S. 346, held
that the district court of Alaska is to be regarded as the
supreme court of the territory, within the meaning of Sec-
tion 15 of the Act of March 3, 1891, and because of such
status and order of the supreme court, a decree of that court
was subject to review by the Circuit Court of Appeals of the
Ninth Circuit. Justice Harlan, in McAllister v. United
States, 141 U.S. 174, 179, said,*</p>
<p>"It is clear that the district court of Alaska 
was invested with the power of a district and cir-
cuit court of the United States, as well as with
general jurisdictions to enforce in Alaska the laws
of Oregon."</p> 
<p>which, by Section 7 of the Act of May 17, 1884, 23 Statute,
was declared to be law of Alaska so far as they were appli-
cable and not in conflict with the provisions of that act,
or of the laws of the United States, and held that a judge
of the district court of Alaska is not a judge of a court
of the United States within the generally accepted meaning
of that term.</p> 
<p>The cases cited by the Government do not appear to</p> 
<pb></pb>
<p>me to be the issue. In United States v. Henkle, 198
U.S.1, the supreme court of the District of Columbia is
held to be a court of the United States within the meaning
of Section 1014, supra., authorizing the removal of a per-
son charged with an offense against the United States.</p> 
<p>Much emphasis was placed by the Government upon
United States v. Hasken, No. 15322 Federal Cases. In that
case Judge Hillyer, at page 215 - 26 Federal Cases, says:</p> 
<p>"The act of Congress respecting fugitives from justice,
1 St. 302., in pursuance of Article 4 Section 2, Consti-
tution U.S., provides a method by which offenders
against state and territorial laws, who have fled from
justice, may be delivered up to the state or terri-
tory demanding them, but makes no provision for the
case of those persons who have committed offenses
against the United States in one district and have
fled to another.</p> 
<p>These cases do not, it seems to me, help the com-
plainant. They are all predicated upon an offense against
the United States, which is the express requirement of
Section 1014, supra. If the offense here charged were an
offense against the United States there would be no ques-
tion as to the duty of this court to order the removal.
By at of Congress the Territory of Alaska, under the Con-
stitution and laws of the United States, became an inchoate
state, not yet adminted, but organized, with separate
legislature under a territorial governor and other officers
appointed by the Preeident by consent of the Senate. The
legislative power extended to all rightful subjects pertain-
ing to local self-government not inconsistent with the laws
and Constitution of the United States. That Congress had
in mind the different relation of the local laws of the
territory and national laws with relation to extradition or
removal, I think is made manifest by the provisions of the</p>
<pb></pb> 
<p>Alaska Criminal Code and the general provisions of Congress.</p>
<p>Section 5278 of Revised Statutes, relating to
fugitives from juetice of a state or territory, makes pro-
vision for extraditing offenders. The executive of a
territory, under this Section, has the same rights and
bears the same duties as the governor of a state. In re
Morgan, 28 Fed. 298. Ex Perte Reggul, 114 U.S. 642,
Section 2502 at Page 771 of the Laws of Alaske Code, make
special provision for extraditing a person charged with a
felony, thereby recognizing local application of the local
laws of Alaska. Section 410 of the Act of August 24, 1912,
37 St. 512, provides that all laws of the United States
heretofore passed, establishing the executive and judicial
departments in Alaska, shall continue in full force and
effect until amended or repealed by act of Congress; that
except as therein provided, all laws in force in Alaska
shell continue in full force and effeet until altered,
amended or repealed by Congress or by the territorial legis-
lature; that the authority granted to the legislature to
alter, amend, modify or repel lews in force in Alaska shall
not extend to the customs, internal revenue, postal or other
general laws of the United States.</p>
<p>There is, by this provision, clearly a line of
demarcation placed by Congress between the local laws af-
ecting the territory and laws affecting generally all of
the states and territories.</p> 
<p>Section 2099 of the laws of Alaska, supra., provide:
"That the common law of England, as adopted and
understood in the United States, shall be in
force in said district except as modified by
this act."</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>This expression, I think, further emphasizes the line of
demarcation suggested, as it is fundamental that federal
courts have no jurisdiction of common law offenses, but
are limited to acts made criminal by congress, and congress
is charged with knowledge of this fact.The common law
offenses by this provision are placed in the same category
and relation as the offenses defined by the criminal code,
and it would hardly be contended that this court would have
jurisdiction to direct the removal of an offender against
this common law of the territory.<add><unclear></unclear></add></p> 
<p>The offense charged <add>(kidnapping)</add> is not an offense under any law
of the United States to which my attention has been directed,
or any cognizable by the Unites States courts as such.
Congress, in passing this law, exercised its power as a local
legislature rather than its power as a general government
of the United States. Allen v. Meyer, 1 Alaska Rp. 114.
The intention of Congress undoubtedly was to constitute the
"Alaska Criminal Code", taken largely from the Oregon Crim-
al Code, which was extended to Alaska in 1884, a territor-
ial act as distinguished from the laws of the United States.
United States v. Jackson, 102 Fed. 478; United States v. 
Pridgeon, 153 U.S. 48.</p> 
<p>The Compiled Laws of Alaska have no greater force
than a law enacted by a territorial legislature, subject to
congressional approval, and as such, its provisions are not
laws of the United States and do not come within the cog-
nizance of the United States courts. Maxwell v. Federal
Gold &amp; Copper Co., 155 Fed. 111; In re Moran, 203 U.S.96;
United States v. Jones, Adms., 236 U.S. 106. And Jackie
Marshall, <unclear></unclear></p> 
<pb></pb>
<p>(COPY)</p>
<p>The authorities of Alaska are not without remedy,
full and complete provision being made by the extradition
laws, which are open to all the state and territories.</p> 
<p>I think that the court has not the power to order
the petitioner removed to the district court of Alaska.</p>
<p>JEREMIAH NETERER
JUDGE.</p> 
<p>FILED IN THE
U.S. District Court 
Western Dist. of Washington
NORTHERN DIVISION
NOV 23 1915
FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk.
By Emy Deputy</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>