<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0149.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Lee Fong v. John Sullivan. Answer</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0149.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Lee Fong v. John Sullivan. Answer</title>
<date when="1902-09-04">September 4, 1902</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1902-09">September 1902</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Bryant, F. E.</term>
<term>Yesler, H. L.</term>
<term>Forrest, W. R.</term>
<term>Melor, E. W.</term>
<term>Riplinger, James</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, King County, Washinton</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Fong, Lee</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Sullivan, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wiestling, J. M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Buller, Ellis E.</persName>
<persName>Sillian, Micheal</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanfod, C. H.</persName>
<persName>George, R. R.</persName>
<persName>Gilber, William B.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court for the District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<ab>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, 
IN AND FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
NORTHERN DIVISION.</ab>

<ab>In the Matter of the Application 
of Lee Fong for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus.</ab>

<ab>ANSWER.</ab>

<p>Comes now John Sullivan, as Chief of Police of the
City of Seattle, King County, Washington, and in compliance
with the order from this Honorable Court, and in answer to 
petition herein, says: That he is the Chief of Police of 
the City of Seattle, and the one to whom the order in this 
cause was directed, and on whom served, and the one having 
in charge and custody at said time the said Lee Fong, and 
this much of the allegations of the petition is admitted,
but as to each and every other allegation contained in said
petition, he has not sufficient knowledge or informtion upon
which to form a belief, and therefore denies each and every
other allegation contained in said petition.</p>

<p>John Sullivan, as Chief of Police of the City of 
Seattle, King County, Washington, further answering said petition,
and for cause why he had said petitioner in his custody
and why a writ of habeas corpus should not issue, says:</p>

<p>That on the 29th day of August, 1902, a complaint
was filed before Hon. R. R. George, one of the Justices of
the Peace and Police Judge in and for the City of Seattle,
charging the defendant, Lee Fong, with the violation of Sections</p>

<ab>1</ab>

<pb/>

<p>6 and 7 of Ordinance No. 710 of the City of Seattle, 
and upon said complaint being filed, a warrant was issued 
from said Court directing the said Sullivan to make the arrest
of said Lee Fong, and by reason of the authority of said
complaint and warrant, the said Lee Fong was in the custody
of said Sullivan as Chief of Police. A certified copy of said
warrant and complaint, as well as a certified copy of said ordinance,
are hereby attached, referred to and made a part of 
this answer. </p>

<ab>John Sullivan</ab>
<ab>Chief of Police of the City of Seattle.</ab>

<ab>State of Washington,
County of King.</ab>

<ab>ss.</ab>

<p>JOHN SULLIVAN, being first duly sworn, says: That 
he is the Chief of Police of the City of Seattle, King County,
Washington, and the one upon whom was served an order from 
this Honorable Court to show cause why a writ of habeas corpus
should not issue for Lee Fong, and the one having in
charge the said Lee Fong at the time of the service of said
order, and that he has read the answer herein, knows fully
the contents thereof, and believes the same to be true.</p>

<ab>John Sullivan</ab>

<ab>Subscribed and sworn to before me this
4th day of September, 1902.</ab>

<ab>Ellis <unclear>E</unclear> Butler</ab>

<ab>Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle. </ab>

<ab>2</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>THE CITY OF SEATTLE 
IN THE JUSITCE COURT IN AND FOR SEATTLE PRECINCT
King County, Washington.</ab>
<ab>Before R. R. George,
Police Judge.</ab>

<ab>THE CITY OF SEATTLE
vs. Lee Fong.</ab>

<ab>Criminal Complaint.</ab>

<ab>STATE OF WASHINGTON,
County of King,
The City of Seattle..</ab>

<ab>ss.</ab>

<p>F. E. BRYANT, being first duly sworn, says: 
That on the 29th day of August 1902, at the City of Seattle, in
said King County, Washington, the said Lee Fong did commit
a misdemeanor as follows, <del>to-wit</del> by carrying on a public 
laundry without any permit from the City Council, to-wit:
Then and there being the said defendant, Lee Fong, did 
wilfully and unlawfully, at Number 1410 Fir Street, in said 
City of Seattle, establish, maintain and carry on a laundry
within the corporate limits of the said City of Seattle and 
at said place, without first obtaining the consent of the
City Council of said City, the said laundry not being located
in a building constructed either of brick, stone, nor
covered with a metal roof, all of which is contrary to Ordinance
No. 710, Sections 6 and 7, of the City of Seattle,
entitled "An Ordinance regulating the establishment and maint
enance of public laundries and public wash-houses within</p>

<pb/>

<p>the limits of the City of Seattle, approved February 6,
1886, and against the public morals, peace and good order
of the City of Seattle.</p>

<ab>F. E. Bryant</ab>

<ab>Subscribed and sworn to before me, this 30th day of 
August, 1902.</ab>

<ab>R. R. George
Police Judge.</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>WARRANT OF ARREST.</ab>

<ab>THE CITY OF SEATTLE,
Plaintiff,
vs.
Lee Fong,
Defendant.</ab>

<ab>WARRANT</ab>

<ab>State of Washington, 
County of King,
The City of Seattle.</ab>

<ab>ss. </ab>

<ab>In Justice Court, Seattle
Precinct, R.R. George, Police Judge.</ab>

<p>THE STATE OF WASHINGTON to the CHIEF OF POLICE OF SAID CITY,
OR SHERIFF OR CONSTABLE OF SAID COUNTY, GREETING:</p>

<p>WHEREAS, F. E. Bryant has this day complained in
writing, under oath, to the undersigned, one of the Justices
of the Peace and Police Judge in and for said Seattle Precinct,
King County, that on the 29th day of August, 1902,
Lee Fong, in said City, County and State, did commit the offense
of unlawfully establishing, maintaining and carrying
on a laundry in said city without a permit from the City
Council of said City.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, In the name of the State of Washington,
you are commanded forthwith to apprehend the said Defendant
and bring him before me to be dealt with according to Law.</p>

<p>Given under my hand this <del>3rd</del> 30th day of August, 1902.</p>

<ab>R.R. GEORGE
Police Judge.</ab>

<ab>STATE OF WASHINGTON,
County of King,
The City of Seattle.</ab>

<ab>ss.</ab>

<p>I Hereby Certify, That I have arrested the within
named Lee Fong and have him now in court.
John Sullivan
Chief of Police.</p>

<ab>By F. E. Bryant,
Police Officer.</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>STATE OF WASHINGTON,
County of King,
City of Seattle.</ab>

<ab>ss.</ab>

<p>I, R. R. George, a Justice of the Peace and Police
Judge of the City of Seattle, King County, Washington, do
hereby certify that the foregoing and annexed complaint and 
warrant is a true and correct copy of the original complaint
and warrant in said cause on file in my office, the same being 
the case of The City of Seattle,

Plaintiff,
vs. 
Lee Fong,
Defendant,

and that the annexed and attached papers are all the process 
and other papers relating to the action and filed with me,
and all of which is correct.</p>

<ab>Dated at Seattle, Washington, -by- day of September,
1902.</ab>

<ab>R. R. George
Police Judge of the 
City of Seattle. </ab>
<pb/>

<ab>ORDINANCE NO. 710.</ab>

<p>AN ORDINANCE regulating the establishment and maintenance of 
public laundries and public wash-houses within the limits
of the City of Seattle.</p>

<p>WHEREAS, The indiscriminate establishment of public 
laundries and public wash-houses, where clothes and other
articles are cleaned for hire, is injurious and dangerous
to public health and public safety, and prejudicial to the
well-being and comfort of the community and depreciates the
value of the property in those neighborhoods where such public
laundries and such public wash-houses are situate:</p>

<p>The City of Seattle does ordain as follows:</p>

<p>Section 1. On and after the passage of this ordinance 
it shall be unlawful for any person or persons to establish, 
maintain or carry on the business of a public laundry
or a public wash-house, where clothes or other articles are
cleansed for hire, wtihin the corporate limits of the City 
of Seattle, without having first complied with the conditions
hereinafter specified.</p>

<p>Sec. 2. It shall be unlawful for any person or
persons to conduct or maintain a public laundry or wash-house
within the city of Seattle without having first obtained 
a certificate signed by the health officer of the
City of Seattle that the premises are properly and sufficiently
drained and that all proper arrangements for carrying on
the business without injury to the sanitary conditions of the 
neighborhood have been complied with, also a certificate
signed by the chief of the fire department of the City of
Seattle that the stoves, washing and drying apparatus and </p>

<ab>1</ab>

<pb/>

<p>the appliances for heating smoothing irons are in good condition,
and that their use is not dangerous to the surrounding 
property from fire, and that all proper precautions have 
been taken to comply with the provisions of the ordinances
of the city then in force making regulations concerning the 
erection and use of buildings and for the protection of property
from injury or destruction by fire. </p>

<p>Sec. 3. It shall be the duty of the health officer,
also of the chief of the fire department, respectabively, 
upon application from any person or persons proposing to 
open or conduct the business of a public laundry within the
City of Seattle to inspect the premises in which it is proposed
to carry on said business, or in which said business
is being carried on, with a view to ascertain whether the
said premises are provided with proper drainage and sanitary
appliances, also whether the provisions of the ordinances of
the city then in force making regulations concerning the
erection and use of buildings and for the protection of 
property from <del>fire or</del> injury or destruction by fire, have
been complied with, and if found in all respects satisfactory
then to issue to such person or persons the certificates
provided for in section 2 of this ordinance. No charge
whatever shall be made or compensation or fee collected or
received for the performance of any of the services required 
by the provisions of this ordinance in the inspection of 
premises or the issuance of a certificate, but all such services
shall be performed free of charge.</p>

<p>Sec. 4. No person or persons owning or employed 
in the public laundries or public wash-houses provided for
in section 1 of this ordinance shall wash or iron clothes 
between the hours of 10 o'clock p.m. and 6 a.m., nor upon</p>

<ab>2</ab>

<pb/>

<p>any portion of that day known as Sunday.</p>

<p>Sec. 5. No person or persons engaged in the laundry
business within the City of Seattle shall permit any
person suffering from any infectious or contagious disease
to lodge, sleep or remain within or upon the premises used 
by him, her or them for the purpose of a public laundry.</p>

<p>Sec. 6. It shall be unlawful, from and after the 
passage of this ordinance, for any person or persons to establish,
maintain or carry on a laundry within the corporate
limits of the City of Seattle, without having first obtained
the consent of the common council, except the same be located 
in a building constructed either of brick or stone and 
covered with a metal roof. </p>

<p>Sec. 7. Any person or persons establising, maintaining
or carrying on the business of a public laundry or
a public wash-house where clothes or other articles are
cleansed for hire, within the limits or the City of Seattle,
without first having complied with the provisions of section
2 of this ordinance, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and,
upon conviction thereof, shall be punished by a fine of not
less than ten dollars nor more than one hundred dollars, or
by imprisonment for not more than thirty days, or by both
such fine and imprisonment; and any person who shall violate
any of the provisions of sections 4, 5 and 6 of this ordinance
shall be guilty of a misdemenor, and, upon conviction
thereof, shall be punished by a fine of not less than five
dollars nor more than one hundred dollars, or by imprisonment
for not more than thirty days, or by both such fine and 
imprisonment. </p>

<pb/>

<p>Sec. 8. The certificates from the health officer
and the chief of the fire department, as required by section
2 of this ordinance, shall be exhibited in some conspicuous
place on the premises, and the same shall be produced on the 
demand of any officer of the City of Seattle. </p>

<p>Sec. 9. The police authorities are hereby directed 
to have the provisions of this ordinance strictly enforced.</p>

<p>Sec. 10. Ordinance No. 263, entitled "An ordinance
to restrain and regulate laundries and wash-houses within the
fire limits of the City of Seattle for the purpose of the
prevention of fires," approved April 10, 1882, and all other
ordinances and parts of ordinance are hereby repealed; provided,
that this ordinance shall not in any manner affect any
cause or proceeding pending or being prosecuted at the time
this ordinance takes effect or that may be hereafter commenced
and prosecuted for violations of said ordinance No.
263 committed prior to the time of the passage of this ordinance;
but, as to all such past violations, said ordinance
No. 263 shall be and remain in full force. </p>

<p><del>Approved February 6, 1886</del></p>

<p>Sec. 11. This ordinance shall take effect and be
in force from and after its passage and approval by the Mayor.</p>

<p>Passed the Common Council of the City of Seattle
the 5th day of February, 1886, and approved by me the 6th 
day of February, 1886.</p>

<ab>H. L. Yesler,
Mayor. </ab>

<p>Filed February 6th, 1886.</p>

<ab>W. R. Forrest, Clerk</ab>

<p>Published February 8th, 1886.</p>

<pb/>

<ab>STATE OF WASHINGTON,
County of King,
City of Seattle,</ab>

<ab>ss.</ab>

<p>I, <unclear>Jas</unclear> Riplinger, City Comptroller and ex-officio
City Clerk of the City of Seattle do hereby certify that the within
and foregoing is a true and correct copy of Ordinance No. 
710 as the same appears on file in my office.</p>

<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF I have set my hand and affixed the seal
of the City of Seattle this 4th day of September,
A. D. 1902.</p>

<ab><unclear>Jas</unclear> Riplinger
City Comptroller and ex-officio
City Clerk of the City of Seattle.</ab>

<ab>By E.W. Melor
Dep. </ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Orginal</ab>

<ab>Tx</ab>

<ab><unclear></unclear> of the Nothern
<unclear></unclear> this 4th
<unclear></unclear> ofSeptember, 1902.
<unclear>Wiestling</unclear></ab>

<ab>Attorney for 
Petitioner</ab>

<ab>No. 2333</ab>

<ab>In the United States
District Court
FOR THE DISTRICT of Washington
Northern Division</ab>

<ab>In the matter of the 
application of Lee
Fong for a writ of 
Habeas Corpus</ab>

<ab>Answer to Petition
for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</ab>

<ab>FILED IN THE 
U.S. DISTRICT COURT,
DIST OF WASHINGTON.
SEP 4 1902
R.M. HOPKINS, CLERK</ab>

<ab>HM Matthew
Deputy</ab>

<ab>Mitchell Gillian
Ellis D E <unclear>Bruler</unclear></ab>

<ab>Attorney for John Sullivan
Chief of Police.</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>