<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0490.013">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ng Kwack Kang v. King County. Points and Authorities</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0490.013</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ng Kwack Kang v. King County. Brief of United States</title>
<date when="1915-12-20">December 20th, 1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno>Case No 3157</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1916-01">January 1916</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>White, Henry M.</term>
<term>Kum, Ng</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Kang, Ng Kwack</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, Adam</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay</persName>
<persName>Moodie, Albert</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
<person role="clerk">
<persName>Crosby, Frank L.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>King County</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#mmd">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0490.013"/>

<p>
In the United States District Court, In and for the Western District
of Washington, Northern Division.

In the matter of the application of 
Ng Kwack Kang, for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus.

No. 3157
Points and Authorities

This case not only involves the right of a child of a 
native born <add>Chinese</add> citizen to enter into the United States, but involves
the larger question of parentage. If the petitioner is the son of 
Ng Kum, then he is the heir of Ng Kum, and as such heir he is entitled 
to the right of inheritance, which, if the ruling of the
Secretary of Labor and Commerce shpuld be upheld, would, not only 
deprive the petitioner of the right of entry into the United States,
but would deprive the petitioner of the rights of succession and inheritance
as the heir of Ng Kum.

It is conceded upon a question of citizenship alone that a
decision of the Secretary of Labor and Commerce is final,
unless there appears to be an abuse of discretion. But the petitioner in 
this case contends that the decision of a ministerial officer as to
his parentage, is not final, and that he has a right to a judicial 
hearing, to determine the question of his parentage. The petitioner
seeks to review the findings of the Commissioner of Immigration, not
alone upon the question of citizenship and abuse of discretion, but
upon the question of his parentage, For your petitioner to be, by 
a ruling of a ministerial officer, unjustly deprived of the right 
of succession and inheritance, would be to deprive him of his property 
without due process of law.

The petitioner in this case seeks admission into the United 
States, not as an American born citizen of the United States, but as
the son of his father, which has been legally adjudged an American b
orn citizen. (See Exhibit B, Ng Kwack Kang) For the United States 
Government to take this young boy before executive officers, and
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
in what might be in every sense of the word, termed " a star chamber
proceeding"; without being confronted by witnesses, with no opportunity
for cross-examination, without the aid of counsel, and upon 
the unsworn and ex parte statements and conclusions of what appears
biased and prejudiced officials - to be by them, upon conjecture and 
doubt officially declared that he is not the son of his father, and
to deny him the right of entry into the United States, the opportunity
and advantaged of education, and last, but not least, the loving
care of his father, and to say that such a determination is final,
and that the applicant cannot have his parentage judicially determined
would be a monstrous and <add>an</add> iniquitious proceeding, contrary to 
all the rules of fair play.

Parentage has never been determined by ministerial officers
.. is not now determied by ministerial officers.. and will never
be finally determined by ministerial officers.

It will be noted from the examination of Ng Kum set forth
in "Exhibit B", November 17th, 1910, that Ng Kum gave the following
testimony:
Q. What are your names?
A. NG KUM, given name - NG HONG FAN, marriaqge name - no others.
Q. When were you married?
A. When I was twenty years old to Chin She, natural, 29
Back Wut Village, Sn, living now and since I married her
in Gong Ben Sn, China.
Q. Have you any children?
A. One son, NG KG Kwock Teun, 10, born 8/15, forgot year. No
daughters.
This testimony was given at a time when there could have 
been no motive for making a false statement.
At this point it might be well to consider the nativity 
of Ng Kum. In the record the following question appears to be 
propounded by the inspector:
</p>
<pb></pb>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>