<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0359.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>A. C. Hallam v. Henry M. White. Memorandum Decision</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0359.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">A.C. Hallam v. Henry M. White. Memorandum Decision</title>
<date when="1921-02-16">February 16, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-02">February 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Reagan, F.C.</term>
<term>Garland, Marion</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hallam, A. C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Garland, Marion</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington - Northern Division.</p>

<p>No. 5779.</p>
<p>Memorandum Decision, Filed, Feb. 16, 1921.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of A.C. HALLAM for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>-oOo-</p>

<p>Hon. Robt. C. Saunders, U.S. Attorney,</p>
<p>F.C. Reagan, Assistant " " "</p>

<p>For Petitioner,</p>

<p>Marion Garland,</p>

<p>For Respondent.</p>

<p>-oOo-</p>

<p>CUSHMAN, District Judge.</p>

<p>Trial has been had upon the petition and answer.</p>

<p>Petitioner sues to be discharged from the custody of the chief of police at Bremerton, who, it is alleged, detains him upon a conviction before the police judge of the City of Bremerton, the charge being that of conducting, without the payment of the city license, a dance hall at the Navy Yard Hotel, which hotel petitioner leases from the United States, and which is physically within the limits of the City of Bremerton and adjacent to the Puget Sound Navy Yard.</p>

<p>The petitioners avers that the police court of Bremerton has neither jurisdiction over petitioner, nor the subject matter. Petitioner's lease is from the Secretary of the Navy. Section 10 of the lease provides:-</p>

<p>"The lessee agrees to use said premises for hotel purposes with the right to conduct and maintain or to carry on upon said leased premises any and all enterprises which may be incidental to such hotel, or which may be useful or convenient in connection therewith, upon approval of the Commandants as provided in Paragraph 7; provided, however, that the activities of the Navy Yard Hotel will be limited to housing, subsisting and otherwise serving Navy Yard employees; and to keep said premises in a clean</p>

<pb/>

<p>and sanitary condition and to strictly abide by and perform all requirements of law, ordinance, or other regulations touching said premises or any buisness to be carried on in and about the same, and agrees that said premises shall not be used for any unlawful purpose or for any purpose which will injure the reputation of said building."</p>

<p>Article I., Section 8, subdivision 17, of the Constitution of the United States provides:-</p>

<p>"To exercise exclusive legislation in all cases whatsoever, over such district (not exceedings ten miles square) as may, be cession of particular states, and the acceptance of congress, become the seat of the government of the United States, and to exercise like authority over all places purchased by the consent of the legislature of the state in which the same shall be, for the erection of forts, magazines, arsenals, dockyards, and other needful buildings.</p>

<p>The States of Washington consented to the acquirement of such property by the general statute: -</p>

<p>"The consent of the State of Washington be and the same is hereby given to the acquisition by purchase or by condemnation, under the laws of this state relating to the appropriation of private property to public uses, by the United States of America, or under the authority of the same, of any tract, piece, or parcel of land, from any individual or individuals, bodies politic or corporate, within the boundaries or limits of this state, for the sites of locks, dams, piers, breakwaters, keeper' dwellings, and other necessary structures and purposes required in the improvement of the rivers and harbors of this state, or bordering thereon, or for the sites of forts, magazines, arsenals, docks, navy-yards, naval stations, or other needful buildings authorized by any act of Congress, and all deeds, conveyances of title papers for the same shall be recorded as in other cases, upon the land records of the county in which the land so acquired may lie; and in like manner may be recorded a sufficient description by metes and bounds, courses and distances, of any tract or tracts, legal divisions or subdivisions of any public land belonging to the United States which may be set apart by the general government for any or either of the purposes before mentioned by an order, patent, or other official document or papers describing such land; the consent herein and hereby given being in accordance with the seventeenth clause of the eighth section of the first article of the constitution of the United States, and with the acts of Congress in such cases made and provided; and the jurisdiction of this state is hereby ceded to the United States of America over all such land or lands as may have been or may be hereafter acquired by purchase or by condemnation, or set apart by the general government for any or either of the purposes before mentioned * * * * *."</p>
<p>(sec. 6853 Rem. &amp; Bal. Code).</p>

<p>-2-</p>

<pb/>

<p>While the hotel may, in a sense, not be part of the Navy Yard proper, in view of the provisions of the foregoing section of the lease, and in the absence of any showing to the contrary, the hotel must be held to fall fairly within the term "other needful buildings" in the foregoing constitutional provision.</p>

<p>The ruling laid down in Concessions Co. v. Morris (109 Wash., 46), to the effect that Camp Lewis was not "within the State of Washington", in the meaning of the taxing laws, applied to the present case would, necessarily, result in the conclusion that the police court had no jurisdiction over the person of petitioner; but it is not necessary to place the ruling on that narrow, ground.</p>

<p>Respondent concedes that Government property is exempt from taxation, but contend<del>s</del> that the city has taxed, by its license requirement, only the trade, or occupation of the petitioner. But the Government has the untrammeled right to use its own as it sees fit and to its own advantage. If petitioner can only use this building, the property of the United States, under license from the city, although the latter is not a direct charge upon the property, it is, none the less, a charge that it needs no argument to show lessens the income value of Government property. If argument where needed to demonstrate this, it is furnished by respondent, for it is said in its brief:-</p>

<p>"For the court to hold that a man can lease Government property, for a private use, and thereby escape an occupation tax, is doing away with the principals of equity. It will destroy the business man of Bremerton. The Buisness man of Bremerton must pay taxes, assessments and licenses to maintain and keep up the city, and if Mr. Hallam, can conduct, as he is doing, a bakery, laundry, restaurant, pool room, furnish lodging, dancing halls and any other business that he may desire, in competition with the other buisness men of Bremerton, without paying a license, the U.S. Government becomes an agent of special privileges, and a destroyer of the legitimate business man and the man that pays the upkeep and maintance of our Government."</p>

<p>The reasoning quoted would be equally applicable if an</p>

<p>-3-</p>

<pb/>

<p>attack were made upon the exemption of the Government property from a direct tax. The use of the property by petitioner may, in so far as he is concerned, be considered, in one sense, as a private use, but, in so far as the United States is concerned, it is not a private use.</p>

<p>If carrying on such business on such Government owned property gives an advantage such as that pictured, that advantage cannot but add to its rental value and, certainly, where the property is not only government owned, but, as shown by paragraph 10 of the lease above quoted, is being devoted to Government use, the authority of the state cannot hamper or impede such use or lessen the value thereof by imposing a license upon the petitioner, who rents such property to the financial advantage of the Government, and operates it as a hotel for the accommodation of the personnel of the Navy, to the advantage of its operations.</p>

<p>Ohio v. Thomas, 173 U.S., 276;</p>

<p>Johnson v. Maryland Advance Sheet, U.S. Supreme Court, No. 289, Decided Nov. 8, 1920.</p>

<p>Concessions Co. v. Morris, 109 Wash., 46.</p>

<p>It is no doubt true, as stated in 37 CYC., 869, that</p>

<p>"The exemption of public property from taxation does not extend to improvements on the public lands made by pre-emptioners, homestead, and other claimants, or occupants, at their own expense, and these are taxable by the state."</p>

<p>But a Navy Yard and the needful lands and buildings occupied and used in connection therewith are not "public lands" in any sense.</p>

<p>Public lands are open to be acquired and occupied by the public.</p>

<p>The petitioner will be discharged.</p>

<p>-4-</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 5779.</p>

<p>In the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern <del>Southern</del> Division</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of A.C. Hallam for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Memorandum Decision.</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Feb 16 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>

<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<pb/>

<p>Union</p>
<p>Printing Binding &amp; Stationary</p>

<p>1264 Phones 1265</p>

<p>Memorandum</p>

<p>M <gap></gap></p>

<p>Please Call</p>

<p>M <gap></gap></p>

<p>Indenture -</p>

<p>Phone</p>

<p>Time <gap></gap>M.</p>
<p>Date</p>

<p>Mr. Reagan will bring order for withdrawal</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>