<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0461.152">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>M. L. Coovert for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Russell, Ellie" xml:id="edr">Ellie Russell</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">M. L. Coovert for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</title>
<date when="1893-06-22">June 22, 1893</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1890-1901, vol 1</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1893-06">June 1893</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Coovert, M. L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="sheriff">
<persName>Nerton, George</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Clarke County</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#edr">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p><!-- <note>RofJ 1-60</note> --></p>
<p>280
TX</p>
<p>In re- M. L. Coovert</p>
<p>Judgement
No 6.</p>
<p>Filed June 22 1893
In the 
U. S. Circuit Court.
A. Reeves Ayres.
Clerk
By R. M. Hopkins</p>

<p>In the Circuit Court of the United States for the
District of Washington, Ninth Circuit,
Northern Division:</p>
<p>Ex parte
M. L. Coovert.
} Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>No. <del>3</del>6</p>
<p>Now, at this time, comes on this cause to be heard upon the petition
of M. L. Coovert, duly filed in this court, praying for the issuance
of the writ of habeas corpus.
And upon the demurrer to said petition, duly filed by George Nerton, sheriff of 
Clarke county, Washington, and upon the evidenceand exhibits submitted with said 
petition, and upon the writ of habeas corpus issued out of this court on the 13th day of 
June, 1893, and upon the return of Geroge Nerton, sheriff of Clarke county, State of Washington, to said writ; and the motion to discharge the petitioner and the body of 
M. L. Coovert in the foregoing writ of habeas corpus mentioned being brought before 
the court at the time and place in said writ named, and the return thereto being read, 
and the petitioner appearing by Mr. C. E. S. Wood, his soliciotor, and moving the Court 
for his discharge, and the sheriff of Clarke county, George Nerton, appearing by C.D. 
Bowles,his solicitor, and the court having considered the said petition and demurrer 
thereto, the exhibits, the writ of habeas corpus and the return thereto, and the motion to discharge the petitioner, and having heard the argument in the remises and being fully 
advised,and it appearing to the court that the facts and circumstances are not sufficient 
to justify the imprisonment of the said M. L. Coovert and no sufficient cause for the
detention of the said M. L. Coovert appearing, it is hereby-</p>
<p>Ordered, adjudged, and decreed that the said law of the State of Washington 
prohibiting the sale of cigarettes and referred to in the petition is in contravention of
article I of section 8 of the Constitution of the United States and null and void, in so 
far as it prohibits or attempts to prohibit the selling, giving, or furnishing to any one by
the importer of a box of packages of a slide paste board box containing ten paper
wrapped cigarettes having upon it the U. S. Interal Revenue
Stamp and caution notice as required by law, also number of manufacturer district and state which box
was received by the importer from without the State of Washington packed in a paste board
box or carton, and said carton <del>with other</del> enclosed
with others in a paper wrapper tied with sting cord-
and that the said M. L. Coovert be by said George Nerton, Sheriff of Clarke county, 
forthwith discharged from imprisonment and detention for the cause as in said petition
aforesaid.</p>
<p>And it is further ordered, adjusted, and decreed that the said M. L. Coovert, petitioner,
shall enter into a recognizance in the sum of two hundred and fifty ($250.00) 
dollars with the clerk of this court, with one or more sureties, for his appearance to 
answer the judgement of the appellate court in the premises.</p>
<p>C. H. Hanford, Judge.</p>
<p>Dated this 22nd day of June, 1893.</p>

<p>And Afterwads, to wit, the <gap></gap> <unclear></unclear>
June, 1893, the same being the <gap></gap> Judicial
day of the Redular June term of said Court, Present the Honorable
Cornelius H. Hanford, United States District Judge, presiding, the following
proceedings were had in said cause, to wit:</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>