<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0433.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>James A. Balch v. J.W. Waughop. Commitment</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0433.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">James A. Balch v. J.W. Waughop. Commitment</title>
<date when="1888-06">June, 1888</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1888-06">June, 1888</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Guilland, David</term>
<term>Navarre, James A.</term>
<term>Balch, Hattie M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>King County</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Balch, James A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Waughop, D.J</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jones, Richard A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the Third Judicial District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>COMPLAINT. <add>AND COMMITMENT</add></p>

<p>TERRITORY OF WASHINGTON,
County of Yakima
<del>In the matter of . . . . . an insane person</del></p>

<p>David Guilland, being duly sworn, on oath, says there is in said county an
insane <del>(idiotic)</del> person, whose name is James A. Balch, who, by reason of insanity <del>( )</del>, is
unsafe to be at large (or is suffering under mental derangement) ; and affiant therefore asks that said person be arrested and taken
before a Judge of Probate within said county for examination.</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 20 day
of June A.D. 1883</p>

<p>J.A. Navarre, Probate Judge.</p>

<p>D. Guilland</p>

<p>COMMITMENT.</p>

<p>James A. Balch the person named in the foregoing affidavit, being this day brought
before me, Judge of the Probate Court Yakima county, for examination on a charge of
insanity, and no jury being demanded either by him or by anyone in his behalf, and having heard the testimony of
David Guilland witness  who has
<add>in Yakima City</add>
been acquinted with the accused during the time of the alleged insanity; and Drs. W.F. Morrison
and J.O. Clark who <add>respectfully and</add> legally qualified physicians, after hearing the testimony of witnesses,
after a personal examination of the accused, having made the certificate by law required; and being myself satisfied that the
said James A. Balch is insane <del>(or idiotic)</del> and being further satisfied of the truth of all
the matters set forth in the certificate of said Physicians, I do hereby order the said James A. Balch
to be confined in the Hospital for the Insane at Fort Steilacoom, and
the Sheriff of this county is charged with the execution of this order.</p>

<p>The seal of the said <unclear></unclear>
Witness my hand and seal this 20 day of June 1883
James A. Navarre
Probate Judge of Yakima County W.T.</p>

<p>(Seal)
Yakima County
W.T.
Probate Court</p>

<p>After inquiry as by law required, I find the said James A. Balch, is unable to pay
his expenses in the hospital at the sum of forty five 00/100 Dollars for over
two months, he has relatives who - <unclear></unclear> (see code sec. 1632, 1655, 2697-8) have
some property in Klickilat County and he has a wife Mrs. Hattie M. Balch
in Syle Klickilat Co. W.T. Whereas my hand and seal this 20 day of June seal
<unclear></unclear></p>

<pb></pb>

<p>No. 342</p>

<p>Copy of order of
COMMITMENT
of James A Balch of
Yakima County to the
HOSPITAL + FOR + THE + INSANE,
AT FORT STEILACOOM,
Washington Territory</p>

<p><del>To
From..
County.</del></p>

<p>Date of admission June 8 1883</p>

<p><del>I hereby certify that the within are true and correct copies of
the original Complaint, Physicians Certificate and Commitment
in the matter of . . . . .
an insane (or idiotic) person, this day committed by me to the
Hospital for the Insane of Washington Territory.</del></p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Territory of Washington
County of Yakima          } ss</p>

<p>IN THE PROBATE COURT OF YAKIMA CO., W.T.</p>

<p>In the matter of the insanity of        Warrant of commitment
James A. Balch.                         to insane Hospital &amp; c.
Insane</p>

<p>To the Sheriff of Yakima County, Washington Territory,
GREETING:</p>

<p>Whereas, James A. Balch has this day been brought before J.A. Navarre,
Judge of the Probate Court in and for said Yakima, Co., W.T. charged
with being insane upon the application and complaint of David
Guilland, and it appearing to the satisfaction of the said Judge
that the said James A. Balch is insane and unsafe to be at large.
Therefore, in the name of the United States, you are commanded
forthwith to carry the said James A. Balch safely to the Hospital for
the insane in Washington Territory, near Steillacoom, and place him in
charge of the proper officers of said hospital and make return of
this writ with your donings thereon.</p>

<p>(Seal of Probate Court
of Yakima Co., W.T.)</p>

<p>WITNESS the Hon. J.A. Navarre, Judge of the
Probate Court of Yakima County W.T. and the
Seal of the said Court affixed this 2nd
day of June, 1883</p>

<p>J.A. Navarre,
Judge of the Ex-Officio Clerk Probate Court.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>In RE
James A. Balch,
Insane.</p>

<p>Warrant of Commitment
to Insane hospital.</p>

               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>