<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0356.031">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Gin Kato v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0356.031</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Gin Kato v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1920-10-25">October 25, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-10">October 1920</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Strench, William G.</term>
<term>Ketchikan, Alaska</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Kato, Gin</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Kiefer, James</persName>
<persName>Winston, Will H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the United States District Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>No. 5631</p>
<p>Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of GIN KATO for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE, THE JUDGES OF THE ABOVE ENTITLED COURT:</p>
<p>The petition of Gin Kato respectfully represents:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That he lawfully entered the United States on or about the 15th day of July, 1884, and ever since has been a resident of the United States of America.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>That on the 17th day of June, 1920, at Ketchikan, Alaska, your petitioner was arrested by one William G. Strench, an immigration inspector upon a departmental warrant issued by the Department of Labor of the United States of America on the 3rd day of June, 1920, charging your petitioner with being employed in a house of prostitution at Ketchikan, Alaska.</p>

<p>III.</p>

<p>That after an alleged pretended hearing your petitioner was ordered deported under departmental warrant of deportation dated September 25th, 1920, and is now in custody of Henry M. White, United States Immigration Commissioner at the Port of Seattle, Washington, in this district, for the purpose of being deported to Japan on the 27th day of October, 1920.</p>

<p>IV.</p>

<p>That the detention and proposed deportation of your petitioner is unlawful and an invasion of the rights of your petitioner upon the following grounds:</p>

<p>(a) That your petitioner continuously resided in the United States for thirty-five (35) years prior to his arrest.</p>

<pb/>

<p>-2-</p>

<p>(b) That said proposed deportation of your petitioner is an invasion and a violation of the rights of your petitioner under the Treaty between the United States of America and the Emperor of Japan, of whom your petitioner is a subject, dated November 22nd, 1894, and proclaimed by the United States of America March 21, 1895.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, Your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus may be issued to the Honorable Henry M. White, United States Immigration Commissioner at the Port of Seattle, commanding him to produce the body of your petitioner before this Honorable Court, there to submit to and receive whatever the court shall order in the premises.</p>

<p>Gin Kato</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>

<p>James Kiefer</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner, Suite 327 Colman Bldg., Seattle, Washington.</p>

<p>United States of America )</p>
<p>Western District of Washington ) ss</p>
<p>County of King. )</p>

<p>THIS IS TO CERTIFY, that on this 25th day of October, 1920, before me, the subscriber, a Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, duly commissioned and sworn, personally came Gin Kato, the petitioner above-named, who being by me first duly sworn, deposes and says; That he is the petitioner above-named; that he has heard the foregoing petition read and explained in Japanese language and that the facts therein stated are true.</p>

<p>Gin Kato</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me on this 25th day of Oct. 1920.</p>

<p>James Kiefer</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 5631</p>

<p>U.S. District Court, Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of GIN KATO, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Petition for Writ of Habeas corpus.</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Oct 25 1920</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<p>James Kiefer,</p>
<p>Suite 327 Colman Bldg.,</p>
<p>Seattle, Washington</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>