<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0184.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Harry Gong vs. United States. Criminal</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0184.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Harry Gong vs. United States. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">November 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Barbour, J. H.</term>
<term>Chong, Co</term>
<term>Dock, Wong Jun</term>
<term>Harms, L. A.</term>
<term>Lowe, Herman</term>
<term>Ming, Chuey</term>
<term>Nui, Sum</term>    
<term>Seung, Ho</term>    
<term>Sing, Ah</term>    
<term>Smith, Wilfred F.</term>
<term>Wise, J. M.</term>
<term>Wong, Go</term>    
<term>Yow, Yut</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
<term></term>


</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Harry Gong</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>United States District Court, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
    <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>"Exhibit A"</p>

<p>Record of testimony given by Yut Yow, Chinese prostitute, at Police 
Station, Portland, Oregon, November 4, 1913, in re legality of her
residence in the United States and other matters.</p>

<p>Examination conducted by Inspector in Charge J. H. Barbour.</p>
<p>Herman Lowe, Chinese Interpreter.</p>
<p>Wilfred F. Smith, Stenographer.</p>

<p>Police Officers Harms and Wise, present.</p>
<p>YUT YOW, duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>Q What is your name ? A Yut x Yow.</p>
<p>Q Any other name or names? A Also known as Ah Sing.</p>
<p>Q You will now be requested to make a statement in regard to the 
legality of your residence in the United States and other matters.
It is your privilege to refuse to make any such statement, and you 
are informed that any statement you make may be used against you 
in subsequent proceedings. A All right.</p>
<p>Q How old are you? A Forty-five.</p>
<p>Q Where were you born? A San Francisco.</p>
<p>Q What year? A I don't remember now.</p>
<p>Q Have you ever been in China? A No.</p>
<p>Q Didn't you go to China when you were young? A No.</p>
<p>Q Havn't you ever been out of the United States? A No.</p>
<p>Q What is your father's name? A Co Chong.</p>
<p>Q Has he any other name or names? A No.</p>
<p>Q Where is your father now? A He is dead now, died in China.</p>
<p>Q Was he ever in this country? A He went to China.</p>
<p>Q When? A K.S.26</p>
<p>Q How did he go? A By way of Seattle, I think. He came to Portland 
from San Francisco and then to Seattle.</p>
<p>Q What was his business in this country? A He was a laborer.</p>
<p>Q Where did he live? A Hop Sing Building, San Fraciscon, on Jackson
Street.</p>
<p>Q Where is your mother? A My mother went to China and died there 
also.</p>
<p>Q Was she <add>ever</add> in this country? A Yes; she went to China a long time ago.</p>
<p>Q Did you ever have any brothers or sisters? A One older brother,
Ho Seung, died in Astoria long time ago.</p>
<p>Q Did you ever live in Astoria? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q How long and when? A Only a few months; in K.S. 26 I left there.</p>
<p>Q. Are you married? A I was married to a Wong Jun Dock in Astoria, 
K.S.25.</p>
<p>Q What was his occupation? A He was a laborer.</p>
<p>Q Has he always been a laborer? A Yes,</p>
<p>Q Do you know where he was born? A I don't know.</p>
<p>Q Where <add>is</add> he now? I don't know.</p>
<p>Q When did you and he separate? K.S.34.</p>
<p>Q Have you married any one else since that time? A No.</p>
<p>Q Have you lived with any other man since that time? NO.</p>
<p>Q How do you support yourself? A Seamstrees.</p>
<p>Q What kind of sewing do you do? A I sew buttons on.</p>
<p>Q What do you charge for sewing a button on? A Five cents.</p>
<p>Q How many buttons can you sew on in a day? A some days I make
<fw>YUT YOW (1)</fw>
<pb/>
as much as a dollar, and some days I don't make anything at all.</p>
<p>Q. Is that the sole occupation you have? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q. Who was the big fat man who was in your room at the time you were 
arrested -- were you sewing a button on him? A A friend of mine.</p>
<p>Q What was he doing in your room? A Just visiting there.</p>
<p>Q Visiting you, in bed with you, at three o'clock on the morning?
    A He wasn't in bed.</p>
<p>Q Were you up and around at three o'clock in the morning? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Isn't it true that you got out of bed and left him in bed when 
the officers entered your room? A I was sitting on a chair
when they broke in the door.</p>
<p>Q How were you dressed when the officers arrested you? A Just as I 
am now.</p>
<p>Q Did you have shoes and stockings on? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Who was this friend who was visiting you at three o'clock in the 
morning? A A good friend of mine.</p>
<p>Q What is his name? A His name was Sum Nui.</p>
<p>Q How long had he been in your room? A (No answer)</p>
<p>Q Did you have sexual relations with him in your room? A No.</p>
<p>Q Can you explain his presence in your room at three o'clock in the
morning? A I was afraid of the dark and he came up to keep me
company.</p>
<p>Q Do others come to console you in the dark? A No.</p>
<p>Q Any one else ever stay with you in your room at night? A No.</p>
<p>Q At waht different places in Portland have you lived? A. I lived
in the Hong Mo Building on Fourth Street opposite the big hotel
before I moved down to my presence place on Fourth Street.</p>
<p>Q Did you live in the Hong MO Building alone? A. Yes.</p>
<p>Q How long have you been living in rooms by yourself? A Several years.</p>
<p>Q Do you share your present room with any other woman? A Yes,
with Ah Sing, one of the women arrested this morning.</p>
<p>Q What is her occupation? A I don't know; she came from
San Francisco.</p>
<p>Q How did she get into your room? A I rent my room from the landlord
and she rents her room from the landlord.</p>
<p>Q How much do you pay for your room? A Ten dollars a month.</p>
<p>Q Who do you pay it to? A I don't know.</p>
<p>Q Have you any papers or evidence showing your right to be and remain
in the United States? A I had a certificate of residence but 
it was destroyed in the San Francisco fire.</p>
<p>Q Do you know the number of it? A I don't remember the number.</p>
<p>Q How old were you when you registered? A I registered I think when
I was thirty years old.</p>
<p>Q Have you any other papers? A No.</p>
<p>Q Have you any husband or any one to look out for your interests? 
A I divorced my first husband.</p>
<p>Q How did you divorce him? A He went to China and left me.</p>
<p>Q Have you any man at the present time,any one who is interested in you
who will look out for you? A Yes, Chuey Ming.</p>
<p>Q Has he any other name? A I don't know.</p>
<p>Q Where can he be found--what store is he in?
A He is in Portland.</p>
<p>Q In what store? A He goes in and out at the On Lee store.</p>
<p>Q What are your relations with him--are you living with at the 
present time? A. No.</p>
<p>Q. Does he come to see you? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Does he have sexual relations with you occasionally? A I like to 
marry him.</p>
<p>Q Have you been living with him? A I intend to marry him.</p>
<p>Q Have you been having sexual relations with him at all, and is that
why you intend to marry him? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Is it true that you have been a prostitute for some years in this
city? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q For how many years? A Fifteen years</p>
<fw>YUT YOW (2)</fw>
<pb/>
<p>Q Is it <add>not</add> true that you were born in China? A I was born in San-
Francisco.</p>
<p>Q Are you sure of that? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q How can you prove it? I can't prove it.</p>
<p>Q Can any one prove it that you know? A There are some, but I don't 
know where they are; some went to China possible and some died.</p>
<p>Q Have you any living relatives in this country? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Who and where are they? A Go Wong, living in Portland; my father 
was his cousin.</p>
<p>Q Do you know where he is? A He is living in Chinatown somewhere.</p>
<p>Q Any other relatives in this country? A No.</p>
<p>Q. Can you identify these letters, papers, envelopes and cards which 
were found in your room amongst your personal effects? A These 
are the things they got out of my room.</p>
<p>Q Have you been out of Oregon in the last three or four years? A No.</p>
<p>Q Have you ever been arrested before? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Where and by whom? A By immigration officers.</p>
<p>Q How long ago? A A long time ago; don't remember when.</p>

<ab>(Signed by mark) Yut Yow her x mark</ab>

<ab>Witness to mark:
Signed) W. F. Smith.</ab>

<p>I hereby certify that the foregoing is a true and correct 
transcript of testimony taken by me in shorthand.</p>
<ab>W. F. Smith,
Stenographer.</ab>



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>