<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0187.020">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
    <title>Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0187.020</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
    <title level="m" type="main">Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal</title>
<date when="1914">1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-08">August 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Allen, Clay</term>
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Fishburne, George P.</term>
<term>Grayson, Marie Robina</term>
<term>Lakin, Edward M.</term>
<term>Turner, Charles A.</term>
<term>White, Henry M.</term>
<term>Wilson, W. D.</term>

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Marie Robina Grayson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Clay Allen</persName>
<persName>G. P. Fishburne</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
    <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT,
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, 
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the 
Application of Marie Robina Grayson, alias Marie
Robina, for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus. )
No. 2780.
ASSIGNMENT OF ERRORS.</p>

<p>Comes now Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration
at Seattle, Washington, for the United States Government, 
the respondent and appelant in the above entitled 
cause, by Clay Allen, United States Attorney for the Western 
District of Washington, and George P. Fishburne, Assistant
United States Attorney for said District, and says that in 
the record and proceedings in this cause and in the order and
judgment of discharge, dated the 20th day of July, 1914, and
filed and entered in the Clerk's office July 20, 1914, and
in the decision of the Court made and filed the 17th day of 
July, 1914, there is manifest error in this, to-wit:</p>
<p>I. 
That the Court erred in issuing the writ of habeas 
corpus.</p>
<p>II. 
That the Court erred in assuming jurisdiction of 
the case.</p>
<p>III. 
That the Court erred in holding that he had 
jurisdiction and power to discharge the petitioner Marie Robina 
Grayson, alias Marie Robina, when the records showed that
she had previously had a due and legal hearing before C. A. 
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
Turner, an immigration inspector, and that on testimony and 
proof taken before said investigator, W. D. Wilson, Secretary 
of Labor, had ordered the petitioner to be deported on the 
ground that she was a prostitute and had been found 
practicing prostitution subsequent to her entry into the 
United States.</p>
<p>IV.
That the Court erred in finding that the petitioner 
was legally married.</p>
<p>V. 
That the Court erred in finding that by marriage 
the petitioner was made a citizen of the United States, when 
it appeared by the record that she could not be lawfully 
naturalized.</p>
<p>VI.
That the Court erred in finding that petitioner was <add>not</add>
subject to deportation after the Secretary of Labor had 
found that she should be deported on the ground that the 
petitioner was a prostitute and had been found practicing 
prostitution subsequent to her entry into the United States.</p>
<p>VII.
That the Court erred in finding marriage conferred 
citizenship upon the petitioner, and prevented her deportation,
when the records showed that she was not a person of 
good moral character, nor in any other way qualified to be 
naturalized according to the laws of the United States.</p>
<p>VIII. 
That the Court erred in not finding that the question
of deportation of the petitioner was exclusively within
the province of the Secretary of Labor and the immigration
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
authorities.</p>
<p>IX.
That the Court erred in setting aside a ruling of 
the immigration authorities that the marriage of the 
petitioner was void so far as the Immigration Department was 
concerned.</p>
<p>X. 
That the Court erred in finding that he had a right 
to set aside a ruling of the Immigration Department as to 
the effect of marriage as shown in the case at bar on the 
citizenship of the petitioner, and in not holding that it 
was a question exclusively within the province of the 
Immigration Department.</p>
<p>XI.
That the Court erred in setting aside the ruling 
of the Secretary of Labor that the said alien should be 
deported on the ground that she was a prostitute and had 
been found practicing prostitution subsequent to her entry 
into the United States, because the conclusion and order of 
the said Secretary of Labor as to whether a woman were 
married or not as marriage affects the right of the Immigration 
Department to deport an immigrant.</p>
<p>XII.
That the Court erred in holding that the marriage 
of the petitioner could interfere with the immigration
authorities to deport her on the ground that neither the 
common law as to the effect of marriage nor the naturalization
statutes were ever intended or allowed to interfere
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
with the immigration laws of the United States.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration
at Seattle, Washington, respondent and appellant herein, 
prays that his assignment of errors be entered upon the 
record in this cause, and that upon the hearing of this appeal
it may be adjudged by the United States Circuit Court of 
Appeals for the Ninth Circuit that the order and judgment, 
dated July 20, 1914, and entered July 20, 1914, and the 
decision, made and filed July 17, 1914, be in all things 
reversed, set aside and held for naught, and that it be 
adjudged and decreed that the applicant, Marie Robina
Grayson, alias Marie Robina, be remanded to the custody of 
the respondent herein to be further dealt with according to 
law.</p>
<p>Dated at Seattle, Washington, August 20th, 1914.</p>
<ab><del> By G. P. Fishburne</del> <add>Clay Allen</add>
United States Attorney.</ab>
<ab>G. P. Fishburne
Assistant United States Attorney.</ab>


    
<fw>-4-</fw>
<pb/>
 <p>2x</p>
<p>No. 2780</p>

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT 
OF THE UNITED STATES
FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application 
of Marie Robina Grayson, alias 
Marie Robina, for a Writ of
Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>ASSIGNMENT OF ERRORS.</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. District Court, 
Western Dist. of Washington, 
NORTHERN DIVISION
AUG 20 1914</p>
<ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk,
by Ed M Lakin Deputy</ab>





</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>