<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0411.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Albert Rhude v. A.P. Hotaling Company of Puget Sound. Request for Writ.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace" xml:id="GT">Grace Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0411.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Albert Rhude v. A.P. Hotaling Company of Puget Sound. Request for Writ.</title>
<date when="1884-11-10">November 10, 1884</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archive</repository>
<collection>King Frontier Justice</collection>
<idno>Case 4185</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1884-11">November 1884</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Albert Rhude</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>A.P. Hotaling Company of Puget Sound</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Maurice McMicken</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Roger Greene</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Third Judicial District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington Territory</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#GT">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<ab>In the District Court of the Third Judicial District of Washington
Territory, holding terms at Seattle.</ab>
<ab>In the Matter of the application of
Albert Rhude for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</ab>
<ab>To the Honorable Roger S. Greene,
Judge of the above entitled court:,</ab>
<ab>The petition of Albert Rhude respectfully shows:</ab>
<p>That he the said Albert Rhude is unlawfully imprisioned, detained, 
confined, and restrained of his liberty, by J.H. McGraw, Sheriff
of King County, Washington Territory at the City of Seattle in
said King County. <add>That the cause or pretense of the restraint according to best of the knowledge and belief of this applicant is what pretends to be a warrant of arrest issued in caused <unclear></unclear> that petitioner is defendant.</add></p>
<p>That the said imprisonment, detention, confinement, and restraint
are illegal; and that the illegality thereof consists in this towit:</p>
<p>That the said cause No. 4184 on the docket fo said district court,
wherein the A.P. Hotaling Company of Puget Sound is Plaintiff, and
your petitioner is defendant is not a cuase wherein the defendant can
be arrested or held to bail.</p>
<p>That no warrant of arrest as required by law was ever issued in
said cause; that no affidavits required by law were ever filed in
said cause; that the order in said cause for a warrant for the arrest
of this petitioner specified as the amount in which the defendant should
be held to bail the sum of one thousand dollars, which said sum was
more than double the demand of the plaintiff in said cause, and one 
hundred dollars in addition thereto; that the court did not in said
order fix the amount of the bond to be given by the plaintiff in said
<pb></pb>
any bind whatever of the plaintiff in said cause; that no bond as required
in sectionCXIX of the Code of Washington, or any bond whatever
was filed by the plaintiff in the office of the clerk of said court before
the issuance of the warrant of arrest of your petitioner in said 
cause; that the proof on which the said order was made is insufficent 
for the granting of such an order an the facts alleged in such proofs 
are untrue; that no copy of the complaint or summons in said cause
have ever been served upon this defendant or had this defendant ever
been served with any process or papers in said cause<del><unclear></unclear></del>;; That no copy
of the warrant of arrest in said cause had ever been delievered to him
by the sheriff as required by law; that the paper purporting to be a 
warrant in said cause and under which your petitioner is now illegally
restrained and imprisoned as aforesaid, did not contain a short statement
of or any statement whatever of the alleged causes for which the 
order was granted, as required by law. That the complaint of the 
plaintiff in said cuase did not state facts sufficient to constitue a 
cause of action against this petitioner.</p>
<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus Shoul
be granted directed to the said J.H. McGraw Sheriff as aforesaid,
commanding him to have the body of your petitioner before your honor
at a time and place therein to be specified, to do and recieve what 
shall <del><unclear></unclear></del> be considered by your Honor concerning him, together
with the time and cause of his detention, and said writ; and that he
may be restored to his liberty and that in the meantime he
be admitted to bail in such <unclear></unclear> as to the court may
seem just.</p>
<ab>Dated on the 8th dya of November A.D. 1884</ab>
<ab>Albert Rhude</ab>
<ab><unclear>Shawn</unclear> Harris + <unclear></unclear>
Attys for Petitioner</ab>
<pb></pb>
<ab>Territory of Washington,
County of King | ss.</ab>
<p>Albert Rhude being
first duly sworn, on oath says: That he is the Petitioner
<del>petition</del> in the above entitled action; that he has heard the foregoing
petition read, knows the contents thereof, and believes the same to be true; that
<del>he makes this affidavit because</del></p>
<ab>Albert Rhude</ab>
<ab>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 10th
day of November 1884
Maurice Mcmicken
Notary Public in and for King County, Washington Territory.</ab>
<ab>No 4185
In the District Court, Third Judicial District, holding terms at Seattle</ab>
<ab><del><unclear></unclear></del>
Application for 
Habeas Corpus 
of Albert Rhodes
Defendant</ab>
<ab>Petition for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</ab>
<ab>Filed .......... 188
Filed
Nov 10 1884
By James Seavey, Clerk
By James P Ludlow
Deputy.</ab>
<ab>Struve, Haines amperstand McMicken
Attorneys for Pet</ab>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>