<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title></title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Yu, Jingming" xml:id="jy">Jingming Yu</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington</title>
<date when="2022-06-20">June 20, 2022</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-08">August 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
                  
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#jy">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0000.000"/>

<p>In the Matter of the Extradition of FLETCHER DECKER.</p>
<p>__________</p>

<p>TRANSCRIPT OF PROCEEDINGS Before Robert W. McClelland, U. S. Commissioner, at Room No. 316 Marion Building, Seattle, Washington, August 24th and 25th, 1921.</p>

<p>_____</p>

<p>APPEARANCES: Miss CHARLOTTE KOLMITZ, Asst. U. S. Attorney, and IVAN L. HYLAND, Esq., (Of Messrs. Tucker &amp; Hyland) For the Petitioner; ADAM BEELER, Esq., (of Messrs. Beeler &amp; Sullivan) appearing for Defendant.</p>

<p>----------</p>


<p>G. H. L. MURRAY,    Being first duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>DIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>By Miss KOLMITZ:</p>

<p>Q    What is your name?</p>
<p>A    George H. L. Murray</p>
<p>Q    Your residence?</p>
<p>A    Seattle.</p>
<p>Q    What is your business or occupation?</p>
<p>A    British <add>Vice</add> Consul at Seattle.</p>
<p>Q    On whose behalf, and under whose authority do you appear here?</p>
<p>A    The Government, at Saskatchewan, Canada.</p>
<p>Q    Where is the Province of Saskatchewan?</p>
<p>A    In Canada.</p>
<p>    Miss. KOLMITZ: That is all. Any questions, Mr. Beeler:</p>
<p>    Mr. BELLER: No.</p>

<p>G. H. L. Murray<!--signed--></p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 26th day of August, 1921.</p>

<p><unclear>A. M. Clellarrd</unclear></p>
<p>U. S. Commissioner</p>

<p>Seal<!--written and circled--></p>


<p>CLAUDE H. FICKLIN,  Being first duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>DIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>By Miss KOLMITZ:</p>

<p>Q    What is your name?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Now at this time, if it please the Court, I desire to object to this proceeding, and object to the introduction of any further testimony herein on these grounds; First, that the warrant of arrest issued by the United States Commissioner fails to show upon its face that the Commissioner was authorized to issue, as required in a proceeding of this kind, any extradition, expressly under the treaty of 1842 between Great Britain and the United States, and I have a case directly in point on that objection, and that therefore the warrant of arrest is illegal and void. And, second, object to the introduction of any testimony in this proceeding on the ground that the information and complaint made by F. W. Chard, and which is the basis for this whole proceeding, does not allege facts sufficient to constitute the crime of theft or stealing, as defined by the laws of Canada, and I have the Statute of Canada here to establish that fact. There are a few other objections which I have, but which I do not think should be raised at this time, but which I will raise at the proper time, but I do raise those two at this time.</p>
<p>    (Argument.)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The only question that struck me at the time the warrant was issued, was on the affidavit of Thomas Waters, Deputy Marshal. The question came to my mind; I hadnt much time to look it up, as to whether the affidavit should not have been made by some representative of the British Government of Canada. However, the original complaint was afterwards amended, and that complaint was sworn to by George H. L. Murray, a representative of the British Government; I dont know that it would be necessary to issue a new warrant, an alias warrant, to conform to the ammended complain. I rather take it that the process follows all the pleadings in the case, the original and amended; what do you have to say about that, Mr. Hyland:</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: It seems to me that we have to prove, as a matter of fact in this proceeding, that the extradition is sought by a foreign country, and the original complaint does not show that, as a matter of fact, but the amended complaint does; and I doubt very much whether it is necessary for the complaint to show that, if the proof is shown at the time of th ehearing, that the complaint is sought by a foreign government, and that is the reason for Mr. Murray's testimony here, to supplement and show why the proceeding is brought; it does tno seem to me it makes any difference, whethe rin the original complaint or not, as long as showing is made upon the hearing it was done at the request of the foreign government.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I dont exactly catch your argument in regard to the insufficiency of the warrant; do you contend that the warrant should show on its face, or allege onits fact the authority of the Commissioner for issuing the warrant?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Exactly so, and this decision is absolutely in point. (Reads decision)</p>
<p>    (Argument)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The question arises, have I a right to amend this, or issue an alias warrant; I don't see the logic of it, but if it is necessary I am willing to do it; I can certify that I am authorized to, but that is a very funny sort of proceeding.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: This is a summary proceeding; it seems to me you would have a right to amend that any way you like; of course, I think that the hearing ought to go ahead just the same.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I have the right, or the Government has the right, or the Government of Canada has the right to amend its complaint; I dont know any reason why the process cannot be amended, or an alias warrant issued and served on the amended complaint; this original warrant was issued on the first complaint. I declare I dont see the logic of those decisions at all. I can put a self serving declaration in here that I am duly authorized to act; that does not establish the fact at all.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: You can say on your warrant you are authorized to do this.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Yes; the very fact I have done it is tantamount to that sort of a statement. I believe I will think about it until after lunch; look up my appointment; I dont want to get anybody into trouble.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I have another point I want to present when we convene, before we proceed with the introduction of evidence.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: It dont have reference to jurisdiction?</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: You content there is no complaint under the laws of Canada?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: That is one of my contentions, yes.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: It seems to me that ought to be a matter of proof; it is established by the complaint and affidavit; whether that is sufficient or not. We will adjourn until 2 o'clock.</p>
<p>    (At this time an adjournment was taken until 2 p. m.)</p>

<p>--------</p>


<p>AFTERNOON SESSION, 2 p. m.</p>
<p>Hearing resumed:</p>

<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I thought I was right, Mr. Beeler; I dont think it is necessary for me to certify that fact, but I have certified it on the bottom of the warrant.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Then shall we read the authorization into the record, so that it will be complete, as well as on the warrant; this transcript of the record will go up, and it may as well be in there.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The warrant goes up with the transcript.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: The authorization of the Commissioner will go up as part of the record. We will read that into the record when the time comes.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Does the record show in what capacity you are appearing for the government?</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: The British Vice Consul.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: For the purpose of the record, I want to object to the changing or amending of the warrant at this time.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Very well.</p>
<p>C. H. FICKLIN,   Recalled, testified as follows:</p>
<p>Q   (By Miss Kolmitz) Please state your name again, please.</p>
<p>A    I gave him my initials, not the full name.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: If the Court please, at this time I desire, in view of the fact that the Court has overruled my motion on that warrant, to interpose a demurrer to the sufficiency of the information and complaint, and I will ask the Court, if you have the original of that information and complaint to get it, while I present that matter to the Court.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Is your argument directed to the original or amended complaint?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: To the information and complaint; I think this is the original, is it not?</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: We will put it in for that purpose, if you want to argue it; it is not in evidence yet.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: This is the information and complaint upon which the complaint is based?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: No, the petition.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: There is a complaint filed, and original and amended?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: No, the petition.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I am making my objection to the information and complaint executed by T. W> Chard, dated the 14th day of June 1921, and executed before A. J. G. McCohen; that is the information and complaint I am objecting to, because it is upon the information that this proceeding must ultimately rest; it must stand or fall upon the information and complaint, because that is the information that was issued in Canada, and there isnt another basis upon this subsequent information that was issued here. I presume that Your Honor has the record of which this is a copy.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: No, I dont think I have; I have nothing of that kind before me here. Well, there is in evidence here a certified copy of that proceeding.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: It is just an ordinary copy, if Your Honor please; I havent as yet offered the record.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: This is not a certified copy, this is a true copy.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: I haven't offered the record yet.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Read the charged, and I think you will find it sufficient.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Here is the information and complaint upon which this proceeding is based; it would ultimately rest upon some information and complaint made by some one in Canada for the application of the extradition; and that information and complaint is exactly the same as the one here. (Reading) "I, Thomas Walter Chard, of Regina, in the Province of Saskatchewan, taken this 14th day of June in the year 1921, before the undersigned, A. J. MacEchen, one of His Majesty's Justices of the Peace in and for the said Province, who saith that Fletcher Decker formerly of new Wiwa Hill Post Office, in the said Province, on or about the 15th day of November A. D. 1915, near Wiwa Hill Post Office, aforesaid, in the said Province, did steal about Three Hundred (300) bushes of flax the property of Claude Ficklin and was thereby guilty of theft. (Signed) T. W. Chard. Sworn before me the day and year first above mentioned at Regina, in the said Province. (Signed) A. J. G. MacEchen, a Justice of the Peace in and for the Province of Saskatchewan." Now that is the information and complaint upon which this entire proceeding rests; it cant rest upon anything else, because it is upon that that the warrant to apprehend was issued, and it was upon that that the petition was subsequently issued. Now this information does not allege facts sufficient to constitute a crime under the Canadian statute; the only thing that it alleges is that Fletcher Decker on or about November 15, 1915, did stea; no allegation that the stealing was with intent to comfort it to himself, or that he did appropriate it; merely alleges the conclusion; Might just as well allege tha tthe man murdered a man--did commit murder at such and such a time, and by reason thereof he is guilty of murder.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: In other words, I take it you are raising th epont now there is no allegation of aspertation; is that the idea?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: It is lacking that, and lacking a more material element, it is lacking in the allegation of intent. I will call Your Honor's attention to the statute  upon which this is based; the statute is set out in the papers, that the intent must be shown. Now Section 347 of the Canadian Statutes defines theft. (Reads definition)</p>
<p>    (Argument)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: This is the complaint that was filed before me: "Affiant further says taht at the time aforesaid, to-wit, on the 15th day of November, 1915, it was, and now is, provided by the said Criminal Code of Canada, in and by Section 347 of said Criminal Code of Canada, the same then, and now being in force in said Province of Saskatchewan. in the Dominion of Canada, aforesaid, as follows, to-wit: and it sets out the statute which you have read, together, and in particular the four conditions constituting stealing, and alleging that that is the statute he violated. Of course that is an allegation, as I said this morning, which it seems to me would have to be established differently from establishing a question of law in this county, which the Courts are bound to take judicial notice of; that being a foreign statute would have to be established, as a matter of fact, by the proof. Now as to whethe rth ecomplaint in Canada, as filed in Canada, was sufficient in Canada, and before the Courts of Canada, it seems to me to be a question or an issue to bedetermined up there; I am only acting on the complaint as filed before me under the statute of the United States. Now that complaint does set out in particularity the offense, taking and carrying away, and the intent to steal, and sets out the statute in particularity which he violated.</p>
<p>    (Further argument)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I will overrule the objection; note an exception.</p>

<p>Q    Where do you live, Mr. Ficklin?</p>
<p>A    I live in Eastern Oregon.</p>
<p>Q    Where were you living on or about the 15th day of November, 1915?</p>
<p>A    I was living in Saskatchewan, Canada.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know the defendant, Fletcher Decker?</p>
<p>A    Yes, mam.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know this man seated opposite you?</p>
<p>A    I know Mr. Decker.</p>
<p>Q    Is that the same Mr. Decker you knew then?</p>
<p>A    Yes, mam.</p>
<p>Q    Did you have any difficulties up there with Mr. Decker about that time?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to that.</p>
<p>Q    Have any transactions at all with Mr. Decker about that time?</p>
<p>A    Not in 1915, but a little later we had some dealings.</p>
<p>Q    Was any flax belongign to you taken from you?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to that, Your Honor.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: That is proper, I think.</p>
<p>A    I lost some flax out of one of my graineries in the fall of 1915.</p>
<p>Q    Just state the circumstances and all the facts you know regarding that.</p>
<p>A    Well, in the fall of 1915, I had two farms, and I was living on one, and the farm where the flax was located I was not living on; I threshed some flax early in the fall, some in October, and I was living on the other farm, I was not at this farm where the flax was for a period of time, several weeks, and I wen tou there one afternoon and found some of the flax gone; the window had been broken out, and about half of the flax was missing. I went in town and notified the Mounted Police, and secured around the country for several days to see what I could do to locate it, and the police did not come out at that time, and there was nothing more done; I didnt find any one; I got someof the neighbors to helpme, and looked around, and could not locate anything; there was nothing more done about it for a couple of years; and I kind of had an idea that may be Mr. Decker had taken my flax from different reports, and different ones that told me that seemed to know more about it than I did; tales going around the country that he had taken my flax, and was kind of making fun of it, and different ones came to me and told me if I would go to him and ask him about it that he would--that I could get it out of him; and neighbors came to me and told me they could prove and swear he had taken it; he had told then he had taken it away; I reported it to the police several times, and the police officers had been out there at numerous times, and different officers from Regina, and special men came out there and could not get any evidence; they claimed to me that they were practically sure Mr. Decker had taken it, bu tthey could not get the evidence. So after Mr. Decker had thrashed one fall, when I though he would have some money I went out and broached the subject to him, and asked him about it, and we had an understanding, and he told me that he had taken the flax, or a portion of the flax, and would pay me for it. At first, when I went over there and he didnt know anything about the flax at all, and I told him I had waited long enough, I was tired of fooling with him, and if he did not come through, I had evidence I could prove he did take it, and he better come and settle with me for somethin gnear what I lost in the flax.</p>
<p>Q    Just what did he say to you about taking the flax?</p>
<p>A    Well, I cant remember just exactly as to the very words he used; when I asked him about it he said he didnt know anything at all in regard to it, first, and I told him that I thought he did, and he finally admitted that he had taken a portion of the flax, and claimed that he had been lead into it by different aprties, older ment--I htink that he said older men, or some such statement as that, and he wanted a little time to straighten it--to see other parties and straighten it up, and I told him taht time was no advantage with me, I would give him until a certain time the next day, to straighten up with me for taking that flax, and he came the next day and gave me some money and some grain.</p>
<p>Q    How much did he say he had taken?</p>
<p>A    Well, he told me at that time that he had taken--I cant just remember; he told me at that time that he had taken something--I dont know, I think he claimed at that time that he had taken a load of flax; and at the time when he came to settle with the grain, I had a talk with him; I asked him--I was personally acquainted with him, I said "Fletcher, why are you in this kind of business for; you are a young man?" Well, he told me that he was in debt, and I think that he told me at that time he took all the flax; now I wont say for sure, but I will say that at first he told me that he had only taken a potion of it, and it seems as thought there was others connected with it, any way, he didnt want to--it seems he wanted to settle for it all, and did not want to implicate the other parties.</p>
<p>Q    How many bushels in a load?</p> 
<p>A    I could not say; anywhere from sixty to a hundred, I suppose.</p>
<p>Q    How much did he settle for?</p>
<p>A    Well, he settled for--</p>
<p>Q    What was the money value?</p>
<p>A    He gave me something around between four hundred and fifty and five hundred dollars in money and grain; probably be four hundred and seventy-five or eighty dollars cash--equivalent to that.</p>
<p>Q    And near what post office was your place there?</p>
<p>A    Near the Wiwa Hill Post Office.</p>
<p>Q    And this was the transaction and the crime which complaint was made to the authorities there at Saskatchewan, was it?</p>
<p>A    Yes, mam.</p>

<p>         Cross Examination:</p>

<p>By Mr. BEELER:</p>
<p>Q    Do you swear that Mr. Decker took your flax, did you see him?</p>
<p>A    I didnt see him take it.</p>
<p>Q    Would you say that he took your flax?</p>
<p>A    I will say that he told me he took it.</p>
<p>Q    A part of it, you mean?</p>
<p>A    A portion of it, and I will say further, that when we had the last settlement, as near as I can remember, I asked him--I told him, "Now"--I aske dhim what he was doing; why he was in this business for; he said he had been lead into it by older men; I advised him to go straight, and get out of that kind of business, and I think, as far as I can remember, we had quite a little talk, and we sit down; he brought this load of wheat, and we sat down by the side of the grainery, after we unloaded this wheat, and I talke dto him like I would my brother or anybody, and I advised him to get out of that kind of business and go straight; and I advised him further, if he had trouble with the police in settling this up, they might still want to get any evidence, I was going ahead and settle it up, to get it squared up, and he need not be feared of me, I would not put in any evidence against him; and I think tha the told me at that time that he took it all; now I wont swear to it.</p>
<p>Q    But you told him at the time that you would put in no evidence gainst him if he would pay up the money?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir; I told him if I was called as a witness I would tell the truth; as far as I was concerned I would put in no evidence against him; if I was called against him as a witness in the case I would tell what I knew.</p>
<p>Q    You would not urge prosecution?</p>
<p>A    No; I had urged it for two years.</p>
<p>Q    Before anything was done?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    After you were paid--</p>
<p>A    I was practically through with it.</p>
<p>Q    In other words, the way you felt then, and the way you feel now, you would not go to Canada voluntarily and testify aginst him, would you?</p>
<p>A    No sir.</p>
<p>Q    You are living in Oregon now, are you not?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Been living there for how long?</p>
<p>A    A year ago in February.</p>
<p>Q    A year ago last February?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Man of family?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    If I may ask, what occupation are you engaged int here?</p>
<p>A    At the present time?</p>
<p>Q    Yes.</p>
<p>A    I am running a transfer business</p>
<p>Q    And you propose to reside in Oregon continuously?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir, as far as I know.</p>
<p>Q    Don't intent to go back to Canada?</p>
<p>A    On business.</p>
<p>Q    You intend to go back?</p>
<p>A    I intent to go back on business.</p>
<p>Q    That will be only for a short while?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Was there any statement made as to who this other party was that was implicated in this theft of flax?</p>
<p>A    Not from Mr. Decker; no.</p>
<p>Q    By anybody else?</p>
<p>A    Different rumors around the country.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Objected to as immaterial.</p>
<p>A    Several implicated.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Yes, I think it is probably immaterial.</p>
<p>Q    Was Mr. Robinson?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: I object to that as immaterial.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: The witness testified that there was only one load he accused this man of taking; if there was other flax, we should be permitted to interrogate this witness--</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: There may be some other parties that are guilty, but we are not trying them here.</p>
<p>Q    Robinson was living up there?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Objected to as immaterial.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Sustained.</p>
<p>Q   You know of disputes between the Robinson's and Mr. Decker, dont you?</p>
<p>A    No sir.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Objected to as immaterial.</p>
<p>Q    I mean the Robinson's who have made affidavits here.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: There are lots of Robinson's/</p>
<p>Q    Do you know Cassius M. Clay Robinson?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: I object to that as immaterial.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: This is preliminary.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I will let him answer that.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know Cassius M. Clay Robinson?</p>
<p>A    Not personally acquainted with him; I know him when I see him.</p>
<p>Q    He is a farmer up there?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Been up there in that vicinity near you for severl years?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know Charles Burdette Robinson?</p>
<p>A    I don't know him by the name of Charles; I know a man by the name of Bob Robinson.</p>
<p>Q    Are Bob Robinson and Cassius M. Clay Robinson brothers?</p>
<p>A    Bob and Charley and Cassius--the two I know they are called Bob and Cash.</p>
<p>Q    They are brothers?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Did you ever talkt o these two men during the year from November 1915, up to the time you were settle dfor this flax in 1917?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Did these two men ever tell you that Decker had admitted to them that he had taken this flax?</p>
<p>A    One of the brothers, I cant call the name of which one, told me that he could prove that Mr. Decker had taken the flax; that was my authority for going to Mr. Decker in regard to the flax.</p>
<p>Q    Both of these Robinsons have been in a good many scrapes up there, havent they?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Objected to as immaterial.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Sustained.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I presume I will be allowed an exception to all these rulings?</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Yes.</p>
<p>Q    What time, Mr. Ficklin, in 1917 was it when you had this alleged conversation with Mr. Decker?</p>
<p>A    What time in 1917?</p>
<p>Q    Yes.</p>
<p>A    It was in the fall at harvest time, probably around October; I would not say for sure, but around October.</p>
<p>Q    Of 1917?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    That was three years ago; it will be four years this coming October?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    At the time you learned of this did you make any complaint to any of the authorities up there?</p>
<p>A    At the time the flax was taken?</p>
<p>Q    No, at the time you had this conversation with him?</p>
<p>A    Did I make a complaint to the authorities?</p>
<p>Q    Yes.</p>
<p>A    In regard to the flax?</p>
<p>Q    Yes.</p>
<p>A    No sir.</p>
<p>Q    Had he ever been arrested after this discussion of yours?</p>
<p>A    Not that I know of.</p>
<p>    Miss KOMITZ: Objected to as immaterial.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know when he was arrested?</p>
<p>A    For this?</p>
<p>    Miss KOMITZ: Objected to as immaterial anad not proper cross-examination.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Well, may be it has something to do with this proceeding, I dont know.</p>
<p>A    What was the question?</p>
<p>Q    Do you know when he was arrested?</p>
<p>A    I cant tell you the date, or when it was; he was taken into Gravelbourg and arrested, and I believe he was leet out on bail sometime; taht would be after 1917; I cant just figure when it was.</p>
<p>Q    At any rate, you are sure it was after your conversation with him?</p>
<p>A    Oh, yes.</p>
<p>Q    But it was on no complaint of your's?</p>
<p>A    No sir.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know whether any of these Robinson's made this complaint?</p>
<p>A    I don't know.</p>
<p>Q    Did you ever have anything to do with bringing about these proceeding here?</p>
<p>A    No sir.</p>

<p>         RE-DIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>By Miss KOLMITZ:</p>
<p>Q    Where is Gravelbourg you jsut mentioned?</p>
<p>A    Gravelbourg, Saskatchewan, just southwest of Moose Jaw of the C. &amp; R.</p>
<p>Q    In Canada?</p>
<p>A    Yes, mam.</p>
<p>Q    And he was arrested there and admitted to bail?</p>
<p>A    Yes, mam.</p>
<p>Q    As far as you know, do you know what happened after that?</p>
<p>A    No, mam.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know how he happened to be down there at that time?</p>
<p>A    No, mam.</p>

<p>Claude N. Frelleu<!--signed--></p>

<p>Subscribed and sword to before me this 26th day of August, 1921.</p>

<p>R. W. McClelland<!--signed--></p>
<p>U. S. Commissioner</p>
<p><!--Seal, written and circled--></p>


<p>THOMAS WATERS,   Being first duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>         DIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>By Miss KOLMITZ:</p>
<p>Q    What is your full name?</p>
<p>A    Thomas Waters.</p>
<p>Q    What is your occupation?</p>
<p>A    Deputy United States Marshal.</p>
<p>Q    And did you arrest this defendant?</p>
<p>A    I did.</p>
<p>Q    About when?</p>
<p>A    3rd day of August.</p>
<p>Q    1921?</p>
<p>A    1921.</p>
<p>Q    And state what conversation you had with the defendant after seeing him?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Objected to on the ground that the question is entirely too broad.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Conversation he had with the defendant at the time he was arrested?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Yes.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: You mean on this charge?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: On this charge, yes sir.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: If it was on this charge--</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Objection overruled.</p>
<p>A    We went to Ronald Station, Mr. Burke of the Department of Justice, and I, and we had a telegram from the Department of Justice at Portland, directing us to arrest this party; we went out there and asked him if he was Mr. Decker, he sai dhe was, and we told him we had a telegram advising us to arrest him; he at first--</p>
<p>Q    (By The Commissioner) Was that before or after he was put under arrest that he made the statement to you?</p>
<p>A    Why, I havenet said he made any statement yet; I was telling how we came out there to arrest him.</p>
<p>Q    Had you arrested him before you talked with him?</p>
<p>A    As soon as he admitted his identity we tol dhim we had a telegram from Portland advising us to arrest him.</p>
<p>Q    And pu thim under arrest?</p>
<p>A    Put him under arrest, yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    (By Mr. Beeler) This conversation was had after?</p>
<p>A    After.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: We object to all this.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Let him say a little further how it came up.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: He already testified this conversation came up after he arrested him.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: What is the difference.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Question of identity.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: He admitted his identity, and then was informed he was put under arrest, after admitting his identity, after being put under arrest; as I understand him, he had a certain conversation with the officer; I believe that would be improper.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: I will ask him this question. If you will let the witness proceed I think you will fin dit is not objectionable.</p>
<p>Q    Did he ask you on what charge he was being arrested?</p>
<p>A    He did.</p>
<p>Q    What did you say to him?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to that, Your Honor.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Nothing objectionable about that.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The officer just testified that the told him he had a warrant for his arrest, and put him under arrest.</p>
<p>Q    (By The Commissioner) Did you inform him at that time that any statement he made to you might be used against him?</p>
<p>A    I did not.</p>
<p>Q    (By Miss Kolmitz) I will ask you this: Did you ask him any questions, or were you confined to answering his questions?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to that, Your Honor, as immaterial.</p>
<p>Q    Were you answering the defendant's question, or were you trying to get information from  him?</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: My understanding of the rule is--</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: We will show this information that the defendant gave to the marshal was volunteered information; was a voluntary statement which the Marshal was not the least bit interested in, and it was forced on him. He went out there, as he said, to arrest the man; he aske dhim his name, put him under arrest; the man volunteered the information, and tried to get some information from the Marshal; there is nothing improper about it; if there was any duress, of course, it would be objectionable.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The very fact he was under arrest was duress.</p>
<p>    Mr.<!--error in document?--> KOLMITZ: Not when the Marshall<!--error in document?--> was not asking for information.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: As I understand the rule, it is the duty of the officer to inform the defendant if he makes any admissions the statements may be used against him, then if with that information he makes statements they are voluntary admissions against his interests.</p>
<p>    Mr. Beeler: There is no question but what that is the law; we object to this character of questions.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: Just a question of identity, if Your Honor please.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Well, it is admitted that was made before he was put under arrest.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: The name Decker, but there may be a million Decker's.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The witness testified that he defendant told him that he was the man named in this warrant, which he had for his arrest, and thereupon he arrested him.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: I did not so gather it.</p>
<p>Q    (By The Commissioner) That was the testimony, Mr. Waters?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    (By Miss Kolmitz) Did you tell him you had a warrant for his arrest?</p>
<p>A    I told him I had a telegram from Portland advising us to arrest him.</p>
<p>Q    (By Mr. Hyland) Giving his full name?</p>
<p>A    Fletcher Decker; the first thing I asked him when I went up to him, if he was Fletcher Decker.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to any voluntary statement of the witness; <del>in</del>not responsive to any question.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: He stated very fully, he went and aske dhim if his name was Fletcher Decker, he asid it was; he tol dhim he had a warrant for his arrest, told him what for; and he admitted that he was--</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: No, that is what I want to ask him.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Already testified; ask it over again; that was what I understood him to say.</p>
<p>Q    Did the defendant ask you why he was being arrested?</p>
<p>A    He did.</p>
<p>Q    What did you answer?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to that, what the officer might have told him.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: That is all right; it was the duty of the office either to read the warrant or tel him what the content of it was.</p>
<p>Q    What did you tell him?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: He alrady testified he didn't have any warrant, merely had a telegram.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: He has a right to advise a man what he is being arrested for.</p>
<p>Q    What did you tel him?</p>
<p>A    I told him I did not know what the charge was, merely a telegram from Portland; I presumed it was some offense he had committed in Oregon.</p>
<p>Q    What did the defendant answer to that?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to that, what the defendant may have answered to that; certainly it would not be proper; no showing he had been advised that any statement he might make might be used against him.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: He had a right to tell him he was not the man.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: That was after the arrest then?</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: No, he told him he had a telegraphic warrant for his arrest; the defendan twanted to know what for, and the officer told him he though it was for some offense in Oregon; it was the duty of the officer when he arrests a man under a warrant, either to read the warrant or tell him the contents of it, then make the arrest; if the defendant wants to make a statment, it is teh duty of the officer to tel him whatever statment he makes may be used against him, and with that information, if the defendant then makes a statement if is a voluntary statement against his interests; but up to that time it is the duty of the officer to tell him he has a warrant, and what the warrant charges--what he is being arrested for; all that part of the conversation is admissible evidence. Now we have gotten that far; is there anything else?</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: He said he thought it was a crime in Oregon; that was what the officer said.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Yes.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: The question was, waht, if anything, did the defendant say at that time he answered any questions the officer asked him.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: That was what I was objecting to, because he had been put under arrest, but he had not been tol dby th eofficer that anything he might say would be used against him, jsut as Your Honor ruled.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: He had not been put under arrest yet; he asid before he was arrested that he told him he thought it was for an offense committed in Oregon.</p>
<p>    THE WITNESS: He was under arrest at that time.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: He told him he was under arrest; the witness has tol dus that.</p>
<p>    THE WITNESS: As soon as he admitted his identity I read the telegram to him.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I think that is all there is to it.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: That is all we cared about, was the question of identity--the other statements corroborating his identity, that was all. If Mr. Beeler can find anything objectionable about that matter he shold satisfy the Court, and, furthermore, satisfy himself.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: His identity has already been proven by the witness Ficklin.</p>
<p>    Miss. KOLMITZ. That is all we care to ask this witness.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: No Questions.</p>

<p>Marcus Waters<!--signed--></p>

<p>Subscribed and sword to before me this 27th day of August, 1921.</p>

<p>R. W. McClelland<!--signed--></p>
<p>U. S. Commissioner</p>
<p><!--Seal, written and circled--></p>

<p>--------------</p>


<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: We offer in evidence the original record from Canada certified to by the proper authorities.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Probably it had better be marked for identification.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Mark it Exhibit "A".</p>
<p>    (Original record marked "Exhibit "A" offered by the Government)</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: That has merely been offered. I want to object to certain documents. First, I want to object to the warrant dated August 5, 1921; Your Honor will observe there were two warrants issued, one dated June 14th and one August 5, 1921. The record show she was arrested, as Mr. Waters, the last witness, that he arrested him on August 3rd. I apprehend that the purpose and the reason of this warrant to apprehend dated August 5, 1921, was executed--</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: You mean August 4th?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: August 5th here, was executed after this amended petition or complaint, whatever it is called, was executed, but this warrant of August 5th, which is there, and which they are now offering--here is the warrant dated August 5th; there is one warrant dated August 5th, and another warrant dated June 14th, 1921. The defendant was arrested by reason of the warrant of June 14th, because Mr. Waters has just testified that he was arrested on August 3rd, and the record shows that therefore he was arrested two days prior to the issuance of this warrant.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: My warrant reads August 4th, which would be the day after the telegraphic warrant.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: There was a warrant issued here in June; the complaint was made five years ago; this warrant you are talking abou thas never been executed. The warrant of August 5th, there is no official return on it at all, merely a warrant that was issued, and he was arrested under the warrant of the 4th of August.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: He could not have been, Your Honor, because he was arrested on the 3rd day of August, the Marshall has so testified.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The Marshal may have taken him under arrest on the telegraphic warrant, but the formal warrant issued by me was issued on the 4th day of August, and served by the Marshal on the 4th day of August, signed by Thomas Waters, Deputy. Go ahead and make your objection.</p> pg 30

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>