<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0162.084">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ray Raymond v. Territory of Washington. Counsel Statement</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
<name n="Hidalgo, Emily" xml:id="eh ">Emily Hidalgo</name>
<name n="Ham, Bethany" xml:id="brh">Bethany Ham</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0162.084</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ray Raymond v. Territory of Washington. Counsel Statement</title>
<date when="1886-12-15">December 15, 1886</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Eastern Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>Spokane County Government; Clerk, Territorial Case Files, 1879-1889</collection>
<idno>SPO-1886-09; SPO-1886-10</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term>December 1886</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Clement, D. A.</term>
<term>Wycoff, George</term>
<term>Woods, W. J.</term>
<term>McDermott</term>
<term>Donaldson, T.</term>
<term>Finch, James</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Spokane County, Washington</term>
<term>Walla Walla County, Washington</term>
<term>Spokane Falls, Washington</term>
<term>Ogden, Utah</term>
<term>Butte City, Montana</term>
<term>Murray, Idaho</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Raymond, Ray</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Griffitts, Thomas C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Stout, J. Kennedy</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Caton, Nathan T.</persName> 
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Stanford, Frederick</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Fourth Judicial District</orgName>
<placeName>Spokane County, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#lkw">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2021-07" who="#eh">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">
        
<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0162.084"/>

<p>Territory of Washington<lb/>  
of Spokane} ss</p>

<p>In the District Court 4th Judicial District holding
terms at County seat of
Spokane County</p>

<p>Territory of Washington<lb/>
vs. Plaintiff<lb/>
Ray Raymond Defendant</p>

<p>Territory of Washington}<lb/>
County of Spokane} ss </p>

<p>Thomas C. Griffitts, J. Kennedy
Stout, N.T. Caton, and Frederick Stanford
being each individually duly sworn
depose and swear as follows:
That they and each of them are of counsel a
attorney for defendant Ray Raymond in
this cause that said defendant cannot
safely proceed to trial therein at this time
of this court for the following reasons:
The indictment against her was returned
herein December 1, 1886, and the defendants
plea entered of not guilty on Dec. 1, 1886.
That immediately thereafter defendant
counsel made a motion for change of
venue herein and present the same to the
hearing at the earliest time the convenience
of the court and counsel for the Territory
permitted, and said motion was finally 
determined and awarded Dec.
14, 1886, defendant by her counsel immediately 

<pb/>

give in there this return for a continuance.
That the said motion for a change of venue was
made by defendant and her counsel in the utmost 
good faith and they are greatly taken 
by surprise both by the affidavit filed herein
by the territory and on the said motion and at
the <unclear/> of the same and believing
their said motion were taken, they did not
know a motion for a continuance herein
would be necessary until the final determination 
of said motion for a change of
venue. That until the finding and <unclear/>
of the indictment hererin neither affiant nor
defendant knew with what crime defendant
would be accused nor what the issue herein
would be whether she would be accused
of any offense whatsoever or of an offense
insodoing the issue of malice in the killing
of Finch. That at time such indictment
was presented this term of this court had
duly been in sworn and counsel for defendant
had been constant in attendance.
Then now and ever since said indictment
was returned into the court and
defendant counsel herein have been
in about constant attendance
at this court and engaged either in 
the trial of counsel therein or in watching

<pb/>

and waiting for the trial of pending causes
or preparing for the trial of cause still
pending in this court set for trial
and of pursing importance and still
to be tried herein that considerable time
since the finding of said indictment have
been occupied by defendants counsel in
the preparation for and hearing of said
motion for a change of venue and since
its determination in the preparation
of a showing for the continuance; that
in addition to their other habeas as afore
detailed counsel immediately set
about making such preparation
as they could under the circumstances
for the trial of the cause although well
aware they could not fully prepare
thereupon and in fact counsel believes
that the late <del/> date in the term when
this indictment was presented, the
bona fide efforts they had made and the
parts directed in the showing for
change of venue made by them and which is here
referred to as part of the view herein and the continuation
of that case at this <del>cause</del> term of court and the
return of the indictment herein and the great
expense and delay of procuring a jury
herein at this time, with the facts heretofore

<pb/>
<!-- begin SPO-1886-10-->
States in this affidavit would appear to the 
dissention of this court and prevent them 
from being compelled to go to trial 
at this time, that from to the finding 
of the indictment herin defendant and 
affiants had made inquiry concerning 
one George Wycoff who affiants were 
informed lived about 22 miles from 
Spokane Falls and when affiant had 
been informed was in defendants' 
parlor on the night of the killing of 
Finch, and had been reliably informed 
that said Wycoff was temporarily absent 
from his home and from Spokane 
County and about Walla Walla county 
somewhere but just where affiants 
could not learn, that shortly after the 
finding of the indictment – herein 
affiants directed a subpoena to issue herein 
for him, </p>

<p>that they were subsequently informed 
he could not be found and they have only 
learned within two days that he has 
been found and is somewhere in Spokane 
Falls as a witness for the prosecution 
there – said Wycoff is wholly unknown
 to affiant <add>defendant</add> and her counsel by sight even 
and they are unable to say whether or

<pb/>

not he was <del>for</del> in defendant's parlor as 
aforesaid at time of the killing is what he 
<del/> can will swear to 
on said trial, but affiants have heard that he claims
to have been an eye=witness to the shooting. That 
since the finding of this indictment – affiants 
have also learned that the prosecution have 
still another witness by the name of Donalson 
but whose given name is unknown to 
affaints, and who was not a witness upon 
the preliminary examination herein 
for before the fgrand jury and whose 
name is not in the indictment who also 
claims and intends to swear that he was 
present <add> at the time</add> <del>that night</del> of the Killing of Finch 
and was in defendant's parlor at the time 
and that he was an eye=witness to the shooting. 
That whether or not <unclear>Mr</unclear> Donalson was 
present in defendents parlor at the time of the shooting 
of Finch affiants do not know <add> of their own knowledge the have heard of that effect</add> except from his statements, but affiants
allege that – they are informed <del/>
 that if he was present in said 
parlor he occupied a position therein 
which rendered it impossible for him to 
see the occurences leading to and act of 
shooting of Finch, and that the same fact is 
true of the said George Wycoff and that he

<pb/>

if present at all in defendant's parlor at time of said 
killing also occupied a position where 
he could not see any view the of fray 
out of which the killing arose or the act 
of killing. That neither affiants nor
the defendant knew until since the 
finding of this indicment that the 
prosecution had or claimed to have 
such witness and affiants and claimed 
that the prosecution had procured the 
witness Wycoff within the last two 
days. That neither affiants nor defendant
know fully what the prosecution intends 
to prove by said witness in the trial 
of this cause and they are not sufficiently 
acquainted with said witnesses at this time
to be able fully to meet them and guard
agaisnt surprise on the trial of the
current this time <del/> affiants have refer
to the affidavit of defendant herein filed
in support hereof, affiants further allege
that they have used all possibile diligence
to prepare to meet such witnesses since
they became aware that the Territory
had procured there and would offer
their Testimony and have been unable
to do so, 

Affiants further allege as another ground  for this motion;

<pb/>

That one of the grounds of defense which they expect
to maintain on part of defendant in their cause
is that <del>on the time</del> of insanity at the time
of the killing, that defendant is and for many years
has been afflicted with a species of insanity and
mental disorder, <del>which</del> and that the same is
hereditary in her family, and that – at the time
of the killing, of said Finch defendant was
insane and in such mental condition as
to be incapable of committing the crime
with which she is charged in this indictment
That on the trial of this cause affiants expect
to prove by one W. J. Woods of Ogden in
The Territory of Utah, That – he has known
defendant for about 15 years; That – he was
married to defendant 14 years ago and
lived with her 5 or 6 years and by her
had two children; That – at the time she
was his wife and he living with her as such
she was afflicted with the disease of
<add>Emotional and nervous hereditary</add> insanity the same as that with which
she was afflicted at the time of the killing
alleged in the indictment – herein
but the details of what said witness <del/>
will <unclear/> to bearing upon this issues
affiants cannot fully state, but affiants 
expect to prove by him the facts above stated
and the fact that insanity is a hereditary Trait
in defendants family. That one letter received

<pb/>

by one of defendants counsels in the month of July, 1886
with the envelope in which the same was received
is presented herewith marked
A. B. and made part of this affidavit
That since the finding of this indictment 
it has been impossible to procure the attendance
of said witness <add><unclear>words</unclear></add> at this term of this court
is to procure a deposition from him even
if his deposition <del/> would be
proper and admissible but that from
information from and friendly disposition
of said witness towards defendant, and
from the fact that defendant has sufficient
money to pay the expense of said
witness from Ogden aforesaid to Spokane
Falls or the place  of holding this court
and the expense of his attendance
herein, and that she will pay the 
same to procure his attendance
all of which is have stated as facts, affiants
believe and have reasonable grounds
to believe, there they can procure the personal
attendance of said witness at the 
next term of this court for the trial of this
cause –</p>

<p>Affiants further expect to prove and can
prove by said witness word that somewhere
in her sound mind and lucid

<pb/>

intervals defendants is a peaceable, kind=hearted 
woman, exceedingly timid
and cowardly and afraid of assaults or
force of any kind and not in any manner
given to quarreling or the use of firearms,
This testimony is mentioned in view of the 
fact that defendant is charged with
maliciously and purposely killing James
Finch and that is in a fact that said
Finch was at the time of the killing <del>of
Finch</del> with which she is charged a total stranger
to her.</p>

<p>That affiants expect to prove substantially that
same facts as above stating concerning defendants
insanity <add>and peaceable disposition</add> by the <del/> are
William Mc Dermott, who is now a 
resident of Butte City, Montana, that
one of affiants has seen and talked with said
Mc Dermott within the last two months
and is informed by him that he will swear
That defendant is and for many years
has been insane and afflicted with such
mental disorder and that it is hereditery 
in her family; that the said McDermontt
is a brother = in = law of defendant
and has known her long and intimately
and is intimately acquianted with
her family, that when not under the
influence of such disease defendant is

<pb/>

a woman of peaceable character and
kind disposition; that he will attend the
trial at this court at such time as the
same shall take place if he be notified
of the time and the place of the trial: That since
the finding of that indictment affiants
have been unable to communicate with
said Mc Dermott for the reason That
as they are informed and believe he is
traveling somewhere in the mining
regions of Idaho and only temporarily away
from home, That one of affiants N. T.
Caton, saw and conversed with said
McDermott near Murray I. T. about
six weeks ago affiants believe from
these facts that his attendance can be
procured at the next term of this 
court to testify in the trial of this
<del>court</del> cause</p>

<p>That affiants epect to prove by both of said 
above named witnesses that <add>one of <del>Deft</del></add> defendants 
Aunt. <del>was</del> was afflicted with the same species
of insanity and became therefore
hopelessly insane and that other
members of her family have also been
afflicted with insanity.</p>


<p>Affiants expect to prove substantially the
same facts as above alleged by the

<pb/>

members of <del>off</del> defendants family. To-wit two
brothers and one sister, all of whom are
<del>not</del> non-residents of and now absent
from the Territory of Washington but
whose personal attendance within 
court at the trial of this cause affiants
hope to obtain if given time to do so. That
it has been impossible since the finding of
this indictment for counsel to propose
for the trial of this issue on this term of this
court for the reasons stated herein.
<del>and for the just <unclear>reason that</unclear></del></p>

<p>That none of defendants family reside in
the Territory of Washington and affiants'
know of no other witnesses by which
They can prove the facts to which 
either the witness Woods or McDermott
will Testify as above stated, except as to members
of defendants family as above stated
and affiants counsel state in detail
what they can prove by such members
of her family for the reason they have
not sufficiently communicated with
them of and concerning this issue, but
if their case is continued until the
next term of this court affiants allege
it is their purpose to acertain to what
such persons can testify and to
know their testimony and they
<pb/>

believe they since be able to do so.</p>

<p>And affiants say that this <unclear>account</unclear>
is not made for delay, but that
justice may be done.</p>

<p>Thomas C. Griffiths<lb/>
J Kennedy Stout<lb/>
N. T. Caton<lb/>
F Stanford</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to 
before me this 15th day of
December, 1886<lb/>
D A Clement<lb/>
    Clerk
</p>
</div1>
    
</body>


</text>
</TEI>