<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0374.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Jow Mun Fuey v. Luther Weedin. Order to Show Cause</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name> 
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0374.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Jow Mun Fuey v. Luther Weedin. Order to Show Cause</title>
<date when="1922-06-05">January 5, 1922</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1922-01">January 1922</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Weedin, Luther</term>
<term>Cusham, Edward E.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Fuey, Jow Mun</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Weedin, Luther</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Landon, Daniel</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Revell, Thomas P.</persName>
<persName>Faulkner, Judson F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Cushum, Edward E.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-10" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Original</p>

<p>186</p>

<p>United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>


<p>No. 6453</p>
<p>Order to Show Cause</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application 
of Jow Mun Fuey for a Writ of
Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>The above named petitioner having made application to
this court for a Writ of Habeas Corpus addressed to the United
States Commissioner of Immigration Luther Weedin, and to such
persons or agents acting by, through or under him, or in behalf
of the United States Government, in whose custody the petitioner
is shown by his petition to be confined and restrained of his
liberty as alleged in his said petition illegally and unwarranted,
and without power or authority of law and not under virtue of or
by power or authority of the statutes of the United States; and
the court being fully advised in the premises;</p>

<p>IT IS ORDERED That the Commissioner of Immigration in
charge of the Immigration Station and Detention House at Seattle,
or such persons acting under or in behalf of said Commissioner,
or the United States Government, having custody of said Jow Mun
Fuey, show cause before this court at the Court Room in the
Federal Building in the City of Seattle, on the 9th day of 
January, 1922, at 10 o'clock in the forenoon of said day,
why said application should not be granted, and in the mean time
you, the said Commissioner of Immigration Luther Weedin, in
charge of the Immigration and Detention Station at Seattle, Wash-
ington, as well as said persons who are acting under and through
you in behalf of the United States Government, refrain and desist
from deporting said Jow Mun Fuey from said District, or carrying</p>

<pb/>

<p>into effect any warrant or order for his deportation which may
be held by you, or either of you.</p>

<p>IT IS FURTHER ORDERED That a certified copy of this
order shall be served on the United States Commissioner in charge
of the United States Immigration Station at Seattle, or on such
Government official in charge of said Joy mun Fuey as sufficient
authority for the above instruction.</p>

<p>Edward E Cushman</p>
<p>District Judge</p>

<p>The within is a full true and correct
copy of an original writ this day issued.</p>

<p>WITNESS my hand and official
seal this 5 day of June 1922</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk.</p>
<p>By Elm <unclear>Layin</unclear></p>
<p>Deputy.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>