<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Territory of Washington
County of Spokane }ss
In the district court of the Fourth 
Judicial District of the Territory
of Washington holding times as Cheney
in the county of Spokane for the counties
of Spokane Lincoln and Douglas.

Ther territory of Washington 
vs. 
S.P. White } Indictment for murder in second degree
S.P. White whose full jurisdiction cause
is to the grand jusry unknown in assured 
by the grand jusry of the Counties of Spokane
Lincoln and Douglas in said Territory
and the district aforesaid by this indictment
of the crime of murder in the 
second degree committed as follows:
The said S.P. White on the Twenty first 
day of December AD 1884 in the
county of Lincoln in the Territory of 
Washington and the district aforesaid
in and upon one Ames Light Beardon
feloniously wilfully purposefully and by
his malice aforethought did make an
assault and that the said S.P. White a
contained revolving pistol, then and there
charged with gun powder and one leaden
bullet, then and there feloniously 
wilfully purposely and by his malice aforethought
did discharge and shot off to against, and
upon the said Ames Light Beardon;
and that the said S.P. White, with the
leaden bullet aforesaid and by this
pistol aforesaid then and there by the
force of the gun powder aforesaid by
the said S.P. White discharged and shot 
off an aforesaid then ans there feloniously 
wilfully purposely and of his own malice 
aforethought did strike penetrate and 
wound the said Ames Light Beardon in
and upon the left side of the body of the 
said Ames Light Beardon giving to the said
Ames Light Beardon then and there with 
the leaden bullet aforesaid as as afore-
said discharged and shot and of the 
pistol aforesaid by the said S.P. White
in and upon the left side of the body
of the said Ames Light Beardon one mortal
wound of the depth of six inches and
of the breadth of one-quarter of an inch
of which said mortal wound the said
Ames Light Beardon from the said twenty-
first day of December A.D. 1884 until
this twenty second day of the same month of December
A.D. 1884 in the county aforesaid
did languish, and lay inching did
live on which said twenty-third day of 
December A.D. 1884 the said Ames Light
Beardon at the county aforesaid of the 
mortal wound aforesaid died. And 
as the Grand jury aforesaid upon said
oath fo say then the said S.P. White
the said Ames Light Beardon in the manner
and by the means aforesaid feloniously, 
wilfully, purposely and of his malice
aforethought did kill and murder,
against the peace and dignity-of the
Territory of Washington and contrary to 
this form of the statute in such case
make and provided.
Dated at Cheney in the District aforesaid
the 17th day of April A.D. 1885
S.C. Hyde
Prosecuting Attorney

Names of Witnesses <unclear></unclear>
the Grand Jury
H.S. Beardon J.L. Beardon
Charles Prindle H. Portch
A.J. Reeves J Lisle
E.A. Portch Mrs. M.A. Lisle
Frank Beardon</p>
