<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0241.036"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Typed Submission to Court</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>

<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0241.036</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Typed Submission to Court</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1885-07">July 1885</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Albright, Robert</term>
<term>Arnold, Emma</term>
<term>Campbell, Alex</term>
<term>Dolan</term>
<term>Downey, R.M.</term>
<term>Foster</term>
<term>Fulmer, Peter</term>
<term>Lockwood, William M.</term>
<term>Lowe, A.H.</term>
<term>Reich, George</term>
<term>Sherman, E.H.</term>
<term>Smith, Clara</term>
<term>Walker, Charles</term>
<term>Walker, Helen</term>
<term>Walker, M.A.</term>
<term>Whitem</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Port Townsend</term>
<term>Tacoma, Pierce County, Washington Territory</term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Walker, M.A.</persName>
<persName>Walker, Charles</persName>
<persName>Walker, Helen</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Campbell, A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court For The Western District of Washington Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="#sab">transcribed, encoded</change> 
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0241.036"/>

<p>2</p>

<p>some other parties there, amongst them Charles Walker, Mrs. Walker and William Lockwood; in coming up, went to mother's house, on Railroad street, and <unclear></unclear> folks there; went out to <unclear></unclear> on the railroad track, about 10:30 p.m., with my stepfather, Mr. Dolan; went in house after arriving there and sat down; they were dancing; had received an invitation from Walkers to go; met my stepfather and asked him to go; on night in question did not want to go, as I was tired and told my stepfather; he said he had been working hard all day, but had intended to go, and that I might as well go now; went to Walkers for a good time; staid there till about 12:30; it was between that hour and 1 o'clock when we started to leave; all our folks went at the same time; they were Mr. and Mrs. Dolan, my new wife Mrs. Hunter, Miss Arnold, Wm. Lockwood and myself; went down the track and parted at Pacific avenue depot wih Mr. and Mrs. Dolan; Lockwood went with us; he (L.) did not stay at our house very long after reaching it and started for home, as I supposed; did not hear anything at Walker's about Lockwood returning; there is one room in the Walker house, about 12x14 feet; at what time Lockwood left us at our house I could not say; it took us from fifteen to twenty minutes to reach our house. [The house is on E, between Nineteenth and Twenty-first streets.] Reached our house somewhere near 1 o'clock or after. At Walker's we had lemonade and beer; Lockwood drank beer, about three or four glasses I think; he walked straight, and I suppose he was sober; could not say that he was under the influence of iquor; do not think he was drunk; was acquainted with Lockwood; to go from the railroad track to the Walker house, one would turn off on road this side of and near the house, which stands about ten feet from bank of cut; above the house the road is high up on the bank, and it would be difficult to go up; Lockwood has a gray terrier dog; the dog was not with him when he left our house.</p>
<p>Cross-examined: Reached Walker's about 10:30 p.m. on night of 15th; did not look at watch; my stepfather said it was 12:30 a.m. when we left Walker's; Lockwood was there; do not know positively how much he had been drinking; saw him drink three or four times; did not go out of the house with him while there; danced and had a good time till 12:30 a.m.; I live the second house from Lockwood; think it s about a mile from Walker's to where I live; when we reached our house, Lockwood paused only a moment at the door, and then passed on to next yard; didn't see him again till next morning, when he was dead.</p>
<p>Mrs. Hunter sworn: Live in Tacoma; my husband's name is William Hunter; met the Walker's on Wednesday night; it was about 9 o'clock when we got there; there were present Charles Walker, Mrs. Walker, Will Lockwood, Miss Whitton, Mrs. Dolan and my sister, Miss Arnold; there was dancing at the house; M.A. Walker was not present; we left there about 1 a.m.; during the time we were at the house, we had cakes, lemonade and beer; when we went home there were with us the Dolans, Lockwood, my sister, my husband and myself; there was no conversation when we parted, except bidding each other good-night; heard no conversation between Mrs. Walker and Lockwood; Lockwood drank two or three glasses of beer; he was not under the influence of liquor; we went home from there; do not known distance from there to our house, but the time consumed in walking to our house was about fifteen or twenty minutes: Lockwood went with us to house, and went away at once, across the lot next to ours; it was about 1:30 when he left; Lockwood has a dog, but it was not with him that night; did not see Lockwood afterwards; did not see the Walkers again; did not see M.A. Walker at house; understood he was at Port Townsend; heard so from Lockwood; Walker's house is a plain house, with one room 10x10 in size; it was dark</p>
<!-- new column -->
<p>1601 1/2</p>

<p>when we left, the moon was not shining, we had but one lantern to go home by, and Dolan carried the lantern.</p>
<p>Cross-examined: We got to Walker's about thirty minutes before my husband and Mr. Dolan; there was violin music in the house; there was beer in a keg, which was drawn out when wanted; the beer was not in a pail or tub; at 12 o'clock; think we staid nearly three-quarters of an hour afterwards.</p>
<p>Emma J. Arnold sowrn: I reside in San Francisco; for six weeks I have been in Tacoma, stopping at my sister's, Mrs. Hunter, on E street; on Wednesday evening was at Mrs. Walker's: got there about 9 o'clock; my brother-in-law and Mr. Dolan did not reach there until about 9:30; M.A. Walker was not there; it was about 12:45 when we left; heard no conversation on leaving; heard no conversation between Lockwood and Mrs. Walker; it was a very dark night; there was one lantern in our party, carried by Mr. Dolan; went home by way of railroad track; to reach Walker's house, one turns off the track before reaching house; reached home in about thirty minutes; Lockwood did not stop at our house; he was not intoxicated and acted perfectly gentlemanly; did not appear to be under the influence of liquor he went to back gate of the house where he lived; did not see Lockwood's dog at Walker's; noticed the dog was with him on E street.</p>
<p>Cross examined: Beer was drank at Walker's; it was in a keg and was drawn from a faucet.</p>
<p>H. F. McKay sworn: Live in Tacoma; am a policeman; on the morning of JUly 16 I saw a light in direction of depot on Pacific avenue; a man carrying light seemed to be walking fast; went towards light and met Kirkbride, the brakeman; he said a man had ben run over on the track on the grade and asked me to call the coroner; I went up and called the coroner; the coroner wanted to know if it couldn't be postponed until morning, as it would not be possible to get a jury; told the coroner the train men refused to touch the body, and would not come down the track until the coroner had been there, and that he (coroner) had better go, as a jury might be obtained; shortly after started for the scene

with the coroner and a <unclear></unclear> of men; a man named Hank, with a companion, the LEDGER reporter, and I got  there first; it was shortly after 3 a. m., and daylight was beginning to break; Officer Linquist and the coroner arrived soon after; the body was close to the rail and on the inside of it; the head lay towards the south; one foot was on the rail and smashed; the other foot was close to rail and must have been caught by flange and cut or jammed; the face was between the ties; could see one side of face; put my hand on left arm; body was perfectly cold; Kirkbride and Kelly were by the body when I reached there; recognized the man as William Lockwood; did not look at face very closely; there was a cut in back of head, and cut on shoulder; where the body was found there is a cut, and the banks are about ten feet high; to go to the Walker house a person would turn off at road this side fo house; the bank is pretty steep.</p>
<p>Cross-examined: The body was about 200-300 feet above road crossing; when Kirkbride reached me I was on Pacific avenue below Thirteenth; went after coroner at once and Kirkbride went back; went ot LEDGER office and told the reporter that a man had been run over by engine on the track up the grade; the reporter said he would go with me; went back to coroner's office the latter had got up and dressed, and on coming down all of us went out together; noticed blood in the ear of body; bloud not flowing freely.</p>
<!-- new column -->
<p>H. B. Lockwood sworn: Live in Tacoma on E street, near Nineteenth; have resided here for two months; am a brother to deceased, William M. Lockwood; am acquainted with defendants; became acquainted with them soon after reaching <unclear></unclear> on Wednesday evening I was coming from Port Townsend;  M.A. Walker was with me; we were on the steamer Olympian; thought we got into Tacoma about 10:30 p. m. of Wednesday night; it might have been later; from the boat I went home; left Walker at Nineteenth street to go up  E street; left boat with Walker; we walked up; stopped to get a drink of water at a grocery store on Pacific avenue; had no conversation with Walker worth mentioning; bid each other goodnight at Nineteenth street, Walker taking the main road ast the site of the Weiler house; think it was about 11 o'clock when we arted; we were walking fast in coming up; saw Walker no more after that; I went home; heard of my brother's death the next morning at 3:30 o'clock; could not tell who called me; my brother and I got up and <unclear></unclear> down to the place where <unclear></unclear> body lay; saw the coroner, McKay, Walkers at <unclear></unclear> how long my brother had been <unclear></unclear>with Walkers; one night, on the 8th of July last, my brother William came home, to my room, woke me up and said the Walker <unclear></unclear> were after him; <unclear></unclear> he was much excited; he wanted to know where my revolver was; sent him to the <unclear></unclear> where I kept the revolver in a drawn then undressed and went to bed; he <unclear></unclear> "if they come, say I am in bed;" went out into kitchen, but saw no one; he told me that he had been walking up the track with <unclear></unclear>. Walker when he saw the Walker <unclear></unclear> coming down the track; Mrs. Walker told him to go to one side, and she would meet her brothers; he did as she said; then he saw them going after him; the next morning he said he did not want to see the Walkers until he had received a letter from Mrs. Walker, so he would know what story she had told; my brother was in sound health, and had no organic disease; did not see him on that night; my brother was between 29 and 30 years of age, weighed about 150 pounds, and was of medium build.</p>
<p>Cross-examined: When I left Walker it was close on to 11 o'clock; at the time my brother told me about his trouble with the Walker he was very much excited; he has <unclear></unclear> intoxicated once or twice since <unclear></unclear> have been here; we went to <unclear></unclear> Port Townsend together, but not to play together; did not play there for the same person; went down on the Wildwood and returned to Tacoma on Olympian; went down on last Tuesday and returned on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dr. Wintermute sworn: Reside in Tacoma; am a hysician and coroner of this county; was called on Thursday morning about 8 o'clock to get up and go out to look at the body of a man which had been run over on the track; reached the place after 3 o'clock; found the body of a man laying between the rails; on the inner side of one rai; one arm was cut off: one foot was cut off, the other foot was crushed; the head lay between the ties, so that his face was only partially visible; there was a vertical cut in the forehead, above the bridge of the nose; the skin of forehead wound "as broken; the man was dead: had been for some time; rigor mortis had set in; position of the head was down; the right arm was over the track; the left foot was on top of rail and laying over the rail;and the right leg was inside of rail; turned the Lady over, put it on <unclear></unclear> and look in to the depot; held on inquest at 9 o'clock that morning; have filed the papers with Judge Campbell; Dr. Reich made a postmortem examination of body on night of 17th to 18th of July: was with him;</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>

