<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>R. M. HOPKINS, a witness called on behalf of the petitioner, after being duly sworn testified as follows:</p>

<p>Q. [Gilman] Mr. Hopkins you reside at Seattle?</p>

<p>A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know the petitioner in this case, Mrs. <del></del>McKay? A. Yes sir</p>

<p>Q. How long have you known her? A. Since December 1883.</p>

<p>Q. In 1883 and 1884 did you hold any official position? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. What was it? A. Deputy United States marshal.</p>

<p>Q. Did you ever have occasion to arrest the petitioner?</p>

<p>Mr. Ronald: We object to that as not the best evidence: it is immaterial and incompetent.</p>

<p>The COURT: It is the best kind of evidence if he knows the fact he can state.</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: We except.</p>

<p>The COURT: Exception allowed.</p>

<p>Q. Did you have occasion to arrest the defendant?</p>

<p>A. I did.</p>

<p>Q. For what?</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: We object.</p>

<p>The COURT: Objection overruled, and exception allowed.</p>

<p>A. Disposing of spiritous liquors to Indians.</p>

<p>Q. Now, where did you arrest her? A. I arrested her in King County, about eight or nine miles this side of Tacoma.</p>

<p>Q. Where was she living then, what kind of a place? A. At that time she was in a cabin on the beach.</p>

<p>Q. I wish you would detail to the Court Mr. Hopkins the circumstances of that arrest, what you saw at that time.</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: We object for the same reason, irrelevant and immaterial.</p>

<p>The COURT: Objection overruled; exception allowed.</p>

<p>A. I had a United States warrant for her. I also had a warrant for a man at the same time --</p>

<p>The COURT: You are not asked for that. You are asked to state the details of the arrest, what you saw and the situation of affairs</p>

<p>A. Wll, I first saw her in the morning, fornoon, on the beach near the cabin. I kept away from the house until night. I went there I think between six and seven in the evening. It was after supper I know. I had one man go to oone end of the house and I went to the other, and the third man in the boat, and knocked

<fw>[Hopkins, D-EX. <gap></gap> 7. <gap></gap> 76--60.</fw>

<pb...></pb...>

at the door. Some one asked who was there. I did not tell who I was or what I was. I told him I wanted to come in. He would not let me in. It was a man's voice that answered me. He would not let me in. I talked to him three or four minutes---</p>

<p>RONALD: I object to what the man said.</p>

<p>Q. Was it in her presence? A. It was in her hearing. Finally I asked him if there was not a woman in the house. He said no.. I said I went to see for myself. Still he did not open the door. Then I dont know whether I told him what I wanted but I gave him to understand if he did not open the door I would make an entrance. With that he opened the door partly. I pressed in past him. The cabin was dark. I lighted a match, although there was fire in the cabin I could not see around. I lighted a match and I heard some one's voice. It was this Mrs. McKay.</p>

<p>Q. Where was she at that time A. She was lying down on a bed on the floor.</p>

<p>Q. How many rooms were there in the cabin? A. Only one. That was the room I was in.</p>

<p>Q. Did this man come out of that room? A. Yes ssir.</p>

<p>Q. Now, I will ask you to describe that man, Mr. Hopkins, tell who he was?</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: We object to that.</p>

<p>The COURT: Objection overruled and exception allowed..</p>

<p>A. He was what is commonly called Dago.</p>

<p>Q. What is he, white or black? A. Black.</p>

<p>Q. Where is he? A. This morning?</p>

<p>Q. Has he not been in attendance upon court all forenoon? A. I saw him during the fornoon.</p>

<p>Q. Where was he? A. On one of the benches in the court room.</p>

<p>Q. How long, if you know, had this man and woman been living there together in that one roomed cabin? A. I dont know other than that evening.</p>

<p>Q. Did you find anything in the cabin Mr. Hopkins?</p>

<p>Mr. Ronald: We object.</p>

<p>The COURT: Objection overruled, and exception allowed.</p>

<p>Q. If so waht? A. I found there personal effects, like house-keeping.</p>

<p>Q. Anything else? A. Keg of beer and some whiskey.</p>

<gap></gap>

<fw>[Hopkins, D-EX. <gap></gap> 8- <gap></gap> 76--66.</fw>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>CROSS-EXAMINATION</p>

<p>Q. [Ronald] That was in 1883? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. You dont know annything about how this woman has been living since her husband has been gone, in the last three years? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Did you know her husband was gone to Scotland, and she was not living with him any more? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You dont know how this woman has been getting along <del></del> for the last few years? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. She may be the most industrious and honest woman you ever saw? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. For all you know? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You say she may not? A. She was not.</p>

<p>Q. You nknow all about her in the last three years? A. At that time you said.</p>

<p>Q. I say since that time.</p>

<p>A. I dont know anything about her since that time.</p>

<p>REDIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>Q. [[Gilman] Describe more accurately and particularly that man you seen here?</p>

<p>A. He is a large man, both tall and heavy.</p>

<p>Q. Portly? A. Yer. I think his hair is a little curly.</p>

<p>Q. He is black is he? A. Yes sir</p>

<p>RONALD: We will move to strike out all the testimony concerning any person s living in that house other than the woman.</p>

<p>The COURT: objection overruled and exception noted.</p>

<p>-----0-----</p>

<fw>[Hopkins, RD-EX. <gap></gap> 9. <gap></gap> 76--69.</fw>

