<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0181.040">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Seventy-six Hindus v. Seattle Department of Immigration. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-10">October 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT
OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>2532</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE UNLAWFUL 
DETENTION OF SEVENTY-SIX 
HINDOO ALIENS.</p>
<p>) ) )</p>
<p>PETITION FOR WRIT 
OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>
<p>TO THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT, IN AND FOR THE
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON:</p>
<p>The petition of Moola Singh, Talok Singh, Dalip Singh, Bhagwan
Singh, Pala Singh, Ala Singh, Biahsn Singh, Rulia 
Singh, Kishan Singh, Harijan Singh, Arjan Singh, Hire Singh, 
Bhag Singh, Amarao Singh, Duvan Singh, Puran Singh, Nuarang
Singh, Dalip Singh, Vir Singh, Ratan Singh, Nama Singh,
Bishan Singh, Bishan Singh, Rem Singh, Baboo Singh, Bhagat
Singh, Thakar Singh, Variam Singh, Harnam Singh, 
Gurdit Singh, Kishan Singh, Gurbakhoh Singh, Khazan 
Singh, Paren Singh, Milkha Singh, Narnam Singh, Munshi
Singh, Varian Singh, Sham Singh, Kakoo Singh, 
Basant Singh, Pooran Singh, Sher Singh, Santa Singh, 
Harnam Singh, Munshi Singh, Parem Singh, Partap Singh, 
Naurang Singh, Farzona Ali, Ahas Ali, Bahadar Shah, 
Mir Ahdylla, Nizam Din, Sultan Ali, Bagh Ali, Niaz 
Mohd, Rahmat Alla, Nayat Kahn, Amir Rhan, Amir Khan, 
Mohd Alam, Isay Khan, Amarat Khan, Sanday Khan, Shali 
Khar Khan, Namdar Khan, Gulam Modh, Sanday Khan, Baggn
Khan, Umar Den, Ali But, Hanz Mohd, Chiragh Din, Madda
Din, Ibrahim Din, Ismail Din, Rahmat Ali, Noor Khan, 
and Ishar Singh, respectfully shows;</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>That your petitioners are former residents of
the Philippine Islands and are at this time unlawfully
<pb></pb>
detained by the immigration authorities at the immigration
station, Seattle, Washington.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>That you petitioners were lawfully admitted
at a regular immigration port of entry, Manila, Philippine
Islands; were duly examined by an immigration 
board and duly examined by medical officers of the United 
States government, and passed by said immigration officials
at the said city of Manila, as being fit and proper
persons to land in the territory held and controled
by the United States government, and being strong and
healthy enough and free from disease, to be entitled
to pass the medical officers of the said immigration
department. Said immigrants were duly landed and lives
from varying periods from several months to several 
years in the city of Manila, and in the Philippine
Islands, with the knowledge of the United States 
government.</p>
<p>III.</p>
<p>That you petitioners are now imprisoned and 
restrained of their liberty and detained by color of the 
authority of the United States in the custody of the
Commissioner of Immigration, Seattle, Washington, at the
immigration detention house in said city.</p>
<p>IV.</p>
<p>That the sole claim or authority, by virtue 
of which the said commissioner of immigration has 
restrained and detains your petitioners is a certain
warrant of arrest based upon Section 20 of the Act of 
February 20, 1907, as amended by the Acts of March 26,
1910 and March 4, 1913, which warrant was issued contrary
to law and without any foundation in law, and which 
even cites to be a fact that the aliens entered the 
United States in violation of law, which is not true, 
and of which faact, no proof has ever been offered. The
other facts set out in said warrant or unlawful issue
are untrue and not a cintilla of evidence has been 
introduced or presented to the Secretary or his assistant, 
who has ordered the aliens deported.</p>
<p>V.</p>
<p>That the aliens and your petitioners represent
that they were not given a fair and impartial
hearing, as is contemplated by law. That the immigration
officals and inspectors were biased and prejudiced, 
which facts can be shown by affidavits or viva 
voce testimony, if they are given permission to be heard
by this honorable court. That the government sent certain
testimony to Washington, which your petitioners
have been given no opportunity to answer. That new testimony
can be produced showing that it would be an absolute
impossibility for these men to become public 
charges, and showing that there never has been a time
since their landing on the soil of the United States
when they were even likely to become public charges.
These petitioners have had their constitutional gaurantee
denied them, and the entire proceeding from the landing
of the petitioners on the Steamship Minnesota, has 
<pb></pb>
been a proceeding conducted not in accordance with law.
That the authority so called, exercised by the commissioner
of immigration, Seattle, the comissioner general of 
immigration and the secretary of labor, have not been
fairly exercised, in justice, or in accordance with law; 
said officials have not acted within the jurisdiction 
conferred upon them or in accordance with the provision 
of the act affecting such cases. The government has
contended that these men violated some law on entering, 
which is not true, and there has never been any evidence
before any of the government officials showing any
violation of law, but there is much evidence showing
a proper landing, the inspection and examination of the
aliens, in accordance with law. No evidence showing the
condition of the aliens when they were examined the
first time in Manila, has been produced. The aliens, 
having once been examined, in accordance with law, and
passed, the second attempted examination is improper, 
and not in accordance with law, and in direct violation
of the Act of February 20, 1907, as amended. The allegation
was made by the government, that these men 
unlawfully entered the United States, but this fact was
not proven and is not true. That your petitioners are
not alien immigrants, within the meaning of the Act,
having entered under a previous proper examination at
Manila. Your petitioners produced evidence which was
not met by the government, which positively proves
that the government's contention was untrue.</p>
<p>VI.</p>
<p>That the issuing of the warrant, the holding
<pb></pb>
of the examination by the by the immigration board at Seattle
and on the Steamship Minnesota, the decision of the board
at Seattle, and the decision of the Secretary of Labor, 
or his representative in denying the rights of your
petitioners to land at Seattle, was all contrary to law
and in direct violation of the Act of February 20, 1907,
as amended.</p>
<p>VII.</p>
<p>That there was an abuse of authority on the part
of the immigration board, and the commissioner of 
immigration at Seattle and the Secretary of Labor, or
his representative at Washington, in denying your 
petitioners the right to land at Seattle, as there is
absolutely no evidence upon which to base a decision</p>
<p>VIII.</p>
<p>That your petitioners' imprisonment, restraint and 
detention are in violation of their rights, privleges,
and immunities, under the constitution and laws of 
the United States for the following reasons;</p> 
<p>First; That your petitioners had once been
duly examined and passed and could not lawfully be
again examined, in accordance with law.</p>
<p>Second; The issuing of the warrant was contrary
to law, and especially contracy to the act of
February 20, 1907, as amended by the Act of March 4,
1913, for the reason that your petitioners had never
become charges and had showed no liklihood of becoming
charges, but on the other hand having affirmatively shown
that there was no liklihood of their ever becoming charges.</p> 
<pb></pb>
<p>That these men were examined at Manila under authority 
of the act of February 20, 1907, and if so, that examination
was final and the second examination at Seattle
improper, unless the government saw fit to arrest these
men under authority of Section 20 of said act, which
section makes the entire proceeding illegal and improper, 
as appears on the face of said section as the
wording of that section is mandatory and does not deal
in possibilities which the government is contending for.</p>
<p>IX.</p>
<p>That there was no evidence before the Immigration
Board, the Commissioner of the Secretary, upon
which to base the ruling of the board in rejecting the
petitioners, and in requesting warrants, or the secretary,
in ordering the aliens deported.</p>
<p>X.</p>
<p>The aliens resided, some of them as long as two
years in the Philippine Islands and never became public
charges or showed any liklihood of becoming charges, 
and as they were taken in custody immediately upon arrival
of the vessel, and as they have been detained ever since
their arrival, it cannot be said that they have become
charges, as they have been in custody ever since leaving 
Manila, and they have never had an opportunity to show
the fallact of the government's position.</p>
<p>XI.</p>
<p>In the case of the other aliens who came over
with these petitioners, an alleged rehearing was granted, 
which was not rehearing at all, as the aliens were not
permitted to be represented by friends or counsel, and
<pb></pb>
were not permitted to cross examine witnesses or to have 
any of the other privileges usual in these cases, and
although those other aliens had taken an appeal, without
giving proper consideration or accordance with law
to those appeals, a medical examination was had and the 
appeal in those cases ignored. The aliens have been
denied the privilege of seeing their friends and relatives,
even within the bounds of reasonable restrictions,
as can be shown by competent testimony.</p>
<p>XII.</p>
<p>The aliens have been housed together in a
place only large enough for a third of their number
and in a place where the cubical air space is only a
third or fourth what it should be in keeping with
healthful and sanitary conditions. The second examination
of these men was improper as the Secretary, in a
similar case ruled less than a year ago that men who
had been once examined in Manila were not subject to 
reexamination in this country. The government has ruled
that the Great Northern Steamship Company should in this
case be relieved of deporting these aliens back to the 
place of embarkation, and that the government would defer
this expense, showing the government's admission of their
own error in once admitting the aliens and now again
attempting to re-examine, as, in accordance with the Act
of February 20, 1907, the Steamship Company should defer
the expenses of the deportation.</p>
<p>XIII.</p> 
<p>The Act of February 20th, 1907, provides that
the headtax of Four Dollars ($4.00) for every alien entering
<pb></pb>
the United States shall be collected. These men 
paid this head-tax when they were examined in Manila, and
were not compelled to pay the same on their arrival in 
Seattle, this provision and the law indicating that the
men are supposed to pay this fee but once, and by inference
they are not supposed to be examined more than once.
The Act itself specifically provides that it is 
to apply to and regulate the immigration of aliens into
the United States.</p>
<p>Section Six (6) of the Act of February 20th, 
provides that this Section was not applied to the 
states or territories, the District of Columbia, or
places subject to the jurisdiction of the United
States.</p>
<p>By referring to Section Twelve (12) and the
last ten lines thereof, it will be noted that aliens 
coming from points in the United States are treated 
differently from those coming from foreign ports.</p>
<p>Section Thirty-three (33) provides that for 
the purpose of the Act above quoted the word "United
States" shall be construed to mean the United States 
and any waters, territory or other place subject to
the jurisdiction thereof, except the Isthmian Canal only.</p>
<p>XIV.</p>
<p>It will be noted by referring to page twenty-eight
(28) of the Regulation of July 1, 1907, paragraph 
"G" thereof, that the aliens who have come from 
contiguous territory in the United States, namely from
Manila, are subjected to different disposition than those 
<pb></pb>
who have come from a foreign port.</p>
<p>XV.</p>
<p>It will be noted that this case makes the
present cases very strong, indeed, from the alien 
standpoint, as the present cases do not come within the 
confines of this decision or of numerous other decisions,
which hold the same as this one. The cases holding
that the government must show that the men have become
public charges within a year, and in absence of such 
a showing, they having been under the flag for a year
throws the presumption against the government in that
they have not become charges, and therefore, the 
probability is not only very remote, but becomes almost
an impossibility. This I believe would be the holding
of the Supreme Court, if we appealed and took the matter
before the Circuit Court or that tribunal.</p>
<p>XVI.</p>
<p>Sub-division 4 of Rule 14, simply a 
ruling of the department, provides that the failure
to present a certificate shall be deemed presumptive
evidence that an examination has not occured. That
presumption is only a presumption, however, and when the
men testify under oath that they were examined and passed, 
and the government does not meet that definite
testimony, than the presumption falls and their testimony
under oath stands inasmuch as they can be 
punished for false swearing.</p>
<p>XVII</p>
<p>The Commissioner of Immigration is threatening unless
restrained to deport these petitioners on authority of
warrants which were improperly issued and have no basis in law.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>XVIII.</p>
<p>That three of the aliens, Moola Singh, Ram Singh, and 
Ali Bux held certificates showing that they had been examined
in Manila, but lost the same, either in boarding 
the boat or on the boat coming from Manila. That Boggu
Khan had a certificate and lost the same coming from
Manila, but by reason of the fact that he was not asked
the question, did not testify in his examination of this
fact, and can not be only prove conclusively, but the
government's records in Manila in this case as in the
other three will show this to be a fact and it can be 
proven to competent testimony.</p>
<p>IX.</p>
<p>That a copy of the warrants is not attached hereto
for the reason that the same is entransit and to save
the government's time and by agreement with the United
States Immigration officals, this order is asked on
the strength of a telegram received from a J.B. Densmore, 
acting Secretary of Labor, advising that warrants were
being mailed for the return of seventy-three persons, whose
names are not definitely known.</p>
<p>XX.</p>
<p>That the warrants issued are fatally defective 
in that they do not comply with law and in particular do
not comply with the Act of February 20, 1907 as amended.</p>
<p>XXI.</p>
<p>That the aliens are not amenable to the law
which is the basis for the issuance of these warrants.</p>
<p>XXII.</p>
<p>That the petitioners have had no hearing on the 
ground on which the exclusion is based.</p>
<p>XXIII.</p>
<p>That the Secretary of Labor, rendering the 
decisions in these cases, has violated the law, and 
particularly the Act of February 20, 1907 as amended by the
Acts of March 26, 1910 and March 4, 1913.</p>
<p>XXXIV.</p>
<p>This honorable court has jurisdiction for the
reason that there is a question of law involved, whether
the aliens herein are amenable to the Act of February 20, 
1907, as the aliens are herein claiming that they are not
within the inhibition of the statutes.</p>
<p>XXV.</p>
<p>In some of the cases the petitioners had resided
in the territory of the United States for more than
one year and therefore the government was barred from
proceeding in these cases.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>WHEREFORE your petitioners pray that a writ of 
habeas corpus directing the immigration officals to 
bring the said alien petitioners in court and to show
cause of their detention, or for an order to show cause 
directing the immigration officals to appear in court
on a day certain to answer the petition herein filed, 
and to show cause why the said petitioners should not
be discharged and no longer held.</p>
<p>Your petitioners further pray that they may be
discharged from custody and released as being improperly 
held, and for such other and further relief as to the
court may seem just and proper.</p>
<p>HINDOO ALIENS,</p>
<p>BY Herbert W. Meyers
Attorney for aliens and petitioners.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>