<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>No. 3384</p>

<p>Territory of New Mexico County of Bernalillo In the District Court</p>

<p>In Re, Petition of Juan Rey Abeita for writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Disposed of</p>

<p>Filed in my Office. JUL 5 1897. Chas L. Kunh, Clerk.</p>

<p>Collin Matthew, Attys for Petitioner.</p>

<pb/>

<p>In the District Court of the Second Judicial District sitting within and for the County of Bernalillo for
       the trial of causes arising under the laws of the territory of New Mexico.</p>

<p>To the honorable William D. Lee, Associate Justice of the Supreme Court of the territory of New Mexico
       and Judge of the second Judicial District Court thereof.</p>

<p>Your petitioner Juan Rey Abeita, a citizen of the United States being a citizen commonly known and called
       as Pueblo Indian, and a resident of the court of Bernalillo and territory of New Mexico complaining respectfully
       represents unto your honor that he is the father of three childen whose names and ages are as follows, to-wit
       Louis Abeita aged 14 yers, Vicente Abeita aged 12 years and Antonio Abeita aged 7 years and as such father
       he is entitled to possess on, custody and care of each and all of said children, the same being minors.</p>

<p>Your petitioner further shows that the said minor children are restrained of their liberty by one William B. Creager,
       superintendent of an Indian school maintained by the government of the United States and are kept and confined
       by the said William B. Creager as such superintendent at a place in said county of Bernalillo and North of the city
       of Albuquerque called and known as the government Indian school.</p>

<p>Your petitioner further shows that the said minor children are so restrained and confined against the will and consent
       of your petitioner, their father, and that they are not so restrained and confined by virtue of any process, judgment, decree
       of any competent tribunal or by virtue of any execution issued upon any such judgment or decree.</p>

<p>Your petitioner shows unto your honor that heretofore to-wit; on or about the first day of September A.D.1889 he as the father
       of said children did at the solicitation and request of the said William B. Creager, acting as such superintendent, place the said
       Louis and Vicente</p>

<pb/>

<p>In the custody and care of the said William B. Creager for the purpose of having them attend the said school and receive instuction
       therein, the said children to be at all times and especially during the period known as vacation or holidy subject to recall by your
       petitioner in no sense relinquishing his right as parent over either or any of said children.</p>

<p>Your petitioner shows unto your honor that he has this day made demand upon the said William B. Creager for the return to him by
       the said William B. Creager of the said children which demand is by the said Creager as said superindependent refused and denied,
       the said Creager, falsely pretending as petitioner verily believes that he has a right by reason of his being the said superintendent to
       the care, custody and control of the said children.</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner says that the said detention and restraint is illegal in that it is against the will and consent of petioner as the
       father of the said children and in direct denial an contravention of his rights as such father.</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that your honor cause to be issued the writ of habes corpus to restore and return to the custody of petioner
       the said Louis Abeita, Vicente Abeita and Anotonio Abeita so unlawfully by the said W.B. Creager superintendent as afore-said restrained
       and detained as aforesaid.</p>

<p>Juan Rey Abeita</p>

<p>Territory of New Mexico
       County of Bernalillo

       Juan Rey Abeita of lawful age being duly sworn says that he has heard read the foregoing petition and that the matters and things therein
       stated so far as they are stated of his own knowledge are true and so far as stated on information and belief he believes it to be true.

       Subscribed and sworn to before me this 5 day of July A.D. 1892.</p>

<p>N. C. Collie
       Notary Public</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>