<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0233.011"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Sam Plastino v. Henry M. White. Exhibit C</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0233.011</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Sam Plastino v. Henry M. White. Exhibit B.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1912-01-26">January 26, 1912</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1912-01"></date>January 1912</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>T.M. Fisher</term>
<term>C.E. Keagy</term>
<term>Sam Plastino</term>
<term>Joseph Plastino</term>
<term>Mike Plastino</term>
<term>Goldie Cardiff</term>
<term>Ethel Richards</term>
<term>Helen Barto</term>
<term>Grace Howard</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term> 
<term>Maione, Italy</term>
<term>New York, New York</term>
<term>Spokane, Washington</term>
<term>Greenwood, Canada</term>
<term>Marcus, Washington</term>
<term>San Francisco, California</term><!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sam Plastino</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known --> 
<persName>Adam Beeler</persName>
<persName>John J. Sullivan</persName>
<persName>Jospeh M. Glasgow</persName>
<persName>John King</persName>
<persName>Tolman</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Clay Allen</persName>
<persName>Albert Moodie</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022" who="AS">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0233.011"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>Exhibit C</p>
<p>Tacoma, Wash., January 26, 1912.</p> 
<p>T.M. Fisher,
Immigrant Inspector.</p> 
<p>C.E. Keagy,
Immigrant Inspector, Recorder.</p> 
<p>In the matter of the arrest of
PLASTINO, Sam,</p> 
<p>The above named party was informed that he was arrested under and
by virtue of Department warrant 53259/150, dated January 12,1912, issued
by the Acting Secretary of Commerce and Labor, in that he entered the United
States in violation of the act of Congress approved Feb.20,1907, amended by the
Act approved March 26, 1910, to wit: That the said alien is unlawfully within
the United States in that he has been found receiving,sharing in or deriving
benefit from the earnings of a prostitute or prostitutes.; that this hearing
is for the purpose of giving him an ample opportunity to show cause why he should
not be deported to the country whence he came in conformity with law.</p>
<p>Copy of warrant referred to attached, exhibit A.</p> 
<p>Alien sworn, testified:</p> 
<p>Inspector: What is your name?</p> 
<p>Alien: Sam Plastino.</p>
<p>Q Your age? A 25 years.</p>
<p>Q Where were you born? A Maione, Italy.</p>
<p>Q When did you leave Italy? A 1897 or 1898 and I came to the United States
landing at New York from a steamer--I forget its name-- I think it was a
French line.</p> 
<p>Q Did you come to the U.S. under the name Sam Plastino? 
A Yes, as second class, my father cmae with me named Mike Plastino.
We went away from New York right away to Spokane, Washington. That was my
destination; I was 11 or 12 years old; we went to my brother Joe at Spokane.</p>
<p>Q Have you been out of the United States since that time?
A Yes, in Canada 7 or 6 years ago to Greenwood, Canada, for several months.</p> 
<p>Q Where did you cross the line?
A Marcus, Washington.</p>
<p>Q Were you examined by the immigration officers at that place? A
A I don't remember.</p> 
<p><del>Q Were you examined by the immigration officers at that place></del></p> 
<p>Q Where is your father now? A In Spokane, he has been in this country 30 yrs.</p> 
<p>Q Of what country is he a citizen? 
A I don't know.</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>Q What is his address in Spokane?
A 222 Second Avenue.</p> 
<p>Q Did you ever take out final citizen papers in this country?
A I don't know; I have taken out papers in this country?
I took out my first paper in Spokane, about 6 or 7 months ago; the papers
are at the Clerk's office in the Federal Building. They were the only papers
I ever took out.</p> 
<p>Q Did you ever vote in this country A No.</p> 
<p>Q What country do you consider yourself a subject of? A United States.</p> 
<p>Q You haven't your full papers have you? A I think it is not necessary.</p> 
<p>Q Were you ever married? A No.</p> 
<p>Q You were convicted Dec. 7, 1911, on the charge of having transported Goldie
Cardiff from Seattle to San Francisco for the purposes of prostitution?
A Yes.</p> 
<p>Q You have not yet been sentenced? A No.</p> 
<p>You were arrested August 26, 1909, in San Francisco on a charge of vagrancy Police Court Department No.1? A <del>N</del> Yes.</p>
<p>Q You were arrested again June 13, 1910, on the same charge? A y es.</p> 
<p>Q And was on Jan.8,1911? A Yes.</p> 
<p>Q You were arrested in Spokane, Wash.July 31,1907 in company with Grace Howard
and charged with unlawful co-habitation? A Yes.</p> 
<p>Q You were convicted on that charge were you not? A. No.</p>
<p>Q Weren't you convicted and sentenced to 33 days on the Co. jail?
A Yes.</p> 
<p>Q On July 23, 1908, were you not arrested charged with having carnal
knowledge of an imbecile? A Yes. The case was dismissed.</p>
<p>Q Isn't at the present time a five-thousand bond held in this case?
A. No. (The records 3930 of the superior court, Spokane, show that the bond is
still standing)</p> 
<p>Q You were arrested July 22, 1908, charged with rape were you not?
A Yes, the case was changed.</p>
<p>Q On March 27, 1911, in Spokane, you were arrested on the charge of raping
a girl Helen Barto? A. Yes</p> 
<p>Q You were heard before the superior court and the defendant demurred which was
sustained, and the states appealed to the supreme court and the bond is still
in force for $1500? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q You were arrested Sep.19, 1911, and fined $25 and the costs for selling
liquor without a license A Yes.</p>
<p>Q You were arrested on charge of larceny August 14, 1911,? A Yes, I was not
convicted.</p> 
<p>Q On May 12, 1911, you were arrested at Spokane, and charged with rape on a girl
from a telegraphic warrant from San Francisco?
A Yes, the case is still pending and I have up a $5000.00 bond.</p>
<p>Q How long did you live with Goldie Cardiff?
A Never, she was used to come around me and my place and show money.</p>
<p>Q Did you ever receive earnings from her? A No.</p>
<p>Q Did she ever give you money? A No.</p>
<p>Q Do you know Ethel Richards? A Yes. She never lived with me.</p>
<p>Q Did she pose as your wife in Seattle and Spokane? A No.</p>
<p>Q Was she a prostitute? A No.</p>
<p>Q Did you ever receive any of her earnings? A No, I threw away money; I didn't
care for their earnings.</p>
<pb></pb> 
<p>Q Do you know Grace Howard? A Yes. That is the same party.</p>
<p>Q You were living living with another prostitute at Seattle were you not?
A No, I had them in my rooms; when I went out for a good time.</p>
<p>Q What was your business?
A Merchant in Spokane at 322 Main Street; I had a pool room for about one year
me and my brother.</p>
<p>Q What did you have at Seattle?
Q Two restaurants one on 507 Jackson St., Called Plastino's Cafe for about 6
or 7 months; I had a restaurant at the corner 5th and King, Seattle, in a
saloon; I had a lunch counter; it was in the restricted district</p>
<p>Q What did you do in San Francisco? A I had a cigar store 545 Broadway.</p> 
<p>Q That is in the restricted district? A No it is in the Italian town; I had it 
5 or 6 months.</p>
<p>Q What else did you do? A Then I came back home when I got arrested; when
I was arrested I had a pool room and cigar store on Front Street and if I
had no business I attended bar.</p>
<p>Q You heard the testimony of Goldie Cardiff in the court in the trial of your
case in which she testifed she turned money over to you?
A Yes, it wasn't true.</p>
<p>Q Have you anything else you wish to say showing your right to be and
remain in this country?
A I was working here since I was 11 years old.</p> 
<p>Q You have a right to be represented by counsel if you desire?
A If my brother in Spokane will get a lawyer for me, I want a lawyer, if
he will not, I don't care for any.</p> 
<p>Q Then if your brother in Spokane does not see fit to retain a lawyer
for you do you waive your right to be represented by counsel?
A Yes.</p>
<p>Q By your brother you mean Joe Plastino?
A Yes, Sir.</p> 

<p>Foregoing is transcript of testimony taken by me.</p>
<p>(Signed) Charles E. Keagy, 
Immigrant Inspector.</p>
</div1> 
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>