<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0088.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0088.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Type of document</title>
<date when="1887">1887</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1887">1887</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McKay, Alice</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, Della</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020-05" who="#lkw">encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#nl">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Mr. S. J. MURPHEY, a witness called on behalf of the Respondent, after being duly sworn, testified as follows:-</p>

<p>Q. [Gilman] Where do you reside? A. Tacoma.</p>

<p>Q. What is your business? A. Livery man.</p>

<p>Q. Have you during the past year been on the police force in Tacoma? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know the petitioner in this case, Alice McKay? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Where does she live? A. She lives in Tacoma, 4th ward.</p>

<p>Q. What kind of a place does she live in? A. Well, she lives in a house along with Antone.</p>

<p>Q. Who is this man? A. He is Adago. He is here today.</p>

<p>Q. Describe his size? A. He is a large man, about as tall as I am and heavy set.</p>

<p>QQ. Is he <sic>blackx</sic>? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. He has been in the court room to day? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. When you were on the police force did you have any occasion to arrest Mrs. McKay? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. For what? A. Drunkenness.</p>

<p>RONALD: We object to that.</p>

<p>Q. Where did you arrest her? A. Right by her house in the street.</p>

<p>Q. Was she on a publicstreet in a drunken condition? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. When was that? A. That was in June, sometime, sir.</p>

<p>Q. This year? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know <sic>wtat</sic> the character of this Antone is, what his business is?</p>

<p>RONALD: We object.</p>

<p>The COURT: You may answer. Exception allowed.</p>

<p>A. He is a gambler.</p>

<p>Q. Have you ever at any other time seen Mrs. McKay drunk? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. How often have you seen her drunk? A. Oh, I have seen her drunk off and on for the last 14 years.</p>

<p>Q. Where? A. Well, in Tacoma, ten years in Tacoma, I have known her before.</p>

<p>Q. On the public streets.</p>

<p>A. Yes sir.</p>

<fw>[Murphey, D-EX. <gap/> 10. <gap/> 76--74.</fw>

<pb/>

<p>CROSS-EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>Q. [Ronald] You were discharged from the police force? A. I was not.</p>

<p>Q. She made an affidavit against you did she not? A. She did not..</p>

<p>Q. You dont like her? A. I have not got anything against her? at all.</p>

<p>Q. You have no prejudice against her at all? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You seen her drunk a great many times in the last year? A. I have seen her drunk two or three times <del/></p>

<p>Q. You arrested her before a Justice of the peace? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. What Justice? A. Judge Howes, he is dead.</p>

<p>Q. When did he die? A. He died two or three weeks ago.</p>

<p>Q. You never took her before Justice Senter? or Justice Harris? A. I did not sir.</p>

<p>Q. Why did you not take her before them? A. Well, they were not in the place.</p>

<p>Q. You swear she was drunk? A. I do sir.</p>

<p>Q. You have nothing against her? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You also swear she lives in the house with this Italian Antone? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. You know that? A. I know she lives in the same house.</p>

<p>Q. Under the same roof? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. You are as certain of that as of anything else you have sworn to? A. I am sir.</p>

<p>Q. She is living in a state of adultery with him? A. I dont know anything about that.</p>

<p>Q. How many rooms are there in the house? A. There is two or three rooms</p>

<p>Q. Which one does <sic>anone</sic> use? A. I dont know, sir.</p>

<p>Q. How do you know that he uses either one? A. I know because he lives there.</p>

<p>Q. How do you know that? A. I have been in his house.</p>

<p>Q. Which room does he use in her house? A. I think he uses the back room. There is two rooms in the main part and he has got a bed room in the back part.</p>

<p>Q. You arrested her by her <sic>hsuse</sic>? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. What were you doing in her house? A. I was in there with her when she got the money to pay her fine.</p>

<p>Q. In his room? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. You did not associate with him yourself? A. Well, I dont associate himh him, no sir..</p>

<fw>[Murphey, C-EX. <gap/> 11. <gap/> t76--80.</fw>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>