<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0178.022.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Mac Fock v. State of Washington. In the Matter of the Application of Mac Fock for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0178.022</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Mac Fock v. State of Washington. In the Matter of the Application of Mac Fock for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1913">1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-08">August 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Mac Fock</term>
<term>Ellis DeBruler</term>
<term>L. Frank Brown</term>
<term>Victor M. Place</term>
<term>Phillip Tindal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Republic of China</term>
<term>Port of Seattle</term>
<term>United States</term>
<term>Washington</term>
<term>Boston</term>
<term>County of King</term>
<term>Western District of Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Mac Fock</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>State of Washington</persName>
<persName>Ellis DeBruler</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Victor Place</persName>
<persName>L. Frank Brown</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Earl B. Brockway</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
<persName>Edward Cushman</persName>
</person>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#AS">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of MAC FOCK 
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>:::</p>
<p>No. 2500.</p>
<p>Now comes the petitioner, through the undersigned Counsel, 
and answering the return to the Writ of Habeas Corpus heretofore
granted herein, and particularly the affirmative return to said 
Writ, found on pages III and IV, alleges:</p>
<p>I</p>
<p>That he denies each and every allegation contained on 
page 3 of said affirmative return to said Writ, except that he.,
the said Ellis DeBruler, as Commissioner of Immigration aforesaid, 
holds the said Mac Fock under an order of deportation to 
the Republic of China, from which he came to the United States, 
arriving at the Port of Seattle on the Steamship Ixion on the 
14th day of April, 1913; that said Mac Fock, upon his arrival 
on said port of Seattle, applied for admission into the United 
States as a returning native born American of Chinese descent, 
and that there upon a hearing was had before the respondent as
Commissioner of Immigration, upon evidence both oral and documentary, 
duly offered in said matter, and that said documentary 
evidence includes a certain certificate then in the possesion 
of the said Mac Fock, the original of which constitutes a part 
of the original record of the hearing of said Mac Fock before 
the Bureau of Immigration and the Department of Labor. </p>
<p>AND FOR A FURTHER AFFIRMATIVE REPLY to said affirmative 
return to said Writ, your petitioner alleges:</p>
<p>I</p>
<p>That for fifteen (15) years, your petitioner remained 
in the United States, living in various Eastern cities, after 
obtaining the decree of the United States Commissioner set forth 
<pb></pb>
in his petition herein. That early in the year 1900, he returned 
to China via the port of Seattle, and previous to his departure, 
presented his certificate of discharge to the local immigration 
commissioner, asking for a pre-investigation of his status. The 
local commissioner at that time communicated with the Department 
in Boston as to the genuineness of the petitioner's discharge, 
and was informed by the Department of Boston that said discharge 
was genuine, and that your petitioner was the rightful holder
thereof, all of which may be verified by a letter from the Boston 
Department under date of April 30, which is on file in this 
case. That during the month of April of the present year, the 
petitioner returned to this country via the Port of Seattle, and 
on March 22, was examined by the local inspectors. That under the 
rules and regulations of the immigration department, and particularly 
rule 4 and 24, the officer conducts a private examination 
with on the witnesses present whom he may designate; that 
this petitioner had no Counsel, and no one to warn him or tell 
him what his rights in the premises were, and under said rule, 
even if he had been able to procure one, his Counsel is only 
permitted to look at the testimony, but to take no part in the
proceedings; that no provision was made for summoning witnesses 
from a distance, or for taking depositions, and he was tried in 
a way that in law and fact amounted to force and duress and abuse 
of discretion on the part of the immigration department, particularly 
in view of the decision of the United States Commissioner
heretofore set forth in the petition herein, and take through 
a star chamber proceeding of the most un-American sort, and 
never warned that by speaking frankly and fairly to the Immigration
officers, he was possibly depriving himself of his constitutional 
rights, and that all said rules and regulations of 
said Department are calculated to amount to confessions from an 
immigrant and to compel him against his will to make statements
which in fact are not true, which was the case of this petitioner 
and this petitioner is informed and believes and so states the
<pb></pb>
fact to be, that all oral testimony, including the statement of 
this petitioner, under them, as alleged in the affirmative 
return of the respondent, that he was born in China, is evidence 
that should not and cannot in a Writ of Habeas Corpus proceeding, 
be used against him, but only the record evidence, according 
to the constitution of the United States in such case made 
and provided.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner prays to be dismissed as 
in his original petitioner set forth. </p>
<p>L. Frank Brown</p>
<p>Victor M. Place</p>
<p>Attorneys for Petitioner.</p>
<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON
COUNTY OF K I N G</p>
<p>}}} ss</p> 
<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>:: ss</p>
<p>L. Frank Brown, being duly sworn on oath, deposes 
and says: that he is one of the Counsel in this cause, duly 
authorized to act for the petitioner, and is familiar with the 
facts, and that to the best of his knowledge, information and 
belief, the facts herein stated are true.</p>
<p>L. Frank Brown</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 21st day of August, 1913.</p>
<p>Phillip Tindall</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>