<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0116.013"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Moses Keokuk v. Albert Wiley. Letter from Attorney Defendants</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0116.013</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Moses Keokuk v. Albert Wiley. Letter from Attorney Defendants</title>
<date when="1868-11-23">November 23, 1868</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1870-05">May 1870</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fonte</term>
<term>Keokuk, Moses</term>
<term>Nerisor, Rigg</term>
<term>Wiley, Albert</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Franklin County</term>
<term>Kansas</term>
<term>United States of America</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Keokuk, Moses</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Wiley, Albert</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Christian, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Kingman, Samuel Austin</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Supreme Court</orgName> 
<placeName>Kansas</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020-11" who="#lkw">transcribed, encoded</change>    
<change when="2019" who="#sab">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0116.013"/>

<p>Thereupon the defendant by his counsel filed in said court then and there a motion for a new trial, which said motion was in writing and in the following words viz:</p>

<pb/>

<p>That his exceptions be allowed noted and made a part of the Record of this case which was accordingly done.</p>
<p>The jury after having heard the proofs adduced the arguments of counsel and the charge of the court as above set forth relived to there room under charge of an officer to consider of their verdict. Shall <unclear></unclear> therefore said jury returned their verdict in words and figures as follows to wit: We the jury find for the plaintiff and assess his damages at one Thousand dollars.</p>
<p>A.D. Anderson foreman of jury</p>

<p>Thereupon the defendant by his counsel filed in said court then and these a motion for a new trial, which said motion was in writing and in the following words viz:</p>

<pb/>

<p>Keokuk Chief of the <lb/>
Sac &amp; Fox Indians Plff<lb/>
vs<lb/>
Albert Wiley et al defts }</p>

<p>In the District Court of Douglas County Kansas. Motion for new trial.</p>
<p>And now comes the said Albert Wiley by Riggs Nevison &amp; Foote his attorneys and moves the court to set aside the verdict heretofore rendered in this case and to grant a new trial in this action for the following reasons to wit</p>
<p>1st That the damages given of the jury in this case are excessive.</p>
<p>2 That the verdict of the jury given in this case is not sustained by the evidence nor by sufficient evidence and is against and contrary to the weight of the evidence and is against and contrary to the law of the case.</p>
<p>3 That the proceedings of the court were irregular in the impanelling the jury in this action in this to wit: That in impanelling the jury one Walter

<pb/>

Willis was called as a juror and was challenged by the defendant counsel for cause.</p>
<p>The cause of challenge given and assigned by the defendant counsel being that the said Walter Willis had served once already on a jury as a talesman on the trial of a cause in said court during the term thereof them being holden and the said Walter Willis on being challenged as aforesaid then and there stated in open court that he had so served as a talesman and which fact was also then and there proven by the Record of the Court and admitted by this court and the counsel for the plaintiff. Wherefore the court &amp; proceeding irregular whereby the defendant was injured.</p>
<p>4 That the law used in his charge of the law to the jury in this action.</p>
<p>5 That the court erred is refusing to charge the jury as requested by the defendant counsel.</p>
<p>The court then rendered a judgement

<pb/>

in said action which upon the verdict of said jury which was as follows. It is therefor ordered and adjudged by the court here that the said plaintiff Keokuk do recover of and from the said defendant Albert Wiley the said sum of one thousand dollars his damages assessed aforesaid and that the said defendant pay all costs in and about the said expended taxed at $ <gap/> and hereof lett execution issue</p>
<p>That afterwards to wit: on the 21st day of may AD 1869 and at the same term of court at which said suit was tried as aforesaid said motion for a new trial came for hearing before said court. Whereupon James Christian Esq appeared as attorney for the plaintiff and Riggs Nevison &amp; Foote for the defendant Wiley and was argued by counsel and after hearing the arguments of counsel the court then and there overruled said motion for a new trial to which ruling of the court the said

<pb/>

defendant then and there duly excepted, and on motion of the defendant the court granted to said defendant until the 22d day of June AD 1869 to make and file a <unclear>made</unclear> case for the Supreme Court.</p>

<p>That on the 22d day of June AD 1869 the said parties appeared by their respective attorneys in open Court and by agreement of said plaintiff and defendant by their attorneys the Court then and there extended the time in which the defendant was to make and file a <unclear>made</unclear> case for the Supreme Court to the 2d day of the next term of said Court.</p>
<p>We have examined the above and find the case made correct in every respects.</p>
<p>James Christian<lb/>
Atty for Ptff</p>
<p>Riggs Nevison &amp; Foote<lb/>
Attys for Albert Wiley def</p>

<p>Allowed time having been extended in open court until this date 
Aug 19 1869. Owen A. Bassett<lb/>
Judge</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
