<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>**********</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of MAC FOCK
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>No. 2500
RETURN TO WRIT.</p>
<p>To the Honorable Judge of the United States
District Court for the Western District of Washington:</p>
<p>Comes now Ellis De Bruler, Commissioner of Immigration
 at the Port of Seattle, and makes this return to 
the writ of habeas corpus heretofore issues in the above 
entitled matter and produces in court the body of said 
Mac Fock and alleges as follows:</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>He admits the allegations of paragraphs one and 
two of the petitions for the writ except that he denies 
the charge under which Mac Fock is held is illegal, and 
he denies that he is held for deportation as one already 
in the country but alleges the fact to be that he, the said 
Mac Fock is held as one about to be returned to
China without having been granted admission into the United States.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>He admits the allegation of paragraph three of 
the petition.</p>
<p>III.</p>
<p>He admits the allegations of paragraph four of the</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>petition down to and including the words "United States" 
on line five of the page two of said petition and denies 
each and every other allegation therein contained.</p>
<p>IV.</p>
<p>Answering paragraph five of said petition, he 
admits the allegations of lines 13 to 18 of page 2 
inclusive, except that denies that the said Mac Fock 
has done than to claim to excercise rights of 
citizenship for seventeen years. He denies each and 
every other allegation therein contained except as 
expressly admitted in the affirmative matter hereinafter 
pleaded.</p>
<p>V.</p>
<p>He admits that Mac Fock is the same person referred
to in a certain certificate of Felix W. McGettrick, 
who was the United States Commissioner in the State of 
Vermont on the 12th day of June, 1896, which certficate 
is hereinafter more fully referred to, and he admits 
that said Felix W. McGettrick was at the time duly
qualifed as such United States Commissioner to perform
all acts proper to be performed by such Commissioner,
but he denies that said certificate constitutes any 
order of discharge or that the said Mac Fock holds, or 
has any order of discharge whatsoever. He denes each 
and every other allegation contained in paragraph six 
not expressly admitted in the affirmative matter herein
after pleaded.</p>
<p>For a further affirmative return to said writ, 
Ellis De Bruler alleges:</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>I.</p>
<p>That he, the said Ellis De Bruler, as Commissioner
of Immigration aforesaid, holds the said Mac Fock as an 
alien immigrant under an order of deportation to the 
Republic of China, of which the said Mac Fock is a native 
and citizen and from which he came to the United States 
arriving at the Port of Seattle on the Steamship Ixion
on the 14th day of April, 1913; that the said Mac Fock 
upon his arrival in said Port of Seattle, applied for 
admission into the United States as a returning native 
born American of Chinese descent; that thereupon a 
hearing was had before the respondent of Commissioner
of Immigration upon evidence both oral and documentary, 
duly offered in said matter; that said documentary 
evidence includes a certain alleged certificate then in 
the possession of the said Mac Fock, the original of 
which constitutes a part of the original record of the 
hearing of said Mac Fock before the Bureau of Immigration
of the Department of Labor. Said oral evidence 
includes the statement of the said Mac Fock under oath 
that he was born in China, said statement having been 
made by him twice directly and positively under oath
(see page 1 for certificate and pages 22 and 27 for 
statement as to place of birth); that said certificate 
is the document referred to in the petition for the writ 
of habeas corpus as an order of discharge, and that said 
certificate is neither an order nor an original record 
of judgment before the Commissioner, nor a certified 
or authenticated copy of any record of judgment before
<pb/>
said Commissioner. The full original record of the 
hearing in all matters pertaining thereto before the 
Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, and of the appeal
to the Secretary of Labor, is filed herewith. Said 
original record is the record of the proceedings and on
which said Mac Fock is held. That as appears by said 
record the respondent herein as Commissioner of Immigration
duly considered all evidence offered and thereupon 
the application of the said Mac Fock for admission into 
the United States was denied and he was ordered returned 
to China. That it further appears therefrom that the
said Mac Fock thereupon appealed from said decision of 
said Commissioner to the Secretary of Labor and the said 
Secretary of Labor, after due consideration of said appeal
on the 3rd day of June, 1913, affirmed the decision 
of the said Commissioner of Immigration.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, Respondent asks that the writ of 
habeas corpus herein be discharged and the petition
dismissed.</p>
<p>Ellis De Bruler</p>
<p>Commissioner of Immigration.</p>
<p>E B <unclear>Brakury</unclear></p>
<p>Assistant United States Attorney.</p>
<pb/>
<p>United States of America
Western District of Washington } SS.</p>
<p>Ellis De Bruler, being first duly sworn on oath, 
deposes and says: That he is the Commissioner of Immigration
at the Port of Seattle and respondent in the 
above entitled action; that he has read the foregoing 
return to the writ of habeas corpus herein, knows the 
contents thereof and that the same is true as he verily believes.</p>
<p>Ellis De Bruler</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 2nd
day of July, 1913. <unclear>Edm Lakin</unclear></p>
<p>Deputy Clerk, U.S. District Court. 
Western District of Washington.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>