<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0366.499"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet, start on page 90 of doc -->

<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Decision</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0366.499</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Decision</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1921-09-15">September 15, 1921</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-09"></date>September 1921</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fletcher Decker</term>
<term>Charlotte Kolmitz</term>
<term>Beeler</term>
<term>Sullivan</term>
<term>Robert C. Sanders</term>
<term>Tucker</term>
<term>Hyland</term>
<term>Jeremiah Neterer</term>
<term>Harshberger</term>
<term>Leitch</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Dominion of Canada</term> 
<term>United States of America</term>
<term>Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland</term><!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Fletcher Decker</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>Beeler</persName>
<persName>Sullivan</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Charlotte Kolmitz</persName>
<persName>Robert C. Saunders</persName>
<persName>Tucker</persName>
<persName>Hyland</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName></placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022" who="AS">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0366.499"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION
OF FLETCHER DECKER FOR A WRIT OF
HABEAS CORPUS AND WRIT OF CHRTI-
ORARI.</p> 
<p>No. 6215.</p>
<p>D E C I S I O N.</p>
<p>Filed Sept. 15. 1921.</p> 
<p>Beeler &amp; Sullivan, Attorneys for Petitioner.</p>
<p>Charlotte Kolmitz, Asst. U.S. Atty and Robt. C. Saunders.
U.S. Atty, Attorneys for United States.</p> 
<p>Tucker &amp; Hyland, Attorneys for Dominion of Canada.</p>
<p>NETERER, District Judge, - - - - -</p>
<p>The petitioner seeks release because of illegal
detention predicated upon the fact that the warrant of arrest
is illegal for the reason that, first: "That the complaint
made and filed with said commissioner fails to show that said
commissioner had jurisdiction in matters relating to extradi-
tion and second, that said warrant of arrest fails to recite,
allege or show upon its face that the said commissioner who
issued the same as aforesaid had any right or power or author-
ity in law to <add>issue</add> the same."</p> 
<p>The petitioner bases his application upon In
Re Ferez, 8 Fed. Cas. 4544, In Re Kelley, 25 Fed. 268; In
Re McDonnell, 16 Fed. Cas. 8771; U.S. vs. Stowwell, 27 Fed.
Cas. 16409; Exparte Lane, 6 Fed. 34; Byrne's Fed. Crim.
Proc. 26; 19 Cyc. 68; Bishop's New Crim. Proc. Sec. 187;
1 Cooley on Torta, p. 302; Anderson on Jud. Writs &amp; Proc.
p. 36, 112; Com. vs. Fay, 112 Mass. 235.</p>
<p>In obedience to the writ the United States
Marshal produced the petitioner and stated that he held the
said petitioner pursuant to judgment and commitment of United
States Commissioner, an Extradition Commissioner, and there-
with produced the record of the Commissioner in support of
such judgment and commitment. It appears that complaint was
<pb></pb>
filed before the U.S. Commissioner and warrant issued. The
warrant was served upon the petitioner, who thereupon appeared
before the United States Commissioner and voluntarily entered
into a recognizance in writing for his appearance before the
Commissioner at a fixed date and was released. At the appoint-
ed time he appeared and through his counsel objected to the 
jurisdiction of the commissioner; upon the ground that the
warrant its face does not disclose that the commissioner had
been empowered to hear extradition proceedings and the complaint
was insufficient. An amended complaint was thereupon filed,
and the petitioner demurred to the sufficiency of the complaint
for the reason that the complaint filed before the magistrate
in Canada was insufficient to support extradition. The mat-
ter proceeded to trial; testimony was introduced, and the
Commissioner found the petitioner to be the identical party
charged who committed an offense contrary to the Criminal
Code of Canada, covered by the Extradition Convention between
the United States of America and the Kingdom of Great Britain
and Ireland, and proclaimed by the President of the United 
States of America on the 25th day of March, 1890, supplemental
to the Tenth Article of the treaty concluded between the same
High Contracting Parties on the 9th day of Agust, 1843, and
directed the Marshal to commit the petitioner until such sur-
ender shall be made to the Province of Saskatchewan of the
petitioner. The judgment recites that the said Commissioner
was authorized, commissioned and appointed United States
Commissioner in and for the Western District of Washington
to hear and determine all matters of extradition, and to act
in the matter of the prosecution of fugitives from justice 
<pb></pb>
from foreign countries. In the order of commitment the
recital was omitted.</p>
<p>The cases cited by the petitioner were deter-
mined upon issues deemed vital othen than the fact that the
warrant of arrest failed to show that the Commissioner had
authority in law to issue the same under the Extradition Act.
Judge Brown in Exparte Lane, supra, at 37, said:</p>
<p>"I should be loath, however, to hold that the
proceedings were void upon this account****since I am
by no means certain that the court upon an application
for discharge upon a writ of habeas corpus woul dbe 
bound to take judicial notice of the fact that the Com-
missioner had been appointed for this purpose."</p>
<p>It is not necessary to a decision in this
case to pass upon the question as to whether the court is
bound to judically know that the Commissioner was appointed
for this purpose.</p> 
<p>The Supreme Court in In Re Cortez, Petitioner,
136 U.S. 330, held that if the Commissioner has jurisdiction
of the subject matter and if the person, and the offense
charged is within the terms of the treaty of extradition, and
competent legal evidence is produced upon which to predicate
his conclusion, the conclusion of the Commissioner may not be
reviewed</p>
<p>This Court does judicially know that the Com-
missioner was appointed for this purpose, but his knowledge is
not vital to this issue. Extradition proceedings are not
viewed with that technical nicety as obtains in the final 
trial of a criminal issue. When the petitioner entered into
recognizance without objection and was released from the
operation of the warrant, he waived any irregularity or infor-
mality in the warrant, and after entry into recognizance he
responded by force of the recognizance and not by force of the
warrant. Lancey vs. State, 16 N. E. 504 (Ind.); State vs.
Shedder, 44 Pac. 34 (Kan.); State vs. Goff, 61 Pac. 680 (Kan.)
<pb></pb>
Washburn vs. People, 10 Mich. 372; People vs. Jones, 24
Mich. 214; People vs. Turner, 74 N. W. 519. The fact that
the Commissioner had no right to release the petitioner on
bail is immaterial since the petitioner was in fact released,
nor is it material that the recognizance given was without
force, since the petitioner voluntarily presented himself, and
when the amended complaint was filed before the Commissioner
he voluntarily pleaded thereto, submitting himself to the jur-
isdiction, and thereby waivd any irregularity or informality
in the complaint, cases supra; and the fact that the Commis-
sioner signed the commitment as United States Commissioner,
failing to add as Extradition Commissioner, or to certify such
fact in the commitment, under the record in this cas can only
be held a clerical omission and not vital. State vs. William-
son, 81 N.C. 540.</p> 
<p>The writ is discharged.</p>
<p>Neterer
J U D G E.</p> 
<pb></pb>
<p>FILED IN THE
UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
Western District of Washington,
NORTHERN DIVISION
SEP 15 1921
F.M. Harshberger, Clerk
By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p> 
</div1> 
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>