<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia.</p>
<p>In the Matter of Ching Hing.</p>
<p>Opinion of the Court.</p>
<p>The question raised in this case grows out of a rule issued
by this Court, returnable November 14th, 1914, directed to Louis
F. Post, Assistant Secretary of Labor, requiring him to show cause
why he should not answer certain questions propounded to him by
one Thomas G. Lewis, under a commission to take the testimony of
said Post issued by the Honorable Jeremiah Neterer, Judge of the
District Court of the United States for the Western District of
Washington. The first and material question which the witness
refused to answer was:</p>
<p>"2. Were you on duty at the Department of Labor on each of
the following dates: September 24, 1914, September 25, 1914 and
September 26, 1914?"</p>
<p>The return shows that the witnesses refused to answer on the
following ground:</p>
<p>"That question relates to the internal administration of the
Department, and I regard it as calling for an answer that might
be prejudicial to the public interest. For this reason, I decline
to answer until otherwise instructed by the Secretary of Labor."</p>
<p>The litigation in the United States Court in Washington from
which the commission issued was based on a petition for Habeas
Corpus filed by one Ching Hing, who was detained by the Immigration
officers of the District of Washington under an order of deportation
which had been confirmed on appeal to the Secretary of Labor. His
petition further alleges that his appeal was not heard by the Secretary of
Labor or by the Assistant Secretary of Labor, who were at 
their respective offices in Washington, and that thus he has been
deprived of his liberty without due process of law. It appears
from the brief in behalf of the Commissioner that the order of
exclusion or deportation on appeal was signed by one J.B. Denamore
<pb/>
as "Acting Secretary of Labor."</p>
<p>Section 25, of the Immigration Act of Feburary 20, 1907 (34
Stat. pp. 898, 906) provides in part as follows:</p>
<p>"Provided, that in every case where an alien is excluded from
admission into the United States, under any law or treaty now existing
or hereafter made, the decision of the appropriate immigration
officers, if adverse to the admission of such alien, shall be final
unless reversed on appeal to the Secretary of Commerce and Labor."</p>
<p>Under Rule 5 of the "Regulations Governing Admission of Chinese"
the Chinese applicant if adjudged to be inadmissible, "shall be advised
of his right of appeal to the Secretary of Labor," and (c) "the
notice of appeal shall act as a stay upon the disposal of the applicant
until a final decision is rendered by the Secretary of Labor."</p>
<p>Section 179, R.S. U.S. reads as follows: "In any of the causes
mentioned in the two preceding sections the President may, in
his discretion, authorize and direct the of any other department
or any other officer in either department, whose appointment
is vested in the President, to preform the duties of the vacant
office until a successor is appointed, or sickness or absence of
the incumbent shall cease."</p>
<p>Under this section, the following Executive order (No. 1783)
was issued by the President:</p>
<p>"Pursuant to the authority contained in Section 179 of the
Revised Statutes, I hereby authorize and direct John B. Denamore,
Solicitor of Labor, to perform the duties of
Secretary of Labor, duing the absence of the Secretary of Labor and
the Assistant Secretary of Labor." June 5, 1913.</p>
<p>It will therefore be seen that the question prepounded to the
witness Post, which he declined to answer, goes to the jurisdiction
of the officer who assumed to act as Secretary of Labor in signing
the mandate, or order of exclusion, under which Ching Hing is detained.</p>
<p>As stated by Judge Dooling of the United States District Court
for the Northern District of California in the case of In re Tsuie
Shee, et. al. on October 23, 1914; "The appellants were by law
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
entitled to appeal to the Secretary of Labor, and entitled to have
their appeal heard and determined by him except as above stated, and
the determinatin of their appeal by another not authorized is neither
a fair hearing, nor due process of law."</p>
<p>Briefly stated, the question asked respondent was whether or not 
he was on duty in the Department on three named days. Upon his answer, 
to an extent, depends the liberty of Ching Hing. He declines
to answer because the answer "might be prejudicial to the public
interest." In exactly what manner it might be "prejudicial to the
public interest" for any official to testify as to whether he was,
at a given time, performing the duties charged upon him by law and
for which he was being paid at public expense, when the fact becomes
important in a judicial investigation affecting the liberty of an
individual -- even a Chinaman -- is not apparent on this record. 
In the instant case, upon the record before the Court, it is impossible
to find any prejudice to the public interet in requiring an 
answer to the question propounded.</p>
<p>This case is differentiated from Book v. Covinggrove, 177 U.S.
459, where the information sought of the Collector of Internal Revenue
was prohibited by a regulation of the Secretary of the Treasury
made under authority of law and for the purpose of making more efficient
the Internal Revenue Service, and also from such cases as
Gody v. Pentland, 85 Pa. 22, in which public officials are protected
in their refusal to produce records on grounds of public policy.
Here the question of the public policy involved in the answer sought
is as capable of being decided by the Court as by the Executive official,
because apparently all the information surrounding the alleged
privilege of respondent in before the Court. And upon this information,
the Court is of the opinion that it is the duty of respondent
to answer the question put to him. An analagous situation might be
supposed if the judgment of a court against a citizen was questioned
because of the lack of jurisdiction in the Court to render the judgment,
and the Court should refuse to permit an investigation as to 
the fact of such jurisdiction. If the Department of Labor has acted
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
without authority, and an individual has been denied his liberty as
a result of such action, it is most extraordinary for the Department
to assert that public policy requires a concealment of the truth in
regard to such lack of authority. Indeed, if the Department had
authority to act, and that authority were questioned in a proper
judicial proceeding, by a Court having jurisdiction of the matter, 
it would seem reasonable that the request due by one co-ordinate
branch of the Governmnet to another would discountenance a councealment
of the facts upon which the Department acted.</p>
<p>An order will be signed requiring the respondent to answer.</p>
<ab>Gould
Justice.</ab>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>