<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>Seattle, Washington,
December 20, 1913.</p>
<p> In re cases of 
GREGORI KORNILIN,
MOISEI ALIOSHIN,
IVAN RIABOFF,
JAKOB EPHIMOFF,
PETER KEONLIN,
and
IVAN EMELIN.
EX ss "Tamba Maru,"
December 19, 1913.</p>
<p>At a meeting of the Board of Special Inquiry, covened pursuant to the instructions of the
Commissioner composed of 
Inspectors T.W. Lynch (Chairman)
J.E. Wilkes, and A.T. White.
Stenographer Trent Doser
Interpreter Henry G. Gerome</p>
<p>Held for Special Inquiry by Inspector A.T. White as L.P.C.</p>
<p>Alien sworn, testified as follows: Name is Gregori Kornilin; Russia, Russian; male, aged 28
years; married; reads and writes; farm laborer; last permanent residence, Simbirsk, Krasnoie,
Russia; nearest relative in Russia, father, Ivan, Kornilin, Simbirsk, Krasnoie, Russia; destined 
to Vancouver, Canada, but they would not let me land so I want to go to Portland, Oregon; has
cousin, Pavel Semeionoff, care of Stancheff Brothers. 75 North Third Street Portland, Oregorn;
ticket to Vancoiver via Victoria; $65.00 in gold; paid own passage; never in the United States.</p>
<p>Q  Have you a passport?    A  Yes.  Presents passport dated November 24, 1913, issued at
Valdivastok, Russia, permitting the bearer to leave Russia.
Q  When did you leave your home in Russia?  A  On the 17th of October I left my village.
Q  Where did you start for?   A   I wanted to go to Canada.
Q  Did you buy a ticket direct to Canada from your home?    A  I bought my ticket in Japan.
Q  When you left your home in Russia did these eight other boys who are on this boat leave at the
same tim eiwth you?   A  We all left together from the same village.
Q  All going to Canada  A  All to Canada.
Q  Why didn't you get your passport before you left home?   (Interpreter explains that all passports
are issued at Valdivastok and al applicants appear there for same.)
Q  Have you any relatives in Canada?    A  I have a second cousin.
Q  How did you happen to decide to go to Canada?    A  The reason I wanted to go to Canada was
because we had all received letters from Canada stating that they were doing well there and that we
had better come over here too.
Q  Did you receive any letters from Portland?   A  Same thing.
Q  Did he says he was doing well too and asked you to come over?    A  He says <pb></pb>
times are very good here and said you can get work here easy.
Q  Why did you want to go to Canada instead of the United States?   A  We understood it was nearer
and also that they did not request any money to be shown.
Q  Why did you not land in Canada?  A  We didn't know why; they would not let us.
Q  What did they tell you?  A  No more poeple are allowed to enter because there are too many out of
work here.
Q  How long since you had a letter fro you cousin in Portland?  A  I received a letter about the
first of October.
Q  Have you that letter with you?   A  No.
Q  That man in Portland is a real blood cousin is he?   A  He is my cousin; my father and his father
are brothers.
Q  Have you any work promised you in this country?  A  He says you can get plenty of work.
Q  Did he say he had a position for you - a job?    A  No, he didn't say anything of that sort.
Q  Have you ever been in any charitiable or penal institution?  A  No.
Q  Do you believe in polygamy?  A  No.
Q  Do you belong to any societies?  A  No.
Q  Do you believe in organized government?  A  I beleive in law.
Q  Do you believe that the form of government now existing in Russia is all right?  A  The form of
Government is all right but somehow we have not got enough land.
Q  Do you beleive in killing the officers because they are government officers?   A  No, we could
not do that.
Q  Do you believe in the teachings of the anarchists and annihilationists of Russia?    A  I do not
know what anarchists are.
Q  Did you ever hear of people are banded together and throw bombs and try to kill the officials of
Russia?   A  I have not heard of it and I do not believe it.
Q  What would you do if you were landed in this country?    A  I will get a rooming house and then
look for work.
Q  What kind of work do you think you could do?   A  I can do all the farm work.
Q  You are not familiar with farm work as it is done in this country, are you?  A  I have an idea
that it is about the same.
Q  Have you ever applied for admission to the United States?    A  No.
Q  And the only kind of work you can do is farm labor?  A  No, besides farm labor I understand
common labor too.
Q  What kind of work did you do in Russia other than ordinary farm labor?   A  I worked in the woods
and I worked in the mines at spare times.
Q  What kind of mines?  A  Coal mines.
Q  There is no one else in the United States you know except the man in Portland    A  No, Oh, there
is a lot of others, about twenty friends around Portland, but no relatives.
Q  You don't know their names or addresses?   A  They all work in the same place and they all live
in the same place.
Q  BY INSPECTOR WILKES: Have you got anyone dependent upon you for support in Russia?   A  I have a
wife and two children. They do not have to rely on me for support: my father and brother could
support them if I could not.
Q  What wages do you expect to earn in the United States?   A  I do not know, I think about a couple
dollars a day.
<pb></pb>
Q  Are both of your children in Russia?   A  Yes, sir.
Q  BY INSPECTOR LYNCH: Have you any property in Russia?   A  Yes, I have a home and nine acres of
land. I can get about $800 for it.
Q  Your cousin in Portland, what is his business?   A  He works on a railroad in the woods.
Q  He has no property that you know of?   A  I don't know he only lives here a year.</p>
<p>The applicant is an ignorant peasant of average intelligence and of good physique.</p>
<p>MOISEI ALIOSHIN sworn, testified as follows: Name is Moisei Alioshin; Russia, Russian male, aged
38 years; married; reads and writes; farm laborer; last permanent residence, Simbrisk, Krasnoie,
Russia; nearest realtive in Russia, wife, Axinia, residing at Simbirsk, Krasnoie, Russia; destined to 
Vancouver, Canada, but they would not let me land so I want to go to Portland, Oregon; has no relatives 
in U.S.; ticket, produces order for passage from Victoria to Vancouver; money, $46.00; paid own passage; 
never in the United States.</p>
<p>Q  Have you a passport?  A  Yes, presents passport dated November 24, 1913, issued in
Valdivastok, Russia, permitting the bearer to leave Russia.
Q  When did you leave your home in Krasnoie?    A  About the first of November, 1913.
Q  And you bought a ticket to where?    A  I bought a ticket from my village to Valdivastok and from
there to Yokohama and from there to Vancouver.
Q  Could you not buy a ticket in your home village direct to your destination?  A  No.
Q  Did you leave home with the other eight Russians who are now on this boat?   A  The whole bunch
went together.
Q  Are any of them related to you?  A  No.
Q Why did you start fro Vancouver rather than the United States?    A  Because I have a brother in
Vancouver.
Q  He advised you to come?  A  Yes he advised me.
Q  Did you ever have any letters from any friends in the United States?   A  Yes from Portland
letters saying please come you will be better off here than in the old country.
Q  Why did you not land iat Victoria?   A  I don't know why.
Q  They told you you could not land?    A Yes, they told me so.
Q  Did they say you must go back to Russia or Japan?    A  They told me to go to Seattle. He only
questioned one of us.
Q  Which one?   A Jakob Ephimoff.
Q  Have you any property in Russia?   A  I have a house and some land.
Q  How much land?   A  I have land enough for one soul, nine acres.
Q  Were you able to make a living off your nine acres?   A  No, it is not enough land. It is very
hard to make a living.
Q  How many persons are dependent on you for support?   A  Wife and two sons.
Q  How will they make a living while you are away?   A  I left them enough bread for a year and $100
in cash.
<pb></pb>
Q  What would you do if you were landed?    A  I think I have enough money until I go to work. If
not all i have to do is to send a telegram to my brother in Vancouver and he will send me money.
Q  What kind of work will you do?   A  I can work also in the woods and in gold mines.
Q  Do you believe in polygamy?    A  No.
Q  Have you ever been an inmate of any penal or charitable institution?   A  No.
Q  You are not crippled or deformed in any way?   A  No.
Q  Do you beleive in government by law?   A  Yes.
Q  Do you belong to any societies?   A  All I belong to is the village community.
Q  Do you beleive in the teachings of anarchy?   A  I do not kknow what it means.
Q  Do you not know that in Russia there are certain persons banded together to overthrow the
government and make attempts from time to time to overthrow the officers?   A  During the Japanese
war there was all kinds of murders.
Q  Didn't you ever hear of the anarchists who throw bombs and try to kill Russian officials?    A  I
live in a small village, and I never hear of it. We thought there was something like that in the
cities.</p>
<p>The applicant is of good physique, or average intelligence, but apparently not very well
informed.</p>
<p>IVAN RIABOFF sworn, testified as follows: Name is Ivan Riaboff; Russia. Russian; male, aged 38
years; married; reads and writes; farm laborer; last permanent residence, Krasnoie, Simbirsk,
Russia; nearest relative in Russia, wife Anna, Krasnoie, Simbirak, Russia; destined to Vancouver,
Canada, but they would not let me land so I want to go to Portland, Oregon; has brother-in-law,
Stephen Philatoff, care of Stancheff Brothers, 73 North Third Streek Portland, Oregon; produces
order for passage from Victoria to Vancouver; $50.00; paid own passage; never in the United States.</p>
<p>Q  Have you a passport?   A  Yes, presents passport dated November 24, 1913, issued at
Valdivastok, Russia, permitting the bearer to leave Russia.
Q  When did you leave your home village?    A  About 50 days ago.
Q  These other men left at the same time?   A  All together.
Q  All going to Vancouver?   A  Yes.
Q  You bought a ticket to Valdivastok then to Yokohama and then to Vancouver?   A  Yes, sir.
Q  Have you any relative in Vancouver or Canada?    A  Yes, sir. An uncle - mother's brother - in
Vancouver.
Q  Any relative in the United States?   A  I have my wife's brother.
Q  Have you any property in Russia?   A I have three acres of land and a house and some cattle.
Q  How many people dependent on you for support?    A  I have my wife a 17 year old son and a 15
year old daughter.
Q  How will they make a living now that you have left them?   A  I left them plenty of corn that
they could sell and realise a few hundre dollars besides corn for their own consumption.
<pb></pb>
Q  What would you do if you were landed from this boat?   A  Any kind of labor I can get.
Q  Where would you go?   A  Go to Portland.
Q  Do you believe in polygamy?   A  I do not.
Q  Were you ever an inmate of any charitable or penal institution?   A  No.
Q  Do you believe in organised government?   A  Yes, sir.
Q  Are you affiliated with any anarchist associations?   A  I do not understand what that is.
Q  Do you know that in Russia there are certain associatiosn which are banded together for the
purpose of killing government officials?    A  I have heard of that.
Q  You do not belong to any of them or do not believe in that practice?   A  No.
Q  Are you in good health?   A  Good health.
Q  Not crippled or deformed in any way?   A  No.</p>
<p>The applicant is of average intelligence but not very well informed. he is of good physique.</p>
<p>JAKOB EPHIMOFF sworn, testified as follows: Name is Ivan Riaboff; Russia; Russian; male, aged 34
years; married; reads and writes; farm laborer; last permanent residence, Grasnoie, Simbirak,
Russia; nearest relative in Russia, wife Agaphia, Krasnoie, Simbirsk, Russia; destined to Vancouver,
Canada, but they would not left me land so I want to go to Portland, Oregonl has cousin Alexei
Kalimoff, care of Stancheff Brothers, 73 North Third Street Portland, Oregon; has order for passage
from Victoria to Vancouver; $52.20; paid own passage; never in the United States.</p>
<p>Q  Have you a passport?   A  Yes, presents passport dated November 24 1913, issued in
Valdivastok, Russia, permitting the bearer to leave Russia.
Q  Have you ever applied for admission to the United States before?   A  No.
Q  You left your home village in Russia with these other eight Russians who are now detained?   A  I
left with the rest of them.
Q  And you bought a ticket to Valdivastok, thence to Yokohama, thense to Vancouver, B.C.?   A  Yes,
sir.
Q  Why were you going to Vancouver B.C.?    A  I have a cousin there.
Q  Why did you attempt to go to Canada rather than the United States?   A  Well my relatives wrote
to me from Portland and Vancouver and we thought that that was the nearest and would be less
expense.
Q  Why did you not land at Victoria?    A  They would not let me land.
Q  Why?   A  I don't know why.
Q  What did they tell you?   A  Well, some officer told me that they didn't want any laborers there.
There is nowork here; go to Seattle.
Q  Did he tell you that you would have to go back to Russia?    A  No.
Q  Well did he tell you you could go to Canada from Seattle?    A  No, he did not say so.
Q  Did you have an interpreter in Russian to talk?   A  There was a passenger who spokane Russian.
Q  What kind of work did you follow in Russia?   A  I worked on my land and also worked in the
woods.
<pb></pb>
Q  How much land have you?   A  Sven and a half acres.
Q  How much of a family have you dependent upon you for support?    A  I have a sone 17 years old
and a daughter 17 years old and a wife.
Q  Where did you get the money to come to this country?   A  Sold cattle and worked in the woods and
shold some corn.
Q  You do not know how to do thae kind of work you would be required to do in this country, do you? 
A  I am not afraid of the work.
Q  What reason have you to believe that you could get work?   A  They wrote to us there is plenty of
work here.
Q  When was that?   A  About two months ago?
Q  Who wrote you?   A My cousin in Portland and my cousin in Vancouver.
Q  Did they say they had a job for you?   A  No, he said there was plenty of work you can get.
Q  Have you ever been an inmate of a penal or charitable institution?   A  No.
Q  Do you believe in the teachings of the amarchists?   A  No,
Q  Do you know what I means by anarchy, do you?   A  So far as I am concerned, I don't know what it
is; we don't study it.
Q  Do you know there are people in Russia banded together to make attempts to kill officials because
of their official character?    A  I do not understand that.
Q  Never heard of it?   A  No.
Q  You were refused permission to land in Canada by the Canadian Immigration officers, were you not?
A  Yes.
Q</p>
<p>The applicant is of good physique, good intelligence but has no education and is not very well
informed.</p>
<p>PETER NEONILIN sworn, testified as follows: Name is Peter Neonilin; Russia; Russian; male, aged
34 years; married; reads and writes; farm laborer; last permanent residence, Krasnoie, Simbirsk,
Russia; nearest relative in Russia, wife Helen, Krasnoie, Simbirsk, Russia; destined to go to
Vancouver, Canada, but they would not let me land so I went to go to Portland, Oregon; has cousin
Alexei Kalimoff, care of Stancheff Brothers, 73 North Third Streek Portland, Oregon; has order for
passage from Victoria to Vancouver; $46.00; paid own passage; never in the United States.</p>
<p>Q  Have you a passport?   A  Yes, presents passport dated November 24, 1913, issued at
Valdivastok, Russia, permitting the bearer to leave Russia.
Q  Have you ever applied for admission to the United States before?   A  No.
Q  You are traveling with the other eight Russians who are now on this boat?    A  Yes.
Q  Are you related to any of them?   A  No.
Q  Is Jakob Ephimoff related to you?    A  He is a third cousin.
Q  When you left home you bough a ticket from your village to Valdivastok, thence to Yokohama,
thence to Vancouver, B.C.   A  Yes.
Q  Neither you or any other members of the party, so far as you know, cane out with the intention of
coming to the United States?    A  We all was to go to Canada and if we didn't like it after a while
we would come here.
<pb></pb>
Q  Why did you attempt to go to Canada rather than the United States?   A  They gave us tickets to
Canada.
Q  Didn't you ask for tickets to Canada?    A  I was not going to Canada. They sold me a ticket to
Canada.
Q  You wanted to go to Canada, didn't you?   A  I don't know, I have no relatives there, All I have
is friends there.
Q  You wanted to go there didn't you? You started for there when you left home?   A  We were all
going together.
Q  When you left your home in Russia you started to go to Vancouver, B.C., didn't you?   A  I was
going to Canada.
Q  What was your reason for going to Canada?    A  I was going with my neighbors you know.
Q  Have you any friends or relatives in Canada?   A  Just my neighbors, no relatives.
Q  Did you reeive any letters from any of them>   A  From Portland?
Q  Yes.   A  Yes, I received a letter from Portland.
Q  What did those letters contain in the way of suggestiosn or information?   A  My counsin wrote to
my father and told him that if I wanted to come I could get lots of work, and if he needs it I can
give him a little money until he gets to work.
Q  You are not familiar with the means of work which are open to laborers in this country are you? 
A  I think according to the letters that the work is the same.
Q  Were you ever confined in a charitable or penal institution?   A  No,
Q  Do you belong to any anarchistic societies?   A  No.
Q  You know what they are?   A  This is the first time I hear the word anarchist.
Q  You know what annihilationist means?   A  No.
Q  Do you know that in Russia there are certain people banded together who believe in the killing of
government officials?   A  Never heard of it.
Q  Your cousin in Portland is a common laborer?   A  Yes, sir.
Q  Have you any property in Russia?   A  I have a cow a horse a house and nine acres of land.
Q  How many people dependent upon you for support?   A  Wife and five children.
Q  Where did you get the money to come to Canada - to buy your ticket?   A  I had my own money.
Q  Where did you get it?    A  I sold some cattle andgrain.</p>
<p>The applicant is not very bright, not very well informed, apparently honest in his statements,
and of good physique.</p>
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>