<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0236.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Toguchi v. White, Commissioner of Immigration. Writ Discharged</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0236.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Toguchi v. White, Commissioner of Immigration. Return</title>
<date when="1916">1916</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>United States District Court, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</repository>
<collection>Seattle, Washington</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1916-12">December 1916</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>James Kiefer</term> 
<term>Clay Allen</term> 
<term>Albert Moodie</term> 
<term>Kunijiro Toguchi</term> 
<term>Justice Brewer</term>
<term>Jeremiah Neterer</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Washington, United States</term> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Kunijiro Toguchi</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>James Kiefer</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Clay Allen</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-04" who="#AS">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">
<pb></pb>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON 
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p> 
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION
OF KUNIJIRO TOGUCHI FOR WRIT OF
HABEAS CORPUS } 
No. 3482.  
Filed December 29, 1916.</p>
<p>WRIT DISCHARGED</p> 
<p>James Kiefer, For Petitioner.</p> 
<p>Clay Allen, U.S. District Attorney, 
Albert Moodie, Asst. " " " ) ) For  Government.</p> 
<p>NETERER, District Judge:</p> 
<p>The petitioner is an alien, whose mother resides in
Japan, and whose uncle lives in Detroit, Michigan, where he
is engaged in conducting a Japanese silk and dry goods and
bamboo funiture business.This company has a branch store in
Japan, where petitioner was employed, and for the last three
years was Manager of this branch store. He came to the United
States at the request of his uncle, to take a position in the
Detroit store as a salesman, and as he advances in knowledge
and business methods, to substitute for one of the partners,
so that they may be relieved from time to time. The uncle sent
to petitioner $100.00 to apply on his expenses, and told him
to apply to him for more money on landing, if needed.No salary
was agreed upon to be paid to the petitioner.</p> 
<p>The Board found the petitioner to be twenty-five years of
age,"intelligent, but on the whole made an unfavorable impression
because of his evasiveness and crafty expression*****;that the
alien is coming to the United States in violation of the alien
contract labor provision of the Immigration Act", and rejected
him on that ground, and ordered his deportation to Japan. On
appeal, the secretary of Labor affirmed the finding of the
Board and Commissioner.</p> 
<p>The petitioner contends that he is not within the prohibitory
clause of the Immigration Act. If the petitioner is not within</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>the prohibitory clause of the Immigration Act, the Commissioner
of Immigration has no jurisdiction to detain and deport him by 
erroneously concluding questions of law, Gonzales v. Williams, 
192 U.S. 1, and such act would bring this case to the same status 
as denying a fair hearing, Chin You v. U.S., 206 U.S.8. But
if the alien is within the prohibition of the Immigration Act, 
and the hearing was fairly conducted, the decision of the Sec-
retary of Labor, is binding, Louis v. Frick, 233 U.S. 291. A
court has jurisdiction to determine whether the reasons given by
the Commissioner excluding aliens come within the meaning of the
Immigration Act, Geiow v. Uhl, 239 U. S. 3. The fact that peti-
tioner made an unfavorable impression upon the Board can there-
fore be dismissed without further comment. The only question
for decision is whether the alien comes within the provisions
of the act, supra. The portion of the act which it is claimed
is violated, provides that</p>
<p>"persons***who have been induced or solicited 
to migrate to this country by offers or promises 
of employment or in consequence of agreements****
express or implied to perform labor in this country
of any kind, skilled or unskilled******"</p> 
<p>are excluded.The violation of this act, by its express pro-
visions, is made a crime, and the statute being penal, its
provisions must be strictly construed, U. S. v. Gay, 80 Fed.
254. The act under consideration was brought forward from
the act of Feb. 26, 1885, 23 Stat. 533, which act was intended
to apply only to cheap, unskilled labor, Trinity Church v. U.
S., 143 U. S. 457, in which Mr. Justice Brewer, for the court,
at page 458-459, said:</p> 
<p>"It must be conceded that the act of the cor-
poration is within the letter of this section,
for the relation of the Rector to his church is 
one of service, and implies labor on the one side
with compensation on the other. Not only are the
general words 'labor' and 'service' both used, but
also, as it were to guard against the narrow, inter-
pretation and emphasize the breadth of meaning, to
that is added 'of any kind'".</p>
<p>Specific exemptions are made in the act. The court further</p>
<pb></pb> 
<p>said, pages 464-456:</p>
<p>"It appears also from the petitions and in the 
testimony presented before the committees of Con-
gress that it was this cheap unskilled labor which 
was making the trouble, and influx of which Congress
sought to prevent."</p> 
<p>This act was amended March 3, 1891, 26 Stat. 1084, and in U.
S. v. Laws, 163 U.S. 258, the court held that a contract with
an alien to come to this country and work upon a sugar plantation
in Louisiana as a chemist was not within the act
citing the Holy Trinity Church, supra. The court, at page
266 said:</p> 
<p>"If, by the terms of the original act, the provisions
thereof applied only to unskilled laborerswhose presence
simply tended to degrade American labor, the meaning of
the act as amended by the act of 1891 becomes, if possible,
stil plainer. Now by its very terms it is not intended
to apply to any person belonging to any recognized prof-
ession. We think a chemist would be included in that
class."</p> 
<p>On March 3, 1903, 32 Stat. 1213, the act was further amended.
The Committee on Immigration, H.R. No. 982, 57th Congress, first
session, stated:</p> 
<p>"The general purpose of this bill is to bring
together in one act scattered legislation heretofore
enacted in regard to the immigration of aliens into
the United States******to eliminate any part thereof
which has become obsolete as a result of subsequent
legislation; to amend such portions thereof as have
been found, either as the result of experience in
enforcing the law or by judicial decision, to be in-
adequate to accomplish the purpose intended, and to
add such further provisions as seem to be demanded by
the concensus of enlightened public opinion, besides
such as are rendered necessary because of territorial
acquisitions of the United States beyond its continental
bounds",</p> 
<p>The Senate Report No. 2119, 57th Congress, First Session, stated:</p>
<p>"The necessity for such reenactment is due in
part to the fact that as the result of judicial 
decisions as well as of adminstrative experience,
the efficiancy of such laws to accomplish the evident
purpose of their enactment, has been shown to be
materially lessened since the time of their enactment,
and therefore a new expression of legislative will upon
the subject of Immigration has become desirable."</p>  
<p>In this act was included the words "skilled and unskilled labor",
and Senator Gallinger moved to strike out the words, Congressional
Record, Vol. 36, page 2752, which was agreed to, and the House</p>
<pb></pb> 
<p>conferees concurred in the Senate action, the change in the act
being thet the words "offers", "solicitations" and "promises"
were substituted for the word "contract", it being understood
that the provisions of the bill should be enlarged to meet the
difficulties caused by the decisions of the courts that an en-
forceable contract must exist in order to come within the pro-
visions of the law. There is no suggestion in the report that
it was the intention to enlarge the scope of the bill to include
persons other than those to which the court had held it applic-
able, except the insertion of the words "learned profession"
in the last proviso.</p> 
<p>Following the adoption of the Act of 1903, the Circuit
Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, In re Ellis, 124 Fed.
667, held that aliens imported under contract who are expert
accountants were not members of any recognized learned profes-
sion, within the terms of the exemption, and were therefore not
entitled to enter.</p> 
<p>Contention is made that the intent of Congress mes to
restrict the prohibition to manual laborers and not to apply it to
those engaged in other employment. It mill be noted that the
terms "labor" on service" was included in the Act of 1885. The
same term has been carried through into the Act of 1913. While
the Supreme Court, in Holy Trinity Church, supra, held that the
intention was simply to apply the term to unskilled manual labor, 
and while the terms "skilled" and "unskilled" were stricken from
the act as passed in 1903, the terms were included in the act
of 1907, and on reference to the act of 1913 under which this
petitioner seeks to enter, we find the use of the same expres-
sions. While there is nothing further in the act to indicate
any intent or limitation with relation to these terms, reference
to Section 4 of the Act of March 4, 1913, I think, is conclusive
of the question which is here presented. This section, taken
In connection with the entire act, I think, clarifies the pur-
pose and fixes the intent of the congress without any question.
<pb></pb></p>  
<p>Section 4 provides that,</p>
<p>"It shall be a misdeameanor for any person,
company, partnership or corporation, in any manner
whatsoever to prepay the importation or immi-
gration of any contract laborer or contract laborers
into the United States, unless such contract laborer
or contract laborers are exempted under the terms
of the last two provisos contained in Section 2 of
this act."</p> 
<p>The first proviso is that,</p> 
<p>"that the provisions of this law applicable to
contract labor shall not be held to exclude profes-
sional actors, artists, lecturers, singers, ministers
of any religious denomination, Professors for Colleges
or Seminaries, persons belonging to any recognized
learned profession, or persons employed strictly as
personal or domestive servants."</p> 
<p>By this seetion all persons are excluded who do not come within
the exemption. The provisions are not limited to "labor" or
"service", but are limited expressly by the exemptions. The
petitioner does not bring himself within the exemptions stated:
The fact that no salary is agreed upon is immaterial, as under
the engagement the law would imply reasonable compensation.
There is nothing to indicate that the petitioner was not accorded
a fair trial.</p>
<p>The writ will be discharged and the petitioner remanded
to the custody of the Immigration Commissioner.</p> 
<p>Jeremiah Neterer
JUDGE</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>