<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Territory of Washington} In the District Court
Spokane County}ss 4th Judicial District
holding terms at
county seat of Spokane
County.
Territory of Washington, Plaintiff
vs.
Ray Raymond Defendant
Territory of Washington
County of Spokane}ss
I Charled Aldrich
being first duly sworn onmy oath
say: I am a resident of Spokane 
County, Washington Territory, and a
citizen of said Territory and of the
United States. I live 17 miles outside
of the city of Spokane Falls in said
County and I am frequently in the city of
Spokane Falls I was in the city of Spokane 
Falls at the time of the commissions of the
alleged offense of the killing of James
Finch and the charge therefore brought
against this defendant I was present
at the offense before Justices Peel
and Booge in the city of Spokane
Falls, and heard a portion thereof
and listened on the crowds present
at such examination and the fallowing
excitement and prejudice there
manifested against defendant
and on the facts and among
the people of Spokane Falls and persons 
causing them from other
parts of the county, and I heard
many statements of what purported
to be the facts in the case, and many
expressions of bitter prejudice
against her such as "she ought
to be hung" and the like and that she
ought to be punished. That the officers
ought to lock her up in the city jail and
if she was a decent woman they would
lock her up there; that she had therefore
killed a man, and other expressions of
prejudice and excitement and almost
universal expression of belief in her
guilt and since said time I have heard
bitter expressions from citizens of the
county both in Spokane Falls and in
the part of the county where I live
and have recently heard a prominent
citizen resident in those portion of
the county say she killed the man unnecesarily 
and ought to be punished for
it, and I have heard many other ex-
pressions of belief in her guilt, from
those facts and from conversations
with citizens of the county and of the
knowledge I have of the state of public
and individual faling upon the
subject and against defendant
herein I do not believe the de-
fendant can have a fair trial of this
case in this county of Spokane 
on account of and owing to the
prejudice of the inhabitants of said
county against her.
Chas. Aldrich
Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 4th day of December
Thomas C. Griffitts
Notary Public
Wash. Terr.</p>
