<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0357.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Wu Kao v. Henry M. White. Exhibit B</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0357.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Wu Kao v. Henry M. White. Exhibit B</title>
<date when="1920-09-04">September 4, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-09">September 1920</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Monterey, California</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Kato, Gin</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Reynolds</persName>
<persName>Ballinger</persName>
<persName>Huston</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Exhibit B.</p>

<p>Sep. 4, 1920</p>

<p>Hon. Henry M. White,</p>
<p>Commissioner of Immigration,</p>
<p>Seattle, Wash.</p>

<p>Dear Sir:</p>

<p>We have the honor to request that the following be laid before the Board of Special Inquiry incident to their consideration of the case of Wu Kao, (Ng Go) ex. S.S. Kashima, October 23, 1918, Manifest No. 5-4:</p>

<p>We respectfully submit to your Board of Special Inquiry:</p>

<p>First: That the applicant, Wu Kao entered the United States from the S. S. Kashima at the port of Seattle, almost two years ago, being at that time a Chinese person entitled by treaty and law to exercise all the rights, privileges and immunities enjoyed by the citizens or subjects of the most favored nation:</p>

<p>Second: That since entering the United States, the applicant, Wu Kao, has purchased, acquired and established a valuable interest in a mercantile enterprise located and now doing business at Monterey, California, and for more than one year last past, has exclusively and wholly devoted his time and effort to the conduct of said mercantile enterprise:</p>

<p>Third: That the applicant, Wu Kao, has submitted to the United States Immigration Service the testimony of two persons other than Chinese and other evidence as to the validity of his mercantile holdings in the United States and as to the bona fides of his exclusive occupation in caring for said holdings:</p>

<p>Fourth: That in the case of Chin Fong, No. 506, October term of 1919, decided May 17, 1920, the Supreme Court of the United States held in part as follows:</p>

<p>"The evidence establishes the fact that respondent entered the United States as a merchant and was such at a fixed place of business for at least a year before his departure for China and that his stay in China was intended to be temporary. He hence contends that the Commissioner, as representing the executive branch of the Government, had no authority to determine that his original entry was unlawful. This contention the District court ruled against and the Circuit Court of Appeals ruled in favor of, and constitutes the question in the case. The Circuit Court of Appeals, by Circuit Judge Morrow, passing upon it said: "The Acting Secretary of Labor in approving the decision of the Commissioner of Immigration did so upon the ground that "the original entry of this man (respondent) was obtained by fraud, "but this was not the question submitted to the Commissioner of Immigration or to the Secretary of Labor for decision. The question was not whether the applicant was legally admitted in 1896-1897 or 1906. The question was whether he had been a merchant in the United States at least one year before his departure from the United States in 1912 (Chin Fong v. Backus, 241 U.S. 1-5)", and upon that question, it was decided that, "the evidence was all one way, establishing beyond controversy that all of the facts required by the statutes and the rule of the Department of Labor".</p>

<p>The conclusion was that the Commissioner did not consider this evidence or pass upon it, but deciding that appellee's original entry was fraudulent, ordered his deportation. In other words, it was held that the Commissioner ignored the question presented to him and the evidence pertaining to it, reviewed and reversed the judgment of another time and tribunal, took away the right that had been exercised under it and which gave the assurance that respondent could go to China and return again. The order of deportation was, therefore, declared to be void. For this the Court cited the case of Chin Fong v. Backus, supra, and the various statutes applicable to the exclusion of Chinese persons from entry into the United States."</p>

<p>"The Government appeals against the explicit words of the provision of the exclusion laws, which is, it is said, to keep the country free from undesirable Chinese, or if they fraudulently enter, to expel them, and, it is insisted, that it would be a perfunctory execution of the purpose to let one in who may be immediately put out again. That intention, it is urged, should not be ascribed to the laws, and in emphasis it said, "such a legislative absurdity is unthinkable". But this overlooks the difference in the security of judicial over administrative action to which we have adverted, and which this Court has declared, and in the present case the right that had been adjudged and had been exercised in relieance upon the adjudication.</p>

<p>Judgment affirmed."</p>

<p>Fifth: That on behalf of the applicant, we respectfully submit that this ruling of the Supreme Court makes it untenable, in considering the applicant's status, to ignore or decline to recognize the said applicant's status as a domiciled Chinese merchant of the United States.</p>

<p>It is the applicant contention that he has never been and is not now a Chinese laborer and by every relevant provision of treaty and law he is entitled to all the rights, privileges and immunities enjoyed by the subjects of the most favored nation; that he has submitted proofs of that contention and that if the executive officers of the Government now seek to deprive him of the domicile and business which he has in good faith acquired in the United States they must undertake it before a judicial tribunal.</p>

<p>If such were the decision of the highest court in the land concerning one who was seeking re-entry after an original</p>

<p>2</p>

<pb/>

<p>entry based upon fraud, it certainly would seem reasonable that it should apply to one who has been in the country for almost two years and is now actively engaged herein in the conduct of a going business.</p>

<p>We respectfully ask your careful and fair consideration of the application, earnestly believing that in the light of the foregoing, Mr. Wu Kao is fully entitled to your favorable judgment.</p>

<p>Yours very truly,</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>