<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0116.012"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Moses Keokuk v. Albert Wiley. Letter from Attorney Petitioner</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0116.012</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Moses Keokuk v. Albert Wiley. Letter from Attorney Petitioner</title>
<date when="1868-11-23">November 23, 1868</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1870-05">May 1870</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Alix, Charles E.</term>
<term>Christian, James</term>
<term>Dorwin, Thomas</term>
<term>Garnes, Andrew</term>
<term>Jones, Henry</term>
<term>Keokuk, Moses</term>
<term>Montgomery, William P.</term>
<term>Murphy, Thomas</term>
<term>Shannon, Wilson</term>
<term>Wiley, Albert</term>
<term>Willis, Walter</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Douglas County</term>
<term>Franklin County</term>
<term>Kansas</term>
<term>United States of America</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Keokuk, Moses</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Wiley, Albert</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Christian, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Kingman, Samuel Austin</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Supreme Court</orgName> 
<placeName>Kansas</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020-11" who="#lkw">transcribed, encoded</change>    
<change when="2019" who="#sab">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0116.012"/> 

<p>The defendant here rested his case and after the argument of counsel. the plaintiff counsel asked the court to charge the jury as follows:</p>
<p>1 That the President of the United States the chief officer of the Executive Department of this government cannot control a statute nor dispense with its execution nor can he authorize a person or officer to do what the law forbids.</p>
<p>2 That he cannot take upon himself nor authorize his clerk or secretaries to supersede a law or supply its deficiencies and that all instructions from the executive which are not authorized by law are illegal and void and no inferior officer is bound to obey them and if he does so he acts at his peril.</p>
<p>That when the President has done all the law requires of him he has done not only all that he ought to do but all that he can do as the depositary of the Executive power without transcending

<pb/>

the bounds of his lawful authority and if he does this thoughts unintentionally his order affords no protection to the subordinate agent that he employs.</p>
<p>4 That any public officer obeying the President instructions acts at his peril of those instructions are not warranted by law.</p>
<p>5 That instructions or orders from the heads of departments or <unclear>bureaus</unclear> not in accordance with law do not justify the illegal acts of the inferior agent to whom they are given.</p>
<p>6 That the letter or instructions of Commissioner Mix does not justify the illegal act of agent Wiley. he is answerable for any illegal act.</p>
<p>7 That when ever the elements of fraud, malice, gross negligence
or oppression mingle in the controversy, the case allows the jury
to give what is term exemplary
or vindictive damages.</p>

<p>8 That in cases of torts and actions

<pb/>
<fw>9</fw>

for false imprisonment the jury are the only proper judges of how much the plaintiff ought to recover</p>
<p>The court accordingly charged the jury as the counsel for plaintiff asked, and instructed and charged the jury as above requested by the plaintiff counsel, to which charges and instructions then and there given as aforesaid by the court to the jury the defendant by his counsel then and there duly excepted, and asked that his said exceptions be noted, allowed and made a part of the Records in the case which was accordingly done.</p>
<p>The defendant by his counsel then and there asked the court to charge the jury as follows viz:</p>
<p>The jury in arriving at their verdict can only give a judgement for such damages as the proof could show the plaintiff has actually sustained</p>
<p>Which charge and instructions to

<pb/>

the jury so asked by the counsel for the defendant the court then and there refused to give to the jury in which refused of the court so to charge and instruct the jury the defendant by his counsel then and there duly excepted and asked that his exceptions be allowed, noted and made a part of the Record of the case which was accordingly done. And thereupon the counsel for the defendant then and there asked the court to charge and instruct the jury as follows:</p>
<p>2 The jury is arriving at their verdict can only give a judgment for such damages as the proof shall show the plaintiff was sustained.</p>
<p>Which charge and instructions to the jury so asked by the counsel for the defendant the court then and there refused to give to the jury to which refusal of the court so to charge and instruct the defendant by his counsel then and there duly excepted and asked

<pb/>

that his exceptions be allowed noted and made a part of the Record of this case which was accordingly done.</p>
<p>The jury after having heard the proofs adduced the arguments of counsel and the charge of the court as above set forth retired to their room under charge of an officer to consider of their verdict <unclear/> thereof <unclear></unclear> said jury returned their verdict in words and figures as follows to wit: We the jury find for the plaintiff and assess his damages at one Thousand dollars.</p>
<p>A.D. Anderson foreman of jury</p>



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
