<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0267.004.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>In the Matter of the Application of L.J. Urann for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. Traverse.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Stapleton-Deno, Zoe L." xml:id="zlsd">Zoe L. Stapleton-Deno</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0267.004</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">In the Matter of the Application of L.J. Urann for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. Traverse.</title>
<date when="1905">1905</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1905-07">July 1905</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>L.J. Urann</term>
<term>Morris Wolf</term>
<term>L.C. Smith</term>
<term>Vince H. Faben</term>
<term>Kenneth Mackeeboh</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Ninth Circuit, Western District of Washington</term>
<term>Circuit Court</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>L.J. Urann</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>L.C. Smith</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
 <persName>Morris Wolf</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Vince H. Faben</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Kenneth Mackeeboh</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>US Circuit Court</orgName>
<placeName>Ninth Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#zlsd">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE NINTH CIRCUIT WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>
    
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION OF L.J. URANN FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.} TRAVERSE.</p>
    
<p>And now comes L.J. Urann, by his attorney Vince H. Fabe<del>r</del><add>n</add> and
for traverse of the return herein alleges as follows.</p>
    
<p>I.</p>
<p>Said petitioner denies that his detention is lawful but on the
contrary that it is unlawful, forceable and against his will.</p>
    
<p>II.</p>
<p>That said Governor's warrant was issued contrary to law and 
against the provisions of the <del></del><add>constitution</add> and sections 5270 and 5280
inclusive and contrary to the law and the statute in the State of
Massachusett<del>e</del>s.</p>
    
<p>III.</p>
<p>That it is not true that the petitioner is a fugitive from
justice or that larceny is a felony or a treason or other similar
crime under that law of the State of Massachusetts and that said
petitioner has not violated any law of the State of Massachusetts
which is the subject of extradition between the States of the
United States.</p>
    
<p>IV.</p>
<p>That the petitioner in the month of January, 1904, became indebted
to the complaining witness in the State of Massachusetts
upon an account for money had and received and that the amount
thereof was adjusted and agreed upon in the month of April, 1904,</p>
<pb/>
    
<p>and that said amount of money was stipulated and agreed between the parties.</p>
    
<p>V.</p>
<p>That thereafter it was agreed between the complaining witness 
and the petitioner that said sum of money should be paid partly
in cash and partly in security and in persuance thereof the said
complaining witness went to the State of Main and inspected the
security consisting of a farm of the agreed value of Five
Thousand Dollars ($5,000.00) and the balance amounting to Three
Thousand Dollars ($3,000.00) was in cash and that said sum was
determined upon between the parties after full knowledge of all 
the facts in the premises were known.
</p>
    
<p>VI.</p>
<p>That the complaining witness and petitioner lived near
neighbors in Boston and that the petitioner stayed in Boston
assisting in said adjustment for about five months and that for 
many months prior to the time that the petitioner left the State 
of Massachusetts the complaining witness knew that the petitioner
was going to leave the State and that he intended to go to 
Seattle, State of Washington to reside and said complaining
witness knew at all times the address and residence and place of 
business of the petitioner for more than one year last past.</p>
    
<p>VII.</p>
<p>That after the complaining witness knew of the facts more than
five (5) <del>circuit</del><add>separate</add> sessions of different grand juries were had and
held in the presinct where said parties resided and the complaining 
witness made no claims of criminal intent and since this
petitioner has resided in the State of Washington more than
eleven (11) sessions of the Grand Jury were held in said presinct</p>
<pb/>
<p>and no charge of crime was made.</p>
    
<p>VIII.</p>
<p>That the prosecution or pretended prosecution is not made in
good faith nor for the purpose of punishment of crime or any
other public purpose <add>but only the purpose</add> of collection and extorrion and for private
game.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE your petitioner prays for relief as he has heretofor
set forth in his petition for the writ and that he be discharged 
and released.</p>
    
<p>Vince H. Faben</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner.</p>

<p>State of Washington
County of King} ss</p>

<p>L.J. Urann being first duly sworn on oath deposes and says:
That he is the petitioner; that he has read the foregoing
traverse and knows the contents thereof and believes the same
to be true.</p>

<p>Louis J. Urann</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 3rd day of July, 1905.</p>
 
<p>Vince H. Faben</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of
Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>
    
<pb/>

<p>/TF/</p>
<p>No. 1313</p>
<p>In the Circuit Court
OF THE UNITED STATES
FOR THE
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>
    
<p>In the Matter of 
the petition of 
L.J. Urann</p>
    
<p>Traverse</p>
    
<p>FILED IN THE
U.S. Circuit Court,
Western Dist. of Washington.
Jul 3 1905</p>
<p>A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk</p>
<p>PM Hob<unclear>ins</unclear> Dep.</p>
<p>Vince H. Faben
Atty for Pet.</p>

<p>PIONEER B'DY &amp; P'TG CO., TACOMA_23843</p>
    
    
    
    
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>