<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ng Kwack Kang v. King County. Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1915-11-10">November 10th, 1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives at Seattle</repository>
<collection>Pacific Alaska Region</collection>
<idno>Case No 3157</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-11">November 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Kang, Ng Kwack</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, Adam</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>King County</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#mmd">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0490.001"/>

<p>
IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT, IN AND FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT
OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.

In the Matter of the application 
of NG KWACK KANG, for a Writ of 
habeas corpus.

No. 3157
Patition of NG KWACK KANG, by
and through ADAM BEELER of
the law firm of BEELER and SULLIVAN, 
his attorney.

Comes now ADAM BEELER, of the firm of BEELER and SULLIVAN,
Attorneys, as attorney for and in behalf of NG KWACK KANG, a son
of NG KUM, an American citizen of the City of Boston. State of Massachusetts, 
and respectfully makes his application for a Writ of 
habeas corpus, and alleges as follows:

I.
That the said NG KWACK KANG, is imprisoned and restrained 
of his liberty by the Unites States Commissioner of Immigration,
HENRY M. WHITE, or by some person or persons acting through, by, or
under him, and that said NG KWACK KANG is imprisoned at the Detention 
House at the Immigration Station in the City of Seattle, King
County, State of Washington, and within the jurisdiction of the
above entitled court, under the charge that the said NG KWACK KANG
is an alien, a subject to the President of the Chinese Republic, and
has no legal right to be admitted into the United States, and that
he should be deported according to law; and your petitioner further
informs this Honorable Court that said imprisonment, restraint, and 
Order of Deportation is Illegal, arising from the following facts, 
to-writ: That the said NG KWACK KANG arrived  at the Port of Seattle
on a voyge from China, on or about June 26th, 1915, on the S.S.
TITAN, and said NG KWACK KANG was denied admittance into the United
States on the ground that he was not legally entitled to be admitted
therein; that said NG KWACK KANG was given a hearing by the Immigration 
officials on or about the 30th day of June, 1915; that further 
evidence was taken in said case by the Department of Labor, through
</p>

<pb></pb>
<p>
the Immigration officils; and that on the 16th day of August, 1915,
an Order was issued by the Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle,
finding that said NG KWACK KANG was not entitled to enter or remain
in the United States, and that he should be deported; that an appeal
was taken by said NG KWACK KANG, through his attorney in Boston,
Massachusetts, to the Secretary, then on October 21st, 1915, said
Order of Deportation was affirmed by the Assistant Secretary, and
said NG KWACK KANG was ordered deported.

Your petitioner is informed and believes, and so states
the fact to be, that said Commisioner of Immigration, HENRY M.
WHITE of Seattle, Washington, in charge of the District of Washington,
or his agent or agents, acting by, under, or through him,
for the United States Government, is about to deport and return the 
said NG KWACK KANG to China, in violation of treaty relations 
between the United States and China, and in violation of the laws 
and statutes of the United States in relation to the Chinese Exclusion 
Act, and in violation of the laws relative to the acts and powers
of the Secretary of Labor and the Assistant Secretary of Labor,
in that said NG KWACK KANG is being deprived of his liberty without
due process of law and without being given a fair hearing by said
Commissioner of Immigration, HENRY M. WHITE, or his agents or officials,
acting by, under or through him <add>or</add> for the United States Government.

Your petitioner further alleges that the right of appeal
from the finding of the Commisssioner of Immigration, HENRY M. WHITE, 
or his agents or officials, acting by, under or through him, or
for the United States Government in and for the District of Washington,
by the statutes in such cases made and provided for in relation
to the Chinese Exclusion Laws, has been violated and that his full
rights have not been accorded to your petitioner, NG KWACK KANG
in this: that W.B. WILSON is the Secretary of Labor, and LOUIS POST
</p>

<pb></pb>
<p>
is his only Assistant Secretary of Labor; that the said appeal of 
said NG KWACK KANG to the Secretary of Labor, from the decision denying
the right to enter and remain int he United States, came up
for hearing and consideration, and under the law should have been
heard by the said Secretary of Labor, unless the said Secretary
being absent, then said Assistant Secretary should Act, but that
the said Order affirming the finding of the said Commissioner of 
Immigration of Seattle, is made by and in the name of the Assistant
Secretary, without designation any name or authority so vested 
in Assistant Secretary, or that the said Secretary was absent
and not able to perform his duty, and that the said Secretary of 
Labor neglected or refused to hear or consider said appeal, and
hence the said NG KWACK KANG has been denied his right of appeal,
according to law. 

Your petitioner on information and belief, further states
that the said NG KWACK KANG has not had a fair and impartial trial
before the said NG KWACK KANG has not had a fair and impartial trial 
before the said Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, King County,
Washington; that there is no evidence in the records to sustain 
the Exclusion and Deportation Order that said decision is arbitrary
and not supported by evidence, and that said NG KWACK KANG,
after the Department had given him a hearing before the Immigration
Official at Seattle, Washington, was not advised of his right
to have witnesses appear for and in his behalf; that said NG KWACK
KANG was denied the right to face the witnesses whose testimony 
was taken by the United States Government, or the right of cross-examination 
thereof, and that evidence was taken without NG KWACK KANG 
being then and there facing said witnesses who gave evidnce for and 
in behalf of the United States Government.

Your petitioner further states that said NG KWACK KANG was denied a fair hearing, in that private confidentual letters passed between the Immigration Officials and the officials of the
</p>

<pb></pb>
<p>
Department of Labor at Washington, and that NG KWACK KANG was not 
apprised of said communications, or given the right to cross-examine
the parties who wrote said letters, and tha said parties
who wrote said letters were not under oath, and said letters were
prejudicial, were not legal evidence, and the writing and consideration
of same in connection with NG KWACK KANG's case denied him
a fair and impartial hearing.

Your petition further alleges that NG KWACK KANG is
a minor son of an American Citizen, NG KUM, his father having been
discharged from custody by the United States District Judge Cox of the 
Northern District of New York, on April 11th, 1901, and to deny
NG KWACK KANG, of his right to enter and remain in the United States,
is depriving him of his liberty without due process of law, and is
in violation of the Constitution of the Unites States.

Wherefore, your petitioner prays that his court find that
said NG KWACK KANG has not been accorded the rights and privileges
as allowed by law, and that he has not been given a fair and impartial
trial, and that he is a son of an American citizen, and that 
he be discharged and allowed to join his father, who is an American 
citizen in Boston, Massachusetts.

DATED this 10th day of November 1915.

NG KWACK KANG, petitioner
BY and THROUGH <signatures>Adam Beeler</signatures>

Attorney for petitioner.

STATE OF WASHINGTON
COUNTY OF KING}SS

ADAM BEELER, being first duly sworn, on oath deposes and
says: That he is one of the attorneys for the said NG KWACK KANG:
that he has read the foregoing Patition, knows the contents thereof, 
and that the same is true, of his knowledge, he alleges upon information
and belief to be true
<signatures>Adam Beeler</signatures>
Subscribed and sworn to before me this 10th day of November 1915.
<signatures>W.S. Law</signatures>
Notary Public in and for the
State of Washington, residing
at Seattle.
</p>
<p>MISSING IS IMG_0191 to IMG 0194</p>
<p>
The President of the United States of America, to
United States Commissioner of Immigration,
HENRY M. WHITE:

We command you that you have the body of NG KWACK KANG,
by you imprisoned and detained under Order of Deportation, as it
is said, together with the time and cause of such imprisonment and
detention and order of deportation by whatsoever name the said
NG KWACK KANG, shall be named or charged. before Honorable
JEREMIAH NETERER. Judge of the Unites States District
Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division,
at the Federal Building, in Seattle, State of Washington, on the
15th day of November, 1915, at Two P.M
</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>