<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0472.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Thomas S. Brown and et al v. Thomas Jefferson Hamilton. Petition for Writ</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0472.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Thomas S. Brown and et al v. Thomas Jefferson Hamilton. Petition for Writ</title>
<date when="1887-10-15">October 15, 1887</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1887-10-15">October 15, 1887</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Emery, C.D.</term>
<term>Rochester, Junius</term>
<term>Ledgerwood, W.E.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>King County</term>
<term>Kitsap County</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Brown, Thomas S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Geods, G.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Downing, George</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Schubard, Chas.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Young, C.J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Wegner, Peter J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Hamilton, Thomas Jefferson</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Hunday, Charles F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Richard A. Jones</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Third Judicial District of Washington Territory</orgName> 
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE THIRD JUDICAL DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON 
TERRITORY, HOLDING TERMS AT SEATTLE.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application
of Thomas S. Brown, G. Geods, George        No. 5267
Downing, Chas. Schubard, Carl Jong          PETITION
Matson named in the process as
C.J. Young and Peter J. Wegner for
a Writ of Habeas Corpus and discharge.</p>


<p>TO THE HON. RICHARD A. JONES, JUDGE OF THE ABOVE STYLED COURT: </p>

<p>Your petitioner Junius Rochester petitions the Court and says -
That in this petition he appears in behalf of and as the agent of
Thomas S. Brown, G. Geods, George Downing, Chas. Schubard, Carl Jong Matson
named in the processes as C.J. Young and Peter J. Wegner.</p>

<p>II
That the said persons above named <add>were</add> defendants in cases of the
United States against them before Hon. C.D. Emery, United States Commissioner
at Seattle in King County, with jurisdiction to hear and try certain
causes at law</p>

<p>III
That the above named persons are and each of them is illegaly,
wrongfully and without any authority of law restrained of his liberty
by Thomas Jefferson Hamilton United States Marshal for Washington
Territory, at McNeils Island at the United States Penitentiary in the
County of Washington Territory</p>

<p>IV
That the cause and pretense of the restraint of the liberty of
said persons and each of them is the alleged commission of acts which
are in no wise a violation of any law of the United States or of the
Territory of Washington, and which constitutes no crime, misdemeanor or
offense whatever.</p>

<p>V
That the illegality of the restraint herein complained of consists
in the wrongful, unlawful and unwarranted detention of each of said
persons named herein as detained by the said Hamilton upon an alleged
commitment issued by C.D. Emery as aforesaid, which charges no offense
against the laws of the United States or Territory of Washington, and</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>your petitioner further says, that the recitals in said commitments and
in each of them, upon which the said Hamilton holds the said persons
shows that there has been no crime or offense committed by said persons
or either of them, and that the acts with which they and each of them is
charged do no constitute any offense against the laws of the United
States or Washington Territory, or any crime, misdemeanor or offese
whatever: that the several commitments in the case of each of said
persons are identical except the names of several defedants
are different in each: a true and exact copy of one of said commitments,
to wit: commitment in the case of Thomas S. Brown upon which said
Thomas S. Brown is held as aforesaid, and which is the sole and only
authority of the said Hamilton for detaining the siad persons or any
of them, is hereto annexed as part hereof and made a part of this
petition [marked exhibit A] and petitioner further says that the only
offense charged against the said Thomas S. Brown or against any of
said persons herein named is unlawfully restrained of their liberty,
is that each "of said persons" on or about the 10th day of October
1887, in the Territory aforesaid, disobeyed the orders of the Master of
the American ship Ivanhoe".</p>

<p>Petitioner says that there is no other or further cause for 
such detention save as above stated:</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays your Honor to grant unto the said 
Thomas S. Brown, G. Geods, Gerorge Downing, Chas. Schubarb, Carl Jong Matson
named in the processes as C.J. Young and Peter J. Wegner a Writ of Habeas
Corpus commanding and ordering the said Thomas Jefferson Hamilton to
produce before your Honor at such time and place as your Honor deems 
wise and meet the bodies of the said Thomas S. Brown, G. Geods, George 
Downing, Chas. Schubarb, Carl Jong Matson named in the processes as
C.J Young and  Peter J. Wegner, and that your Honor will hear and determine
whether they are or either of them is illegally detained or restrained
of his liberty and that they and each of them be discharged and
permitted to go their way without further delay detention, </p>

<p>Metcalfe + Rochester          Junius Rochester
Lewis + Gilman                  Petitioner and
attys for plff + petitoner      on behalf of plaintiffs</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>TERRITORY OF WASHINGTON 
COUNTY OF KING
------------------ - S. S. </p>

<p>PERSONALLY APPEARED BEFORE ME JUNIUS ROCHESTER 
WHO UPON OATH DEPOSES AND SAYS THAT HE APPEARS HEREIN UPON THE
HALF AND AS THE AGENT OF THOMAS S. BROW., G. GEODS GEORGE DOWNING,
CHARLES SCHUBARD, CARL JOHN MATSON KNOWS AS C.J. YOUNG AND
PETER J. WEGENER, THAT HE IS THE PETITION ON THEIR BEHALF NAMED
HEREIN AND IN THE AFORESAID AND HEREIN PETITOIN, THAT HE HAS READ
THE SAID PETITION AND KNOWS THE CONETENTS THEREOF AND BELEIVES 
THE SAME TO BE TRUE. </p>

<p>Junius Rochester

   SWORN  TO AND SUVSCRIBED
BEFORE ME THIS 15TH. DAY OF OCTOBER 1887.</p>

<p><unclear>Jacob Mctrafe</unclear>
Notary Public in and for
Washington Territory</p>

<pb></pb>
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>