<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0472.002"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0472.002</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">September 14, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date>13 May 1897</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Pierce, John A.
Speck, Robert D.
Baldwin, Harris 
Hanford, C. H. 
Aspland, Lise C.
White, E. T.
Pomeroy, Frances A. 
Aspland, Andrew 
Aspland, Ella May 
Brown, Abel 
Wilkinson, M. A.  
Aspland, John H. 
White, E. T. 
Aspland, Jennie 
Switzer, W. D. 
Magnus, Franz
Sempee,John M. 
Sawyer, Mary
Spence, William C. 
Corbett, J. E. 
Eldridge, John 
Hair, N. C. 
Valentine, John E. 
Backus, C. F. 
Donovan, G. J.
Low, J. R. 
Thomas, C.
Monroe, W. A. 
Fenton, James E. 
Prather, Leander H.
Cisna, M. A. 
Dempsey, C. C.
Willia, C. Thomas 
Gould, P.
James, Thomas
Doane, H. W.
Roadnight, J. F.
Lipschuetz, I.
Valentine, J. E. 
Morgan, U. H.  
Hair, N. C.
Van Ness, John Q. 
Gill, William 
Frazier, R. J. 
O'Brien, 
Lipschuetz, Isador
Boyd, L. F.
Hillard, Barry N.
McNulty, Philip
Byers, William
Traut, A.
Bishop, B. H.
Cannon, H. L.
Crowley, J. A.
Frazier, R. J. 
Fenton, James, E. 
Pierce, John A. 
La Valley, William J.
Semper, William
Flynn, James
Swift, Harry
Drain, James A.
Rogers, John R.
</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Spokane County, Washington
Wallace, Idaho
Cannon Precinct, IWashington
Precinct No. 2, Washington
Shoshone County, Idaho
Olympia, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Webster, George</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Webster, George</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName> Del Cary Smith
Fenton, James E. 
O'Brien</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Pierce, John A.
Baldwin, Harris</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H. </persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Circuit Court of the United States, Ninth Judicial Circuit, District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>Spokane County, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0472.001"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES/, NINTH JUDICIAL CIRCUIT.</p>
<p>DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON. NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the application of
George Webster,</p>
<p>for</p>
<p>A Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>To the Hon. C. H. Hanford, Judge of the Circuit Court of the
United States, Ninth Judicial Circuit, District of Washington,
Northern Division.</p>
<p>The petition of George Webster respectfully shows to your
Honor:</p>
<p>First- That the said petitioner is now a prisoner imprisoned
and confined in the County Jail at Spokane, Spokane County, State
 of Washington, in the custody of Robert D. Speck, Sheriff of Spokane
County, State of Washington.</p>
<p>Second- That the cause or pretense of the restraint of the
said petitioner according to the best of his knowledge and belief
is, that on the 13th day of May, 1897, John A. Pierce as proecuting
attorney in and for the County of Spokane, State of Washington,
made and filed with the Clerk of the Superior Court of the State of
Washington, in and for Spokane County, an information, charging the
above named petitioner with the crime of murder in the first de-
gree, which said information is in writing in words and figures as
follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintiff,</p>
<p>v.</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Defendant.</p>
<p>Information for Murder
in the First Degree.</p>
<p>Whereas the hereinafter specified public offense has been com-
mitted by the said defendant George Webster, and whereas the said
defendant George Webster is not under indictment therefor; and whereas
the said defendant is in custody charged with having committed the
said public offense; and whereas the said court is in session, and 
no Grand Jury of, in or for said County is in session; now, there-
fore, John A. Pierce, Prosecuting attorney in and for the County of
Spokane, and State of Washington, and in the name and by the au-
thority of the State of Washington, by this Information informs
the said court and gives the said court to understand, know and
be informed that the said defendant George Webster is hereby charg-
ed with a public offense, to-wit; the crime of murder in the first
degree, committed as follows, to-wit; that on the sixth day of May,
A. D. 1897, and within three years before the filing of this In-
formation, at the County of Spokane and State of Washington, the
said defendant George Webster, then and there in the said County
and State being, then and there unlawfully, felioniously and pur-
posely, and of his deliberate and premeditated malice, killed Lise
C. Aspland, by then and there purposely, and of his deliberate and
premeditated malice, shooting and mortally wounding the said Lise C.
Appland with a gun, commonly called a revolver, which he, the said
George Webster, then and there held in his hand, contrary to the 
Statutes- in such case made and provided and against the peace and
dignity of the State of Washington.</p>
<p>JOHN A. PIERCE.
Prosecuting attorney and 
Informant.</p>
<p>By</p>
<p>HARRIS BALDWIN
Deputy Prosecuting Attorney</p>
<p>State of Washington )
) ss
County of Spokane. )</p>
<p>Harris Baldwin, being first duly sworn, upon his oath
deposes and says; that he is the duly appointed, qualified and act-
ting deputy prosecuting attorney in and for the County of Spo-
kane, State of Washington, and that all and singluar the several
statements, allegations, matters and things set out in the above
and foregoing information are true.</p>
<p> HARRIS BALDWIN</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this 13th day of May, A. D. 1897.
E. T. WHITE</p>
<p>Notary Public for the State of
Washington, residing at Spokane
Washington.</p>
<p> (SEAL of Notary Public.)</p>
<p>Names of Witnesses known to the prosecuting attorney at
the time of filing this information:</p>
<p>Frances A. Pomeroy
Andrew Aspland
Ella May Aspland
Abel Brown
M. A. Wilkinson</p>
<p>John H. Aspland
E. T. White
Jennie Aspland
W. D. Switzer
Franz Magnus</p>
<p>John M. Sempee
Mary Sawyer
Wm. C. Spence
J. E. Corbett
John Eldridge</p>
<p>Second-a- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken
in said cause in said Superior Court that the said cause coming on
regularly for trial, one N. C. Hair, was called as a juror in said
cause upon being examined touching his qualifications to act
 as a jurir in said cause, answered that he was at said time the
client of John A. Pierce who was then the prosecuting attorney for 
Spokane County, Washington, and who was then representing the 
State of Washington in the said cause, and thereupon the said George
Webster by his attorneys, challenged the said juror N. C. Hair, for
implied bias on the ground that the relation of attorney and client
at said time existed between the sad juror and the said prosecut-
ion attorney/ and that the said juror N. C. Hair was, under the pro-
visions of Sec. 345 of Vol. 2 of Hills Code of the State of Washing-
ton, which is as follows; "Standing in the relation of guardi-
an and ward, attorney and client, master and servant, or landlord
and tenant, to the adverse party; or being a member of the family
of, or a partner in business with, or in the employment for wages
of the adverse party etc., "disqualified and incompetent to 
 </p>
<p>Second B- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken
in said cause in said Superior Court, that the said cause coming
on regularly for rial one John E. Valentine was called as a juror
to answer questions touching his qualifications to act as a juror
in said cause, and upon examination of the said juror John E. Val-
entine, touching his qualifications, he, the said huror testified
as follows;
</p>
<p>Q From what you read did you form an opinion as to the guilt of 
innocence of the defendant?
A Well, as is natural when a person reads anything of that kind 
he would have an opinion.
Q Have you that opinion now?
A Well, somewhat.
Q Is that such an opinion as would require evidence to remove or
change?
A Some. Yes sir.
Q Would it require strong evidence to change your opinion?
A Fairly good.
Q In that such an opinion as would require the evidence of at
least one witness to change?
A Yes sir.
Q Is that opinion that you have now, a fixed and decided opinion
from what you have reas?
A no.
Q Assuming what you have read to be true have you, then a fixed
and decided opinion?
A Yes sir. If it was true,
Q Welll, at any rate you now entertain an opinion that would re-
quire strong evidence to remove?
A Well, it would require some evidence, yes sir. Not particularly
strong evidence; it would require some evidence.
Q It would require some evidence of at least one witness?
A Yes sir.
Q To change your present opinion?
A Yes sir.
</p>
<p>(Statemet of Facts p. 195-196</p>
<p>That thereupon the said petitioner by his said attorneys chal-
lenged the said juror John E. Valentine, for cause on the ground
of actual bias, which said challenge of the said petitioner wasthen
and there denied by the said Superior Court, to which the said pe-
titioner duly excepted and an exception was allowed. And petitioner
alleged, that under the laws of the State of Washington in force
at the time of the trial of this cause, the said petitioner was en-
titled to exercise twelve peremptory challenges; and petitioner
further alleges, that upon the trial of said cause upon the said in-
foormation he, the said petitioner did exercse eleven peremptory
challenges, and did excuse eleven jurors peremptorily.</p>
<p>Third- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in 
said cause in the said Superior Court, of the State of Washington, in
and for the County of Spokane, that on the 14th day of May, A. D.
1897, the attorneys for the said petitioner made and filed with the
clerk of the said Superior Court a motion to quash and set aside
the said information, which said motion is in writing in words
and figures as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THESTATE OF WASHINGTON FOR SPOKANE COUNTY
</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintiff,</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Defendant.</p>
<p>Comes now the above named defendant by his attorneys
Del Cary Smith, and moves the court to quash and set aside the in-
formation 
filed herein and for grounds of said motion alleges;
</p>
<p>1- That the information filed herein is not verified as re-
quired by law.
</p>
<p>2- That it does not appear from said information or from any
of the record or proceedings in this cause, that the State of Wash-
ington is entitled to prosecute herein by information.</p>
<p>3- That as appears from the information in this cause, this
court has no jurisdiction of the person of the defendant, or of the
subject matter of this action.</p>
<p>4- That said information is not direct or certain as regards
either the party charged, the crime charged, or the particular cir-
cumstances of the crime charged.</p>
<p>5- That said information charges more than one crime and in
more than one form.</p>
<p>6- That the said act or omission charged as the crime in said
information is not clearly and distinctly setforth in ordinary and
concise language as required by law.</p>
<p>7- That the act or omission charged as the crime in said in-
formation is not stated with such a degree of certainty as to en-
able the court to pronounce judgment upon a conviction according to
the rights of the case.</p>
<p>8- That said information does not inform the said defendant of
the nature and cause of the accusation against him.</p>
<p>9- Tht it has never been judicially or otherwise established,
that there was or is probable cause to believe that the said defend-
ant ever committed the crime attempted to be alleged in the said
information, and as appears from the records in this cause, on file
with the clerk of this court, the said information was filed against
the said defendant without any probable cause first having been
established and shown.</p>
<p>10 That at a pretended preliminary examination held in this
cause, on the 12th day of May 1897, before Hon. C. F. Backus, a 
Justice of the Peace, the said defendant over the objections of his
counsel was denied the rights and protection guaranteed to him by
the laws and Constitution of the State of Washington, and that said
Justice, over the objections of defendant admitted all manner of
sham, irrelevant, incompetent, immaterial and hearsay testimony
against him.</p>
<p>11- That said information does not substantially comply with
the requirements of the criminal code of the State of Washington.</p>
<p>This motion is based upon the files and records herein.</p>
<p>Del Cary Smith,
Attorney for defendant.</p>
<p>No. 771
Filed May 14th, 1897, at 9:15 o'clock, A. M.</p>
<p>J. R. Low, Clerk</p>
<p>G. J. Donovan, Deputy.</p>
<p>Fourth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken
in t he said Superior Court, that the said motion of the said peti-
tioner to quash and set aside the said information came on regular-
ly for hearing before the Judge of the said Superior Court
and upon the argument thereof, the same was overruled, to which the
said petitioner then and there duly excepted, and an exception was 
allowed by the said Superior Court.</p>
<p>Fifth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in
said cause in the said Superior Court, that the at-
torneys for the said petitioner on the 25th day of May, A. D. 1897,
made and filed with the Clerk of the said Superior Court a demurrer
to the said information which said demurrer is in writing, in words
and figures as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON FOR SPOKANE COUNTY</p>
<p>The State of Washington</p>
<p>Plaintiff,</p>
<p>DEMURRER</p>
<p>v.</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Defendant.</p>
<p>Comes now the above defendant by his attorney
Del Cary Smith, and demurs to the information filed herein and for
grounds of demurrer alleges; 
</p>
<p>That said information does not substantially conform to the
requirements of the criminal code of the State of Washington.</p>
<p>2- That the facts charged in said information do not consti-
tute a crime or public offense.</p>
<p>3- That as appears from the record in this court in this cause,
this court has no jurisdiction of the person of the defendant or the 
subject matter of the action.</p>
<p>4- That said information does not inform the defendant of the
nature and cause of the accusation against him.</p>
<p>5- That it does not appear from said information or from any of
the records or proceedings in this cause, that the State of Wash-
ington is entitled to prosecure theis cause by information.</p>
<p>6- that as appears from all the records in this cause the in-
formation herein is void and the defendant is now deprived of his
liberty without due process of law.</p>
<p>7- That the said information is not direct and certain as re-
gards either the party charged, the crime charged, or the particular
circumstances of the crime charged.</p>
<p>8- That the act or omission charged as the crime in said infor-
mation is not clearly and distinctly setforth in ordinary and con-
cise language as required by law.</p>
<p>9- That the act or omission charged as the crime in said infor
mation is not stated with such a degree of certainty as to enable
the court to pronounce judgment upon a conviction according to the
rights of the case.</p>
<p>10- That said information charges more than one crime and in
more than one form.</p>
<p>11- That it has never been judicially or otherwise established
that there was or is probable cause to believe that the said defend-
ant ever committed the crime attempted to be alleged in the said
information, and as appears from the records in this cause, on file
with the clerk, the said information was filed against the said de-
fendant without any probable cause first having been established
and shown.</p>
<p>Del Cary Smith
Attorney for the defendant.</p>
<p>No. 771
Filed May 25th, 1897.</p>
<p>J. R. Low, Clerk,</p>
<p>By</p>
<p>W. A. Monroe, Deputy.</p>
<p>Sixth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in 
said cause in said Superior Court, that the said cause coming on
regularly to be heard upon the said demurrer, and the said Superior
Court having heard argument thereon, overruled the same to which
order overmling the same the said petitioner then and there duly
excepted, and the said exception was allowed by the said Superior
Court.</p>
<p>Seventh- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in
said cause in the said Superior Court, the jury which was im anell-
ed and sworn to try the said petitioner upon the said charge
in the said information, did, on the 25th day of September, A. D. 
1897, render and reutrn unto the said Superior Court their verdict
in said cause, which is in writing, in words and figures asfollows
to-wit;</p>
<p>Case No. 771</p>
<p>VERDICT OF THE GUILTY</p>
<p>We, the jury of the case of the State of Washigton, Plaintiff</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>George Webster</p>
<p>Defendant,</p>
<p>find the defendent George Webster, GUILTY as charged in the infor-
mation.</p>
<p>Spokane, Washingotn, Sept 25th, 1897.</p>
<p>C. Thomas,</p>
<p>Foreman.</p>
<p>No. 771
Filed May 25th, 1897.</p>
<p>J. R. Low, Clerk,</p>
<p>By</p>
<p>W. A. Monroe, Deputy.</p>
<p>Recorded Journal 41, page 449</p>
<p>Eighth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken
in said cause in said Superior Court, that on the 15th day of Nov-
ember, A. D. 1897, the attorneys for the said petitioner made and 
filed with the Clerk of the said Superiorb Court, a moti on in ar-
rest of judgement which said motion in arrest of judgment is in writ-
ing, in words and figures as follows, to-wit;</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, IN AND FOR THE 
COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintiff,</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Defendant.</p>
<p>Comes now the above named defendant by his attorney's Del Cary
Smith and James E. Fenton, and moves the court that judgment upon
the verdict herein be arrested and stayed, and that the information 
herein be dismissed, and that the defendant be dischaged from cus-
today and for grounds of said motion the defendant alleges;</p>
<p>1- That the facts as stated in the information herein does not 
constitute a crime or misdemeanor.</p>
<p>2- That the prosecuting attorney had no authority to file the 
information in this cause.</p>
<p>3- That the information herein is not verified as required by
law.</p>
<p>4- That the above entitled court had no jurisdiction of the said 
defendant or of the charge in the information herein.</p>
<p>5- That the verdict rendered herein does not conform to the
information herein.</p>
<p>6- That there is a variance between the evidence in this cause
and the allegations in the information herein.</p>
<p>7- That the statutes under which the information herein was
filed, and under whichthe said defendant was tried and convicted,
is unconstitutional and void, and in violation of the 5th and 14th
Amendments to the Constitution of the United States.</p>
<p>8-That the said information herein charges more than one
crime and in more than one form.</p>
<p>9- That the verdict rendered in said cause is indefinite and
uncertain and wholly insufficient to support a judgment thereon.</p>
<p>10- That the records and proceedings in this cause does not
sufficiently show that the defendant entered any plea to the infor-
mation filed herein.</p>
<p>11- That the records and proceedings in this cause do not show
that the said defendant was present in court, during the material
steps taken in the trial of said cause.</p>
<p>This motion is based upon all records, proceedings 
and filed in the above entitled cause.</p>
<p>Del Cary Smith
and James E. Fenton,
Attorneys for defendant.</p>
<p>No. 771
Filed Nov. 15th, 1897,</p>
<p>J. R. Low, Clerk,</p>
<p>By W. A. Monroe,</p>
<p>Deputy.</p>
<p>Ninth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in
said cause, that the said cause coming on regilarly to be heard upon
the said motion in arrest of judgment, and the same being argued te
the said Superior Courtoverruled the same, towhich ruling the said
petitioner then and there excepted and an exception was then and
there allowed by the said Superior Court.</p>
<p>Tenth- That thereafter such proceedings were had an take n in
said cause, in said Superi or Court, that on the 16th day of Novem-
b er, A.D.1897, the Hon. Leander H. Prather as Judge of the said
Superior Court rendered and made his judgement and sentence in said
cause, which said judgment and sentence is i n writing in words and
figures as follows, to-wit;</p>
<p>In the Superior Court of the State of Washington</p>
<p>in and for the County of Spokane.</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintiff,</p>
<p>v.</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Defendant</p>
<p>JUDGEMENT AND SENTENCE</p>
<p>Whereas at a day of the said Superior Court, before the Hon.
Leander H. Prather, Judge of said Court, on the 13th day of May, 1897
in open Court, and in due form of law, John A. Pierce, Prosecuting
attorney in and for said County, in said State, presented, preferr-
ed and caused to be filed, and there was on the said 13th day of May
1897, filed in the said Court, an information against t he said de-
fendant, George Webster, charging him, the said defen dant, George
Webster, with the crime of Muder in the first degree, in that he,
the said defendant, George Webster, in said County and State, on, to-
wit, the 6th day of May, 1897, then and there unlawfully, felonious-
ly and purposely and of his deliberate and premeditated malice, did
kill Lise C. Aspland, by then and there purposely, and of his de-
liberare and premeditated malice, shooting and mortally wounding
the said Lise C. Aspland, with a gun, commonly called a revolver,
ehich he, the said defendant, George Webster, then and there held 
in his hand; and,</p>
<p>Whereas the said defendant George Webster, thereafter and on t
the 13th day of May, 1897, being personally present in open court
with his attorneys, James E Fenton and Del Cary Smith/ was duly
and personally arraigned upon the said information in open court,
and on the 14th day of May, 1897, this said defendant, George Webster
bei ng present in person and by his attorneys in open Court, did
plead not guilty to the said crime in the said information charged,
and</p>
<p>Whereas, thereafter and on to-wit, the 17th day of May, Septem-
ber, 1897, in due course of law, a jury of twelve good and lawful
men was duly selected, accepted, impanelled and sworn to well and
truly try and true deliverance make between the said State of Wash-
ington and the prisoner at the bar, to-wit, the said defendant
George Webster, whom they, the said jury, then and there had in 
chargem accordi ng to the evidence, and</p>
<p>Whereas, after hearing the evidence in the said cause, and the
arguments for the said State of Washington and the said defendant,
George Webster, respectively, and after hearing and receiving the
instructions of the said court, the said jury did retire in charge
of sworn officers to deliberate on their verdict in said cause,
and thereafter and on-to-wit; the 25th day of September, 1897, the
said jury did return and render into open court, the said defendaant
George Webster, being then and there personally present, in open
court, with his said attorneys, the following verdict, to-wit;
Case No. 771</p>
<p> VECR D I C T O F G U I L T Y</p>
<p>We, the jury in the case of the State of Washington, Plaintiff
vs. George Webster, defendant, find the defendantGeorge webster
GUILTY as charged in the information.</p>
<p>Spokane, Washington. Sept. 25th, 1897.</p>
<p>C. Thomas, Foreman.</p>
<p>And whereas, thereafter and on to-wit; the 27th day of September,
1897, the said defendant George Webster, by his said attorneys, gave
a nd filed in said court notice of motion for a new trial and motion
for a new trial herein, and on to-wi t, the 8th day of November,
1897, did file in the said Court affidavits in support of said mo-
tion for a new trial; and on the 15th day of November, 1897, the
said defendant George Webster, being then and there personally pre
ent with his said attorneys in open court; and thereafter, and on, 
to-wit, the 15th day of November, 1897, the said defendant George
Webster, with his said attorneys being personally present in open
court, the said motion in arrest of judgment was overruled by the 
said court.</p>
<p>And the said court having on said 15th day of November, 1897,
fixed the 16th day of November, 1897, as the day on which the said
court would make, render and enter judgment and sentence upon said
verdict,-</p>
<p>NOW, on this, the 16th day of November, 1897, the said c
court being in session, and the said defendant, George Webster being
personally present with his said attorney, Del Cary Smith, in
open court, the said court informed the said defendant George Web-
ster of the said cerdict of the said jury, and then and there asked
the said defendant, George Webster, if hem the said defendant George
Webster had any cause to show wh y said court should not pro-
nounce, an d make, render and enter judgment and sentence of said 
court upon said verdict; and there, being no cause shown by or on
behalf of the said defendant, George Webster, the court prnounced
made, rendered and entered and does hereby make, render and enter,
upon the said verduct the following sentence, to-wit;</p>
<p>Upon the verdict of the jury in this cause, finding you, the
said defendant, George Webster, guily of murder in the first degree
for the killing of Lise C. Aspland, the judgment of this court
is that you are guilty of the crime of murder in the first degree,
therefore, the judgment and sentence of thi s court is that you, the
said defendant George wWebster, be taken hence by the sheriff of 
said county to the jail of said county, and there safely and secure-
ly kept until a time and day certain, to be fixed in the warrant
for your execution; and that upon said day, between the hours of
six o'clock and ten o'clock  in the forenoon of saidm day, so to be
so fixed, you be taken from t he saud jail by the said sheriff to a 
place to be by him selected and provided, within the yard of the
jail of said county, in the city of spokane, County of Spokane,
State of Washington, and that you then and there by the sheriff be
hanged by the neck until you are dead.</p>
<p>Done in open court, this the 16th day of November, 1897.</p>
<p>Leander H. Prather,</p>
<p>JUDGE</p>
<p>No. 771
Filed Nov. 16th, 1897
at 3 o'clock, P.M.
J. R. Low, Clerk</p>
<p>M. A. Cisna, Deputy.</p>
<p>Recorded Journal 41, page 529</p>
<p>Eleventh- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken
in said cause in said Superior Court, that on the 16th day of Nov-
ember, A.D.1897, the Hon. Leander H. Prather as judge of the said
Superior Court, issued a death warrant upon the said judgment and
sentence which said death warrant is in writing in words and figures
as follows, to-wit;</p>
<p>In the Superior Court of the State of Washington</p>
<p>in and for t h e County of Spokane.</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintiff,</p>
<p>v.</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Defendant</p>
<p>To C. C. Dempsey, Sheriff of Spokane County, State of Washing-
ton, GREETING:</p>
<p>Whereas at a lay of the Superior Court of Spokane
County, before the Honorable Leander H. Prather, judge of said
Court, begun and held at the City of Spokane, in the said county of 
Spokane, on the 13th day of May, 1897, in open-court, and in due
form of law, John A. Pierce, prosecuting attorney for Spokane
County, State of Washington, presented an information against the
said defendant George Webster, charging him with the crime of murde
in the first degree, in that, he, the said defendant George Webster
i n said county and State, onto-wit, the 6th day of May, 1897, then 
and there unlawfully, feloniously and purposely, and of his deliber-
ate and premeditated malice, did kill Lise C. Aspland, by then and
there purposely and of his deliberate and pemeditated malice,
shooting and mortally wounding the said Lise C. Aspland, with a gun
commonly called a revolver, which he, the said George Webster, then 
and there held in his hand; and,</p>
<p>Whereas this case came on regularly for hearing in the Super-
ior Court of the State of Washington in and for the County of 
Spokane, on the 13th day of May, 1897, the said court beig in sess-
ion, and the said defendant being present in person in open court
and represented by his attorneys, Messrs James E. Fenton and
Del Cary Smith, and the state of Washingto n being represented by
John A. Pierce, prosecuting attorney for said Spokane County, and, it
ap pearing to the court that said defendant had been duly and regu-
larly examined and committed by a magistrate of said county and
state, upon the charge of murder in t he first degree, and that an
information had been duly presented and filed against him, the said
defendant George Webster, in the said Superior Court by John A. 
Pierce, prosecuti ng attorney as aforesaid, charging him the said
defendant, George Webster, with the crime of murder inthe first de-
gree, thereupon the said defendant George Webster, in open court
was duly arraigned under said information and asked to plead thereto
and thereupon the said defendant George Webster pleaded not guilty
to the said crime in the said information charged, and</p>
<p>Whereas, thereafter and on to-wit, the 17th day of September,
1897, in due course of law, a jury of twelve good and lawful men,
to-wit, C. Thomas Willia, P. Gould, Thomas James, H. W. Doane, J.
F. Roadnight, I. Lipschuetz, J. E. Valentine, U. H. Morgan, N. C. 
Hair, John Q. Van Ness, William Gill and R. J. Frazier, drawn from
the body of said Spokane County, were duly selected, accepted, im-
panelled and sworn to well and truly try and true deliverance make
between the State of Washington and the prisoner at the bar, to-wit
the said defendant George Webster, whom they the said jury, t hen
and there hadin charge, according to the evidence; and</p>
<p>Whereas, after hearing the evidence in the said cause and the
arguments for the said State of Washington and the said defendant
George Webster; respectively, and after hearing and receiving the
instructions of the said Court, the said jury did retire in charge
of sworn officers and to deliberate on their verdict in the said cause;
and thereafter, and on, to-wit, the 25th day of September, 1897,
the said jury did return and render into open court, the said de-
fendant George Webster, being then and there personally present
in open court with his s said attorneys, the following verdict, to-
wit:</p>
<p>Case No. 771</p>
<p> VER D I C T O F G U I L T Y</p>
<p>We, the jury in the case of the STATE OF WASHINGTON, Plaintiff
vs. George Webster, Defendant, find the defendant George Webster
GUILTY as charged in the Information.</p>
<p>Spokane, Washington. Sept. 25th, 1897.</p>
<p>C. Thomas, Foreman.</p>
<p>And Whereas, thereafter and on to-wit, the 27th day of Septem-
ber, 1897, the said defendant George Webster, by his attorneys,
gave and filled in said court notice of motion for a new trial and 
motion for a new trial herein, and on, to-wit, the 8th day of
November, 1897, did file in the said court affidavits in support of
sai d motion for a new trial; and on the 15th day of November, 1897
the said defendant, George Webster, being then and there personally
present, with his said attorneys in open court; and thereafter, and on,
tow-ti the 15th day of November, 1897, the said defendant George
Websterm by his said attorneys, filed a motion for arrest of judg-
ment herein, and on the 15th day of November, 1897, the said de-
fendant George Webster, with his sai d attorneys being personally
p resent in open court, the said motion in arrest of judgment was
overruled by the said court; and
</p>
<p>Whereas, the said court did on said 15th day of November, 1897,
fix the 16th day of November, 1897, as the day on which the said
court would make, render and enter judgment and sentence upon said
verdict, and</p>
<p>Whereas, on the 16th day of November, 1897, the said court be-
ing in session, and the said defendant George Webster, being person-
ally present with his said attorneys, Del Cary Smith, in open court
, the said court informed the said defendant George Webster,
had any cause to show why the said court should not prnounce, and
make render and enter judgment and sentence of said court upon said
verdict; and, there being no cause shown by or on behalf of the 
said defendant, George Websterm the said court did then and there
pronounce, make render and enter, upon the said verdict, the
following sentence, to-wit; Upon the verdict of the jury in this
cause, finding you, the said defendant George Webster, guilty of
muder in the frst degree for the killing of Lise C. Aspland, the 
judgmet of this court is that you are guilty/of the crime of mur-
der in the first degree; therefore, the judgment and sentence of 
this court is that you, the said defendant George Webster, be taken
hence by the sheriff of said county to the jail of said county, and 
there safely and securely kepy until a day and time certain, to be
fixed in the warrant for your execuution; mand that upon said day,
between the hours of six o'clocl and ten o'clock in the forenoon of 
said day, so to be fixed, you be taken from the said jail by the
said sheriff to a place to be by him selected and provided withi n
the yard of the jail of said county in the city of Spokane, county
of Spokane, State of Washington, and that you then and there by the 
said sheriff be hanged by the neck until you are dead:-</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, it is by the court ordered, and, in the name of the
STATE OF WASHINGTON, you, C. C. Dempsey, Sheriff of Spokane County
State of Washington, are hereby commanded to take the said defend-
ant, George Webster, on the 14th day of February, A.D. 1989, between
the hours of six o'clock and ten o'clock un the forenoon of said
day, to the said place of execution, in the yard of the jail of said 
Spokane County, and that you, the said C. C. Dempsey, Sheriff as
aforesaid, then and there hang the said defendant, George Webster, by 
the neck until he is dead; and that you, the said C. C. Dempsey, sher
iff as aforesaidm make due execution and return of this warrant and
your proceedings thereon as required by law.</p>
<p>GIVEN under my hand and the seal of said court, this 16th day
of November, . D. 1897
(SEAL)</p>
<p>Leander H. Prather.
Judge of the Superi or Court of
the State of Wash., in and for
Spokane County.</p>
<p>No. 771
Filed Nov. 16th/1897 at 4:30
o'clock P. M. J.R.Low, Clerk
By G. J. Donovan, Deputy.
Recorded Journal 41 page 532</p>
<p>Eleven 1/2- That thereafter such proceedings were had in
said cause, in the said Superior Court, that the said petitioner
George Webster made and filed in the said Superior Court, his pe-
tition for a writ of error Coram nobis, whiych said petition for a
writ of error coram nobis, is in writing in words and figures as 
follows, to-wit;</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON,
IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
<p>No. 771</p>
<p>The State of Washington,)</p>
<p>Plaintiff,)</p>
<p>-vs-)</p>
<p>George Webster,)</p>
<p>Defendant )</p>
<p>George Webster,
Peitioner in error,
-vs-
The State of Washington,
Defendant in error.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the application of George Webster</p>
<p>-for-</p>
<p>A Writ of Error Corim Nobis</p>
<p>To the above named plaintiff the State of Washington, defendant
and respondant in error herein, and to John A. Pierce, Prosecuting
Attorney in and for the County of Spokane, State of Washington.</p>
<p>You, and each of you will take notice that the above named
George Webster, petitioner, relator and defedant above named, will
on Tuesday, the 4th of January, A. D. 1898, at the hour of nine A.
M. of the said day, or as soon thereafter as he can be heard, apply
to the Hon. L. H. Prather, on of the judges of the above entitled
Court, and the Judge who tried the case No. 771, entitled the State
of Washington, Plaintiff, vs. George Webster, defendant, for a Writ 
of Error Corim Nobis, and upon the hearing of said Writ of Error, the
said petitioner, relator and defendant above named, will ask to have
the Errors of Facts assigned in his petition herein, and supported
by the affidavits filed with his petition, tried and decided by a 
Jury, to be impannelled by the said Superior Court, and if the Jury
shall find in favor of said petitioner, relator and defendant, ask 
for a judgment and decree of said Court, revoking and recalling the
judgment and sentence heretofore made and rendered by said Court,
and that upon said hearing the said petitioner will ask for an order
of said Court that execution of said sentence be stayed and ar-
reated pending the hearig and determination of this matter.</p>
<p>Del Cary Smith
Fenton and O'Brien,
Attorneys for Petitioner,
Relator and defendant above named</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON,
IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
<p>No. 771</p>
<p>The State of Washington,)</p>
<p>Plaintiff,)</p>
<p>-vs-)</p>
<p>George Webster,)</p>
<p>Defendant )</p>
<p>George Webster,
Peitioner in error,
-vs-
The State of Washington,
Defendant in error.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the application of George Webster</p>
<p>-for-</p>
<p>A Writ of Error Corim Nobis</p>
<p>The petitioner, relator and defendant above named comes now,
and for this his petition for a Writ of Error Coram Nobis alleges:</p>
<p>1- That on the 13th day of May, A. D. 1899, the Prosecuting
Attorney in and for Spkane County, Washington, filed an information
in the above entitled court, charging the said petitioner, relator
and defendant above named, with the crime of Murder in the first de-
gree, alleged to have been committed as follows: That he the said
petitioner, relator and defendant above named, on the 6th day of May
A. D. 1897, and within three years next before the filing of said 
information in the County of Spokane, State of Washington, then and
there being, did then and there unlawfully, felioniously and purpose-
ly and of his deliberate and premeditated malice, kill Lice C. Asp-
land with a gun, commonly called a revolver, which he the said Georg3
Webster then and there held in his hand.</p>
<p>2- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken upon
the said information. That on the 14th day of September, A. D. 1897,
the said cause No. 771 wherein the State of Washington was Plaintiff
and George Webster, this petitioner was defendant, was called for 
trial, the said State of Washington being represented by John A.
Pierce Prosecuting Attorney, and the said George Webser the peti-
tioner and relator herein being present in person and represented
by Del Cary Smith and James E. Fenton, his attorneys, a jury was ther
upon called to enter the jury box and after being sworn to answer
questions touching their qualifications were examined by Counsel
f or the State and the defendant, the petitioner and relator herein,
whereupon on the 17th day of September, A. D. 1897, the following
jury was impanelled, selected abd sworn to try the said cause to-wit:
Wm Gill, C. Thomas, J. T. Roadnight, W. P. Gould, John Valentine,
N. C. Hair, U. H. Morgan, Thomas James, Isador Lipschaetz, H. W.
Doane, John Q. Van Ness and R. J. Frazier.</p>
<p>That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in said
cause, No. 771, entitled the State of Washington, plaintiff -vs-
George Webster defendant, that on or about the 25th day of September,
cause found and returned to the above entitled Court, their verdict
finding the defendant guilty as charged in the information.
</p>
<p>3- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in
the above entitled cause, that on the 27th fau of September, A. D. 
1897, the said George Webster, the petitioner and relator herein
filed with the Clerk of the above entitled Court, his Motion to va-
cate and set aside the said verdict and for a new trial of said cause</p>
<p>4- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in the 
above entitled cause, that on the 15th day of November, A. D. 1897,
the said Motion for a new trial came on for hearing before the Hon.
L. H. Prather, one of the Judges of the above entitled Court, and
the Judge who tried said cause, and the said motion being argued by
counsel for the State of Washington and for the defendant, and the
said Court being advised, ordered, and adjudged that the said motion
for a new trial be overruled, to which the said George Webster then 
and there excepted.</p>
<p>5- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in said
cause, No. 771, entitled the State of Washington, plaintiff, -vs-
George Webster, defendant that on the 15th day of November, A. D. 
1897, the said George Webster, the petitioner and relator herein,
filed his motion in the above entitled Court to arrest judgment upon
the said verdict.</p>
<p>6- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in said
cause, No. 771, entitled the State of Washingyon, plaintiff, -vs-
George Webster, defendant, that on the 15th day of November, A. D. 
1897, the Hon. L. H. Prather one of the Judges of the above entitled 
Court, and the Judge who tried said cause, made an order overrul-
ing said Motion in arrest of judgmet, to which the said George Web-
ster then and there excepted.</p>
<p>7- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in 
said cause, No. 771, entitled the State of Washingyon, plaintiff, -vs-
George Webster, defendant, that on the 16th day of November, A. D. 
1897, the Hon. L. H. Prather one of the Judges of the above entitled 
Court, and the Judge who tried said cause, made and rendered judgment
upon the said verdict adjudging the said George Webster the petition-
er and relator hearein, to be hanged by the neck until dead.</p>
<p>8- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in the
above entitled cause, that on the 16th day of November, A. D. 1899,
a warrant was issued out of the above entitled Court, directed to
the Sheriff to take the said George Webster the relator and petitioner
herein on the 4th day of February, A. D. 1898, between the hours of
six o'clock and ten o'clock in the forenoon of said day, to the place
of execution in the yard of the jail of said Spokane County, and then
and there hang the said George Webster, the petitioner and relator
herein, by the neck until he should be dead.</p>
<p>9- And the said George Webster the petitioner and relator here
in, further alleges and assigns as an error of fact for which a writ
of Coram Nobis should issue herein, that upon the examination of</p>
<p>isador Lipschetz one of the jurors who tried the said George Webster
the petitioner and relator herein, touching the qualifications of
said juror to sit as a trial juror in said cause, the following ques-
tions were propounded to the said Isadoe Lipschuetz, and the said
Isador Lipschuetz deposed and testified under oath as follows:</p>
<p>Q What is your name?
A I. Lipschuetz.
Q Mr. Lipschuetz where do you live?
A Here in Spokane
Q How long have you lived here, Mr. Lipschuetz?
A About eight years.
Q Are you a married man?
A Yes sir.
Q Your family live here?
A Yes sir.
Q What is your business?
A I am a barber.
Q Where is your place of business?
A 515 Main Street.
Q Do you know the defendant, George Webster?
A I do not.
Q Do you know his attorneys, Mr. Fenton and Mr. Smith?
A No.
Q Do you know anything about the facts in this case?
A No Sir.
Q Have you read anything in the paper about it?
A I did.
Q Did you read what purported to be the report of the shooting
immediately after it occurred, in the paper?
A I read about it in the papers.
Q From the reading of those reports, or from any other reason,
did you form or express any opinion as to the guilt or innocence
of the defendant.
A No sir.
Q Have you now any opinion as to his guilt or innocence?
A No sir.
Q Mr. Lipschuetz, do you understand the meaning of the term
circumstantial evidence?
A Yes sir.
Q What is your notion about that?
A My notion about the meaning of the term circumstantial evidence
is that circumstances, not witnesses, or the things connecting 
the defendant with the case.
Q Would the trial of a cause be willing to convict the defendant
upon purely, solely circumstantial evidence?
A If there was no doubt about the guilt I would.
Q Taking a chain of circumstances that point to the guilt
of a defendant, would you be willing wholly upon circumstantial
evidence to convict in a case of murder in the first degree,
where you knew that your verdict would mean the hanging of a man?
A If there was no doubt or question in my mind that according to 
the evidence he was guilty.
Q Could you remove all doubt from your mind
by hearing of circumstantial evidence only?
A That would depend on how strong the evidence was,
Q If it was strong enough, you think circumstantial evidence alone 
could remove any doubt from your mind as completely as if you
heard witnesses who saw the transaction?
A Well, I would certainly give the prisoner the beneifit of the 
doubt if there was any exisiting.
Q You should enter upon the trial of the cause with a doubt in
your mind in any case, would you not? Would you not give the
prisoner the benefit of the presumption of innocence starting
out in the trial?
A Yes Sir.
Q Then you would start in the trial of any case with a doubt in
your mind in favor of the prisioner?
A Well, I had not thought of the guilt of the prisoner.
Q You mean that you would rely on the presumption of his inn-
ocence until you have heard the evidence?
A Yes sir,
Q Then you hage a doubt in favor of the prisioner in any event in
starting out in a trial?
A Yes, I suppose so.
Q Now, starting out with that doubt, or with that idea of the pre-
sumption of the innocence of the defendant until he is proven guity
could circumstantial evidence alone remove that doubt or remove
the presumption of innocence that would be in your mind?
A Yes sir.
 Q Have you any opinion, Mr. Lipschuetz which would preclude you
from rendering a verdict of guilty in any case, where the offence 
would be punished by penalty of death?
A No sir.
Q You have no conscientious scruples against hanging?
A No.
Q What is your nationality?
A I was born in Germany
Q Do you belong to any secret society here?
A None whatever.
</p>
<p>The Prosecuting Attorney passed said juror for cause.
The said juror, I. Lipschuetz upon examination of Mr. Fenton
of counsel for defendant, deposed as follows:</p>
<p>Q Have you read anything about this case?
A I have
Q When was that?
A At the time the shooting ocurred last spring.
Q When was that?
A Sometime last spring, when it took place.
Q Have you talked about this case, State against Webster?
A Nothing but comment upon what I read.
Q Have you talked with anyone else about the case?
A No sir.
Q Now from what you have read about the case, and from what you
have heard about it, have you formed any opinion as to the guilt
or innocence o the defendant?
A I never form an opinion on newspaper talk.
Q Have you now any opinion as the the guilt or innocence of the de-
fendant?
A None whatsoever.
Q Have you any opinion as to whether or not Mrs. Aspland was kille
A Only from what I saw in the papers. I have no opinion about it.
Q What is that?
A Only what I saw in the papers?
Q Have you any such opinion that would require evidence to change?
A Evidence to change my opinion?
Q Have you now such an opinion as to require evidence to change
that opinion?
A No sir.
Q You say you would convict a person charged with murder in the 
first degree wholly on circumstantial evidence?
A If there was not adooubt as to the evidence as to his being guilty.
Q Suppose that the evidence was slight and circumstantial, would
you then have any conscientious scruples against convicting?
A No sir, I would not.
Q What is your business?
A I am a barber.
Q Where is your place of business?
A 515 Main Street.
Q Are you acquainted with Mr. Pierce?
A Not personally, but I know him when I see him.
Q Are you acquianted with Mr. Fitzgerald?
A. Only by sight.
Q Are you acquainted with Mr. Baldwin?
A No sir
Q Or Mr. Aspland?
A No sir.
Q Did you ever sit on a jury before?
A I sat in a justice court once.
Q Did you ever sit as a juror in this Court before, or any other
district or superior court?
A No sir.
Q If the defendant should go upon the witness stand and testify in
his own behalf, cud you give his testimony the same weight and
credit as that of ay other witness similarly situated?
and surrounded by the same circumstances?
A Yes sur.
Q Would the fact that he should not go upon the witness stand
raise any nference in your mind as to his guilt?
A None whatever.
Q You think that you could give the defendant the benefit of all
resonable doubt?
A Yes sir.
Q Do you know anything that would prevent you from being a fair
and impartial juror?
A Not to my knowledge,
Q Should the jury in this case, a majority of them, be against your
opinion after hearing the evidence, do you think that you could
adhere to the opinion you had formed in your own consciousness
after hearing the evidence
A I certainly could.
Q You think that your verdict would be based upon the evidence as
you understood it and not upon the understanding of your fellow
jurors?
A Yes sir.
Q You are a marrued man?
A. Yes sir.
</p>
<p>The defendant passed said juror for cause.</p>
<p>That the foregoing questions were all the questions propounded
to the juror, Isador Lipschuetz, and the foregoing answers to said
questions were all the testimony and questions of the Juror Isador
Lipschuetz upon his examination as said Juror in said cause and said
juror gave no other testimony upon his said examination.</p>
 <p>Whereas in truth and in fact the said Isador Lipschuetz at the
 time of his said examination as juror, had not been a resident of
 the City of Spokane or the State of Washington, for the period of
 eight years, and in truth and in fact had not been a resident of the
 State of Washington for the period of one year next before the time
 that he the said Juror Isador Lipschuetz was being examined touching
his qualifications to sit as a Juror in said cause, which he the
said Juror Isador Lipschuetz then and there well knew; and in truth
and in fact the said Juror Isador Lipschuetz voted at the town of
Wallace in voting Precinct No. 2 at the general election held in said
Precinct, in the State of Idaho on the 3rd day of November A. D. 
1896, and in truth and in fact resided in the State of Idaho until
the 1st day of Janurary, A. D. 1897. And the said petitioner, rela-
tor and defendant above named alleges; that at the time of the said
examination of the said Juror Isador Lipschuetz touching his qualifi-
cations to sit as juror in said cause, he the said petitioner, relator
 and defendant, had no knowledge whatever that the said juror Isador
 Lipschuetz was not a resident of the State of Washington for the
 period of one year prior to said time, or that he the said juror was
 not an elector of the State of Washington or that he the said juror
 was not an inhabitant of Spokane County, Washington, for the period
 of one year next preceeding the time when he, the said juror, was
 drawn and called, and he the said petitioner, relator and defendant
 herein further alleges; that at the time of the examination of the
 said juror Isador Lipschuetz, he and his said attorneys were wholly
 unacquainted with the said Juror Isador Lipschuetz and had no means
 of knowing at said time how long he had been an inhabitant of Spo-
 kane County, or how long the said juror has resided in the State of
 Washington, or whether or not he the said juror was an elector of the
 State of Washington, but he, the said petitioner, relator and defend-
 ant herein and his sais attorneys relied wholly upon the truth of 
 the answer of said juror as to the length og his residence i Spo-
 kane County, Washington, and that he the said petitioner, relator
 and defendant above further aleges that neither he nor his
 said attorneys became aware of the fact that the said juror Isador
 Lipschuetz had not been a resident oand inhabitant of Spokane County,
 Washington for the periodof one year next preceeding the time that
 the said jurr was drawn, called and examined and that he the said
 juror was not an elector of the State of Washington at the said time,
 and was not competent to act as a juror in said cause, and had no
 knowledge whatever in relation thereto, until the 18th day of Novem-
 ber A. D. 1897, at which time one of the attorneys Del Cary Smith
 for the said petitioner, relator and defendant above named, received
 a letter from the town of Wallace, State of Idaho, informing him of 
 the fact that the said juror had voted in Wallace Precinct, No. 2 in 
Shoshone County in the State of Idaho, at the general election held
 in said Precinct on the 3rd day of November, A. D. 1896, and that
 he the said juror had not been a resident and inhabitatnt of Spokane
 County, Washington, for the period of one year next preceeding the 
 t$me when the said juror was drawn, called and examined; and that
 he the said petitioner, relator and defendant herein further alleges,
that neither he nor his said attorneys had any knowledge whatever at
the time of the said examination or at any time before the 18th day 
of November, A. D. 1897, that the said juror Isador Lipschuetz had
ever at any time resided in the State of Idaho, but relied upon
the truth of the answers of said juror that he the said juror had
resided in Spokane Coounty for about eight years preceeding said time. </p>
<p>10- And the said George Webster the petitioner, relator and
defendant herein further alleges, as his second assignment of error
of fact for which a Writ of Error Coram Nobis should be issued here-
in, that the said juror upon his said examination was asked the fol-
lowing questions.</p>
 <p>Q Do you know anything about the facts in this case?
 To which the said juror then and there answered Noair.
 Q Have you read anything about it in the paper?
 To which the juror answered I did.
 Q Did you read what purported to be the report of the shooting
 immediately after it occurred, in the paper?
 To which the said Juror answered, I read about it in the paper.
 Q From the reading of those reports, or from any other reason,
 did you form or express any opinion as to the guilt or 
 innocence of the defendant?
 To which the juror answered, No sir.
 Q Have you any opinion as to his guilt or innocence?
 To which the juror answered, No sir.
 </p>
 <p>And upon examination by Mr. Fenton of counsel for the
 said defendant, the said juror was asked to and he answered
 the folloeing questions as follows;
 Q Have you read anything about the case?
 A I have.
 Q When was that?
 A At the time the shooting occurred last spring.
 Q When was that?
 Q Sometime last sprng, when it look place.
 Q Have you talked about this case, State against Webster?
A Nothing but comment on what I read.
Q Have you talked with anyone about the case?
A No sir.
Q Now from what you have read about the case, and from what you
have heard about it, have you formed any opinion as to the guilt
or innocence of the defendant?
A I never form an opinion on newspaper talk.
Q Have you now the opinion as to the guilt or innocence of the 
defendant?
A More whatever.
Q Have you now such an opinion as require evidence to change 
 that opinion?
 A No sir.
 Q Do you know anything that would prevent you from being a fair
 and impartial juror?
 N No sir.
 Q Do you know that words prevent you from being a fair and 
 impartial juror?
 A Not to my knowledge.</p>
 <p>Whereas in truth the said juror Isador Lips-
  chuetz although pretending at the tim of said extremeisnm not to
know anything about the facts in the case and that he had formed 
no opinion as to the guilt or innocence of the said relator and pe-
titioner upon said charge, had in fact previous to the commencement
 of said trial of the said relator upon said information, fully dis-
 cussed the facts in said case and had in fact previous to his being 
 called as a juror in said case, formed and expressed an opinion that
  the said petitioner and relator was guilty of the offense charged in
 said nformation and in truth and in fact the said juror Isador Lips-
 chuetz upon his said examination as said juror, in order to remain
 upon said jury and in order to prevent the said defendaht from chal-
 lenging the said juror for cause on account of the expressed and im-
plied bias, testified and swore falsely touching the length of time
he the said juror had reided in Spokane County, and touching the
fact as to whether or not he the said juror had formed or expressed
an opinion as to the guilt of the said relator, and the said petition-
er and relator herein further alleges; that neither he nor his said
attorneys had any knowledge whatever of the prejudice and bias of
the said juror Isador Lipschuetz until aft erthe judgment and sen-
tence of the Court herein upon the verdict of the jury in said cause
but he the said petitioner and relator relied upon the testimony of
the said juror to the effect that he was a fair and impatial juror,
and that he had not formed or expressed any opinion as to the guilt 
or innocence of the said relation and peitioner <unclear></unclear>
  said relator alleges; that he was deceived and mislead by the fraud
  and false statements of the said Juror Isador Lipschuetz touching
  his qualifications to sit as a juror in said cause.
 </p>
 <p>11- And the said petitioner, relator and defendant herein for
 a third assignment of error of fact for which a Writ of Error Coram
 Nobis should issue herein, that after the said cause, the State of 
 Washington against George Webster, had been submitted to the jury
for their deliberation and while the said jury was deliberating up-
on their said verdict, he the said juror Isidor Lipschuetz
was in posession of facts within his own knowledge, and facts that
had not been testified to by any of the witnesses upon the trial of
such cause that conviced him, the said juror Isidor Lipschuetz be-
yound a reasonable doubt that the said petitioner, relator and defend-
and was guilty of the crime charged in the said information, and that
the said petitioner, relator and defendant herein should be hanged
for said offense. And the same petitioner, relator and defendant 
herein alleges, that neither he nor his said attorneys jad any know-
ledge whatever of the said statements made by the said Isidor Lips-
chuetz to one of the jury until after he the said petitioner, relat-
or and defendant herein had been sentenced by the above entitled
Court. </p>
 <p>11 1/2- And the said petitioner, relator and defendant above
  named further alleges; that at the time the said Isidor Lipschuetz
 voted Wallace Precinct No. 2 in the County of Shoshone in the 
 State of Idaho on the 3rd day of November, A. D. 1896, the laws of
 the State required that the said Isidor Lipschuetz should at
 said time, be a resident of the said State for the period
 of six months, which he the said Isidor Lipschuetz then and there
 well knew. And the said petitioner, relator and defendant above
 named, further alleges, that the said Juror Isidor Lipschuetz on the
 8th day of April, A. D. 1897, unlawfully registered as a voter in 
 the City of Spokane, State of Washington, and on the same day made
 and subscribed to the following oath at the time of his registration.</p>
 <p>Voters Affidavit</p>
 <p>from</p>
 <p>April 7th, 1897.</p>
 <p>Voters Affidavit</p>
 <p>from</p>
 <p>April 7th, 1897.</p>

 <p>to</p>
 <p>April 9th, 1897, </p>
 <p>State of Washington )</p>
 <p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Spokane. )</p>
 <p>I, Isidor Lipschuetz do solemly swear or affirm that
 I am a male person over twenty years eleven months and ten days
 of age, that I am a naturalized citizen of the United States;
 that I have been an actual permanent resident of the State of 
 Washington for eleven months and ten days last past, of the
 County of Spokane for seventy days last past, and of the pre-
 cinct ten days last past, and that I have not lost my civil
 rights by reason of being convicted of an infamous crime. </p>
 <p>Isidor Lipschuetz</p>
 <p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 8th day of April, 1897.</p>
 <p>L. F. Boyd,
 City Clerk and ex-
 officio Register.</p>
 <p>To which said oath, the said Isidor Lipschuetz unlawfully and
falsely swore that he had been a resident of the State of Washington
for a period of 11 months and ten days prior to the date of making
said oath, whereas in truth and in fact the said Isidor Lipschuetz
in less than five months and a half previous to the making of said
oath, had voted in Wallace Precinct No. 2 in Shoshone County in the
State of Idaho, as he then and there knew in truth and in fact
the petitioner, relator and defendant is informed and believes, and
therefore alleges, that the said Isidor Lipschuetz is not now a cit-
izen of the United States, and the said petitioner, relator and de-
fendant above named further alleges, that the time the said Juror
Isidor Lipschuetz was being examined touching his qualifications as
a juror at the time that he answered upon said examination, that
he had resided in the City of Spokane for the period of about eight
years, well knew that no paerson was elligible or qualified to act
or serve as a juror in the above entitled Court until he had been a 
continuous resident and inhabitant of Spokane County, Washington,
for the period of one year next preceedings the time when he was drawn
and called as a juror; and he the said juror Isidor Lipschuetz at
the said time of his said examination as juror well knew that he 
was not qualified to act and serve as a juror in saidcause and well
knowing said fact testified falsely in relation thereto in order to
deceieve and mislead this petitioner, relator and defendant and
his said attorneys.
</p>
<p>12- And the said petitioner, relator and defendant herein
further alleges, that the time for appeal in the said cause the
State of Washington against George Webster, expires on the 15th day
of Februrary, A. D. 1898, and that the said petitioner, relator and
defendant herein is now under sentence of the above entitled Court
to be hanged on the 4th day of February, A. D. 1898, and further al-
leges that he the said petitioner, relator and defendant had no op-
porunity whatever to present to, or bring to the attention of, this
Honorable Court any of the errors in fact alleged herein upon the
verdict of the jury in the said cause of the State of Washington
against George Webster, and further alleges, that had this Honorable
Court known of any of the errors of the fact alleged herein, prior to
the rendering of the said judgment and sentence by the said Court
that the judgement and sentence rendered herein would not have been 
made...</p>
<p>WHEREFORE? the petitioner and relator herein being the defend-
ant in the said action in the case of the State of Washington against
George Webster, prays that a Writ of Error Coram Nobis issue herein,
and that upon the hearing of said Writ of Error, the said petitioner,
relator and defendant above named, have the errors of facts assigned
herein tried, and decided by a jury, to be impanelled by this Court
and that if said jury shall find in favor of said petitioner, relat-
or and defendant, that he have a judgment and decree of this Court
recalling and revoking the judgment and sentence heretogore made and
rendered by this Court, adjudging the said defendant guilty of mur-
der in the first degree and sentencing him the said petitioner to
be hanged on the 4th day oof February, A. D. 1898, and that pending
the hearing and determinaton of this matter, the execution of the 
said sentence be stayed and arrested, and that the said petitioner
and relator have such other and further relief as the Court shall
deem just ti the end that speedy justice may be done him the said
relator.</p>
<p>Del Cary Smith
Fenton and O'Brien,
Attorneys for peti-
tioner, relator, and
defendant.</p>
<p>The State of Washington, )
) ss.
County of Spokane. )</p>
<p>I, George Webster being duly sworn say; that I am the pe-
titioner and relator herein and the defendant in the case No. 771 en-
titled the State of Washington, plaintiff, -vs- George Webster, de-
fendant. That I ha ve read the foregoig petition for a Writ of 
Error Coram Nobis, know the contents thereof and the allegation
therein are tru.</p>
<p>George Webster.</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 3rd day of January, A. D. 1898
</p>
<p>Del Cary Smith
N O T A R Y P U B L I C
for Washington, resid-
ing at Spokane.</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintif, )</p>
<p>-vs- )</p>
<p>George Webster, )</p>
<p>Defendant.)</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Petitioner in error,</p>
<p>-vs-</p>
<p>The State of Washington</p>
<p>Defendant in error</p>
<p> STATE OF IDAHO )</p>
<p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Shoshone.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of George Webster,</p>
<p>ss. for,</p>
<p>A writ of error Coram Nobis</p>
<p>Barry N. Hillard being first duly sworn 
on oath deposes and says:- That he is now and has been since
the second Monday in January, A. D. 1891, the duly elected
qualified and acting Clerk of the District Court ad ex-officio
Recorder, Auditor and Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners
in and for Shoshone County in the State of Idaho; that as such
Auditor and Clerk of the Board of County Commissioners he is 
the legal custodian of the Election Register of Wallave Pre-
cinct No.2 of Qualified Electors for the General Election
November 3rd, A. D. 1896, and of the Poll Book of said General
Election held on Tuesday, November 3rd, 1896, in Wallace Pre-
cinct No. 22, in Shoshone County, State of Idaho; that said
books are now in his office and in his custody; that in said
Election Register of Qualified Electors for said Wallace Pre-
cinct No.2 in Shoshone County, State of Idaho, the following
entry concerning one "Isador Lipschuetz", appears of record,
to-wit:-- </p>
<p>"Number 235, Isador Lipschuetz, Date of Registry, Oct 17th,
1896, Where born, Germand, Age 41, Description of Residence,
Idaho Hotel, Certificate of Naturalization exhibit, yes or no,
"No", remarks, "Sworn to them out in Philadelphia, 1876, and 
lost them in Idaho, in Summerfield Store, 1895."
That in said Poll Book for said General Election held Tuesday,
November 3rd, A. D. 1896, in Wallace No. 2 Precinct, Shoshone
County, State of Idaho, the following entry concerning one
"Isadore Lipschuetz" appears of record, to-wit:- </p>
<p>"Number and names of Elector voting, No. 2. "Isadore
Lipschuetz".</p>
<p>Affiant futher says that the aforesaid Poll Book is duly
attested by the Judges and Clerks of said General Election and
was the official return of said General Election to the Board
of Canvassers of said Election. And further affiant saith not.</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to 
before me this the 18th 
day of December, A. D. 1897.</p>
<p>Barry N. Hillard.</p>
<p>Winfield Ervin, Nortary Public.
Shoshone County, Idaho, residing at Murray.</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintif, )</p>
<p>-vs- )</p>
<p>George Webster, )</p>
<p>Defendant.)</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Petitioner in error,</p>
<p>-vs-</p>
<p>The State of Washington</p>
<p>Defendant in error</p>
<p> STATE OF IDAHO )</p>
<p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Shoshone.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of George Webster,</p>
<p>ss. for,</p>
<p>A Writ of error Coram Nobis</p>
<p>The State of Washington, )
) ss.
County of Spokane. )</p>
<p>I, Philip McNulty being duly sworn say; that I was one of the
duly appointed, acting, and qualified judges in and for Cannon Pre-
cinct at the City Election in the City of Spokane, in the State of 
Washington , on the 4th day of May , A. D. 1897, that I am acquianted
with Isidor Lipschuetz who registered in said Precinct on the 8th
day of April, A. D. 1897; that the said Isidor Lipschuetz  is a bar-
ber doing business on Main Street in the City of Spokane, Washington,
of about the age of 41 years and the same person who served as juror
in the cause of the State of Washington against George Webster, de-
fendant above named. That said Isidor Lipschuetz  voted at the said
City Election on the 4th day of May , A. D. 1897, in Cannon Precinct,
and that his name was put opposite the No. 64. That the said
Isidor Lipschuetz is the same person who made and subscribed and af-
fidavit and filed the same with the Clerk of the City of Spokane, to
the effect that he was a naturalized citizen of the United States,
and that he had been an actual permanent reisdent of the State of 
Washington, for 70 days prior to said time, and a resident of Can-
non Precinct 10 days prior to said time.</p>
<p>And affidavit further deposes and says; that on the 3rd day of
January , A. D. 1898, he saw the said Isidor Lipschuetz at his Barber-
Shop on Main Avenue, in Spokane, Washington, and then and there had
a conversation with the said Isidor Lipschuetz, and the said Isidor
Lipschuetz resided then and there stated to affiant that he, tha said Isidor
Lipschuetz resided in the town of Wallace, Idaho, and was in the Bar-
ber business in the said twon of Wallace, on the 3rd day of November,
1896; that he the said Isidor Lipschuetz voted in Wallace Precinct
on the 3rd day of November, A. D. 1896 at the Prseidential Election
held in the said Precinct on said date, and that he the said Isidor
Lipschuetz  also voted in Cannon Precinct on the 4th day of May ,A.D.
1897, at the City Election of the City of Spokane held in said Pre-
cinct on said date, and that he the said Isidoe Lipschuetz served as
a juror in the above entitled case, No. 771, that State of Washington
plaintiff, -vs- George Webster, defendant, in the above entitled
Court, and that he, the said Isidor Lipschuetz, who served upon the
said jury, was the same person who voted in
in Wallace Precinct on the 3rd day of November, A.D.
1896, and the same person who voted in Cannon Precinct in the City
of Spokane, on the 4th day of May, A. D. 1897.</p>
<p>Philip McNulty</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 3rd day of Jan'y, A.D. 1999</p>
<p>W. M. Byers, Notary Public
for Washington, residing at
Spokane, Washington.</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
<p>No. 771.</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintif, )</p>
<p>-vs- )</p>
<p>George Webster, )</p>
<p>Defendant.)</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Petitioner in error,</p>
<p>-vs-</p>
<p>The State of Washington</p>
<p>Defendant in error</p>
<p> The State of Washington )</p>
<p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Spokane.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the appli-
cation of George Webster, for</p>
<p>A Writ of Error Coram Nobis</p>
<p>I, L. F. Boyd, being duly sworn say; that I am now and have
been ever since the 21st day of May, A. D. 1896, the duly elected,
qualified and acting Clerk of the City of Spokane, Washington. That
as such Clerk I am the legal custodian of the Election Register of
Cannon Precinct in the Third Ward in and for the said City, of the
qualified electors for the City Election held in Spokane, Washington,
on the 4th day of May , A. D. 1897, and of the Poll Book of the said
City Election held on the 4th day of May , A.D. 1897, in the said Can-
non Precinct in the Third Wards of said City. That said books are
now in my office and in my custody. That in said Election Register
of qualified electors of said Cannon Precinct in said Third Ward of
said City, the following entry concerning one Isidor Lipschuetz app
pears of record, to-wit:-</p>
<p>" Registration Book, City of Spokane, Cannon Precinct, Third
Ward, Number Registered Votes 225, Registered Poll List, Cannon Pre-
cinct, City of Spokane, Washington, for the year 1897, date of reg-
istration April 8th, 1897, name, Isidor Lipschuetz, age 41 years, oc-
cupation, Barber, Place of residence #1204 Fourth Avenue,
Place of birth, Germany, Time of residence in State 7 years, in 
County 7 ears, in ward 7 months. Time and place of declaration of
intention of naturalization, Philadelphia, Pa. Date of Intention
of naturalization, A. D. 1876, Signature, Isador Lipschuetz."</p>
<p>That the said Poll Book for said City Election held on the 4th
day of May, A.D.1897, in said City and Ptecinct, in the Third Ward in
the City of Spokane, State of Washington, the following entry concern
ing one Isidor Lipschuetz appears of Record, to-wit:-</p>
<p>"Poll Book of elelction held in Cannon Precinct, City of Spo-
kane of Washinto n, on the 4th day of May, A. D. 1897at which
time A. Traut was inspector, J. H. Bishop and P. McNulty was Judges
and H. L. Cannon and J. A. Crowley were Clerks, or said election, the
following named person vating there, No .64, name of voter, Isidor
Lipschuetz."</p>
<p>Affiant further says that the aforesaid Poll Book is duly at-
tested by the Inspector, Judges, and Clerks of said City Election, and
was the official return of said City Election to the City Counsil in
and for the City of Spokane, Washington, acting as a Board of Can-
vassers at said election, and affiant further deposes and sayd that
at the time the said Isidor Lipschuetz registered on the said 8th 
day of April, A.D.1897, he and made subscribed the following oath,
to- wit:--</p>
<p>Voters Affidavit</p>
 <p>from</p>
 <p>April 7th, 1897.</p>
 <p>to</p>
 <p>April 9th, 1897,.</p>
 <p>State of Washington, )</p>
 <p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Spokane. )</p>
 <p>I, Isidor Lipschuetz do solemly swear or affirm that I am 
a male person over twenty years, eleven months ,and ten days of age, 
that I am a naturalized citizen of the United States, that I have 
been an actual permanent resident of the State of Washington for 
eleven months and ten days last past, of the County of Spokane for 
seventy days last past, and of the Precinct ten days last past, and 
that I have not lost my civil rights by reason of being convicted 
of an infamous crime. </p>
 <p>Isidor Lipschuetz.</p>
 <p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 8th day of April, 1897.</p>
 <p>L. F. Boyd,
 City Clerk and ex-
 officio-Register.</p>
<p>And further affiant saith not.</p>
<p>L. F. Boyd.</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 3rd day of January, a. D.1898.
</p>
<p>Del Cary Smith
N O T A R Y P U B L I C
for Washington, residing 
at Spokane, Washington.</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
<p>No. 771.</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintif, )</p>
<p>-vs- )</p>
<p>George Webster, )</p>
<p>Defendant.)</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Petitioner in error,</p>
<p>-vs-</p>
<p>The State of Washington</p>
<p>Defendant in error</p>
<p> The State of Washington )</p>
<p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Spokane.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the application of George Webster, 
for</p>
<p>A Writ of Error Coram Nobis</p>
<p>State of Washington, )</p>
 <p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Spokane. )</p>
<p>I, R. J. Frazier being duly sworn say; That I am one of the
jurors who tried the above named petitioner, relator and defendant.
That I am acquainted with Isidor Lipschuetz who was also one of the
jurors who tried the said petitioner, relator and defendant above
named. That I was present in the Court Room durinng the timw the said
Isidor Lipschuetz was being examined, touching his qualifications
to act and serve as a juror in said cause. And that in answer to
the questions propounded to the said Isidor Lipschuetz as to his
length of residence in Spokane County, he the said juror answered
that he had resided in said City of Spokane for about eight years,
and in answer to the following question; "Do you know anything that
would prevent you from being a fair and impartial juror?" he the said
juror Isidor Lipschuetz answered "Not to my knowledge." And in answe
to the following question, "Have you no such an opinion
as to require evidence to change that opinion?" the said juror answ
ered, "No, sir." Whereas in truth and in fact the said Isidor Lips-
chuetz while the jury were deliberating on the verdict of said cause,
stated to this affiant that he the said Isidor Lipschuetz was in pos-
session of facts within his own knowledge, and facts that have not 
been testified by any of the witnesses on trial of said cause
that convinced him the said Isidor Lipschuetz beyond a reasonable
doubt that the sad petitioner, relator and defendant above named was
guilty of the crime of murder and that he should be hanged for such
offense. And affiant further deposes and says, that the said juror
Isidor Lipschuetz during the deliberation of the jury, became and
was extremely bitter and malicious in his conduct toward said peti-
tionerm relator and defendant above named, and told this affiant
that he said Isidor Lipschuetz, had made up his mind that the 
said George Webster was guilty of said offense before any testimony
in the cause had been offered, and repeatedly said to the affiant
in the jury room "I would like to see Webster taken out of the
jail right now and hung without any further trial or delay of any
kind".</p>
<p>R. J. Frazier.</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 30th day of December, 1897.</p>
<p>Del Cary Smith
N O T A R Y P U B L I C
for Washington, residing 
at Spokane, Washington.</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
<p>No. 771.</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintif, )</p>
<p>-vs- )</p>
<p>George Webster, )</p>
<p>Defendant.)</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Petitioner in error,</p>
<p>-vs-</p>
<p>The State of Washington</p>
<p>Defendant in error</p>
<p> The State of Washington )</p>
<p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Spokane.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the application of George Webster, 
for</p>
<p>A Writ of Error Coram Nobis</p>
<p>State of Washington, )</p>
 <p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Spokane. )</p>
<p>I, James E. Fenton, being duly sworn say that I am one of the
attorneys for the above named petitioner, relator and defendant,
George Webster. That on the 3rd day of November, A.D. 1896, the fol-
lowing provision of the Constitution of the State of Idaho, was in
force and effect touching the qualifications of the electors.</p>
<p>"Articlee VI.</p>
<p>Section 2. Except as in this Article otherwise provided,
every male citizen of the United States, twenty-one years old,
who has actually resided in this State of Territory, for six 
months and in the County where he offers to vote, 30 days next
preceeding the day of election, is registered as provided by law
is a qualified elector; and until otherwise provided by the Leg-
islature, who have the qualifications prescribed in this Ar-
ticle, may continue to hold such school office and vote at such
school elections, as provided by the laws of Idaho Territory." </p>
<p>That the said Constitution of the State of Idaho, which the
said Sec. 2, of Art. 6 was a part, was adopted on the 6th day of
August, A. D. 1899 and the same is now and has ever since said
date been in full force and effect and has not been amended.
</p>
<p>James E. Fenton</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 3rd day of January, 1898.</p>
<p>Del Cary Smith
N O T A R Y P U B L I C
for Washington, residing 
at Spokane, Washington.</p>
<p>The State of Washington, )</p>
 <p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Spokane. )</p>
<p>I, Del Cary Smith being duly sworn say; that I am one of
the attorneys for the above and goregoing named petitioner, re-
lator and defendant named in the foregoing application and af-
fidavits for a Writ of Error Coram Nobis.</p>
<p>That on the 3rd day of January, A. D. L89 , at the hour of 3-30
o'clock P. M. I personally served upon John A. Pierce, Prosecuting
Attorney in and for Spokane County, State of Washington, full true
and correct copies of the foregoing application of George Webster
for a Writ of Error Coram Nobis, and the affidavits thereto attached,
by personally delivering to said John A. Pierce on said date, said
full true and correct copies.</p>
<p>Del Cary Smith</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 3rd day of January, 1898.</p>
<p>W. M. Byers
N O T A R Y P U B L I C
for Washington, residing 
at Spokane, Washington.</p>
<p>No. 771.
Filed January 3rd, 1898.
at 4-30 P. M.
J. R. Low, Clerk.
C. J. Donovan,</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
<p>No. 771.</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintif, )</p>
<p>-vs- )</p>
<p>George Webster, )</p>
<p>Defendant.)</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Petitioner in error,</p>
<p>-vs-</p>
<p>The State of Washington</p>
<p>Defendant in error</p>
<p> The State of Washington )</p>
<p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Spokane.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the application of George Webster, 
for</p>
<p>A Writ of Error Coram Nobis</p>
<p>State of Washington, )</p>
 <p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Spokane. )</p>
<p>I, William J. La Balley being duly sworn depose and say, that
I am a citizen of the United States and a resident of Spokane, Wash-
ington and over the age of twenty-one years. That I am acquainted
with Isidor Lipschuetz, who is a barger engaged in business at 515
Main Avenue in the City of Spokane, Washington, and have been ac-
quaited with the said Isidor Lipschuetz ever since the 4th day of 
November A. D. 1896. That I resided in the City of Wallace, State 
of Idaho from the 4th day of November, A. D. 1896 until the 27th dat
of December, A.D. 1896, continuously. That the said Isidor Lipschuet
who is now engaged in the barber business at 515 Main Avenue Spokane,
Washington, resided in the City of Wallace, State of Idaho, contin-
uously from the 4th day of November, A.D.1896, until the 27th day of
December, A.D.1896, and that I saw the said Isidor Lipschuetz almost
daily between the said 4th day of November, A.D. 1896 and the 27th
day of December, A.D.1896, at the City of Wallace? State of Idaho,
and he the said Isidor Lipschuetz was engaged in the barber business
at the City of Wallace during said time. That the said Isidor Lips-
chuetz who resided in the City of Wallace, State of Idaho from said
4th day of November, A.D.1896 until the 27th day of December, A.D. 1896
is the same Isidor Lipschuetz who served upob the jury in the above
entitled case of the Stateof Washigton -vs- George Webster and the
same person who is now engaged in the barber business at No. 515 Main
Avenue Spokane, Washington. That the said Isidor Lipschuetz had not
been an inhabitant of Spokane County, Washigton for the 
period of oe year next preceeding the 14th day of September, A.D.1897.</p>
<p>William J. LaValley,</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 8th day of January, 1898.</p>
<p>Del Cary Smith
N O T A R Y P U B L I C
for Washington, residing 
at Spokane, Washington.</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
<p>No. 771.</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintif, )</p>
<p>-vs- )</p>
<p>George Webster, )</p>
<p>Defendant.)</p>
<p>George Webster,</p>
<p>Petitioner in error,</p>
<p>-vs-</p>
<p>The State of Washington</p>
<p>Defendant in error</p>
<p> The State of Washington )</p>
<p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Spokane.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the application of George Webster, 
for</p>
<p>A Writ of Error Coram Nobis</p>
<p>State of Washington, )</p>
 <p>) ss.</p>
<p>County of Spokane. )</p>
<p>I, William Semper being duly swoen say; shat I am a citizen
of the United States and a resident of Spokane, Washington, and over
the age of twenty-one years. That I am acquainted with Isidor Lips-
schuetz, a barber now engaged in business at 515 Main Avenue Av-
enue in the City of Spokane, Washington. That I have been acquainted
with him the said Isidor Lipschuetz ever since the 1st day of March
A.D.1895. That the said Isidor  Lipschuetz ever since the 1st day of March
A.D.1895. That the said Isidor  Lipschuetz who us now engaged in the
barber business at 515 Main Avenue, Spokane, Washington, resided con-
tinuously in the State of Idaho for more than one year and a half im-
mediately preceeding the 7th day of October, A.D.1896 and was enfafed
in the barber business in the State of Idaho for the greater portion
of said time. That the said Isidor Lipschuetz who resided in the 
State of Idaho during said time is the same Isidor Lipschuetz who
is now engaged in business at 515 Main Avenue in said City of Spo-
kane, Washington. That said Isidor Lipschuetz had not been a resi-
dent of the City of Spokane, Washington, durng one yaer preceeding
the 14th day of September, A.D. 1897 and was not an elector of the said
State of Washington on the said 14th day of September, A.D. 1897.</p>
 <p>Wm. Semper</p>
 <p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 8th day of January, A.D. 1898.</p>
 <p>Del Cary Smith.</p>
 <p>Notary Public for Washington, residing at Spokane, Washington.</p>
 <p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
 <p>IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
 <p>No. 771.</p>
 <p>The State of Washington,</p>
 <p>Plaintif, )</p>
 <p>-vs- )</p>
 <p>George Webster, )</p>
 <p>Defendant.)</p>
 <p>George Webster,</p>
 <p>Petitioner in error,</p>
 <p>-vs-</p>
 <p>The State of Washington</p>
 <p>Defendant in error</p>
 <p> The State of Washington )</p>
 <p>) ss.</p>
 <p>County of Spokane.</p>
 <p>In the Matter of the application of George Webster, 
  for</p>
 <p>A Writ of Error Coram Nobis</p>
 <p>State of Washington, )</p>
 <p>) ss.</p>
 <p>County of Spokane. )</p>
 <p>I, James Flynn, being duly sworn say; that I am a citizen of
 the United States, now residing at Spokane, Washington, and over
 twenty-one years of age. That I am acquained with Isidor Lipschuet
 a barber now engaged in business at No. 515 Main Avenue Spokane,
 Washington, and that I have been acquainted with the said Isidor Lips-
 schuetz ever since the first day of NovemberA.D. 1894. That
 the said Isidor Lipschuetz, who is now engaged in business at No. 515
 Main Avenue Spokane, Washington, resided in the State of Idaho for
 two immediately prior to November 1s6, A.D. 1896, and was engaged
 in the barber business for a greater portion of the time mentioned.
 That the said Isidor Lipschuetz who resided in the State of Idaho,
 during the said two years prior to November 11st, 1896, is the
 same Isidor Lipschuetz who is now engaged in business as a barber at
 No. 515 Main Avenue Spokane, Washington, and is the same Isidor Lips-
 schuetz who was one of the trial jurors in the above entitled case of
 the State of Washington -vs- George Webster, and that said Isidor
 Lipschuetz had not been a resident of the City of Spokane, Spokane
 County, State of Washington, for one year prior to the 14th day of
 September, A.D.1897 and was not an elector of the State of Washington
 on said 14th day of September A.D.1897.</p>
 <p>Jas. Flynn.</p>
 <p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 8th day of January, A.D. 1989.</p>
 <p>Del Cary Smith.</p>
 <p>Notary Public for Washington, residing at Spokane, Washington.</p>
 <p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
 <p>IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
 <p>No. 771.</p>
 <p>The State of Washington,</p>
 <p>Plaintif, )</p>
 <p>-vs- )</p>
 <p>George Webster, )</p>
 <p>Defendant.)</p>
 <p>George Webster,</p>
 <p>Petitioner in error,</p>
 <p>-vs-</p>
 <p>The State of Washington</p>
 <p>Defendant in error</p>
 <p> The State of Washington )</p>
 <p>) ss.</p>
 <p>County of Spokane.</p>
 <p>In the Matter of the application of George Webster, 
  for</p>
 <p>A Writ of Error Coram Nobis</p>
 <p>State of Washington, )</p>
 <p>) ss.</p>
 <p>County of Spokane. )</p>
 <p>I, Harry Swift being duly sworn say; that I am a citizen of 
the State of Idaho, and that I am over twenty-one years of age.
That I am acquainted with Isidor Lipschuetz, a barber now engaged in
 business at 515 Main Avenue, Spokane, Washington. That I have been
 acquainted with said Isidor Lipschuetz ever since the 1st day of Oc-
 tober, A.D.1895. That said Isidor Lipschuetz, who is now engaged in 
 business at No. 515 Main Avenue, Spokane, Washington, resided contin
 uously in the City of Wallace, State of Idaho from the 1st day of
 October, A.D.1895 until the 20th day of June, A.D.1896, at which time
 said affiant left the City of Wallace temporarily. That from said
 1st day of October, A.D.1895 until 20th day of June, A.D. 1896, said
 Isidor Lipschuetz was engaged in the barber business at
 said City of Wallace, Idaho. That said Isidor Lipschuetz who
 resided in said City of Wallace during said time,
 to-wit:- from October 1st, 1895 until June 20th, A.D. 1896, is the
 same Isidor Lipschuetz who is now engaged in business at No. 515 Main
 Avenue in Spokane, Washington, and is the same Isidor Lipschuetz who
 sat upon the jury in the trial of the above case of the State of Wash
 ington -v-George Webster in September, A.D.1897.</p>
<p>Harry Swift.</p>
 <p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 8th day of January, A.D. 1898.</p>
 <p>Del Cary Smith.</p>
 <p>Notary Public for Washington, residing at Spokane, Washington.</p>
 <p>11 1/2 A. That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken 
 in the said case in the said Superior Court, that the said Petition
 for a Writ of Error Coram Nobis came on regularly for hearing before
 Hon. L. H. Prather, as Judge of the said Superior Court; upon the
 demurrer of the State of Washington thereto, which said demurrer is 
 in writing, the words and figures as following, to-wit:-</p>
 <p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
 <p>IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
 <p>No. 771.</p>
 <p>The State of Washington,</p>
 <p>Plaintif, )</p>
 <p>-vs- )</p>
 <p>George Webster, )</p>
 <p>Defendant.)</p>
 <p>George Webster,</p>
 <p>Petitioner in error,</p>
 <p>-vs-</p>
 <p>The State of Washington</p>
 <p>Defendant in error</p>
 <p> The State of Washington )</p>
 <p>) ss.</p>
 <p>County of Spokane.</p>
 <p>In the Matter of the application of George Webster, 
  for</p>
 <p>A Writ of Error Coram Nobis</p>
 <p>In the Matter of the application of George Webster,
 for
 A Writ of Error Coram Nobis</p>
 <p>Comes now the State of Washington and demurs to the affidavit,
 petition and application of George Webster, affiant and petitioner
 herein, and for cause of dermurrer avers,</p>
 <p>That the said affidavit, petition and application do not state
 facts sufficient to justify or sustain any further proceedings herein</p>
 <p>WHEREFORE, The State of Washington prays that said affidavit,
 petition and application be now dismissed.</p>
 <p>John A? Pierce
 Prosecuting Attorney</p>
 <p>That upon the argument of said demurrer the same was sus-
 tained and thereupon the said petition of George Webster for a Writ
 of Error Coram Nobis was dismissed. To which order sustaining said
 demurrer and dismissing said petition, the said petitioner than and
 there excepted, and an exception was allowed.</p>
 <p>Twelfth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and 
 taken in said cause, that the said petitioner herein George Webster 
 appealed from the said judgement and sentence to the Supreme Court
 of the State of Washington, znd thereafter such proceedings were
 had taken in said cause in the said Supreme Court, of the
 State of Washington, that the said Supreme Court of the State of
 Washington, on the 18th day of April, A.D. 1899, made and rendered
 its decision affirming the said judgment and sentence of the said
 Superior Court.</p>
 <p>Thirteenth- That thereafter such proceedi ngs were had and
 taken in said cause in said Supreme Court, that the said petitioner
 George Webster did on the 18th day of May, A.D.1899, and within
 the time prescribed by the rules of the said Supreme Court and the laws
 of the State of Washington, filed a partition for a rehearing in the
 said Supreme Court, and thereafter such proceedings were had and
 taken in said Supreme Court, that the said petition for a re-
 taken in said Supreme Court, that the said petition for a re-
 hearing was, on the 7th day of June, A.D. 1899, denied.</p>
 <p>Fourteenth- That thereafter such proceedings were hadand
 taken in said cause in the Superior Court, that the Hon. Leander H.
 Prath er, as Judge of the said Superior Court, did on the day 
 of A.D.1899, make an order fixing Friday, the 28th day
 of July, A.D.1899, at the Spokane Counrt Jail in Spokane,Washington
f or the execution of the said petitioner, and as the time and
place for carrying into effect the said judgment and sentence and
place for carrying into effect the said judgment and sentence and
did, at said time, issue a death warrant commanding and directing
the sheriff for Spokane County, Washington, to execute and hang the
said petitioner on the 28th day of July, A.D.1899, which said order
and death warrant is in writing in words and figures as follows, to-
wit; </p>
 <p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
 <p>IN AND FOR THE COUNTY OF SPOKANE.</p>
 <p>THE STATE OF WASHINGTON
 </p>
 <p>Plaintiff, </p>
 <p>W A R R A N T .</p>
 <p>vs.</p>
 <p>George Webster</p>
 <p>Defendant.</p>
 <p>To R. D. Speck, sheriff of Spokane County, State of Wash-
 ington, GREETING:</p>
 <p>W H E R E A S, as a day of the Superior Court of Spokane
 County, before the Honorable Leander H. Prather, judge of the said
 court, begun and held at the City of Spokane in the said county of
 Spokane, on the 13th day of May, 1897, in open court and in due
 form of law, the prosecuting attorney for Spokane County, State of
 Washington, presented again the said defendant, George Webster,
 an informaation charging him with the crime of murder in the first de
 gree in that he, the said defendant George Webster, in said county,
 and state on to-wit, the 6th day of May, 1897, then and there un-
 lawfully, feloniously and purposely and of his deliberate and pre-
 meditated malice, did kill Lise C. Aspland
 with a gun commonly called a revolver which he, the said George Webster, then and there
 held in hi s hand, and</p>
 <p>WHEREAS, this case came on regularly for hearing in the Super-
 ior Court of the State of Washington in and for the county of Spo-
 kane, on the 13th day of May, 1897, the said court being in session
 and the said defendant bei ng present in person in open court and
 represented by his attorneys Messrs J. E. Fenton and Del Cary Smith
 and the state of Washington being represented by the prosecuting
 attorney for the said Spokane County;</p>
 <p>Thereupon the said defendant George Webster, in open
 court and dult arraigned under said infor ation and asled to plead
 thereto and thereupon the said defendan, George Webster, pleaded
 not guilty to the crime in said information charged. And</p>
 <p>WHEREAS, on the 17th day of September, 1897, in due course of
 law, a jury of twelve good and lawful men, to-wit: C. Thomas,
 William P. Gould, Thomas James, H. W. Doane, J. F. Roadnight, I,
Lipschuetz, J. E. Valentine, U. H. Morgan, N. C. Hair, John Q. Van
 Ness, William Gill, and N. J. Frasier were drawn from the body of
 said Spokane County, and were duly selected, accepted and impanell-
 ed and swoen to well and truly try and true deliverance make of
 their verdict in the case of the State of Washington plain-
 tiff, and George Webster, defendant, according to the evidence and
 the instructions of the court, and</p>
 <p>WHEREAS, after hearing the evidence in said case and the argu-
 ment of counsel and after hearing and receiving the instructions of
 the court, the said jury did retire in charge of sworn officers to
 deliberate on their verdict in said cause, and thereafter and on,
 to-wit, the 25th day of September, 1897, the said jury did return
 and render into open court, the said defendant George Webster being
 then and there personally present in open court, with his said at-
 torneys, the following verdict, to-wit:</p>
 <p>Case No. 771 Verdict of Guilty</p>
 <p>We, the jury in the case of the Stateof Washington, plaintiff
 vs. George Webster defendant, find the defendant, George Webster,
 guilty as charged in the information.</p>
 <p>Spokane, Washington, September 25th, 1897.</p>
 <p>C. Thomas, Foreman</p>
 <p>Whereas, thereafter and on to-wit, the 27th day of September,
 1897, the said defendant George Webster by his said attorneys gave
 and filed in said court notice of motion for a new trial herein and
 motion form a new trial herein, and on the 15th day of November,
 1897, the said defendant George Webster being then and there per-
 sonally present with his said attorneys in open court, the said mo-
 tion for a new trial was overruled by the said court and thereafter
 to-wit, on the 15th day of November, 1897, with his said attorneys
 being personally present in open court, the said defendat George
 Webster by his said attorneys filed a motion for arrest of judgment
 herein and the said defendant on the 15th day of November, 1897,
 with his said attorneys being personally present in open court the
 said motion in arrest of judgment was overruled by the said court;
 and,</p>
 <p>WHEREAS, the said court did on the 15th day of Noveber, 1897
fix the 16th day of November, 1897, as the day on which the said
court would make, render and enter judgment and sentence upon said
verdict, and</p>
<p>WHEREAS, on the 16th day of November, 1897, the said court be-
ing in session and the said defendant George Webster being personal-
ly present with his said attorneys Del Cary Smith in open court and
the said court informedthe said defendant George Webster of the said
verdict of the said jury, and then and there asked the said defend-
ant George Webster if he the said defendan t, had any cause to show
why the said court should not pronounce, make and render and enter
judgment and sentence of the said courtupon the said verdict and
there being no cause shown by or on behalf of the said defendant
George Webster, the said court did then and there pronounce, make
render and enter upon the said verdict the following judgment and 
sentence, to-wit;</p>
<p>"Upon the verdict  of the jury in this cause finding you the
said defendant, George Webster, guilty of murder in the first de-
gree for the killing of Lise C. Aspland, the judgment of this
court is that you are guilty of the crime of murder in the first
degree:</p>
<p>Therefore, the judgment and sentence of this court is that you
the said defendant, George Webster, be taken hence by the sheriff
of said county to the jail of the said county and there safely
and securely kept until a day and time certain to be fixed in
the warrant for your execution, and that upon said day, between
the hours of 6 o'clock and 10 o'clock in the forenoon of said day
so to be fixed, you be taken from said jail by the said sheriff to
the place to be by im selected and provided within the yard of the
jaill of the said county in the said city of Spokane, county of Spokane,
State of Washington and that you then and there by the said sheriff
be hanged by the neck until you are dead." </p>
<p>WHEREAS, thereafter an appeal was taken by said defendant to
the Supreme Court of the State of Washington, and at the May session
A.D.1899, the Supreme court of the State of Washington begun and
holden in Olympia, Washington, on the second Monday in May, A.D. 1899
it being the 8th day of the said month, among other the following
was had; and done, to-wit: The following Judgment was rendered and
duly entered of record:</p>
<p>"On Wednesday, June 7th, 1899, the case of the state of
Washington, respondent, vs. George Webster, appellant, No. 3ii3,
this cause having been heretofore submitted to the court upon the t
transcript of the record of the Superior Court of Spokane County,
and upon the argument of counsel, and the court having fully con-
sidered te same and being duly advised in the premises and having
filed its opinion in writing, it is now on this 7th day of June,
A.D.1899, on motion of the prosecuting attorney of Spokane County,
of counsel for respondent, considered, adjudged and decreed that
the judgmet of the said Superior Court be and the same is hereby
affirmed with costs, the petition for rehearing denied, and the
said state of Washington have and recover of and from the said
George Webster, the costs of this action taxed and allowed at sixty
four and 20/100 dollars, and execution issue therefor.</p>
<p>And it is further ordered that said cause be remitted to 
the said Superior Court of Spokane County, Washington, for further
proceeding in accordance with the opinion herein filed." And</p>
<p>WHEREAS, said remittitur from the said supreme court was
duly received and filed in the sad Superior Court of Spokane County
Washington, at 9.35 A.M. on the 20th day of June, 1899, and</p>
<p>WHEREAS, on the 15th day of June, 1899, the court did fix
Saturday June 17th, 1899, as the day on which the said court would
ddraw the death warrant int this case and deliver the same to the
sheriff. And this being the said 17th day of June, 1899, and the
defendanr George Webster being present in open court, with hs
counsel J. E. Fenton, and Del Cary Smith,</p>
<p>NOW THEREFORE, it is by the court ordered and in the name
of the State of Washington, you, R.D. Speck, sheriff of Spokane Couny
Washington, are hereby commanded to take the said George Webster on
the 28th day of July, 1899, between the hours of 6 o'clock and 10
o'clock in the forenoon of said day, to the said place of execution
in the yard of the jail of the said Spokane County, and that you,
George Webster, defendant, by the necknuntil he is dead, and that
you the said R. R. Speck,sheriff aas aforesaid, make due execution and
return of this warrant and your proceedings thereon as required by law.</p>
<p>Given under my hand and the seal of the said court this 17th
day of June, A. D.1899.</p>
<p>Leander H. Prather
Judge of the Superior Court of
the state of Washington, in and
for Spokane County.</p>
<p>(SEAL)
Attest: James A. Drain Clerk of
the Superior Court of the State of 
Washington in and for Spokane Co.</p>
<p>No.</p>
<p>Fifteenth- That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken
in the said cause, that the said petitioner did on the 14th day of
July, A.D.1899, make and file with and presented to the Hon.
John R. Rogers, Fovernor of the State of Washington, his petition
for a commutation of the said sentence of death to that of impris-
onment for life, and thereafter such proceedings were had and taken
in said cause, that the said John R. Rogers, as governor of the 
State of Washington, dened the petition for a commutation
of said sentence.</p>
<p>Sixteenth- That the said petitioner has no other remedy.</p>
<p>Seventeenth- That the said petitioner (page 63)</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>