<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0156.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Fred S. Walton v. John G. Boyle. </title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J" xml:id="sjs">Salma Silva</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0156.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Fred S. Walton v. John G. Boyle. </title>
<date when="1901-09-09">September 9, 1901</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1901-09">September 1901</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Dilley, A. L.</term>
<term>Fechter, O. A.</term>
<term>Hough, George S.</term>
<term>Lince, W. I.</term>
<term>Taggard, J. A.</term>
<term>Moore, A. N.</term>
<term>Doust, H. B.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>North Yakima</term>
<term>Portland Oregon</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Walton, Fred S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Boyle, John G.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>H. J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Whilson, Edward</persName>
<persName>Snyder, Vestal</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
<persName>Fuller, Melville W.</persName>
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The United States Circuit Court, Northern Division, State of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Northern Division, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<ab>In the Circuit Court of the United States, Ninth Judicial Circuit,
District of Washington, Northern Division.</ab>

<ab>In the matter of F. S. Walton, on
habeas corpus.</ab>

<p>John G. Boyle makes return to the writ of Habeas Corpus served
upon him by A. L. Dilley, Deputy United States Marshal for the
District of Washington, upon the 7th day of September, 1901, in the
above entitled matter, which writ is hereto attached, and respectfull
shows:</p>

<p>1. That he is the regularly elected, qualified and acting city
Marshal of the City of North Yakima.</p>

<p>2. That the City of North Yakima now is and was at all times hereinafter
mentioned, duly incorporated under the laws of the State of
Washington as a City of the third class.</p>

<p>3. That on the 4th day of April, 1898, the City Council of of said
City of North Yakima, passed an ordinance No. 265, entitled an
ordinance in relation to licenses, which ordinance was on the 5th
day of April, 1898, duly approved by O.A. Fechter, Mayor of said
City and which ordinance was thereafter duly published <del>and</del> in pursuance
of law and recorded in the ordinance books of said City, a
copy of which is hereto attached, marked exhibit "A"and made a part
of this return. That on the 3 day of September, 1900, the City
Council of said City of North Yakima, passed an ordinance No. 298,
entitled an ordinance to amend sections 1 and 10 of said ordinance
No. 265, entitled an ordinance relating to licenses aprroved April
5th, 1898, which ordinance relating to licenses approved April
5th, 1898, which ordinance was duly approved on the 4th day of
September, 1900, by George S. Hough, Mayor Pro tem, and which ordinance
was thereafter published and recorded in the ordinance book
of said City of North Yakima, a copy of which is hereto attached,
marked exhibit "B" and made a part of this return.</p>

<p>4. That said ordinances now are and ever since the date of their</p>

<pb/>

<p>passage, approval and publication, have been in full force and effect</p>

<p>5. That on the 5th day of September, 1901, the above named
relator, F. S. Walton, in violation of said ordinances and without
first having procured a license therefor, so to do, did unlawfully
hawk certain goods, wares and merchandise, to-wit:</p>

<p>Quaker herbs in the City of North Yakima, by offering said
quaker herbs for sale in said City and by selling the same at public
out-cry in a public place therein as more fully appears from the
complaint for the violation of said ordinances, a copy of which is
to this return attached.</p>

<p>6. That thereupon a complaint, for the violation of said ordinances
duly verified by Vestal Snyder, City Attorney of said City, was
duly filed on the 5th day of September, 1901, with W. I. Lince who
at the time was the duly appointed, <del>or</del> qualified and acting police
justice of said City of North Yakima, a copy of which complaint
with the endorsements thereon, is hereto attached, marked exhibit
"C" and made a part of this return.</p>

<p>7. That thereupon, on the said 5th day of September, 1901, the
said police justice duly issued a warrant for the apprehension and
arrest of said relator, which warrant was duly placed in thehands of
this respondent and thereupon on the said 5th day of September, 1901,
pursuant to the commands therein contained, this respondent duly
arrested and took into custody said relator and took him before said
police justice and thereupon, upon the application of said relator,
a change of venue was granted from said police justice to J. A.
Taggard, Justice of the Peace of North Yakima Precinct, in Yakima
County, State of Washington, being the nearest Justice of the Peace.</p>

<p>8. That afterwards, on the 6th day of September, 1901, said cause
came on regularly for trial before said J. A. Taggard, Justice of
the Peace, as aforesaid, and after the hearing thereof said relator
being present in person and by his counsel, a judgment was rendered
in said Court and cause, whereby it was considered that said relator
pay a fine of Five Dollars, together with the costs of said action,
a copy of which judgment is hereto attached, marked exhibit "D"</p>

<pb/>

<p>and made a part of this return.</p>

<p>9. that said relator having failed and refused to pay said fine
and costs, a commitment was issued by said J. A. Taggard, Justice
of the Peace, as aforesaid, and placed in the hands of this respondent
and thereupon by virtue of the commands therein contained, did
take said relator into custody on the 6th day of September, 1901,
and placed him in the City jail of the City of North Yakima, a copy
of which commitment is hereto attached, marked exhibit "E" and made
<del></del> a part of this return.</p>

<p>10. That said relator so remained in jail until the 7th day of
September, 1901, at the hour of ten o'clock A.M., this respondent
discharged said relator from custody and never since said time has
the said John G. Boyle had the custody or control of said relator
nor has he imprisoned him nor restrained him of his liberty nor has
he had the said relator in his possession, custody or power since
said date and he now has no power, custody or control over him. </p>

<p>11. Said respondent further shows that said writ of habeas corpus
was served upon him on the 7th day of September, 1901, at the hour
of four o'clock P.M. That respondent had no notice, <del>power</del> prior to
said date and did not at said date, nor at any other time prior to
the time the same was served upon him, have any notice or knowledge
that said writ or any writ of habeas corpus has been issued.</p>

<p>12. That this respondent does not hold said relator by virtue of 
said commitment or by process of any Court whatever but pursuant to
the commands in said writ of habeas corpus named, the respondent
with the full consent and at the express request of said relator and
with the full knowledge on the part of the said relator, of all the
facts herein stated, and in order to obey said writ of habeas corpus
in so far as it was in the power of this respondent so to do, has
brought said relator into this Court by virtue of said writ of habeas
corpus and not otherwise and has brought <add>said relator</add> into Court at his express
request and with his full consent and with his full knowledge, that
he was not detained under commitment aforesaid nor under process of 
any other Court of <del>this <unclear></unclear></del> and this respondent now</p>

<pb/>
<p>avers that since he released and discharged said relator from custody
on the said 7th day of September, 1901, that he has <del>restr</del> not restrained
him of his liberty and that he has not had him under his 
power, possession or control.</p>

<pb/>

<p>13-- Respondent further avers that said relator is 
engaged in the sale of what are generally known as patent
medicines; that relator represents himself as a Quaker
Doctor, and that he hawks and vends said medicines by travelling
from town to town and offering the same at public
outcry upon the streets and public places of various towns
visited by him; that said relator carries with him a travelling
troup of players, and gives open air concerts for 
the purpose of attracting corwds of people, in order to be
able to more readily sell his wares; that he is engaged in
the sale of what is known as "Quaker Herbs", "Pile Remedies"
and shaving soap; that the method of conducting the business
of said relator attracts large crowds of people on the
streets, thoroughfares and public places where said business
is carried on; that by reason thereof the said City of North
Yakima is put to large additional expense in policing said
city and preserving the public peace and good order therein.</p>

<p>14-- Said relator, as this respondent is informed and
believes and therefore alleges, sells large quantities of
the medicines and nostrums aforesaid at an enormous profit,
and this respondent averts that said relator can well afford
from the profits made and the quantitites of medicine sold
to pay the license in said ordinance mentioned.</p>

<p>15-- That said relator ships said medicines and nostrums
into the State of Washington in original packages, and
thereafter and when the same are offered for sale, he breaks
said packages and offers the same for sale at retail in
single packages and not in the packages so shipped in.</p>

<p>16-- Respondent further making return to said writ, denies
that said relator is unlawfully imprisoned, detained and
fined or restrained of his liberty by respondent at North</p>

<pb/>

<p>Yakima or elsewhere; denies that he has any knowledge or 
information sufficient to form a belief as to whether said
relator is a resident and citizen of the City of Portland
in the State of Oregon; denies that he has any knowledge or
information sufficient to form a belief as to whether the
trade mark "Quaker Medicine" has been filed by the relator
and as to whether he ahs taken out a trade mark under the
laws of the United States; denies that he has any knowledge
or information sufficient to form a belief as to what said
medicine is composed of, and as to whether it is not composed
of the products of the soil or vegetables of Yakima County;
denies that he has any knowledge or information sufficient
to form a belief as to whether the component parts of said
medicine and quaker herbs and nostrums are grown in various
States of the United States other than the State of Washington;
denies that said relator was detained by respondent
under said committment at the time of the granting of said
writ; denies that the sum of Four Hundred Dollars ($400.00)
is a prohibitive and unreasonable license, and that Twenty-
five Dollars ($25.00) per day is a prohibitive and unreasonable
license; denies that the net profits from the sale of
said medicine would not equal said license; and denies
that the effect of said license is to prohibit petitioner
from doing business in the City of North Yakima; and denies
that it infringes his right under the Constitution of the
United States to engage in business in North Yakima upon
equal terms with the persons selling the products of Yakima
County, and that it interferes with the right of commerce
as guaranteed by the Constitution of the United States
between the citizens of different states; denies that said
ordinance is in violation of the Constitution and laws of the</p>

<ab>2</ab>

<pb/>

<p>United States; denies that said ordinance discriminates
against the residents and products of all other portions of
the United States in favor of the products of Yakima County;
denies that said ordinance is in violation of the right of
commerce; denies that it is a violation of the Constitution
of the United States which gives to the citizens of each
State of the Union like privileges, rights and immunities
in every other State of said Union had by the citizens
of said State.</p>

<pb/>

<p>14. That respondent respectfully protests against the jursidiction
of this Court and respectfully avers that the matters and things
aforesaid do not show a violation of the constitution of the laws
of the United States.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE respendent prays that said writ of habeas corpus be
quashed and that said petition be dismissed and that he recover his 
costs.</p>

<ab>Jno G Boyle</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>State of Washington,
County of King,</ab>

<ab>ss:</ab>

<p>John G. Boyle being duly sworn deposes and 
says that he is the respondent above named; that he has read and 
knows the contents of the foregoing return and the same is true as 
he verily believes.</p>

<ab>Jno G Boule</ab>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me 
this 9th day of September, 1901.</p>

<ab>A. N. Moore</ab>
<ab><del>Notary Public for Washington,
residing at North Yakima, Wn..</del>

Deputy Clerk U.S. District Court,
District of Washington.</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>ORDINANCE NO. 265.</ab>

<ab>An Ordinance in Relation to Licenses.</ab>

<ab>The City Council of the City of North Yakima do Ordain as
Follows:</ab>

<p>Section 1. That it shall be <add>un</add>lawful for any person, firm, corporation
or company to engage in, prosecute or carry on any business,
trade, profession or occupation within the corporate limits of the
City of North Yakima, for which a license is required without having
procured a license theretofore as hereinafter provided.</p>

<p>Section 2. It shall be lawful for any person, firm, corporation
or company to conduct, manage or superintend any show or exhibition
within the limits of the City of North Yakima or within one mile
of the corporate limits thereof for which a license is required
without having obtained a license therefor as hereinafter provided.</p>

<p>Section 3. That the fees or rates of license for the business,
trades, professions and occupations hereinafter named, be and the
same are hereby established as hereinafter set forth.</p>

<p>Section 4. Any person who shall keep or use for hire, within the
City of North Yakima, any dray, cart, truck, wagon, carriage, coach,
express wagon, hack, cab, gurney, omnibus or other vehickle, shall
pay a license fee of twelve dollars per year for each horse or other
animal kept for or used in such business in connection with a vehickl
to be drawn by one horse or other animal, and twenty dollars per
years for each pair of horses or other animals kept for or used in
such business in connection with a vehickle to be drawn by two
horses or other animals, and in case any such person shall keep or
use for hire any vehickle to be drawn by more than two horses or
other animals, a further fee of five dollars shall be required for
each horse or other animal in addition to two. Such person shall
pay said fee for one year in advance and such person shall receive a
license to do business as a licensed teamster for one year from the
date of said license and such license shall state that he is entitled
to use in said business the number of horses or other animals therein
specified, stating the number of single animals and the number of</p>

<pb/>

<p>pairs for which the license fee has been paid. If any person shall
obtain a license under this section and shall thereafter increase 
the number of horses or other animals used by him in said business
he shall obtain a license for such additional horses or other animals
in the same manner as the original license and at the same rate as
hereinbefore required for each horse or other animal in addition to
two, provided that this ordinance shall not apply to livery stables
so far as concerns the ordinary business of such stables.</p>

<p>Section 5. All shows and exhibitions hereafter conducted within
the City of North Yakima or within one mile of the corporate limits
thereof shall be licensed at the following rates:</p>

<p>For each circus and menagerie and sideshows exhibiting on the same 
ground, $100.00.</p>

<p>For any other show or exhibition, Five Dollars, provided that
nothing herein contained shall apply to church fairs or other 
charitable entertainments.</p>

<p>Section 6. Auctioneers shall pay a license of Twenty Dollars per
year, provided that a license may issue for a shorter period at the
rate of $2.00 per day and no license shall authorize any person
other than the licensee named therein to carry on such busines,
provided that a license may issue to a partnership authorizing one
member of such firm to engage in the occupation aforesaid at any
given time and no more.</p>

<p>Section 7. Each hawker or pedler of goods, wares and merchandise
shall pay a license fee of $400.00 per quarter, provided that such 
license may be taken our for a term less than one quarter at the rate
of $25.00 per day, and provided that no person shall be required to
take out a license for peddling newspapers, books, magazines, fruit,
bread, meat, milk, ice or other products of Yakima County.</p>

<p>Section 8. Every pawnbroker shall pay a license fee of twenty
five dollars per quarter and license shall be issued for a shorter
period than one quarter.</p>

<p>Section 9. Every person who posts or tacks up, bills or advertisements of
circuses, menageries, shows, operas, concerts, theatres, exhibitions
and other public amusements, tobacco, baking powder, patent medicine</p>

<pb/>

<p>and other commercial advertisements, shall pay a license fee of ten
dollars per year.</p>

<p>Section 10. The license fee for each riding gallery, commonly
called merry-go-round, shall be twenty-five dollars per day.</p>

<p>Section 11. The license fee for each knife-board, cane-rack, ring
board or other like device shall be five dollars per day.</p>

<p>Section 12. The license fee for each of the following businesses,
trades, professions and occupations shall be as follows:</p>

<p>For each doll-rack or other device for throwing balls or other
projectiles for a prize, $1.00 per day.</p>

<p>For each grapho-phone, photograph or other electrical machine
one dollar per day or five dollars per month.</p>

<p>For each striking machine, lifting machine or other device for
testing strength one dollar per day.</p>

<p>For long tester or other like machine one dollar per day.</p>

<p>For each shooting gallery, ten dollars per month.</p>

<p>Section 13. Any person desiring a license to engage in or carry
on any business, trades, profession or other occupation, hereinbefore
mentioned, shall have a license granted him by presenting to the
City Clerk the receipt of the City treasureer for the amount fixed by
this ordinance as a license therefore, which receipt shall set forth
the kind of business for which a license is desired and no license
shall be issued by the City Clerk until such license fee has been
paid to the City treasurer, and every license shall be granted for
the period specified in this ordinance and shall have the seal of 
the city affixed thereto and specify the business, trade, profession
or occupation for which the same is granted, the name and place of 
business of the person or persons taking out the same and the time
for which such license is to run and the date of granting such license
and no license shall be transferrable except on order of the City
Council.</p>

<p>Section 14. Any person who shall violate any of the provisions of
this ordinance shall be deemed guilty of the misdemeanor and upon
conviction thereof, shall be punished by a fine of not less than ten
nor more than one hundred dollars.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Section 15. All ordinances or parts of ordinances in conflict
with this ordinance are hereby repealed.</p>

<p>Passed the Council April 4th, 1898.</p>

<ab>Attest:
H. B. Doust,
City Clerk.</ab>

<ab>Approved April 8, 1898.
O.A. Fachter,
Mayor.</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Ex. "B."</ab>

<ab>ORDINANCE NO. 298.</ab>

<p>An Ordinance to amend Sections in 1 and 10 of Ordinance No. 265
entitled "An Ordinance relating to Licenses", approved April 5, 1898.</p>

<p>The City Council of the City of North Yakima do ordain as
follows:</p>

<p>Section 1. That section 1 of Ordinance No. 265 entitled "An
Ordinance relating to Licenses", approved April 5, 1898, is hereby
amended to read as follows: Section 1. That it shall be unlawful
for any person or the officers and employes of any firm, corporation
or company, to engage in, prosecute or carry on any business, trade 
profession or occupation within the corporate limits of the City of 
North Yakima, for which a license is required without having firest
procured a license therefor as hereafter provided and any person 
and the officers and employes of any firm, corporation or company
who shall violate any of the provisions of this ordinance shall be
deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon convinction thereof shall be
fined not less than Five Dollars nor more than Three Hundred Dollars
for each offense.</p>

<p>Section 2. That section 10 of Ordinance No. 265, entitled "An 
Ordinance relating to Licenses", approved April 5th, 1898, be amended
to read as follows: "Section 10. The License fee for <del>which</del> each
riding gallery commonly called a Merry-go-round, shall be fifteen 
dollars per day, provided however that if a license for such riding
gallery or merry-go-round is taken out for ten days or more, the
license fee therefore shall ne ten dollars per day."</p>

<p>Section 3. This Ordinance shall be in force and effect from and
after Five days after its passage and publication.</p>

<p>Passed the Council the 3rd day of September, 1900.</p>

<p>Approved the 4th day of September, 1900.</p>

<p>Attest:
H. B. Doust,
City Clerk.</p>

<ab>(Seal)</ab>

<p>Geo. S. Hough,
Mayor Pro tem.</p>

<pb/>

<ab>"Ex, "C".</ab>

<p>In the Police Court of the City of North Yakima, Washington, County
of Yakima, and State of Washington, Before W. I. LInce, Police Justic</p>

<ab>State of Washington,
County of Yakima,

ss:</ab>

<ab>No. 40.</ab>

<ab>People of the State of Washington,
vs. 
Fred S. Walton.</ab>

<p>Vestal Snyder, being first duly sworn, on oath says,
that at the City of North Yakima, Yakima County, State of Washington,
on the 5th day of September, 1901, said Fred S. Walton, did violate
section seven of ordinance number 265, entitled an ordinance in 
relation to licenses" duly passed by the City Council of said City
of North Yakima, on the 4th day of April, 1898, and approved by the
Mayor of said City, numbered 298, duly passed by the City Council
of said Mayor of said City, on the 4th day of September, 1900, <del>and 
approved by the </del> entitled an ordinance to amend 1 and 10 of ordinance 
number 265, entitled as follows; Then and there being the said Fred
S. Walton did then and there hawk certain goods, wares and merchandise 
to-wit: "Quaker herbs", by selling the same at public out cry, in
a public place <del></del> within the City of North Yakima aforesaid,
without first having otained a license so to do, in pursuance <unclear>of</unclear>
the provisions of said ordinances. Said City of North Yakima, is <unclear>a</unclear>
municipal corporation organized and existing under and by virtue <unclear>of</unclear>
the laws of the State of Washington, and at all times herein mentioned 
was such municipal corporation. </p>

<p>Contrary to the forms of said ordinance of the City of North
Yakima and the statute in such cases made and provided, and against
the peace and dignity of the State of Washington.</p>

<ab>Vestal Snyder.</ab>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 5th day of September, 1901</p>

<ab>W. I. Lince,
Police Justice of the City of 
Yakima, Washington.</ab>

<pb/>

<p>"Ex. "D,"</p>

<ab>State of Wash.
vs. 
Fred S. Walton.

Justice Docket.</ab>

<ab>State of Washington,
County of Yakima,

ss:</ab>

<ab>In Justice Peace Court before J. A. Taggard,
Justice of the Peace.

Action for violating City Ord.</ab>

<ab>Officer, J. G. Boyle.
Attys. Vestal Snyder, Plff.
"H.J. Snively, Deft.</ab>

<p>Be it remembered that on this 6th day of September, A.D. 1901,
the papers in this case complaint warrant aff. for change of venue
from City Police Judge, W. I. Lince were filed in this Court, the
complaint against defendant is for violating ordinances of the City
of North Yakima, Nos. 265 and 298 and verified by Vestal Snyder.
The defendant in Court and represented by H. J. Snively and City
atty. Vestal Snyder. Defendant plead not guilty. All papers and
facts on record admitted and after hearing argument of respective 
counsel, it is ordered and adjudged the defendant hereing Fred S.
Walton, pay a fine of $5.00 and costs of this action, taxed at $1.70
and in default of payment of said fine and costs, viz. $6.70 he be 
confined in City Jail of the City of North Yakima, until paid or he 
be otherwise discharged by due process of law.</p>

<p>Dated Sept., 6, 1901</p>

<p>J. A. Taggard
Justice of the Peace.</p>

<pb/>

<ab>COMMITMENT UPON SENTENCE.</ab>

<ab>In Justice Court North Yakima Precinct.</ab>

<ab>State of Washington,
County of Yakima,

ss:</ab>

<p>TO any city Marshal, Keeper of City Jail in City of North Yakima,
Greeting:</p>

<p>WHEREAS, at a Justice Court held at my office in said
County, for the trial of Fred S. Walton, for the offense hereinafter
stated, the said Fred S. Walton was convicted of having on the 5th 
day of September, 1901, in said County, did violate ordinance Nos.
265 and 298 of City of North Yakima and upon conviction the Court
did adjudge <del>the</del> and determine that the said Fred S. Walton pay a 
fine of Five Dollars and one and 70/100 dollars costs of suit and
in default of payment of said fine and costs that he be imprisoned
in the city jail, City of North Yakima, Yakima County, Washington,
until such fine and costs are paid, at the rate of three dollars
per day, not to exceed three days.</p>

<p>THEREFORE, You, the said Marshal are commanded in the name of
the people of the State of Washington, forthwith to convey and 
deliver the said Fred S. Walton to the said Keeper, and you, the
said Keeper, are hereby commanded to receive the said Fred S. Walton
into your custody in said jail, and him there safely keep until said 
judgment is fully satisfied as above set forth, or until he shall
thence be discharged by due course of law.</p>

<p>Dated this 4th day of September, 1901.</p>

<ab>J. A. Taggard,
Justice of the Peace. </ab>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>