<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0366.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Exhibit A</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0366.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Exhibit A</title>
<date when="1921-08-04">August 4, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-08">August 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Waters, Thos.</term>
<term>McClelland, Robt. W.</term>
<term>MacEchen, A. J. G.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Saskatchewan, Canada</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Decker, Fletcher</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, Adam</persName>
<persName>Sullivan</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the United States District Court in and for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</p>

<p>No. 6215</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Fletcher Decker for a Writ of Habeas Corpus and Writ of Certiorari</p>

<p>Exhibit "A"</p>

<pb/>

<p>Copy of Original Petition</p>

<p>United States of America,</p>
<p>Western District of Washington;</p>
<p>Northern Division.</p>

<p>SS Theft Under Sec. 5270 R. S.</p>

<p>TOM WATERS being first duly sworn on oath deposes and says: That he is a Deputy United States Marshal for the Division aforesaid:</p>

<p>That FLETCHER DECKER, on the 15th day of November, A. D. 1915, near Wisa Hill Post Office, in the Province of Saskatchewan, did steal about Three Hundred (300) bushels of flax, the property of Claude Ficklin and was thereby guilty of theft; that complaint was issued by A. J. G. MacEchen, a Justice of the Peace in and for the Province of Saskatchewan; that defendant is now within the jurisdiction of the Western District of Washington, Northern Division; that defendant is extraditable under Section 5270, R. S.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, Affiant prays that a warrant for the apprehension of the said Fletcher Decker may issue, and that he be brought before a United States Commissioner, to the end that the evidence of the criminality aforesaid may be heard and considered and that if upon such hearing, such Commissioner shall deem the evidence sufficient to sustain the charge under the provisions of said  5270 R. S., he shall certify the same, together with a copy of all the testimony taken before him, to the Secretary of State, that a warranty may issue upon the requisition of the proper authorities of said Dominion of Canada for the surrender of him, the said Fletcher Decker, according to the stipulations of said 5270 R. S., and that such commissioner shall issue his warrant for the commitment of him, the said Fletcher Decker, according to the stipulations of said 5270 R. S., and that such commissioner shall issue his warrant for the commitment of him, the said Fletcher Decker to the proper jail, there to remain until such surrender shall be made.</p>

<p>Thos. Waters.</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 4th day of August, 1921.</p>

<p>Robt W. McClelland,</p>
<p>U.S. Commissioner.</p>

<p>I hereby certify the foregoing to be a true copy of the complaint filed this 4 Aug. 1921.</p>

<p>Robt. W. McClelland,</p>
<p>U. S. Commissioner, Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>Seal; Robt. W. McClelland,</p>
<p>United States Commissioner</p>
<p>Western District of Washington.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>