<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>United States District Court
Western District of Washington,
Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the matter of the petition
of Arthur B. Martin
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. } No. 2852
Return</p>
<p>To the Honorable Judge of the United States District
Çourt for the Western District of Washington:</p>
<p>Comes now Henry M. White, United States Commissioner
of Immigration at the port of Seattle, Washington, and
makes this return to the writ of habeas corpus heretofore
issued in the above entitled matter and produces in court
the body of the said Arthur B. Martin, and alleges as 
follows:</p>
<p>I. 
He admits the following allegations of the petition:
1. That the petitioner was arrested June 23, 1910,
charged with a violation of the Mann Act, and upon a trial 
being had was sentenced to five years in the federal penitentiary
at McNeil island; which sentence petitioner has
served.</p>
<p>2. That petitioner was discharged from the federal
penitentary September 10, 1914, and taken into custody
by a United States immigration inspector acting under
respondent's orders, and since said date petitioner has been
detained at the United States immigration station in Seattle
awaiting deportation.</p>
<p>II.
That the respondent denies the remaining allegations
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
of the petition and specifically denies that petitioner was
taken and detained illegally, and that petitioner is a 
citizen of the United States of America.</p>
<p>For a Further and Affirmative Return to said Writ 
the Said Henry M. White alleges:</p>
<p>I. 
1. That petitioner is now in the custody of the United
States immigration authorities under and by virtue of a 
warrant of deportation issued by the Department of Commerce
and Labor, dated July 30, 1910, a copy of which is attached
hereto as "Exhibit A", made a part hereof by reference.</p>
<p>2. That said warrant was issued under the authority of
the Immigration Act of Feburary 20, 1907, as amended,
charging the petitioner with being an alien person of the
excluded class, and now entitled to be or remain in the 
United States, to-wit: That petitioner is an alien who 
imported, procurred and brought into the United States a
prostitute, or a woman, or a girl, for the purpose of
prostitution, or other immoral purposes; and that he entered
without inspection. That the period of three years after
his landing in the United States has not elapsed.</p>
<p>3. That the aforesaid warrant was served upon petitioner
immediately upon his discharge form the federal penitentiary,
as above set forth, and subsequently, to-wit, on the 14th
of September, 1914, a hearing was accorded petitioner for
the purpose of affording him an opportunity to show cause
why he should not be deported under said warrant, and at
said hearing petitioner failed to satisfy the immigration
authorities of his United States citizenship, and is now
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
being held for the purpose of verifying representations of
citizenship made by petitioner at said hearing, in which
statements he purported to give facts and data by which his
United States citizenship could be established.</p>
<p>II.
That on the 25th day of June, 1910, petitioner was
given a hearing before the United States Immigration Commissioner 
at Seattle, Washington, under a charge that he
was in the United States unlawfully, <del>and</del> for the purpose of
affording him an opportunity to show cause why she should
not be deported to the country from whence he came, and in
the course of said hearing petitioner, being under oath to
testify the truth, stated that he was born in Montreal,
Canda, of French-Canadian parents, and resided in Montreal,
Canada, fourteen years after his birth, and then went to the 
state of Louisiana in the United States of America; that he
had never been naturalized and had not voted; that he
always understood he was a citizen of the United States because
his father had been naturalized; and that he was unable 
to swear that his father had been naturalized.</p>
<p>III.
At a subsequent hearing before the Immigration Commissioner
on June 29, 1910, petitioner, under oath, again
stated that he was a native of Canda, having been born at
Vercheres near Montreal, Canada, January 10, 1857; that he
left Canada for the state of Louisiana, United States of
America, in 1877.</p>
<p>IV. 
<del>At a hearing before the United States Immigration
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
Commissioner on September 14, 1914, petitioner, being under
oath, swore he was born in the city of New Orleans,
Louisiana.</del></p>
<p>V.
The full original record of the hearings above referred
to before the United States Commissioner of Immigration
at Seattle, Washington, will be produced at the hearing of
this case.</p>
<p>Wherefore respondent asks that the petition be
denied and <del>a</del> writ of habeas corpus herein be discharged.</p>
<ab>Henry M. White
Commissioner of Immigration.</ab>
<ab>Albert Moodie
Assistant United States Attorney.</ab>
<p>The United States of America,
Western District of Washington,
Northern Divison. }ss.</p>
<p><del>Henry M. White</del>, being first duly sworn, upon his oath
deposes and says:</p>
<p>That he is Commissioner of Immigration of the port of
Seattle, Washington, and respondent herein; that he has
read the foregoing return to the order to show cause, knows 
the contents thereof, and that the same is true as he verily
believes.</p>
<ab>Henry M. White</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 1st day of
October, 1914.</p>
<ab>Albert Moodie
Notary Public referred State of
Washington, residing at Seattle.</ab>
<figure/>
<fw>-4-</fw>
<pb/>
<p>2x No.2852</p>
<p>In the District Court
of the United States
for the
Western District of Washington
Northern Division</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Petition
of Arthur B. Martin for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>Return</p>
<p>Filed in the 
U.S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington
OCT 16 1914
Frank L. Crosby, Clerk,
By EML Deputy.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>