<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0469.001"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0469.001</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">September 9, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date>31 January 1898</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Hanford, C. H. 
Marshal, J. W. 
Whil-Ochen, John
Pugh, Felix
Roberston, F. C. 
Ayres, A. Reeves
Matthew, H. M. 
Ide, C. W. 
Anderson
Jay, Midton R. 
</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Spokane County, Washington
Colville Indian Reservation, Washington
Stevens County, Washington
Kettle River, Washington
Marcus, Stevens County, Washington
Grand Forks, British Columbia, Canada
Seattle, Washington
</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Michel, Antwine</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>C. W. Ide</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>Robertson, F. C. </persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Jay, Midton R.</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H. </persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Circuit Court of the United States, District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0469.001"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, FOR THE DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON.</p>
<p>In the Matter of:</p>
<p>The application of An-
twine Michel for a Writ
of Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>PETITON FOR WRIT</p>
<p>To the Honorable C.H. Hanford, Judge:</p>
<p>The petition of Antwine Michel respectfully shows to Your
Honor:</p>
<p>That he is now and imprisonment detained and confined in
custody of the United States Marshal for the District of Washing-
ton, in the City Jail of the City of Spokane, and within the Dis-
trict of Washington, for a supposed criminal offense against the
laws of the United States.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further avers, That he is committed and
held by the said Marshal in the said Jail aforesaid by virtue of a 
Process and warrant of Commitment issued by J. W. Marshal, United
States Commissioner for the District of Washington, residing at
Spokane; that on the 12th day of January, A. D. 1898, one Felix
Pugh, a deputy Marshal, upon oath, did charge that on the 29th day
of December, 1898, and within the limits of the Colville Indian 
Reservation, your said petitioner, being then and there an Indian,
did, with a knife, unlawfully and felonionsly assault another
Indian name John Whil-Ochen, and did the said John Whil-Ochen then
and there out and wound, whereof the said John Whil-Ochen did not
die. That a copy of the Warrant of Commitment by which your pe-
titioner is held is hereto annexed.</p>
<p>And your petitioner further avers, That he is not held
for, or charged with, any other different crime against the laws
of the United States, and is not held or detained for any other
reason save as set forth herein.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further avers, That he is advised by his 
Counsel, F. C. Robertson, Esq., residing at Spokane, Washington,
and so believes, that his said imprisonment is illegal. and that
said illegality consists in this, to-wit:</p>
<p>That the said place at which the said cutting and wounding
took place for which the petitioner was arrested, is not within
the limits of the Colville Indian Reservation, as the same now is
set apart, designated and created by the laws of the United Sta-
tes, but the said crime, if committed at all, was committed upon
the public domain outside of the limits of said Colville In-
dian Reservation; That the said place where the said crime was
committed, if committed at all, was wholly within the limits of the 
County of Stevens and of the State of Washington. That the place
where the said difficulty occurred between your petitioner and the 
said Indian John Whil-Ochen was at a point northerly from the 
town of Marcus, Stevens County, Washington, and on the northern
bark of Kettle River, aboout nine (9) miles from the said town of
Marcus and at a point along which the public road passes from said
town of Marcus to the town of Grand Forks, British Columbia. That
the said point and place where the said difficulty occurred, under
the laws of the United States and the decisions of this Court, has
been held to be and is within the exclusive jurisdiction of the 
County of Stevens, Washington, for all purposes of civil and
criminal jurisdiction; and the said place and point is not within
the exclusive jurisdiction of the United States of within the ju-
risdiction of the United States whatever;
 </p>
<p>W H E R E F O R E , Your petitioner prays for a Writ
of Habeas Corpus to the end that he may be discharged from custody.</p>
<p>Antwine Michel</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>
<p>F. C. Robertson</p>
<p>Counsel for petitioner.</p>
<p>United States of America, )</p>
<p>) SS</p>
<p>District of Washington, )</p>
<p>Antwine Michel, being duly sworn, on oath deposes and says:
That he is the petitioner mentioned in the foregoing petition sub-
scribed by him; that he has read the same and knows the contents
thereof and that the statements made therein are true, as he 
verily believes.</p>
<p>Antwine Michel</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 28 day of Janurary, 1898</p>
<p>F. C. Robertson</p>
<p>Notary Public.</p>
<p>No. 655</p>
<p>IN THE Circuit COURT 
of the United States</p>
<p>NINTH JUDICIAL CIRCUIT--DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON DIVISION</p>
<p>In the matter of the
Application of Antwine
Michel, for a writ 
of Habeas Corpus Plaintiff</p>
<p>Petition. Defendant</p>
<p>FILED Jan. 29 1898</p>
<p>IN THE</p>
<p>CIRCUIT COURT</p>
<p>A. Reeves Ayres</p>
<p>HM Walthew</p>
<p>Deputy</p>
<p>F. C. ROBERTSON</p>
<p>Spokane Washington</p>
<p>Attorneys for petitioner</p>
<p>DAILY NEWS PRINT</p>
<p>United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington.</p>
<p>In the matter of the
application of Antwine
Michel for a writ of
Habeas Corpus Plaintiff</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>No. 655
PRAECIPE FOR APPEARANCE</p>
<p>Defendant</p>
<p>To the Clerk of the above entitled Court:</p>
<p>You will please enter my appearance as atty
for petitioner
in the above entitled cause.</p>
<p>F. C. Robertson</p>
<p>NOTICE-- Attorneys will please endorse their own Filings. Rule 47.</p>
<p>No. 655</p>
<p>GoB. 5-223</p>
<p>United States Circuit Court</p>
<p>DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>In re</p>
<p>Plaintiff</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>Antwine Michel</p>
<p>Defendant</p>
<p>Praecipe for Appearance.</p>
<p>Filed January 29, 1898,
A. Reeves Ayres Clerk
HM Matthew</p>
<p>Deputy Clerk.</p>
<p>For</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of The Application
of Antwine Michel for a Writ of  O R D E R 
Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>Now on this 29th day of January, 1898, on reading and filing
the petition of Antiwine Michel, it is ordered by the court that
C. W. Ide, United States Marshal, who is in said petition alleged
to have the said Antwine Michel in his custody, do appear before
this court, at the court room in the City of Seattle, on the 31st 
day of January, 1898, at the hour of 10 o'clock A. M. , then and
there to show cause if he can, why a writ of Haveas Corpus should
not ussuem as prayed for in said petition.</p>
<p>C. H. Hanford</p>
<p>Judge.</p>
<p>No. 655</p>
<p>GoB 5-223</p>
<p>THE THE Circuit COURT
OF THE UNITED STATES
FOR THE 
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>In re -</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>Antwine Michel</p>
<p>Order to show cause</p>
<p>Filed Janurary 29, 1898,
A Reeves Ayres Clerk
By HM Mattheew Deputy</p>
<p>In the Circuit Court of the United States for the District of
Washington, Northern Division.
In re- Antwine Michel,</p>
<p>Petitioners Ex parte,</p>
<p>The court having ordered a writ of Habeas Corpus to issue
herein, to the Marshal of the United States for the District of 
Washington,</p>
<p>Now comes the Attorney of the United Srares for the District
of Washington and states to the court that the offense with which
petitioner is charged was not committed at any place within the 
jurisdiction of the United States Courts, but was committed
in the County of Stevens in the State of Washington, in that 
certain territory formerly embraced in the North half of the
Colville Indian Reservation in said county, which was relinquished
from said reservation and restored to the public domain by the
act of Congress of July 1, 1892.</p>
<p>And moves the court to order the said Marshal to deliver
the body of said petitioner to the sheriff of said Stevens County
to be dealt with according to the laws of the state of Washington,</p>
<p>And the court having heard said motion and carefully consid-
ered the same, the court finds the facts stated to be true, and 
sustains said motion. It is therefore ordered and adjudged that
the said Marshal notify the said Sheriff of Stevens County, Wash-
ington, of this order, and upon demand of said Sheriff, said Marshal
shall deliver to said Sheriff the body of said petitioner, but
if no such demand be made within five day then aid Marshal re-
lease said petitioner from custody.</p>
<p>C. H. Hanford</p>
<p>Judge.</p>
<p>No. 655</p>
<p>GoB. 5-2224</p>
<p>IN THE Circuit COURT 
OF THE UNITED STATES</p>
<p>FOR THE </p>
<p>DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>In re-</p>
<p> vs.</p>
<p>Antwine Michel</p>
<p>Order.</p>
<p>Filed January 31 1898
A Reeves Ayres Clerk
By HM Matthew Deputy</p>
<p>In the Circuit Court of the United
States, Northern Circuit, District of
Washington</p>
<p>In the maters of the
Application of Antwine
Michel for a writ
of Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Comes now the petitioner herein
and excepting to the returnto of the
Marshal for the insufficiency
hereby
moves this honorable court 
for an order delivering the
this hereto of petitioner not-
withstanding the said return
of the U. S. Marshal
</p>
<p>F. C. Robertson</p>
<p>Attorney for pe-
titioner</p>
<p>#655 Tx.</p>
<p>U. S. Circuit Court</p>
<p>In re Antwine
Michael on hbeas corpus</p>
<p>Exception and 
motion</p>
<p>Filed Jan 31 1898</p>
<p>IN THE </p>
<p>U. S. CIRCUIT COURT
A. Reeves Ayres.</p>
<p>Clerk</p>
<p>By P. M. Hapkine</p>
<p>Deputy</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Antwine Michael for a writ of
habeas corpus/</p>
<p>Answer and Return upon the Order.</p>
<p>To the Honorable Cornelius H. Hanford, Judge:</p>
<p>Comes now C. W. Ide, United States Marshal for the District of
Washington, and for his answer and return upon the order issued by this
Honorabe Court upon the petition of Antwine Michael, begs leave to say:</p>
<p>first. Resepondent, C. W. Ide, Marshal as aforesaid, is compelled
to inform this Honorable Court that he has no personal knowlede of the
matters and things set forth in petitioner's petition. This petition
was filed in this Honorable Court late Saturday afternoon, January 29th,
1898, and the order issuing from this Court did not come to the posse-
sion of respondent until this morningm thus respondent having been in-
formed, however, by F. S. Robertson, attorney for petitioner, on Satur-
day last that such petition would be filed, and being advised by tele-
gram Saturday night that the same had been done and the order issued
made returnable this morning. Respondent further says that the peti-
tioner, Antwine Michael, is now in custody at Spokane, as respondent
has been informed. That there has not been sufficient time to gather
from the records the absolute facts in the case, and this answer is
therefore made upon information and belief, for the reason that respon-
dent cannot answer in any other wise.</p>
<p>Second. Respondent further answering says, that it is his informa-
tion and belief that the petitioner, Antwine Michael, is an Indian and 
a ward of the United States Government, being under control of an 
Indian-Agent, to-wit, one Anderson upon the Colville Reservatoin, within
the jurisdiction of this Court, and that he, the said Antwine Michael,
did sometime on or about the latter part of December last past with a 
deadly weapon feloniously and purposely make an assault upon the person
of one John whil-Ochen, another Indian ward of the United States, be-
longing to a tribe of Indians unknown to this respondent, byt being under
the control and charge of the said Indian Agent Anderson, on the said
Colville Reservation, within the jurisdiction of this Court. This re-
spondent has been advised and beliebes the fact to be that said assault
was so made upon and within the limits of the Colville Indian Reserva-
tion, heretfore established by executice order dated July 2nd, 1872.
Whether said assualt was committed upon what is known as the North half
of said Reservation, as stated in petitioner's petition, your respondent
has no information or belief.</p>
<p>Third. Respondent further answering says, that pursuant to the
commission of said assault in the manner as aforesaid, that one Felix
M. Pugh in due and legal form made complaint in writing before one J. W. 
Marshal, United States Commissioner for the District of Washington, duly
appointed and acting and residing at Spokane, who thereupon, on the 12th
day of January, 1898, issued his warrant of arrest for him, the said
Antwine Michael, which said warrant of arrest was delivered into the 
hands of a Deputy United States Marshal, who, in obedience to the com-
mand of said warrant, did arrest and apprehend the said Antwine Michael
in all respects according to law, and that it is in pursuance of these 
proceedings that he, the said Antwine Michael, is now in the custody of
this respondent or his authorized deputy at Spokane. That all the pro-
ceedings thereon were in due and legal form and that the said Antwine
Michael has not been discharged by the said Commissioner upon hearing,
or by any other person having authority so to do after inquiry and hear-
ing in the manner as provided by law, and neither has the said Antwine
Michael sought to have said hearing.</p>
<p>Having fully justified the said order, respondent herein asks that
he be discharged and the petition for habeas corpus be dismissed.</p>
<p>Midton R. Jay</p>
<p> United States Attorney.</p>
<p>C. W. Ide</p>
<p>Respondent.</p>
<p>No 665</p>
<p> In U. S. C. Court</p>
<p> In the matter of 
the Appln of
Antoine Michael
for writ
Habeas Corpus</p>
<p> Return and 
Asurn</p>
<p> Field Jan. 31 1898
U. S. Circuit Court
A Reeves Ayres</p>
<p>Clerk.</p>
<p>HM Matthew</p>
<p> Deputy.</p>
<p> Midton R. Jay
U. S. Atty</p>
<p> In the Circuit Court of the United States for the Ninth Circuit,
District of Washington ,</p>
<p> In the matter of the application of :
Antwine Michel, for a Writ of :
Habeas Corpus, :</p>
<p>And now this cause coming regularly on for hearing upon
the answer of Clarence Ide, United States Marshal, to the rule to
show cause why a writ of Habeas Corpus should not issue herein,
as prayed for by the petitioner, and the matters and things
therein set forth beig fully considered, and the court being fully
advised in the premises, it is ordered that a writ of Habeas
Corpus do issue as prayed for.</p>
<p>C. H. Hanford</p>
<p>Judge.</p>
<p>No 655</p>
<p> GoB .5-rrt</p>
<p>IN THE Cir. COURT</p>
<p>OF THE UNITED STATES</p>
<p> FOR THE</p>
<p>DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>In re</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>Antwine Michel</p>
<p>Order grant-
ing petition</p>
<p>Filed January 31, 1898,
A Reeves Ayres Clerk
By HM Matthew Deputy</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>