<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0180.008.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Decision.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0180.008</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Decision.</title>
<date when="1914-02-18">Feburary 18, 1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2628AlbertYoung&amp;KamasaburoSugiura</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-02">Feburary 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Hunter, B. A.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Denamore, J. B.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Saito, Hana</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Washio</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Young, Albert H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sugiuro, Kamasaburo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Myers, H. A. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>McClellan, R. W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Johnstone, Walter L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, G. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Cushman, Edward E.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States
Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Petition of
Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo
Sugiura, alias B.K. Sugiura,
aliens for a Writ of Habeas Corpus } No.2628
Filed
Feburary 19, 1914.</p>
<p>R.W. McClellan,
H.A.P. Myers,
Walter L. Johnstone
For Petitioners.
Clay Allen, United States Attorney,
G.P. Fishburne, Ass't " " 
For Respondent.</p>
<p>Cushman, District Judge.</p>
<p>The above petitioners, for discharge upon habeas
corpus, have been ordered deported, the warrant of deportation
reading:-</p>
<p>"Whereas, from proofs submitted to me, after due hearing
before Immigrant Inspector B. A. Hunter, held at Seattle,
Wash., I have become satisfied that the aliens Albert H. 
Young and Kamasaburo Sugiura, alias B.K. Sugiura, who landed
at some unknown port, have been found in the United States
in violation of the Act of Congress approved Feburary 20, 1907,
amended by the Act approved March 26, 1910, to-wit:</p>
<p>"That the said aliens are unlawfully within the United
States in that they have been found assisting a prostitute
and protecting, or promising to protect from arrest, a prostitute,
and may be deported in accordance therewith:</p>
<p>"I, J.B. Denamore, Acting Secretary of Labor, by virtue
of the power and authority vested in me by the laws of the
United States, do hereby command you to return the said aliens
to Japan, the county from whence they came **."</p>
<p>The warrant for their arrest recited:-</p>
<p>"That the said aliens are unlawfully within the United
States in that they have been found assisting, protecting, or
promising to protect from arrest, a prostitute or prostitutes."</p>
<pb/>
<p>The act under which they were ordered deported provides:-
"That any alien ** who in any way assists, protects, or
promises to protect from arrest any prostitute, shall be
deemed to be unlawfully within the United States and shall be
deported in the manner provided by sections twenty and twenty-one
of this Act." Sec. 3 of the Immigration Act of 1907, as
Amended March 26, 1910, 36 Stat. st L., p. 264.</p>
<p>Petitioners rely upon the following authorities: -
United States v. Sibray
178 Fed., 148, 149;
36 CYC., p.1118;
People vs. Chicago, 152 Ill. App.,
546-552; 38 N.E. 746;
U.S. v. Williams, 200 Fed., 541-2;
(same) 189 Fed., 917;
Frick vs. Lewis, 195 Fed., 696;
U.S. vs. Martin, 193 Fed., 797-8;
Ex parte Saraceno, 182 Fed., 957;
Ex parte Patterson, 166 Fed., 539;
Chin Yow v. U.S., 208 U.S., 11;
Ex parte Long Lock, 173 Fed., 208;
Yamataya v. Fisher, 189 U.S., 86;
47 Law Ed., 721</p>
<p>Respondent relies upon the following authorities:-
In re Unlawful Detention of Nullas
Singh and Seventy-two other Hindu Aliens,
Case No. 2532
Ekiu v. United States, 142 U.S., 651;
35 Law Ed., 1146;
United States v. Ju Toy, 198 U.S., 253;
Lee Moon Sing v. United States, 158 U.S.538;
Du Bruler v. Gallo, 184 Fed., 566, at 569
Williams v. U.S., 186 Fed., 479;
Sinis Calchi v. Thomas, 195 Fed., 701;
United States v. Williams, 175 Fed., 274.</p>
<p>The grounds urged for discharge are that petitioners
have not had a fair hearing and that there was no evidence
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
whatever to support the charge in the warrant of arrest, or
the finding in the warrant of deportation.</p>
<p>"That the said aliens (petitioners) are unlawfully within 
the United States, in that they have been found assisting,
protecting, or promising to protect from arrest a prostitute
or prostitutes."</p>
<p>It is not necessary to determine --- concerning the
warrant of arrest, whether the charge, as set forth therein,
would be sufficient to apprise petitioners with that of which
they were accused --- it not alleging the time, place or naming
the prostitute or prostitutes alleged to have been assisted,
protected or promised protection from arrest, as proceedings
of this character are summary in their nature and, if
it appears from the return that petitioners were actually
apprised of the nature of the accusation against them and
had a fair hearing thereon, it is sufficient.</p>
<p>Petitioners were represented at the deportation
hearing by one of their present counsel. They were tried
and heard together. Petitioner Young, being first sworn and
examined was asked at the commencement of the examination
and proceeding:-
"Q. I believe that you have been tried in the United 
States Court for a certain offences?
A. Yes, I have been tried twice on the same offence.
Q. What offense>?
A. Aiding and abetting in the transporting a Japanese girl,
Hana Saito, in the inter-state commerce from Seattle to
San Francisco and I was tried in Feburary, 1913, and acquitted
and I was reindicted by a grand jury, last grand jury, and
tried for conspiring to violate the same Mann Act and again
by the jury on a second trial and re-arrested by Departmental
warrant for practically the same thing."
The foregoing plainly shows that petitioners knew with what 
they were being charged upon the deportation hearing.</p>
<p>The evidence shows that the woman, Hana Saito, had,
prior to coming to Seattle, lived in a house of prostitution;
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
That, after coming to Seattle, she was followed from San
Francisco by a Japanese named Washio and that the petitioners,
at his solicitation, secured transportation for him and the
woman to San Francisco and accompanied them by steamer to
that city. When they arrived in San Francisco, the four
went direct to the house of prostitution where Hana Saito
had formerly been. There is some testimony that, before 
securing tickets to San Francisco, the petitioners were informed
that this woman had, before coming to Seattle, been
a prostitute living in this house.</p>
<p>There was no evidence that any warrant for the arrest
of Hana Saito had ever been issued; but, on account of
the conclusion reached, it is not necessary to determine
whether the language of the statute "promises to protect from
arrest any prostitute" contemplates the actual existence of
a warrant or proceeding for the arrest of a prostitute, from
which she is promised protection, or whether it may not contemplate 
a promise of protection generally --- either from the
arrest to which those practicing prostitution are generally
subject in municipalities, or the arrest to which alien
prostitutes are subject under the laws of the United States.</p>
<p>It is earnestly insisted by counsel for petitioners
that the words "in any way assists, protects or promises to
protect from arrest" mean in any way assist from arrest, as
by furnishing money to escape to one who is threatened with
arrest. The argument is more ingenious than convincing.
If such were the meaning, there are so many more apt words
in which to express it, that it seems unlikely that such could
have been the intention.</p>
<p>On the other hand, if the words "any alien who in
any ways assists *** a prostitute" are given their widest
meaning, so as to include an alien who gives food, shelter or
medicine to a prostitue, which, it is contended is the only
<fw>4</fw>
<pb/>
other meaning of which they are capable -- a conclusion is
reached which is still more abborrent to reason. A more
satisfactory conclusion is that the intention was to declare
unlawful the presence in the country of any alien who in any
way assists a prostitute to practice prostitution, or towards
its practice.</p>
<p>Holy Trinity vs. U.S.,
143 United States, 457.</p>
<p>Even a prostitute may be something more than a 
prostitute. For example, she may be a milliner as well.
The one who assisted her in the latter business would be
assisting a milliner and could not be fairly condemned as assisting
a prostitute, and one who assisted her in the practice
of prostitution, could not be excused on the plea of 
assisting a milliner.</p>
<p>Under the act so constued, it cannot be said but
that there was some evidence to support the finding of the
Inspector and Acting Secretary.</p>
<p>The fact that both of the petitioners had been acquitted
in this court by juries on charges involving the same
transaction, in no way defeats the action taken, or the determination
reached by the Immigration authorities, for to justify
a verdict of guilty by a jury, it was necessary that the 
jury be convinced of petitioners' guilt beyond a reasonable
doubt, while no such rule is imposed upon the Immigration
authorities.</p>
<p>William Williams vs. United States, ex rel
Antonics Bougaris. 186 Fed., 479.</p>
<p>The letter of the Commisioner of Immigration to
the Commissioner General of Immigration, recommending the
deportation of petitioners and made a part of the return herein
states:-</p>
<p>"They (that is the petitioners) admit that they 
<fw>5</fw>
<pb/>
committed an act which was neither more nor less than the kidnapping
of a prostitute, in the conveyance of whom from Tacoma, 
Washington, to San Francisco, California, they assisted. They
deny that they knew that the woman was a prostitute. It may
be that when they were first approached that they did not know
the woman's character but they were certainly given due notice
before the high-handed proceedings had gone very far."</p>
<p>The same contention was made by the Government ibn both the
criminal trials mentioned. Petitioners at all times have insisted
that the woman went to San Francisco willingly.</p>
<p>While respondent's position upon the warrant --- that
petitioners assisted a prostitute, which necessarily implies
willingness and consent upon her part --- is not strengthed by
the Commissioner's conclusion that they were kidnapping her,
which would, as necessarily, be an involantary proceeding upon
her part, yet, as the Commissioner's report is only a part of
the record upon which the warrant issued and, as pointed out,
there is some evidence to support the finding and warrant,
this inconsistency will not defect the ultimate conclusion
reached and the warrant of deportation based thereon, providing
petitioners were accorded a fair hearing on the charge upon
which they were ordered deported.</p>
<p>Sinis Calchi v. Thomas, 195 Fed., 701;
United States vs. Williams, 175 Fed., 274.
Petition denied and rule discharged.</p>
<fw>6</fw>
<pb/>
<p>No. 2628</p>
<p>In the District Court 
of the United States
for the
Western District of Washington
Northern <del>Southern</del> Division</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Petition
of Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo
Sugiura, alias B. K. Sugiura,
for a Write of Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Decision</p>
<p>Filed in the
U.S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington
Nothern Division
Feb 18 1914
Frank L. Crosby, Clerk,
By EML Deputy.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>