<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>Beeler &amp; Sullivan
Lawyers
Suite 510-11 White Building
Seattle</p>
<p>In the United States District Court, In and for the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Chin Hing, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. } NO. 2857.
Bill of Exceptions</p>
<p>Be It Remembered, that on the twenty-ninth day of September,
1914, came John J. Sullivan, as Attorney for and in behalf of Chin
Hing, an alleged alien, and an alleged son of a merchant of New 
York City, and appealed to the United States of America for a Writ 
of Habeas Corpus, on the ground that one J.B. Densmore, Solicitor
of the Depatment of Labor, acted without authority in ordering the
deportation of said petitioner, and that in consequence he had been
deprived of a fair hearing, and that petitioner's appeal has been
heard and determined by one not authorized to do so; to show cause
an Order was issued from the United States District Court, In and
For the Western District of Washington, Northern Division, and in
due time the United States made a return from said Order and Petition
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, admitting and denying the allegations
in said petition, and the United States further tendered and
made a part of said return, an alleged original record, marked
"Exhibit A", as taken before the Immigration Department. A stipulation
was entered into between counsel for the Government and counsel
for the petitioner to the effect that interrogatories might be
taken propounded to Louis F. Post, Assistant Secretary of Commerce
and Labor, and Corrie M. Stadden of Washington, District of Columbia, 
before one Thomas G. Lewis, a Notary Public, which said interrogatories
listed information from said Louis F. Post, and said Corrie
M. Stadden as to whether or not said Louis F. Post was present in
the city of Washington on the date that said J.B. Densmore acted
and signed the Deporation Order, and reviewed the cause of the said
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
petitioner, Chin Hing. The Order was signed by Honorable Jeremiah
Neterer, Judge in and for the Western District of Washington,
Northern Division, and upon the regusal of Louis F. Post to answer
the interrogratories porpounded by the said Commissioner appointed
by order of the Court, a rule of show cause was issued by Justice
Gould in the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia, counsel for the Government 
petitioned Honorable Jeremiah Neterer to issue an Order withdrawing
said commission to take a propound interrogatories to
said Louis F. Post. An Answer was filed to said Petition by counsel
for the petitioner, Chin Hing, and hearing was had, on which said
date the Court allowed the Government to make a further return, showing
that the Secretary had reviewed the record and affirmed the decision
of the Commissioner for the deportation of the petitioner,
Chin Hing, and on the tenth day of May, 1915 the Court rendered an
Opinion grnating the Petition of the Government withdrawing said
commission to take interrogatories, and on the twenty-ninth day of
May, 1915 the Court signed a Judgement and Order in conformity with
the said Petition, discharging said Writ of Habeas Corpus, and remanding
the petitioner to the custody of the Commissioner of Immigration.
To all of which the petitioner excepted as herein set forth.
Counsel asked the Court to rule:</p>
<p>I.
That the so-called memorandum for the Secretary, or Assistant
Secretary, or Acting Secretary, as shown by the record, was irregular,
illegal, and not given under oath, and its admission to the reocrd
sent up to the Department of Commerce and Labor, constituted illegality,
and unfair hearing on appeal.</p>
<p>II.
That no other person except the Secretary of Commerce and
Labor has a right to rule on appeal, as provided by the treaty,
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
laws and rules governing the admission of Chinese.</p>
<p>III.
That the petitioner had had no fair trial, in that letters,
memorandums, etc. from officials and inspecotrs of the Department
were considered by the Commissioner of Immigration without the
petitioner being given a right to deny the same, or being apprised
of their contents; that the same were not given under oath, and
were not evidence, being hearsay, and not permissable under the
rules governing the admission of Chinese.</p>
<p>IV.
That the evidence of so-called "Exhibit A" disclosed such
irregularity and illegality that the Court should investigate the 
record to do justice.</p>
<p>V. 
That upon the evidence of this proceeding it appears from the
record that the petitioner did not have a fair hearing, as he was 
entitled to upon application for admission into the United States
under the law, constitution and treaty and rules and regulations of 
the United States governing the admission of Chinese, and his detention
and deportation being illegal, he is now entitled to discharge.</p>
<p>VI.
Counsel asked the Court to rule that there was no evidence to
justify the refusing of the United States, through its officials, to
admit the petitioner from entering the United States, and no evidence
to warrant finding that he was not the son of a Chinese merchant and
resident of the United States, but the Court refused so to rule.</p>
<p>VII.
Counsel asked the Court to rule that inasmuch as the issue
was before the Court as to whether or not J.B. Densmore acted with
or without authority, the Court should determine that question and
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
not allow a return to be made on the day of the hearing showing that
the Secretary had examined the original record, when, according to
said first return, as shown by the record, this Court was presumed
to have the record before him, and made a part of said return, but
the Court refused so to rule.</p>
<p>VIII.
Counsel asked the Court to rule that inasmuch as Justicle
Gould had decided that Louis F. Post, Assistant Secretary, should
answer the interrogatories as to whether or not he was in Washington
at the time the appeal of the petitioner was heard, and Order of 
Deportation signed by J.B. Densmore, the Court should not grant
the petition of the Governmnet, and admit the return offered on the
day of the hearing, but should allow the interrogatories to be propounded
and determine the question upon the issues which had already 
been made, to wit: whether or not J.B. Densmore acted with authority
in deciding the appeal and ordering the deportation of Chin Hing, but
the Court refused so to rule.</p>
<p>IX.
That upon the law and the evidence the petitioner is illegally
restrained and detained, and was not given a fair heaing,
either before the Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington,
or on appeal, and his Order of Deportation was signed by one acting
without authority; therefore, the petitioner ought to be discharged 
from custody, but the Court resued so to rule; and ordered that the
Writ of Habeas Corpus heretofore issed, be discharged, and that the
petition of the Governmnet to withdraw the interrogatories heretofore
stipulated, be withdrawn and the petitioner, Chin Hing be remanded
to the custoy of the Commissioner of Immigration; and to said rulings
 and refusal to rule, and to said Order and Judgment of the Court,
counsel for petitioner fuly excepted and said exceptions were allowed
by the Court; the Court having filed an Opinion which is included
<fw>-4-</fw>
<pb/>
in the transcript of the record in this case, and is made a part
thereof. This petitioner later appealed from said decision and order
of the Court entered on the twenty-ninth say of May, 1915, to the
Cicuit Court of Appeals In and for the Ninth Circuit, and filed 
a petition for appeal, and Assignment of Errors, and said appeal was
allowed, and Citation issed, as appears by the record.</p>
<p>Thereupon, petitioner, Chin Hing, tender this, his Bill of
Exceptions to the actions, rulings and judgment of the Court, and
the refusals to ttule in the particulars set out, to have the same
force and effect as if each and every said exception had been separately
signed and sealed, which were signed and made a party of the 
record in this case.</p>
<p>Dated this 9 day of June, 1915.</p>
<ab>Chin Hing
Petitioner</ab>
<ab>By John J Sullivan
His Attorney Solicitor</ab>
<ab>Allowed Jeremiah Neterer
Judge</ab>
<ab>AK
GP Fishburne
Assistant U.S. Atty</ab>
<pb/>
<p>B No. 2857
Original</p>
<p>In the 
Superior Court
State of Washington
King County</p>
<p>In the Matter of the
Application of Chin Hing
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>Bill of Exceptions</p>
<p>Beeler &amp; Sullivan
Lawyers
510-11 White Building
Seattle, Wash.</p>
<pb/>
<p>Copy of within bill of exception
recieved and due service of same acknowledged this
9th day of June 1915
Winter S Martin
Asst Attorney for US</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>