<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1891">1891</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
NORTHERN DIVISION.

IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION OF
CHARLES W.NORDSTROM FOR WRIT OF
HABEAS CORPUS AND RELIEF THEREON.

NOTICE.

To Honorable W.H.Moyer, Sheriff of King County, State of 
Washington.

You will please take notice hereby that, Charles W.Nordstrom,
now in your custody, duly petitioner the United States Circuit Court
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, seeking relief thereupon, and

Whereas, the said Writ and relief was denied, and
Whereas, the said Petitioner duly moved for the right of appeal
and for the transfer of his whole cause to the Supreme Court of the
United States, and

Whereas, the said cause came on for argument as to the granting
of the said appeal and the transfer of the whole cause to the
appellate Court, and was heard upon the 3rd day of April A.D. 1897,
by the Hon.C.H.Hanford, Circuit Judge, and

Whereas, after hearing said application, an order of appeal
was duly granted, and the said cause was so ordered transferred to
the Supreme Court of the United States, a full copy of the aforesaid
proceedings and the order allowing the said appeal, being duly
certified, is hereunto annexed for your information and advice.

And Whereas, under the Revised Statutes of the United States, being
the laws of the United States, particularly Section 766 of the said
Revised Statutes reads as follows, to-wit:

Sec.766. "Pending the proceedings on appeal in the case a mentioned
in the three preceding sections, and until final judgment therein,
and after final judgment of discharge, any proceeding against the

-1-

<pb/>

person so imprisoned or confined or restrained of his liberty, in
any State Court, or by or under the authority of any State, for any
matter so heard and determined, or in process of being heard and determined,
under such writ of habeas corpus, shall be deemed null and
void."

And Whereas, the Supreme Court of the United States, in Re Jugiro
140 U.S.295, construing the said Section, defined the same to mean,
"in cases where the applicant was held in custody under the authority
of a state court or state while the question as to whether his
detention was in violation of the constitution, laws, or treaties
of the United States was being examined by the courts of the United
States having jurisdiction in the premises;" which said decision is
more fully referred to in the case of In re M'Kane, 61 Fed. 205,
where it was held to mean that until final decision in the Supreme
Court of the United States no disturbance of the condition of the
prisoner as he was at the time of the denying of the Writ can in 
anywise be had.

THEREFORE, You are hereby notified that you are to
hold possession or custody of the said Petitioner, Charles W. Nordstrom,
now in your keeping at the City of Seattle, County of King,
State of Washington, in such manner as to your discretion shall
seem meet and proper, in no wise assuming for any cause to execute
any sentence of death whatsoever upon the said Petitioner, Charles
W. Nordstrom, and you will be duly notified of any further proceeding 
in the premises.

You will please govern yourself accordingly:

Respectfully,

Jas. Hamilton Lewis
Attorney for Petitioner.

J Henry Hemming
Of Counsel.

-2-

<pb/>

Tx

No. 604

In the Circuit Court
OF THE UNITED STATES,
FOR THE 
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
NORTHERN DIVISION.

In re Application
of Charles W. Nordstrom
for Writ of 
Habeas Corpus
etc,-

Notice to Sheriff

Jas. Hamilton Lewis

STRATTON, LEWIS, &amp; GILMAN,
Attorney for Petitioner

101-106 OCCIDENTAL BLOCK, SEATTLE

Copy of within
received and due service of the same
acknowledged this day of 
1896.

Attorney for

FILED Apr 6 1897
IN THE
U.S. CIRCUIT COURT
A. Reeves Ayres
CLERK

By A. N. Moore
DEPUTY

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>