<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Territory of Washington} In the District Court 4th JuCounty 
of Spokane}ss dicial District holding
terms at County seat of
Spokane County
Territory of Washington
vs. Plaintiff
Ray Raymond Defendant
Territory of Washington}
County of Spokane}ss Thomas C. Griffitts, J. Kennedy
Stout, N.T. Caton, and Frederick Stanford
being each individually duly sworn
depose and swear as follows:
That they and each of them are of counsel a
attorney for defendant Ray Raymond in
this cause that said defendant cannot
safely present to trial therein at this time
of this court for the following reasons:
The indictment against her eas returned
herein December 1, 1886, and the defendants
plea infered of not guilty on Dec. 1, 1886.
That immediately thereafter defendant
counsel made a motion for change of
venue herein and present the same to the
hearing at the earliest time the convenience
of the court and counsel for the Territory
permitted, and said motion was finally 
determined and awarded De.
14, 1886, defendant by her counsel immediately 
give in there this written for a continuance.
That this did question for a change of venue was
made by defendant and her counsel in the utmost 
good faith and they are greatly taken 
by surprise both by the affidavit filed herein
by the territory and on the said motion and at
the pending og the same and believing
their said motion were taken, they did not
show a motion for a continuance herein
would be necessary until the final determination 
of said motion for a change of
venue. That would the findind and presentment
of the indictment hererin neither affiant nor
defendant knew with what crime defendant
would be accused nor what the issue herein
would be whether she would be accused
of any offense whatsoever or of an offense
insodoing the issue of malice in the killing
of Finch. That at time such indictment
was presented this term of this court had
duly been in sworn and counsel for defendant
had been constant in attendance.
Then now and ever since said indictment
was returned into the court and
defendant counsel herein have been
in about constant attendance
at this court and expressed either in 
the trial of counsel therein or in watching
and waiting for the trial of pending course
or preparing for the trial of cause such
pending in this court and for trial
and of pursing importance and still
to be tried herein that considerable time
since the finding of said indictment have
been recopied by defendant counsel in
the preparation for and hearing of said
motion for a change of venue and since
its determination in the preparation
of a showing for the continuance; that
in addition to their other habeas as afore
detailed counsel immediately set
about making such preparation
as they could under the circumstances
for the trial of the cause attending to well
aware they could not fully prepare
thereupon and in fact counsel believes
that the later date in the term when
this indictment was presented, the
bona fide efforts they had made and the
parts directed in the showing for
change of venue made by them and which is here
referred to as part of the new herein and the continuation
of that cas at this <del>cause</del>term of court and the
return of the indictment herein and the great
expense and delay of procuring a jury
herein at this time, with the facts he afore</p>