<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0492.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Pizzi, Annabella D." xml:id="adp">Annabella D. Pizzi</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>NSF</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0492.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant.</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-06-11">June 11, 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Medcraf, Francis Medcraf</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>The State of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Emery, Geo D.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Lundin, Alfred H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Helsell, Frank P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="justice_of_the_peace">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
                  
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#adp">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT FOR THE
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Petition of Francis Stephen Medcraf for
Writ of Habeas Corpus.

No. 3038</p>
<p>BRIEF OF RESPONDENT, STATE OF WASHINGTON
ON MOTION TO QUASH WRIT. </p>
<p>ALFRED H. LUNDIN,
FRANK P. HELSELL,
Attorneys for State of Washington.</p>
<p>Office and Post Office Address:
1116-24 Alaska Building,
Seattle, King County, Washington.</p>
<pb/>
<p>IT IS WITHIN THE POLICE POWER OF A STATE TO FIX THE
REQUIREMENTS OF THOSE SEEKING TO PRACTICE DENTISTRY IN THE
STATE.</p>
<p>Mr. Justice Gray, in the well known case of Leisy v. 
Hardin (135 U.S. 127), in speaking of the exercise of the
police power, said:

"It is that power which is characterized as that
inherent power essential to the very existence of civil
society, and the sageguard of the inhabitants of the 
state against disorder, disease, poverty and crime.

"The power of a state to make reasonable provisions 
for determining the qualification of those
engaging in the practice of medicine and punishing
those who attempt to engage therein in defiance of
such statutory provisions is not open to question."
Justice Borwn in Reetz v. Michigan, 188 U.S. 505,
citing
Dent. v. W.Va., 129 U.S. 144-
Hawker v. N.Y. 170, U.S. 189.
Watson vs Myd. 218 U.S.- 173-
Collins vs. Texas 223 U.S. 288-
To quote from the opinion in the Hawker vs N.Y- case:

"No precise limites  have been placed upon the 
police power of a state, and yet it is clear that 
legislation which simply defines the qualifications
of one who attempts to practice medicine is a proper 
exercise of that power."</p>
<p>The issues raised in the case at bat are these: Do the
statutes determining the qualification of those engaging in the
practice of dentistry in this state create uniform and unreasonable
classes> So these statutes fail to apply equally to all
within the class created by them?</p>
<p>The State of Washington maintains:
1st. That the statutes in question are uniform as to all 
in like circumstances within the sphere of their operation.
2nd. That the classification is reasonable. Not such an
arbitrary or hostile classification as infringes upon the quality
guaranteed by the 14th Amendment of the Constitution of the United
States.</p>
<pb/>
<p>The statutes fixing the requirements for the practice of
dentiatry in this state apply to:
"Any person or persons seeking to practice dentistry
in the state, or to (own), operate or cause to be operated,
etc., any dental office."
There is no restriction as to the operation, as the law applies
equally to any and all persons.</p>
<p>The provision exempting the persons engaged in the practice 
at the time of the passage of the act applies equally to all who
at that time were practicing, and is reasonable.

State v. Powell (Minn.) 20 F.W., 258.
State v. Vanderlins, 42 Minn., 129. 43 N.W. 789-
Fox v. Terr. of Wash., 2 W.T., 297.
Webster v. State Board, (Ky.) 113 1 S.W.415.
People v. Phippin, 70 Mich., 6. 3771. W. 888-
Ex parte Spinney, 10 <unclear></unclear> 323.
State vs Raudreph 31 Pac 201 (Oregon)</p>
<p>THE REQUIREMENT OF A DIPLOMA FROM A DENTAL COLLEGE IN 
GOOD STANDING IS A REASONABLE REQUIREMENT.</p>
<p>The petitioner well may state that: "The Supreme Court
of the State of Washington has declared the said law herein 
quoted (R. &amp; B. Code, 8416-24) to be not violative of the State 
or Federal Constitution." In the short but well reasoned opinion
in "The Petition of E.G.Thompson for a Writ of Habeas Corpus",
(36 W. 377), the following appears:

"If we are correct in our conclusion that the legislature, 
in the exercise of its police power, has authority, 
under the state and federal consitutions, to regulate
the practice of dentistry within the state by reasonable
rules, it follows that the legislature may provide that
an applicant he possessed of a diploma from some dental
college in good standing. There is nothing unreasonable
in this requirement, nor in the other requirements names 
in the act. Such diploma is evidence of the ability of
the applicant to practice dentistry. It is not conclusive
of such ability, and the detnal board may, therefore, provide
reasonable rules for determining the actual ability
of the applicant."</p>
<p>We submit that petitioner's position that "unless this
court defends and preserves his rights under the Constitution
of the United States, petitioner will be further restrained of 
his liberty, etc., pursuant to said void and unconstitutional
law and in violation of the Constitution of the United States",
<pb/>
is untenable. The statement that the law is void and unconstitutionable
is a mere conclusion. Petitioner speaks of his rights. What
of the rights of the people of the State of Washington? Countless
practitioners in the profession of dentistry have toiled through difficult
and expensive college curricula in order to secure diplomas. 
Petitioner seeks to be given the same privileges without the attendant
labor and expense.</p>
<p>The case of Webster v. State Bd. of Health of Kentucky (113
SW., 415) is in point. That was a case in which mandamus was invoked
to compel the State Board of Health to issue a certificate to
practice medicine. That statutes of Kentucky authorized the Board
of Health to admit an applicant to examination for a certificate to
practice upon his presenting a diploma from a reputable medicinal college,
or furnishing evidence that he was reputably and honorably 
engaged in the practice of medicine prior to February, 1884. The
court denied the writ, holding that the requirement of a diploma 
was reasonable.
"The statute under consideration is a wise and 
beneficient exercise of the police power of the commonwealth,
enacted for the purpose of protecting the
people of the state from imposition by expiries and
quacks."</p>
<p>We commend to the court's attention the case of State ex
rel Crandall v. McIntosh (Mo.) 103 SW., 1078, as being almost identical 
with the case at bar.</p>
<p>Laws '05 Missouri declared that any person desiring to practice
dentistry in the state, who shall have a license from the dental
board of another state , or who should have received a diploma from
a reputable dental college in any of the United States, should have
the right to apply to the Missour Dental Board for examination as
to proficiency, and to be licensed and registered. In a hearing on
return of a writ of mandamus, the court held: That a citizen of
Missouri never having been licensed by any dental board nor having
obtained a diploma from a dental college was not entitled to urge
<pb/>
that such section was unconstitutional as imparing the rights of
citizens of the different states and foreign countries because
foreigners well equipped to practice dentistry in their country
coming into Missouri without a diploma or license from a dental
board or graduates of dental colleges in the District of Columbia
and citizens of other States where no license was required, and who
were not college graduated, were not entitled to examination in 
Missouri.</p>
<p>The Court in part said:
"A cerificate from the faculty of a colleg attesting
that its bearer as a student, day in and day out, with
the technical knowledge taught in such college as contemplated
by the foregoing statute, if of pronounced significance.
It comes from the hands of honorable and competent men; it
pledges the honor of the college that its holder attended
lectures, possessed himself of the learning of his text books,
passed his term and final examinations with credit under the
eyes of his preceptors, and was capable of rendering professional 
services to the people in accordance with the rules of
his art; that he was, in the language of the State ex rel Gregory,
supra, no pretender, no empiric, mountebank, charlatan, or
quack. It is manifest that no practicable examination by a
dental board could go quite so deep or be so searchingly
broad in its meaning as an honest, well- earned diploma of that
sort. The law places its benediction on such a diploma, assigning
it no trifling office, and public sentiment tends to 
support that theory."

See also People v. Griswold (N.Y.) 106, NE.929.
Ex parte Whitley (Cal.) 77 Pac. 879
Gothard v. People (Colo.) 74 Pac. 890.
Harding v. People (Colo.) 15 Pac. 727.
State vs. Knowles 45 alt 877.</p>
<p>In the words of the court in State v. Creditor (44 Kan.
565, 21 Am, St. 306), commenting on a statute providing that (1)
it should be unlawful for any person to practice dentistry without
having a diploma from a reputable medicial college, and (2)
exempting from the requirement of a diploma those engage in the 
practice of dentistry or dental surgery within the state at the
 time of the passage of the act:

"if the regulations operate equally upon all who may
desire to practice, and who possess the required qualifications,
and if they are adapted to the legislative purpose
of promoting the health and welfar of the people by excluding 
from the practice those who are ignorant and incapable,
then the fact that the conditions may be rigorous,
impolitic and unjust will not render the legislation inthat
<pb/>
valid. The authorities uniformly support the exercise of this
power by the state, and statutes similar to the one under consideration
have been repeatedly sustaned."</p>
<p>Citing: Dent v. W.Va., 129 U.S 114.
State v. Vanderlins, 42 Minn., 129.
Hewitt v. Charier, 16 Pick 353.
Eastman v. State, 109 Ind., 278 (58 Am. Rep. 400). 10 N.E. 97
Ex parte Sinney, 10 Nev. 323.
Harding v. People, 10 Col., 387. 15 Pac 727.
Mussor v. Chase, 29 Ohio St. 577.
Thompson v. Hazen, 25 Me. 104.
State v. Gregory, 83 No. 123.
State v. Med. Ex. Bd., 32 Minn., 324. 20 N.W. 238</p>
<p>The New Hampshire cases State v. Hinman and State v. Fennoyer
cited by the petitioner are not in point and are no authority against the
validity of our statutes. The New Hampshire statute, held to be invalid
in the Hinman case, was an act regulating the practice of dentistry.
It required a dentist practicing in one part of the state
to undergo an examination and to pay a certain license fee, while 
dentists residing elsewhere in the state were exempted from these
requirements. There was a discrimination between persons residing
and practicing in the state, founded solely upon the accidental circumstance
of residence, or a change of residence, and for that reason 
the statute was held to be unconstitutional and void.</p>
<p>Although not specifically declared in the act, the manifest
purpose of the legislature was to exclude from a profession requiring
learning, skill and experience those who are unfit to practice, and
thus protect the public from ignorance and incompetency. No arbitrary
or capricious conditions are imponed. The profession and practice
are open to any and all persons who are qualified and can produce a 
diploma as evidence of such qualification. The legislature was fit
to permit those practicing in the state when the act was passed and
who are citizens of the state, to continue in practice without diploma
or other evidence of competency. This fact is made by the legislature
an evidence of skill and competency equivalent to a diploma
from a dental college, and the wisdom of either test we submit, is a
question for the legislature. The act cannot be held to unduly discriminate
<pb/>
between persons or classes and unconstitutional because
it exempts those engaged in practice within the state when the law
was enacted.</p>
<p>We ask that the writ prayed for by the petitioner, Francis
Stephen Medcraf, be denied.</p>
<p>Repsectfully,
ALFRED H. LUNDIN,
FRANK P. HELSELL,
Attorneys for State of Washington.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>