<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0366.020">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title></title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Yu, Jingming" xml:id="jy">Jingming Yu</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0366.020</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington</title>
<date when="2022-06-28">October 30, 1918</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1918-10-30">October 30, 1918</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Wm. Wagner</term>
<term>W. W. Thomson</term>
<term>Matthew Kaip</term>
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Decker, Fletcher</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, Adam</persName>
<persName>Sullivan</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
                  
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#jy">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0366.020"/>

<p>INCORPORATION OF AGRICULTURAL CO-OPERATIVE ASSOCIATIONS.</p>

<p>No. 210-620</p>
<p>The West Lawn Horizon Grain Growers' Association, Limited, having filed a duly executed memorandum of association, is registered under The Agricultural Co-operative Associations Act this thirtieth day of October, 1918.</p>
<p>The association is limited. Registered office: Horizon. Secretary: Wm. Wagner.</p>
<p>W. W. Thomson,</p>
<p>Registrary Agricultural Co-operative Associations.</p>
<p>7655 22-23</p>

<p>____</p>

<p>No. 210-621</p>
<p>The Bergfield Grain Growers' Association, Limited, having filed a duly executed memorandum of association is registered under The Agricultural Co-operative Associations Act this thirtieth day of October, 1918.</p>
<p>The association is limited. Registered office: Regina. Secretary: Matt. Kaip.</p>
<p>W. W. Thomson,</p>
<p>Registrar Agricultural Co-operative Associations.</p>
<p>7656 22-23</p>

<p>____________</p>

<p>ADVERTISEMENTS.</p>

<p>NOTICE TO ADVERTISERS IN THE GAZETTE.</p>

<p>Parties sending advertisements to be inserted in <!--italics-->The Saskatchewan Gazette<!--italics--> will please observe the following rules:</p>
<p>1.   <!--italics-->The Saskatchewan Gazette<!--italics--> is issued on the fifteenth and the last day of each month.</p>
<p>2.   Address "The Saskatchewan Gazette, Regina, Saskatchewan, Canada."</p><p>3.  Advertisements should reach this office not later than the tenth and twenty-fifth of the month, if for publication in the following issue.</p>
<p>4.   Indicate the number of insertions required.</p>
<p>5.   Invariably remit the fees for such advertisements, together with the price of one gazette as below. Otherwise they will not be inserted. The rates are 10 cents for each six words, each figure and contraction counting as one word. No advetisement is inserted for a less charge than one dollar. Where payment is made by cheque amount of exchange must be added: one-eighth of one per cent., minimum 15 cents.</p>
<p>Poundkeepers' notices - Extract from The Stray Animals Act: "The poundkeeper shall forward to the King's printer for publication a notice, accompanied by a fee of $2 for each animal impounded: Provided that the fees payable to the King's printer in connection with each impoundment shall not exceed $5."</p>
<p>Subscribers will also notice that the subscription, $2 per annum, is invariably payable in advance and that the gazette will be stopped from them at the end of the period paid for. Single numbers will be charged 10 cents each, and when more than one are required by advertisers, must be remitted for likewise.</p>
<p>J. W. Reid,</p>
<p>King's Printer.</p>

<p>____________</p>

<p>LEGISLATIVE ASSEMBLY OF THE PROVINCE OF SASKATCHEWAN.</p>

<p>EXTRACTS FROM RULES RELATING TO PRIVATE BILLS.</p>

<p>PETITIONS.</p>

<p>79.  All petitions for Private Bills shall be in duplicate, and shall be delivered to the Clerk of the Assembly not later than the tenth day before the opening day of the session. No petition for any Private Bill shall be received by the Assembly if presented after the first ten sitting days of each session; nor may any Private Bill be presented to the Assembly after the first fifteen sitting days of each session; nor may any Report of any Standing or Special Committee on a Private Bill be received after twenty sitting days of each session, except as provided for under Rule 104.</p>
<p>It shall be the duty of any Committee to which any Private Bill is referred to consider and report the same to the Assembly with all convenient speed.</p>

<p>EXPENSES.</p>

<p>80.  The expenses and costs attending on Private Bills giving any exclusive privilege, or for any object or profit or private, corporate or individual advantage; or for amending, extending or enlarging any former Acts, in such manner as to confer additional powers, shall be borne by the parties seeking to obtain the same, who shall be required to pay the sums provided by Rule 85.</p>

<p>APPLICATIONS AND PUBLICATION OF NOTICES.</p>

<p>82.  All applications for Private Bills, properly the subject of legislation by the Legislative Assembly of Saskatchewan, within the purview of "The British North America Act 1867," whether for the erection of a bridge, the making of a railroad, tramway, turnpike road, telegraph or telephone line, the construction or improvement of a harbour, canal, lock, dam, slide, or other like work; the granting of a right of ferry; the incorporation of any particular trade or calling or of any joint stock company; or otherwise for granting to an individual or individuals, any exclusive or peculiar rights of privileges whatever, or for doing any matter or thing, which in its operation would affect the rights or property of other parties or relate to any particular class of the community; or for making any amendment of a like nature to any former Act or Ordinance, shall require a notice, clearly and distinctly specifying the nature and object of the application, and where the application referes to any proposed work, indicating generally the location of the work and signed by or on behalf of the applicants. Such notice shall be published, during two months between the close of the next preceeding session and the time of the consideration of the petition, in two consecutive issues of <!--italics-->The Saskatchewan Gazette<!--italics--> and four consecutive issues of one other newspaper, published in English.</p>
<p>Within two weeks from the first appearance of such notice in <!--italics-->The Saskatchewan Gazette<!--italics--> and not later than ten days before the opening day of the session, two copies of the said Bill, with the marginal notes inserted, shall be placed by the applicant in the hands of the Law Clerk, of the Assembly, whose duty it shall be to get the said Bill printed forthwith.</p>
<p>83.  A copy of the notice with a statutory declaration of the several publication of advertisement, shall be sent by the parties inserting such notice to the Clerk of the Assembly, not alter than ten days before the opening day of the session, which shall be filed in the office of the Clerk of the Assembly.</p>
<p>84.  No motion for the suspension of this Rule shall be entertained by the Assembly until the same has been favourably reported upon by the Committee on Standing Orders in accordance with Rules 79, 82, and 83, and if the Committee do report favourably, the specific reasons for so reporting shall be fully reported to the Assembly.</p>

<p>FEES AND DEPOSITS.</p>

<p>85.  Every applicant for a Private Bill shall deposit with the Clerk of the Assembly ten days prior to the meeting of the Assembly, the sum of one hundred and fifty dollars, if the said Bill does not exceed ten pages, and ten dollars additional for each page over that number, for the purpose of this Rule four hundred and fifty words shall be held to constitute a page.</p>
<p>In case of a Bill incorporating a company a receipt form the Registrar of Joint Stock Companies for fees as fixed by law for the registration of Joint Stock Companies shall also be deposited with the Clerk of the Assembly as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Accepted cheques in paymenet of fees should be made payable to the Provincial Treasurer and forwarded to the Clerk of the Assembly along with the copies of the Bill.</p>

<p>REMITTANCE OF FEES.</p>

<p>86.  No remittance of a deposit on account of a Private Bill or of any portion thereof shall be ordered by the Assembly unless the same has been recommended by the Committee charged with the consideration of such Bill, or unless the Bill has been withdrawn, rejected or not reported upon, in which cases the actual expenses incurred shall be deducted form the deposit received.</p>

<p>FORM OF BILLS.</p>

<p>87.  All Private Bills for Acts of incorporation shall be so framed as to incorporate by reference to the clauses of the general Acts relating to the details to be provided for by such Bills. Special grounds shall be established for any roposed departure from this principle, or for the introduction of other provisions as to such details and a note shall be appended to the Bill, indicating the provisions thereof, in which the general Act is proposed to be departed from. Bills which are not framed in accordance with this rule shall be recast by the promoters and reprinted at their expense before any Committee passes upon the clauses.</p>

<p>MODEL BILLS.</p>

<p>88.  All Private Bills for Acts of incorporation or in amendment of Acts, where a form of a Model Bill has been adopted, shall be drawn in accordance with the Model Bill, copies of which may be obtained form the Clerk of the Assembly.</p>
<p>    (a) The provisions contained in any Bill which are not in accord with the Model Bill shall be inserted between brackets, and when revised by the proper officer shall be so printed, and Bill which are not in accordance with their rule shall be returned to the promoters to be recast before being revised and printed.</p>
<p>    (b) Any sections of existing Acts or Ordinances which are proposed to be amended shall be reprinted in full with the amendments inserted in their proper places and between brackets.</p>
<p>    (c) Any exceptional provisions that may be proposed to insert in any Bill shall be clearly specified in the notice of application for the same.</p>

<p>MAPS, PLANS AND EXHIBITS WITH PETITIONS.</p>

<p>89.  Before any petition praying for leave to bring in a Billf or the constitution of a railway or for the changing of the route of the railway of any company already incorporated, tramways or canals is received by the Assembly, the person or persons petitioning for such Bills shall deposit with the Clerk of the Assembly the following documents:</p>
<p>    (1) A map or plan upon a scale of not less than one inch to three miles; showing the location upon which it intended to construct the proposed work , and showing also the lines of existing or authorised works of a similar charactyer within or in any way affecting the district or any pat thereof, which the proposed work is intended to serve. Such map or plan to be signed by the engineer or other parties making the same.</p>
<p>    (2) A Book of Reference, in which shall be clearly set out the following information in separate schedules, namely:</p>
<p>Schedule A. - A general description of the nature, extent and proposed character of the contemplated works and an estimate of the probable cost thereof, distinguishing the general items of construction and the costs thereof respectively, as well as the nature, extent and probable cost of all engine and car stock or other outfit or equipment necessary to the use and operation of the proposed undertaking, such schedule to be signed by the engineer or other person preparing the same.</p>
<p>Schedule B. - An exhibit showing the total amount of capital proposed to be raised for the purpose of their undertaking and the manner in which it is proposed to raise the same, whethe rby ordinary shares, bonds, debentures or other securities and the amount of each respectively.</p>

<p>SUSPENSION OF RULES.</p>

<p>104. Except in cases of urgent and pressing necessity no motion for the suspension or modification of any rule applying to Private Bills or petitions for Private Bills shall be entertained by the Assembly until after reference is made to the Committee on Standing Orders, or to one of the Committees charged with the consideration of Private Bills, and a report made thereon by one or more of such Committees, who shall state in such report the grounds for recommending such suspension.</p>
<p>G. A. Mantle.</p>
<p>Clerk Legislative Assembly.</p>

<p>____________</p>

<p>NOTICE REGARDING PETITIONS AND PRIVATE BILLS.</p>

<p>Notice is hereby given in accordance with Rules 79 and 81 that the time for presenting Petitions for Private Bills to the Legislative Assembly of Saskatchewan at its forthcoming session will expire on the sixteenth day of December, 1918, and that the time for presenting Private Bills to the Assembly at such session will expire on the twenty-third day of December, 1918.</p>
<p>G. A. Mantle,</p>
<p>Clerk Legislative Assembly.</p>

<p>____________</p>

<p>NOTICES OF PRIVATE BILLS.</p>

<p>Notice is hereby given that an application will be made on behalf of the Equitable Trust Company at the next session of the Saskatchewan Legislature for an Act directing the Registrar of Joint Stock Companies to issue a license to the said company to exercise its powers within Saskatchewan, excepting that power to accept money on deposit.</p>
<p>Dated at Mocse Jaw, Saskatchewan, this twenty-fifth dady of November, A D. 1918.</p>
<p>Haig &amp; Haig, Barristers, Etc.,</p>
<p>Moose Jaw,</p>
<p>Solicitors for the Applicant.</p>

<p>7713</p>

<p>____</p>

<p>Notice is hereby given that an application will be made at the next session of the Saskatchewan Legislature for An Act to incorporate the Moose Jaw College.</p>
<p>Dated at Moose Jaw this thirty-first day of October, 1918.</p>
<p>Willoughby, Craqig &amp; Beynon,</p>
<p>Solicitors for the Applicant.</p>

<p>7594 21-22</p>

<p>____________</p>

<p>DISSOLUTIONS OF PARTNERSHIP.</p>

<p>Take notice that Edward Mack and John Rothney, carrying on business as farming at Plato, in the Province of Saskatchewan, under the style and name of Mack and Rothney, have dissolved partnership by mutual consent, on the seventeenth day of October, A.D. 1918.</p>
<p>Witness: R. W. Hambly.       (Signed)    Edward Mack.</p>

<p>7568, 7629 22-23</p>

<p>____</p>

<p>Notice is hereby given that the copartnership heretofore subsisting between the undersigned as flour, feed, coal and wood dealers at Ogema, Saskatchewan, under the firm name of Charles Tuck and Company has been this day dissolved by mutual consent. The business hereafter will be carried on by Charles Tuck, by whom all debts of the old firm will be paid and to whom all outstanding accounts due the old firm are to be paid.</p>
<p>Signed at Ogema, Saskatchewan, this twenty-fourth day of October, A.D. 1918, in the presence of:</p>
<p>J. A. Horner, as to signature of Chas. Tuck;     Chas. Tuck.</p>
<p>Thos. Harvey, as to signature of Geo. W. Crittenden.     G. W. Crittenden.</p>

<p>7567 21-22</p>

<p>____________</p>

<p>NOTICES TO CREDITORS.</p>

<p>In the matter of the estate of Walter Elliott Lawledge, deceased:</p>
<p>Notice is hereby given that all persons having claims on the estate of the late Walter Elliott Lawledge, who died on or about the ninth day of April, A.D. 1917, are required to send to The Imperial Canadian Trust Company, at the city of Winnipeg in Manitoba, on or before the first day of December, A.D. 1918, a full statement of their claim and of any security held by them, duly verified, and that after that date the executors will proceed to distribute the assets of the said deceased among the parties entitled thereto, having regard only to the claims filed with them.</p>
<p>Dated at Winnipeg, in Manitoba, this thirty-first day of October, 1918.</p>
<p>The Imperial Canadian Trust Company,</p>
<p>Per their solicitors,</p>
<p>Taylor, Ross &amp; Leach,</p>
<p>Winnipeg, Manitoba.</p>

<p>7614 22-23</p>

<p>____</p>

<p>In the matter of the Northwestern Electric Company, Limited, Regina, Sask.:</p>
<p>Notice is hereby given that the Northwestern Electric Company, Limited, doing business as dealers in electrical supplies and contracting, in the city of Regina in the Province of Saskatchewan, made an assignment under the provisions of The Assignments Act on November 8, 1918, to the Saskatchewan General Trust Corporation, Limited, assignee, for the general benefit of creditors.</p>
<p>A meeting of the creditors will be held on the fourth day of December, 1918, in the office of Saskatchewan General Trust Corporation, Limited, 1811 Cornwall Street, Regina, at the hour of 2 p.m., for the submission to the creditors of a statement of the affairs of the said company, for the appointment of inspectors and giving of directions with reference to the disposal of the assets, and the general ordering of affairs. All creditors are hereby notified to attend the said meeting either in person or by representative duly authorized in writing to vote at the said meeting. All creditors are required to file with the Saskatchewan General Trust Corporation, Limited, Regina, on or before the date of such meeting full particulars of the amount and value of their claims and of any security held by them therefor, duly verified by statutory declaration.</p>
<p>Further notice is given that after the expiration of thirty days from the date of this notice the Saskatchewan General Trust Corporation, Limited, will proceed to distribute the assets of the said company amongst the parties entitled thereto, having regard only to claim duly proved and filed with it as herein set out on or before such date, and shall not be liable for assets of the said company or any part thereof so distributed to any person or persons of whose claim it has not had notice on said date.</p>
<p>Dated at Regina the twentieth day of November, A.D. 1918.</p>
<p>Saskatchewan General Trust Corporation, Limited,</p>
<p>Assignee, Regina, Saskatchewan,</p>
<p>E. E. Murphy, Manager.</p>

<p>7668</p>

<p>____</p>

<p>In the matter of George Samuel Wyman, Wood Mountain, Sask.:</p>
<p>Notice is hereby given that George Samuel Wyman, formerly carrying on business as general merchant in the village of Wood Mountain in the Province of Saskatchewan, had made a sale under the provisions of The Bulk Sales Act to C. R. Rucker, of the village of Wood Mountain in the Province of Saskatchewan.</p>
<p>A meeting of creditors will be held in the offices of The Canadian Credit Men's Trust, Association, Limited, Regina, on Friday, November 29, 1918, at 3 pm., for the submission to the creditors of a statement of the affairs of the said estate, for the appointment of inspectors and the giving of directions with reference to the disposal of the estate and the general ordering of affairs. All creditors are hereby notified to attend the said meeting either in person or by representative duly authorised in writing to vote at the said meeting.</p>
<p>All creditors of the said estate are required to file with The Canadian Credit Men's Trust Aassociation, Limited, Regina, full particulars of the amount and nature of their claims and of any security held by them therefor duly verified by statutory declaration.</p>
<p>Further notice is given that after the expiration of thirty days from the date of this notice The Canadian Credit Men's Trust Association, Limited, will proceed to distribute the assets of the said estate amongst the parties entitled thereto having regard only to claims fully proven and filed with it as herein set out on or before such date, and shall not be liable for the assets of the said estate or any part thereof so distributed to any person of whose claim it has not had notice of on said date.</p>
<p>Dated at Regina this nineteenth day of November, A.D. 1918.</p>
<p>The Canadian Credit Men's Trust Association, Limited,</p>
<p>W. Geddes,</p>
<p>Acting Manager Saskatchewan Division.</p>

<p>7697</p>

<p>____________</p>

<p>POUNDKEEPERS' NOTICES.</p>

<p>Extract from The Stray Animals Act: "The poundkeeper shall forward to the King's printer for publication a notice, accompanied by a fee of $2 for each animal impounded: provided that the fees payable to the King's printer in connection with each impoundment shall not exceed $5."</p>
<p>Under the provisions of The Stray Animals Act notice is hereby given that the following animals have been impounded at the places and on the dates mentioned:</p>
<p>Red and white Hereford cow, twelve years old, weight about 1,200 pounds, white face, dark rings around eyes, under part of body nearly all white, tips of horns cut off, no visible brands; at SE. 10-24-1w2, on November 22, 1918. Robert Moffat, Saltcoats.   7695</p>
<p>Aged brown mare and foal, brand on left shoulder resembling N; at 8-17-25, on November 9, 1918. J. S. Coehran, 114 Ominica St. W., Moose Jaw.    7611.</p>
<p>Black and white steer, two years old, short horns which might have been treaty when a calf; red steer, one year old small horns, white on tail and belly, circular piece out of right ear; at SE. 32-5-2w2, on October 26, 1918. Marshall Watson, Dalesboro. 7634.</p>
<p>Gray mare, two years old, little white on hind legs; bay mare, two years old, white star on forehead; bay mare, two years old, white stripe down forehead; dark gray golding, two years old, white mark on forehead; dark brown golding, white star on forehead; no brans; at 3-28-2, on November 9, 1918. Conrad Graf, Rhein.   7638.</p>
<p>Red horse, ten years old, weight at about 1,000 pounds, white star in face, three white feet; white horse, ten years old, weight about 1,000 pounds; white star in face, three white fet; white horse, ten years old, weight about 1,000 pounds; red horse, nine or ten years old, weight about 1,000 pounds, white star in face, white on right front foot; chestnut mare pony, nine or ten years old, weight about 900 pounds, white in face; at SW. 29-10-5w3, on October 31, 1918. J. Bachand, Gravelbourg.  7619.</p>
<p>Buckskin filly, two years old, weight about 800 pounds, dark mane and tail, at SE. 14-19-19w2, on November 12, 1918. George Mollard, R.R. No. 1, Regina,   7637.</p>
<p>White boar pig, weight about 100 pounds; at NE. 2-24-6w2, on November 14, 1918. L. Anderson Melville.   7647.</p>
<p>Bay gelding, weight about 1,150 pounds, left hind foot white, has been cut badly with white on both front legs, foretop trimmed, bran on left jaw resembling SI in circle; at NW. 21-29-25w3, on November 12, 1918. Wesley Mortin, Pinkham.   7646.</p>
<p>Sorrel mare, weight about 1,200 pounds, small star in forehead, no shoe, no halter, no brands; at SW. 14-43-3w3, on October 29, 1918. Elie Macfaire, Rosthern.   7661.</p>
<p>Bay horse, white face, with halter; gray horse, white face, legs white, brand on left thigh, resembling JT; at NW. 32-5-3w3, on November 16, 1918. Petrea Yorga, Gollier.   7660.</p>
<p>Black cow and calf; black cow and calf, without horns; red cow and calf; black and white yearling steer; no visible brands; at 30-18-4w2, on November 7, 1918. P. H. M. Criddle, Dubue.   7613.</p>
<p>Brown horse, one year old, white stripe on face, hind legs and one front leg white; at NE. 9-3-4w2, on October 3, 1918. Andrew Mackie, Frobisher.   7610.</p>
<p>Bay horse, weight about 1,500 pounds, white face, no visible brand; black horse. weight about 1,500 pounds, no visible brand; at SW. 22-12-5w2, on October 21, 1918. Joe Ijsak Kipling.   7612.</p>
<p>Gray mare, aged, weight about 900 pounds; bay horse, aged, weight about 1,400 pounds, left hind leg white; bay mare, weight about 1,100 pounds, right fore leg white, left hind leg white, white stripe down face; bay mare, weight about 1,100 pounds, fore feet white, small white stripe down face; on November 6, 1918. I. Heurtson, Coleville.  7648.</p>
<p>White pig; at NW. 23-2-24w2, on November 8, 1918. John Frisk, Gallocks. 7657.</p>
<p>Red bull calf, eight months old, split in left ear; red heifer calf, eight months old; red heifer calf, eight months old, white face, white mark on hip; on November 16, 1918. Alex. Reilly Atwater.   7669.</p>
<p>Dark bay stallion, about eleven years old; at SW. 30-14-28, on October 28, 1918. A. C. Yeoger, Donjcan.   7627.</p>
<p>Brindle heifer, about eighteen months old, inch cut off end of left ear when calf, healed and haired over; at NE. 8-6-13w2, on November 23, 1918. John Nichol, Goodwater, R.F.D. No. 1.   7698.</p>

<p>____________</p>

<p>NOTICES OF LOST ANIMALS.</p>

<p>Reward for cattle branded GG<!--"GG" is on top of one another--> right shoulder and horses branded GGI<!--"GGI" is on top of one another, with top to bottom being: I, G, G--> right hip. Joseph Glen, Indian Head, 3537.          XIV 3-XV 2</p>
<p>Strayed from SW. 32-28-13w2, in July, red muley heifer, two years old, no marks or brands; $10 reward. Mike Hawryluk, Pruden. 7662.          XIV 22-XV 1</p>
<p>Strayed from 17-42-18, bay mare, seven yeras old, weight about 1,400 pounds, small patch of white above right hind hoof, leather halter. $15 reward. John Fidyk, Silver Park. 7602, 7683.            22-23</p>
<p>Strayed from NW. 35-15-7w3, about October 20, iron gray mare, four years old, weight about 1,300 pounds, white face; bay mare, three yeras old, weight about 1,300 pounds, white star on forehead, hind feet white; gray gelding, three yeras old, weight about 1,100 pounds, mane cut short, had rope on neck; black horse colt, one year old, white star on forehead. Suitable reward for information leading to recovery. Frank Wittal, Morse. 7682.</p>
<p>Strayed since April 18, 1918, dark brown mare, two and one-half years old, feet white, gray tail, star on forehead; $10 reward. Buium Nacht, Lipton. 7672.</p>
<p>Strayed from SE. 20-34-25w2, on or about October 1, 1918, black heifer, two years old, small white spot on right side back of fore leg. Anton J. Farago, Plunkett. 7620.</p>
<p>Strayed from Kindersley, in March, 1918, sorrel gelding, six years old, weight about 1,050 pounds, brand resembling open key down over bar LS; bay gleding, seven years old, weight about 1,100 pounds, brand resembling open key down over bar LS; sorrel mare, five yeras old, in foal, weight about 1,250 pounds, brand unknown. Reward for information leading to recovery. J. Richardson, Kindersley. 7019.   18-22</p>

<p>____________</p>

<p>NOTICES OF STRAY ANIMALS.</p>

<p>Strayed to E. 32-23-17, bay mare, four years old, white face, hind feet, and one front foot white. Ed. Minogue, Plumbridge.   7628.</p>
<p>Strayed to SW. 2-38-14w3, on or about January 1, 1918, light bay pony mare cold, rising three years, black legs, mane and tail, small white star in forehead, no visible brands; strayed early in May, 1918, small heifer calf, about seven months old, Jersey brindle with white spots. Wesley Cowell, Kensmith.    7601, 7671.</p>


<p>INDEX</p>
<p>____</p>

<p>Appointments:                                                     PAGE</p>
<p>Justices of the Peace................................................1</p>
<p>Notaries Public......................................................1</p>
<p>Commissioners for Oaths..............................................1</p>
<p>Acting Deputy Attorney General.......................................1</p>
<p>Deputy Registration Clerks...........................................2</p>
<p>Issuers of Marriage Licenses.........................................2</p>
<p>Director of Rural Education Associations and School Fairs............2</p>
<p>Administrator of Estates of Deceased Soldiers........................2</p>
<p>Provincial Police Force..............................................2</p>
<p>Voluntary Game Guardian..............................................2</p>

<p>Resignation and Retirements..........................................2</p>

<p>Sitting of the Court of King's Bench.................................3</p>

<p>Orders in Council:</p>
<p>Regulations under The Theatres and Cinematographs Act................4</p>
<p>Regulations Governing Public Health..................................5</p>
<p>License Fees under The Companies Act.................................5</p>
<p>Regulations Governing Purchase of Live Stock.........................5</p>
<p>The Land Titles Act..................................................5</p>

<p>Government Notices:</p>
<p>School Districts empowered to Borrow Money:</p>
<p>The Storthoaks P. S. School District No. 2...........................5</p>
<p>The Gergovia School District No. 4064................................6</p>
<p>The Gumbo Flat School District No. 4086..............................6</p>
<p>The Willow Lake School District No. 2081.............................6</p>
<p>The Barvas School District No. 3452..................................6</p>
<p>The Light School District No. 2346...................................6</p>
<p>The Dafoe School District No. 4038...................................7</p>
<p>The Rosemary School District No. 4093................................7</p>
<p>The Highcroft School District No. 2953...............................7</p>
<p>Incorporation of Joint Stock Companies:</p>
<p>Alaska Fur Manufacturing Company, Limited............................7</p>
<p>The Ruthenian-Canadian Club..........................................7</p>
<p>Independent Laundry, Limited.........................................7</p>
<p>Puritan Flour Milling Company, Limited...............................8</p>
<p>Turner's Weekly, Limited.............................................8</p>
<p>Richland Farms, Limited..............................................8</p>
<p>E. Scarlett, Limited.................................................8</p>
<p>The Sheho Ukrainian People's Home Association........................8</p>
<p>A. M. Jones, Limited.................................................8</p>
<p>Cypress Lodge Building Company, Limited..............................8</p>
<p>Grant and Company, Limited...........................................8</p>
<p>The Loyal Oarnge Temple Company, Limited.............................9</p>
<p>Sweet Brothers, Limited..............................................9</p>
<p>Jones Tractor and Implement Company, Limited.........................9</p>
<p>Registration of Joint Stock Companies:</p>
<p>Todhunter Mitchell Coffee Company, Limited...........................9</p>
<p>Benson-Stabeck Company, Limited......................................9</p>
<p>Change of Name of Companies:</p>
<p>B. J. Jonson Soap Company, Limited...................................9</p>
<p>Artic Ice Company (1913), Limited....................................9</p>
<p>A. Dulmage, Limited..................................................9</p>
<p>Increase of Capital of a Company:</p>
<p>The Palmolive Company of Canada, Limited............................10</p>
<p>Reduction of Capital of a Company:</p>
<p>The Royal Oak Saddlery Company, Limited.............................10</p>
<p>Incorporation of Benevolent Society:</p>
<p>The Evangelical St. Jon's Lutheran Church of the Synod of Missouri..10</p>
<p>Proposed Dissolution of a Joint Stock Company:</p>
<p>The Bolduan Manufacturing Company, Limited..........................10</p>

<p>Government Notices - <!--italics-->Continued<!--italics--></p>
<p>Dissolution of Joint Stock Companies:</p>
<p>Calgary Typesetting Company, Limited................................10</p>
<p>The Rob Roy Cereal Mills Company, Limited...........................10</p>
<p>Denzil Supply Company, Limited......................................10</p>
<p>Consolidated Farm Lands, Limited....................................10</p>
<p>The North American Accident Insurance Company.......................11</p>
<p>W. L. McQuarrie, Limited............................................11</p>
<p>Hazelton and Walin, Limited.........................................11</p>
<p>James Limited.......................................................11</p>
<p>Heller-Aller Company, Limited.......................................11</p>
<p>Companies Struck off the Register:</p>
<p>The Yorkton Holding Company, Limited................................11</p>
<p>Moose Jaw Ukranian-Ruthenian Co-operative Company, Limited..........11</p>
<p>The Rainton Threshing Machine Company, Limited......................11</p>
<p>Rural Telephone Companies empowered to Borrow Money:</p>
<p>The North Ernfold Rural Telephone Company...........................11</p>
<p>The Raymore Rural Telephone Company.................................12</p>
<p>The Kansas Rural Telephone Company..................................12</p>
<p>The Engelfeld Rural Telephone Company...............................12</p>
<p>The Acme Rural Telephone Company....................................14</p>
<p>The Findlater Rural Telephone Company...............................14</p>
<p>The North Weldon Rural Telephone Company............................14</p>
<p>The Dewar Lake Rural Telephone Company..............................15</p>
<p>The Bruce Rural Telephone Company...................................15</p>
<p>The East Yorkton Rural Telephone Company............................16</p>
<p>The Roseville Rural Telephone Company...............................16</p>
<p>Additional Lands Chargeable as Security:</p>
<p>The Minot Rural Telephone Company...................................17</p>
<p>The Argo Rural Telephone Company....................................17</p>
<p>Incorporation of Agricultural Co-operative Associations:</p>
<p>The West Lawn Horizon Grain Growers' Association....................17</p>
<p>The Bergfield Grain Growers' Association............................17</p>

<p>Advertisements:</p>
<p>Notice to Advertisers in the Gazette................................17</p>
<p>Legislative Assembly of the Province of Saskatchewan:</p>
<p>Extracts from Rules Relating to Private Bills.......................18</p>
<p>Notice Regarding Petitions and Private Bills........................20</p>
<p>Notices of Private Bills:</p>
<p>Equitable Trust Company.............................................20</p>
<p>Moose Jaw College...................................................20</p>
<p>Dissolutions of Partnership:</p>
<p>Mack and Rothney....................................................20</p>
<p>Chas. Tuck and Company..............................................20</p>
<p>Notices to Creditors:</p>
<p>Walter Elliott Lawledge.............................................21</p>
<p>North Western Electric Company, Limited.............................21</p>
<p>George Samuel Wyman.................................................21</p>
<p>Poundkeepers' Notices...............................................22</p>
<p>Notices of Lost Animals.............................................23</p>
<p>Notices of Stray Animals............................................23</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>