<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0178.015.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Mac Fock v. State of Washington. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0178.015</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Mac Fock v. State of Washington. Type of document</title>
<date>when="1913">1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Mac Fock</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>State of Washington</persName>
<persName>Ellis De Bruler</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Victor Place</persName>
<persName>L. Frank Brown</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Earl B. Brockway</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
<persName>Edward Cushman</persName>
</person>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE WESTERN
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of MAC FOCK,
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>AFFIDAVIT OF MAC FOCK.</p>
<p>Exhibit A.</p>
<p>---------</p>
<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON } ss.</p>
<p>MAC FOCK, being first duly sworn, on oath deposes and says</p>
<p>I.   That affiant belongs to the Mongolian race, being a 
Chinaman; that he believes that the Judge before whom the application 
for a writ of habeas corpus, to-wit: Judge Cushman, 
of the United States District Court for the Western District of 
Washington, has a personal prejudice against him by virtue of 
the race to which be belongs.</p>
<p>II.  That he is informed and believes, and so states the fact 
to be, that Judge Cushman for many was a prosecutor in 
the United States District Attorney's office for the Western 
District of Washington, and an assistant solicitor of the United
States Government, and in such position formed a habit of thought
and belief and prejudice that the United States of America, through
its delegated official life in Washington, was in the right in 
adminstrative matters under the Chinese laws of the United States, and by which official experience, became, and has become, 
and now is, so impressed with the presumption of guilt of the 
ordinary Chinese character, under the Chinese Exclusion Acts
that although honest in his intention to be fair, it is impossible
by virtue of past experience so to do, and he does not
and will not in the action at bar bring to the determination of 
the issues herein, that equipose of judgment essential for the 
trial of cases in such case made and provided. </p>
<p>III. That affiant is informed and believes and so states the</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>fact to be, that when the application for a writ of habeas corpus 
in the above cause was presented to his Honor, Judge Cushman, and 
that certified judgment upon which the discharge of this affiant
was predicated, namely, the discharge under what is known as the 
McKettrick certificates in the Federal Government, his Honor,
Judge Cushman, smiled, and indicated to the Counsel of his affiant
that it would take very strong evidence to remove from his 
mind the presumpton that a discharge under such a certified
copy was not tinctured with fraud, showing then and there that
he did not, under and by virtue of the Constitution of the United 
States and the traditions both of the common and statutory law
thereof, give the presumption of innocence to this affiant. </p>
<p>IV.  That this affiant has not been bale to file this affidavit 
of bias and prejudice against his Honor, Judge Cushman, sitting 
in and for the Western District of Washington, ten days before 
the beginning of the term of this court, for the reason that affiant
had no knowledge or information that it would be necessary 
to bring a writ of habeas corpus until the 4th day of June
A.D. 1913, and therefore, he was not able to comply with the 
statute in such case made and provided, to-wit, the filing of 
such affidavit of bias and prejudice as herein set forth, within 
the ten days, as required by statute.</p>
<p>V.   That he was not aware of the bias and prejudice of Judge
Cushman in asking for the writ of habeas corpus herein, and did 
not fully consider the same until informed by his Counsel of the 
remarks of Judge Cushman upon the granting of said writ, when the mattes
and things herein set forth are called to his attention, 
and he then stated, and now believes and is informed by his 
Counsel that he cannot have a fair and impartial trial before his
Honor, Judge Cushman, sitting as a United States District Judge
within and for the Western District of Washington, because of 
the facts aforesaid, and because of the tempermental attitude of
the mind of said Judge Cushman, by virtue of being a Governmental</p>
<pb/>
<p>employee for so many years, seeking the deportation of the Chinese
race in general.</p>
<p>VI.  That he has stated fully and fairly to his Counsel, L.
Frank Brown and Victor M. Place, the matters and thiings herein
set forth, and they in good faith believe, as he is informed and 
believes, that such application for the calling in of another 
Judge, according to the statues of the United States of America, 
(36 Statue at large, Section 1090), should prevail, and that his 
Honor, Judge Cushman, as aforesaid, should proceed no further
therein, but another Judge from the interior portions of the 
country who has no such bias or prejudice against the Mongolian 
race in general, or any person seeking entrance therein under and 
by virtue of the McKettrick discharges known to the Government,
might be chosen to sit fairly and impartially upon the issue involved
against this affiant.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, affiant prays that his honor, Judge Cushman,
shall proceed no further herein, and that his Honor, Judge Rudkin, 
of the Northern District of Washington, shall be chosen to proceed
herein, or some other judge who has not the tempermental 
attitude fo his Honor, Judge Cushman, as herein set forth.</p>
<p>Witness <unclear></unclear></p>
<p><unclear reason="chinese"></unclear> (Mac Fock)</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 21st day of June, A.D. 1913.</p><p>Benjamin M. <unclear>Lumir</unclear></p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State 
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>