<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0221.014">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chin Quock Wah vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0221.014</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Chin Quock Wah vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-06">June 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Beeler, Adam</term>
<term>Chin, Quock Wah</term>
<term>Chin, Wing Hin</term>
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Lakin, Edward M.</term>
<term>Sullivan, John J.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>China</term>    
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Chin Quock Wah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Adam Beeler</persName>
<persName>John J. Sullivan</persName>    
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-03" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT, IN AND FOR THE WESTERN 
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of CHIN QUOCK <add>Wah</add>
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. )
NO. 2971.
ASSIGNMENT OF 
ERRORS.</p>

<p>Comes JOHN J. SULLIVAN, and as Attorney for the 
petitioner and appellant in the above entitled cause, says: That in 
the record and proceeding in this case, and in the Order and 
Judgment entered on the twenty-ninth day of May, 1915, there is manifest 
errors in this, to wit:</p>
<p>I. 
That the Court erred in refusing to grant the Writ of Habeas 
Corpus, and discharge the petitioner.</p>
<p>II. 
That the Court erred in admitting in evidence the so-called
record marked "Exhibit A" without further proof than the certificate 
thereunto appended.</p>
<p>III.
That the Court erred in ruling that the so-called record
marked "Exhibit A" was to the effect that CHIN QUOCK WAH had been
granted a full and fair hearing on his application to land in the 
United States.</p>
<p>IV.
That the Court erred in ruling that the so-called record
marked "Exhibit A" proved that the petitioner had been accorded the 
right to appeal from the excluding decision, and that said appeal
had been heard and decided in a fair and legal manner, in accordance 
with the rules and regulations governing the admission of Chinese
into the United States.</p>
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
<p>V.
That the Court erred in overruling counsel for petitioner
that inasmuch as said so-called "Exhibit A" contained no written
decision or order signed by the Secretary of Commerce and Labor, 
it did not appear therefrom that the appeal had been duly acted 
upon by the United States.</p>
<p>VI.
That the Court erred in ruling that the so-called "Exhibit A"
proved that a proper record on appeal had been submitted to, and 
acted upon by the officers authorized by law to act, under and by
virtue of the rules and regulations governing admission of Chinese
into the United States, and the right to appeal from an adverse
decision by the Commissioner at the Port of Entry.</p>
<p>VII.
That the Court erred in refusing to rule as requested by 
counsel for petitioner, that the memorandum for the Assistant Secretary 
included in said record made by the Commissioner-General of Immigration, 
or under his authority, and was not evidence, was not given
under oath as shown by the record, and should not have been made a 
part of the record or admissable.</p>
<p>VIII.
That the Court erred in ruling that the so-called record 
marked "Exhibit A", conclusively proved that the petitioner had been 
accorded a fair hearing, both at the port of entry and on appeal, 
in accordance with the law and treaty between the United States and 
China, and rules and regulations governing the admission of Chinese, 
and that there was evidence to substantiate the findings of the 
Department.</p>
<p>IX.
That the Court erred in refusing to rule that no one but the
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
Secretary of Commerce and Labor has a right to affirm an excluding
decision.</p>
<p>X.
That the Court erred in refusing to rule that letters, etc.
from officials to the Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, and 
to the Department were not evidence, not given under oath, contained
private opinions, and were not admissable, and should not be 
considered by the officials of the Department in determining the 
decision in this case.</p>
<p>XI.
That the Court erred in refusing to rule that there was 
nothing in the record to show that the Assistant Secretary had been
authorized to act.</p>
<p>XII.
That the Court erred in refusing to rule that the record 
showed such unfairness and illegality as to warrant the Court to 
investigate the status, or dispose of the case as law and justice
required, omitting therefrom such evidence as should not have been 
admissible.</p>
<p>XIII.
That the Court erred in not ruling that the McGettrick 
certificate issued July ninth, 1896 to the alleged father of the 
petitioner, and made a part of the record, was not "res adjudicata" of 
his citizenship.</p>
<p>XIV.
That the Court erred in not ruling and finding that teh 
status of the alleged father was made on his trip to China, and his
return therefrom in January, 1914, as a merchant and citizen of the 
United States.</p>
<p>XV.
That the Court erred in not finding that the petitioner was 
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
a minor son of CHIN WING HIN, and a minor son of a Chinese
merchant, and a minor son of a citizen of the United States, and 
therefore should be allowed to land.</p>
<p>XVI.
That the Court erred in rendering a Decree, discharging the 
Writ of Habeas Corpus, and remanding the petitioner to the custody
of the officerst of the United States, and depriving him of his liberty.</p>
<p>XVII.
That said order entered on the twenty-ninth day of May, 
1915 is not warranted by, nor supported by the facts of the law 
in the premises, but is contrary thereto,</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, said CHIN QUOCK WAH, the petitioner and appellant 
herein, by and through his Attorney, JOHN J. SULLIVAN, prays that 
his Assignment of Errors be entered upon the record in this case, 
and that upon the hearing o fthis appeal it may be adjudged by the 
United States Supreme Court, and that the Order and Judgment on the 
twenty-ninth day of May, 1915 made and entered, be in all things
reversed, set aside and held for naught, and that it be adjudged 
and decreed that the petitioner and appellant have an adjudication
in his favor, as prayed for in said amended petition.</p>
<ab>Chin Quock Wah
Petitioner</ab>
<p>BY AND THROUGH</p> <ab> John J Sullivan
His Solicitor</ab>

<fw>-4-</fw>
<pb/>

<p>NO. 2971
ORIGINAL</p>
<p>IN THE 
SUPERIOR COURT
STATE OF WASHINGTON
KING COUNTY</p>

<p>In the Matter of the 
Application of CHIN QUOCK 
WAH, for a Writ of Habeas 
Corpus
<del>Plaintiff
vs.
Defendant</del></p>

<p>ASSIGNMENT OF ERRORS</p>

<p>BEELER &amp; SULLIVAN 
LAWYERS 
510-11 WHITE BUILDING
SEATTLE, WASH.</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington,
NORTHERN DIVISION
JUN101915</p>
<ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk
By Ed M Lakin Deputy
2x</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>