<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0366.016">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Deposition of Charles Burdette Robinson</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0366.016</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Deposition of Charles Burdette Robinson</title>
<date when="1921-07-25">July 25, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-07">July 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Robinson, Charles Burdette</term>
<term>MacEchen, Alexander Joseph Gordon</term>
<term>Ficklin, Claude</term>
<term>Robinson, Cassius M. Clay</term>
<term>Edwards, John Charles </term>
<term>Windeatt, W. F.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Saskatchewan, Canada</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Decker, Fletcher</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, Adam</persName>
<persName>Sullivan</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-07" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Dominion of Canada</p>
<p>Province of Saskatchewan</p>

<p>THE KING vs. FLETCHER DECKER.</p>

<p>THE DEPOSITION of CHARLES BURDETTE ROBINSON, taken this 25th day of July A.D. 1921 before she undersigned Alexander Joseph Gordon MacEchen, a Justice of the Peace in and for the Province of Saskatchewan, in the Dominion of Canada, in the matter of Fletcher Decker who is charged upon oath for that he on or about the 15th day of November in the year of our Lord One thousand nine hundred and fifteen near Wiwa Hill Post Office in the Province of Saskatchewan aforesaid did steal about 300 bushels of flax the property of Claude Ficklin and was thereby guilty of theft.</p>

<p>Now the said CHARLES BURDETTE ROBINSON on his oath saith as follows:</p>

<p>I am a brother of Cassius M. Olay Robinson, and am a farmer residing on the North-West quarter of Section Ten (10), Township Fourteen (14), Range Five (5), West of the Third Meridian in the Province of Saskatchewan in the Domion of Canada, and have been living on the said land since the spring of 1913.</p>

<pb/>

<p>-2-</p>

<p>This quarter on which I have been living is approximately five miles from Wiwa Hill Post Office in the Province of Saskatchewan. I have known Fletcher Decker for about fourteen years. I know him in Idaho, one of the United States of America, before he came to Canada. He lived there in Coeur D'Alene City. He came to Canada before I did. In the year 1915 Fletcher Decker was living about three miles south of my place in the Province of Saskatchewan. In the fall of 1915 I heard in Gravelbourg in the said Province of Saskatchewan that Claude Ficklin had had some flax stolen, and that it had been traced to Fletcher Decker. My brother Cassius M. Clay Robinson was living in the vicinity at that time. I told him what I had heard about Fletcher Decker. I knew that my said brother had business dealing with Fletcher Decker. I was at my said brother's place the morning after I had told him what I had heard about Fletcher Decker. While I was at my brother's place on the said morning Fletcher Decker came up to get a team of horses from my brother. My said brother Cassius had a conversation that morning with Fletcher Decker in my presence. My said brother asked Fletcher Decker how much flax he had taken from Ficklin. Fletcher Decker first denied having taken any flax. My brother continued to accuse him of the theft of Ficklin's flax, and Fletcher Decker at last owned up that he did take it. To the best of my recollection</p>

<pb/>

<p>-3-</p>

<p>Decker said that he took about four hundred bushels. My brother told Fletcher Decker that he thought Decker was likely to be arrested, and asked him what was to be done about his, that is, my brother's, horses. There was some discussion about this. Fletcher Decker first saying he did not know what could be done about the horses, and that at last agreeing that if he was arrested the horses would be turned over to me.</p>

<p>Fletcher Decker is no longer in my vicinity in the Province of Saskatchewan. I understand that he is at present in the United States of America. He was arrested for the theft of the flax already mentioned and let out on bail, and skipped his bail. I have not seen him since he skipped his bail. He was arrested in the Province of Saskatchewan. My said  brother Cassius and I had arranged the night I told him about what I had heard concetning the theft of Ficklin's flax, that when Fletcher Decker came to his place the next morning he would question him about it to find out whether he had stolen Ficklin's flax.</p>

<p>(Signed) Charles Burdette Robinson</p>

<p>I, ALEXANDER JOSEPH GORDON MacECHEN, one of His Majesty's Justices of the Peace in and for the Province of Saskatchewan in the Dominion of Canada, hereby certify that the foregoing deposition was taken on oath before me at the City of Moose Jaw, Province of Saskatchewan aforesaid, and was signed by the deponent in my presence, and I declare that the offence with which FLETCHER</p>

<pb/>

<p>-4-</p>

<p>DECKER is charged is the crime of theft as defined by the Criminal Code of Canada.</p>

<p>(Signed) A.J.G. MacEchen (seal)</p>
<p>A Justice of the Peace in and for the Province of Saskatchewan.</p>

<pb/>

<p>CANADA</p>

<p>PROVINCE OF SASKATCHEWAN</p>

<p>I, Frederick John Charles Edwards, of the City of Regina, in the Province of Saskatchewan, Acting Deputy Provincial Secretary of the Province of Saskatchewan,</p>

<p>Solemnly declare:-</p>

<p>1. THAT I am now and have been since October 6th, A.D. 1920, Acting Deputy Provincial Secretary for the Province of Saskatchewan, and as such am by Law entrusted with the custody of the records of the appointments of all Notaries Public and Justices of the Peace in the said Province.</p>

<p>2. THAT all appointments of Notaries Public and Justices of the Peace are made by Order of the Lisutenant Governor in Council and that the records of such appointments are kept by me in my office and are under my custody and control.</p>

<p>3.THAT annexed hereto and marked as Exhibit "A" to this Declaration is a certificate of the appointment of Alexander Joseph Gordon MacEchen as a Justice of the Peace in and for the Province of Saskatchewan, and that the seal impressed upon the said certificate is the authorized seal of the Department of the Provincial Secretary of the said Province.</p>

<p>4. THAT the appointment of the said Alexander Joseph Gordon MacEchen has not been revoked and is still in force.</p>

<p>THAT I MAKE this solemn declaration conscientiously believing it to be true and knowing that it is of the same force and effect as if made under oath and by virtue of "THE CANADA EVIDENCE ACT".</p>

<p>DECLARED before me at the City of Regina, in the Province of Saskatchewan, Canada, this twelfth day of August, A.D. 1921.</p>

<p>(Signed) F.J.C. Edwards</p>
<p>Acting Deputy Provincial Secretary.</p>

<p>(Signed) (seal) W. F. Windeatt</p>
<p>A Notary Public in and for the Province of Saskatchewan.</p>

<p>Notary Public</p>
<p>My commission expires December 31st, 1921</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>