<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Territory of Washigton} In the District Court of the
County of Spokane}ss 4th Judicial District
holding terms at County
Seat of Spokane County</p>

<p>Territory of Washington
vs. Plaintiff
Ray Raymond Defendant</

<p>Territory of Washington}
County of Spokane}ss </p>

<p>J. Kennedy Stout and Thomas C.
Griffitts, being first duly sworn on oath state
we have had the affidavit of T. Donaldson
George Wycoff anf S.C. Hyde herein filed
and know the contents thereof. That they
and each of them were present together at
the interview between them &amp; said Donaldson
at his hom in Richland Precinct and at
the interview at the home of defendant
spoken of in the said affidavit of Donaldson. 
That said first conversation did
place on the 9th day of August 1886.
The affidavit were led to find said Donaldson
by information received by them that
he had declared he was present at time
of the shooting that in said interview said
Donaldson did not know affiant that Wycoff
witnessed the killing, but on the contrary
did tell them that he occupied a position
where it would have been impossible for

<pb/>

him to have seen a part of the scuffle or
shooting or that it would not
be worth her while to see Wycoff as he
knew nothing about it and subsequently 
and about the time of the interview
at the "Bay Windows" spoken of in Donaldson 
affidavit said Donaldson himself
told affiants that said Wycoff was
gone from his hand and to Walla
Walla County somewhere harvesting
notwithstanding and as soon as he
knew of his return would inform
affiant and he never did inform affiants 
that he had so returned until
after the finding of this indictment.
That in said interview in Richland
Precinct said Donaldson did not tell affiants 
that he witnessed said shooting
byt made quite contrary statements to
that and while alleying he was present
his statement were so understanding and
instatement in themselves an to action
did of known facts in the case that affiants 
can obtain no such
statment from him whereupon to declared if
he could on the premise he would explain
and reside his testimony and it
is permanent there that the interview and

<pb/>

hold in the "Bay Windoes" and which considered
as will on the statement again to Donaldson where by 
of a view of the premises, that the atatement of
said Donaldson were not in any manner cleared
up by luck view of the presmises byt appeared
here in consistent than ever <del>or such as</del>
That in several days after the finding of this indictment 
affiant Thomas C. Griffitts came from 
said Donaldson.
That several days after the finding
of this indictment affiant finds
as late at the 8th day of this month that
affiants learned that said Donaldson
would be a witness
for the prosecution and that he
claimed to be an eye-witness to the
ahooting anf this was the first any of defendants 
counsel or defendant knew that he
would be a witness in this cause or
that they did not know Wycoff by sight
nor did they knowledge except Donaldson who did know him by sight
and had no means of finding him 
until after they were informed by the sheriff that
and either of affiants now and him to know him until he was 
he was on Spokane Falls which was about
the time stated in their previous affidavit
herein, that defendants counsel were well
known to all persons in attendance upon
this court and said Wycoff did not make himself 
know either to defendant or any of
her counsel although subpoenas to attend
at her behalf, that the prosecuting attorney has

<pb/>

never notified defendant or her attorneys of his
purpose to use said witnesses Donaldson
&amp; Wycoff or either of the or of what he expected
to prove by them and they only learned if at first
incidentally and inquiry disclosed the fact that
they were Donaldson was so attending
this court for said purpose. That the presence
of said Donaldson in Spokane Falls and about
the court room did not inform affiants of
any thing as his presence in Spokane Falls
was not unusual. J. Kennedy Stout
Thomas C. Griffitts
<del>That about the time affiant have been
confined to prove resident in this 
county, at last to <unclear></unclear></del></p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to
upon me that 16th day of
December 1886</p>

<p>Frank Hulous
Notary Public
Wash Ter</p>
