<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>Seattle, Washington,
December 20, 1913.</p>
<p> In re cases of 
GREGORI KORNILIN,
MOISEI ALIOSHIN,
IVAN RIABOFF,
JAKOB EPHIMOFF,
PETER KEONLIN,
and
IVAN EMELIN.
EX ss "Tamba Maru,"
December 19, 1913.</p>
<p>At a meeting of the Board of Special Inquiry, covened pursuant to the instructions of the
Commissioner composed of 
Inspectors T.W. Lynch (Chairman)
J.E. Wilkes, and A.T. White.
Stenographer Trent Doser
Interpreter Henry G. Gerome</p>
<p>Held for Special Inquiry by Inspector A.T. White as L.P.C.</p>
<p>Alien sworn, testified as follows: Name is Gregori Kornilin; Russia, Russian; male, aged 28
years; married; reads and writes; farm laborer; last permanent residence, Simbirak, Krasnoie,
Russia; nearest relative in Russia, father, Ivan, Kornilin, Simbirak, Krasnoie, Russia; destined 
to Vancouver, Canada, but they would not let me land so I want to go to Portland, Oregon; has
cousin, Pavel Semeionoff, care of Stancheff Brothers. 75 North Third Street Portland, Oregorn;
ticket to Vancoiver via Victoria; $65.00 in gold; paid own passage; never in the United States.</p>
<p>Q  Have you a passport?    A  Yes.  Presents passport dated November 24, 1913, issued at
Valdivastok, Russia, permitting the bearer to leave Russia.
Q  When did you leave your home in Russia?  A  On the 17th of October I left my village.
Q  Where did you start for?   A   I wanted to go to Canada.
Q  Did you buy a ticket direct to Canada from your home?    A  I bought my ticket in Japan.
Q  When you left your home in Russia did these eight other boys who are on this boat leave at the
same tim eiwth you?   A  We all left together from the same village.
Q  All going to Canada  A  All to Canada.
Q  Why didn't you get your passport before you left home?   (Interpreter explains that all passports
are issued at Valdivastok and al applicants appear there for same.)
Q  Have you any relatives in Canada?    A  I have a second cousin.
Q  How did you happen to decide to go to Canada?    A  The reason I wanted to go to Canada was
because we had all received letters from Canada stating that they were doing well there and that we
had better come over here too.
Q  Did you receive any letters from Portland?   A  Same thing.
Q  Did he says he was doing well too and asked you to come over?    A  He says <pb></pb>
times are very good here and said you can get work here easy.
Q  Why did you want to go to Canada instead of the United States?   A  We understood it was nearer
and also that they did not request any money to be shown.
Q  Why did you not land in Canada?  A  We didn't know why; they would not let us.
Q  What did they tell you?  A  No more poeple are allowed to enter because there are too many out of
work here.
Q  How long since you had a letter fro you cousin in Portland?  A  I received a letter about the
first of October.
Q  Have you that letter with you?   A  No.
Q  That man in Portland is a real blood cousin is he?   A  He is my cousin; my father and his father
are brothers.
Q  Have you any work promised you in this country?  A  He says you can get plenty of work.
Q  Did he say he had a position for you - a job?    A  No, he didn't say anything of that sort.
Q  Have you ever been in any charitiable or penal institution?  A  No.
Q  Do you believe in polygamy?  A  No.
Q  Do you belong to any societies?  A  No.
Q  Do you believe in organized government?  A  I beleive in law.
Q  Do you believe that the form of government now existing in Russia is all right?  A  The form of
Government is all right but somehow we have not got enough land.
Q  Do you beleive in killing the officers because they are government officers?   A  No, we could
not do that.
Q  Do you believe in the teachings of the anarchists and annihilationists of Russia?    A  I do not
know what anarchists are.
Q  Did you ever hear of people are banded together and throw bombs and try to kill the officials of
Russia?   A  I have not heard of it and I do not believe it.
Q  What would you do if you were landed in this country?    A  I will get a rooming house and then
look for work.
Q  What kind of work do you think you could do?   A  I can do all the farm work.
Q  You are not familiar with farm work as it is done in this country, are you?  A  I have an idea
that it is about the same.
Q  Have you ever applied for admission to the United States?    A  No.
Q  And the only kind of work you can do is farm labor?  A  No, besides farm labor I understand
common labor too.
Q  What kind of work did you do in Russia other than ordinary farm labor?   A  I worked in the woods
and I worked in the mines at spare times.
Q  What kind of mines?  A  Coal mines.
Q  There is no one else in the United States you know except the man in Portland    A  No, Oh, there
is a lot of others, about twenty friends around Portland, but no relatives.
Q  You don't know their names or addresses?   A  They all work in the same place and they all live
in the same place.
Q  BY INSPECTOR WILKES: Have you got anyone dependent upon you for support in Russia?   A  I have a
wife and two children. They do not have to rely on me for support: my father and brother could
support them if I could not.
Q  What wages do you expect to earn in the United States?   A  I do not know, I think about a couple
dollars a day.
<pb></pb>
Q  Are both of your children in Russia?   A  Yes, sir.
Q  BY INSPECTOR LYNCH: Have you any property in Russia?   A  Yes, I have a home and nine acres of
land. I can get about $800 for it.
Q  Your cousin in Portland, what is his business?   A  He works on a railroad in the woods.
Q  He has no property that you know of?   A  I don't know he only lives here a year.</p>
<p>The applicant is an ignorant peasant of average intelligence and of good physique.</p>
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>