<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States, for the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the matter of the Deportation 
of Albert H. Young and B.K.
Sugiura. } No. <gap reason="blank"/>
Brief.</p>
<p>The Rule.</p>
<p>The order of this brief will be to take up the
rule of procedure first and afterwards the evidence only
in so far as it bears on the rule.</p>
<p>The matter for consideration in this case seems
to us to be res adjudicata until the case of In Re
Unlawful Dentention of Mullah Singh and Seventy-two other
Hindu Aliens, Case No. 2532, has been reversed by the 
Supreme Court. In that case the court says:</p>
<p>"The jurisdiction of the court is limited to
ascertaining whether the pertitioners were denied
a hearing."</p>
<p>And the Court cites to sustain the proposition the following:</p>
<p>Ekin v. United States, 142 U.S.651;<add>35 L Ed 1146</add>
Yamataya v. Fisher, 189 U.S.86;
United States v. Ju Toy, 198 U.S. 253;
Lee Moon Sing v. United States, 158 U.S.538;
Chin Yow v. United States, 208 U.S. 8.</p>
<p>The Court further says:</p>
<p>"A hearing having been accorded, the court
is precluded from a re-examination of the issue
presented, merely because it is contended that
the conclusion of the immigration officers, based
upon the testimony presented, was wrong."</p>
<p>The Court's decision is borne out by the reasoning
and the exact language of our Supreme Court cases. Thus, in
Chin Yow v. United States, 52 L.Ed. 369, the Court says:</p>
<fw>1</fw>
<pb/>
<p>"But unless and until it is proved to the
satisfaction of the judge that a hearing properly
so called was denied, the merits of the case are
not open, and, we may add the denial of a hearing
cannot be establsihed by proving that the decision
was wrong."</p>
<p>And in the case of De Bruler v. Gallo, 184 Fed.
566, at page 569, that court follows the reasoning of
this court, saying at 569,</p>
<p>"The contention being that the only question
then properly before the court was whether or not
the appellee had been given a fair hearing by the
officers of the Department of Commerce and Labor
upon the order to show cause why she should not
be deported to the country from which she came.
The position of the government in this respect
must be sustained."</p>
<p>Again the court states the rule in another way
in United States vs. Ju Toy, 49 L. Ed. 1040, 1043, where
it says in giving the ruling in Lem Moon Sing vs. U.S.
39 L.Ed. 1082:</p>
<p>"Where the petitioner for habeas corpus
alleged facts which, if true, gave him a 
right to enter and remain in the country,
it was held that the decision of the collector
was final as to whether or not he belonged
to the privileged class."</p>
<p>Again, Chief Justice Holmes states <del>a</del> <add>the</add> rule in a 
case in which a writ of habeas corpus was allowed. Thus
he says in the case of Chin Yow vs. United States, 52
<del>L.</del> Ed. 369:</p>
<p>"Of course, if the writ is granted, the
first issue to be tried is the truth of the
allegations last mentioned. If the petitioner
was not denied a fair opportunity to produce
the evidence that he desired, or a fair
though summary hearing, the case can proceed
no farther. Those facts are the foundation
of the jurisdiction of the district court, if
it has any jurisdiction at all. It must not
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
be supposed that the mere allegation of the facts
opens the merits of the case, whether those facts
are proved or not. And, by way of caution, we
may add the jurisdiction would not be established
simply by proving that the commissioner and the
Department of Commerce and Labor did not accept
certain sworn statements as true, even though no
contrary or impeaching testimony was adduced."</p>
<p>Reason of the Rule.</p>
<p>The reason of this rule is that the determination
as to the rights of aliens to remain in or be exvluded
from the United States is one within the jurisdiction of
Congress alone. It belongs to the political <del>determinant</del> <add>department</add>
of the government <add>alone</add> and the final determination as to who
shall be entitled to enter the United States may be
entrusted to Congress to executive officers. (See a 
statement of the reason of the rule in the case of Lem Moon
Sing vs. U.S., 39 L.Ed. 1084 in last paragraph of first
column of page; and also see the same reason of the rule
laid down in U.S. vs. Ju Toy, 49 L. Ed. 1043 last part
of page). <add>The counts have to none right to interfere than
they wared if these aliens were in their own country
petitioners admission to Courts.</add></p>
<p>Part of Immigration Act Involved.</p>
<p>These two aliens are being deported under that 
portion of Section 3 as mended by the Act of March 26,
1910, which provides that "any alien ***********who in
any ways assists, protects or promises to protect from
arrest, any prostitute, shall be deemed to be unlawfully
within the United States and shall be deported in the
manner provided by Sections 20 and 21 of this Act."
Section 20 provides that any alien who shall enter the
United States in violation of law, etc., shall upon the
warrant of the Secretary of Labor, be taken into custody
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
and deported to the country whence he came. The rules of
the Department, Subdivision 4(a), provide that upon receipt
of a warrant of arrest, the alien shall be taken before
an immigration officer and granted a hearing to enable
him to show cause why he should not be deported; Subdivision
(b) provides that he may inspect the warrant and examine 
the evidence from which it was issued and, at such stage
of the proceedings as the officer before whom the hearing
is held shall deem proper, be apprized that he may be
represented by counsel; Subdivision (c) provides that at
the close of the hearing a full record shall be forwarded
to the bureau, together with any written arguments submitted
by counsel and recommendations of the examining officer
as to whether a warrant for deportation shall issue.</p>
 



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>