<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0233.008"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Sam Plastino v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0233.008</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Sam Plastino v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1916-07-03">July 3, 1916</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1916-07"></date>03 July 1916</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Sam Plastino</term>
<term>Henry M. White</term>
<term>Michele Plastino</term>
<term>Benjamin S. Cable</term>
<term>Daniel J. Keefe</term>
<term>T. M. Fisher</term>
<term>Charles E. Keagy</term>
<term>Joseph Plastino</term>
<term>Joseph M. Glasgow</term>
<term>Tolman</term>
<term>John King</term>
<!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Spokane, Washington</term> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Eastern District of Washington</term>
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term>
<term>Pierce County, Washington</term>
<term>Italy</term><!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sam Plastino</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known --> 
<persName>Adam Beeler</persName>
<persName>John J. Sullivan</persName>
<persName>Jospeh M. Glasgow</persName>
<persName>John King</persName>
<persName>Tolman</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Clay Allen</persName>
<persName>Albert Moodie</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022" who="AS">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0233.008"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>3393</p>
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES
FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.</p>
<p>SAM PLASTINO
vs.
HENRY M. WHITE, United States Commissioner
of Immigration, at Seattle, Washington. }}
PETITION FOR WRIT OF
HABEAS CORPUS.</p> 
<p>TO THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT 
OF WASHINGTON:</p>
<p>The petition of Sam Plastino respectfully alleges:</p> 
<p>That your petitioner is, and ever since the month of June,
1697, has been, continuously a resident and actual inhabitant of the United
States of America; that he is now an inhabitant and resident of the city of
Spokane, Washington; that your petitioner is now of the age of thirty years;
that he wes brought to the United States at the age of about ten years by
his parents; that his father, Michele Plastino, duly made declaration of
intention to become a citizen of the United States in the year 1900; that
thereafter, and before taking out his final citizenship papers, the said
Michele Plastino died; that your petitioner, in mistaken belief that he,
upon attaining the age of twenty-one years, became a citizen of the United
States and entitled to all the rights and privileges of such, failed to ap-
<pb></pb> 
ply for citizenship in the United States until the month of March, 1911,
when he duly made, in the United States District Court of Eastern District
of Washington, his declaration of intention to become a citizen of the
United States. 
</p>
<p>II.</p> 
<p>That your petitioner is now actually imprisoned and restrained
of his liberty, and detained at seattle, Washington, by color of the au-
thority of the United States, in the custody of Henry M. White, Esquire,
United States Commissioner of Immigration, at Seattle, Washington, within
said Western District of Washington.</p>
<p>III.</p> 
<p>That the sole claim or authority by virtue of which the said
Henry M. White, Commissioner as aforesaid, so restrains and detains your
petitioner, is a certain warrant in writing, a copy of which is hereto an-
nexed. marked "Exhibit A," issued by Benjamin S. Cable, Esquire, Acting
Secretary of Commerce and Labor, and a certain order in writing issued by
Dan'l J. Keefe. Commissioner General, Department of Commerce and Labor,
Bureau of Immigration and Naturalization, a copy of which is hereto an-
nexed. marked "Exhibit B;" which warrants and orders are incorporated
herein by reference and made a part hereof, with like effect as if herein
set forth at length.</p> 
<p>That said warrants were issued pursuant to a pretended order
of deportation made by Benjamin S. Cable, Esquire, Acting Secretary of
Commerce and Labor of the United States, upon alleged proofs said to have
been submitted at a pretended hearing before Immigrant Inspector T. M.
Fisher, alleged to have been held at Tacoma, Washington, in the year 1912.</p>
<p>That the pretended record of said hearing and the sole pre-
tended proofs upon which said order of deportation was based are hereto
<pb></pb>
attached, marked "Exhibit C."</p>
<p>IV.</p> 
<p>That at all times referred to in this petition, there was, and
now is, in effect, the following rules of the United States Department of
Commerce and Labor, Bureau of Immigration and Naturalization, relating to
proceedings for the deportation of aliens:</p> 
<p>Rule 22. Subdivision I. Officers shall make thorough
investigation of all cases where they are credibly in-
formed or have reason to believe that a specified alien
in the United States is subject to arrest and deporta-
tion on warrant.</p> 
<p>Subdivision II. (a) The application must state facts
bringing the alien within one or more of the classes sub-
ject to deportation after entry.</p>
<p>Subdivision IV. (a) Upon receipt of a warrant of
arrest, the alien shall be taken before the person or
persons therein described and granted a hearing to enable
him to show cause, if any there be, why he should not be
deported.</p> 
<p>(b) During the course of the hearing the alien
shall be allowed to inspect the warrant of arrest and all
the evidence on which it was issued; and at such stage
thereof as the officer before whom the hearing is held
shall deem proper, he shall be apprised that he may there-
after be represented by counsel and shall be required then
and there to state whether he desires counsel or waives the
same, and his reply shall be entered on the record. If coun-
sel be selected, he shall be permitted to be present during
the further conduct of the hearing, to inspect and make a
copy of the minutes of the hearing, so far as it has pro-
ceeded, and to offer evidence to meet any evidence thereto-
fore or thereafter presented by the Government. Objections
and exceptions of counsel shall not be entered on the record,
but may be dealt with in an accompanying brief. If during
the hearing new facts are proved which constitute a reason
additional to those stated in the warrant of arrest why the
alien is in the country in violation of law, the alien's
attention shall be directed to such facts and reason, and
he shall be given an opportunity to show cause why he should
not be deported therefor.</p>
<p>V.</p>
<p>Your petitioner alleges that no hearing was had before said T.M.
Fisher, or at all, upon the charge that your petitioner had received, shared
in, or derived benefit from the earnings of prostitutes, or upon the charge
<pb></pb>
that your petitioner is or was unlawfully within the United States and
that he has been found receiving, sharing in, and deriving benefit from
the earnings of prostitutes, or upon any charge of similar nature. Your
petitioner further alleges that the only proceedings of any kind, form,
or character, for the deportation of your petitioner, were the proceedings
referred to in paragraph VI hereof. That no warrant or complaint charging
your petitioner with having received, shared in, and derived benefit from
the earnings of prostitutes, or charging him with being unlawfully within
the United States in that he was found receiving, sharing in, and deriving
benefit from the earnings of prostitutes, or charging him with any offence
or act of similar nature or character was ever served upon or exhibited
to your petitioner. That he was never informed that such a warrant had
been issued or such a charge made against him in any form; that he never
inspected and was never permitted or given opportunity to inspect any such
warrant, if such warrant was ever issued; that he never inspected and never
was permitted or given opportunity to inspect the evidence, if any was
taken, or any part thereof, upon which such warrant, if issued, was issued;
that your petitioner was never granted or offered a hearing or opportunity
of any kind to show cause why he should not be deported; that he was never
informed that any action or proceeding for his deportation was pending or
that any inquiry was being made upon or out of which an order of deporta-
tion might issue; that <add>except as stated in paragraph VI hereof</add>he was not present at and had no notice of or op-
portunity to be present at the pretended hearing before the said T. M.
Fisher referred to in the Exhibit A hereto attached. That your petition-
er was never apprised that he might be represented by counsel upon the
hearing of such charge; that he was not represented by counsel at any
hearing thereon; that neither your petitioner nor his counsel was permitted
to, nor did your petitioner or his counsel inspect or make a copy of the
</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>minutes or any part thereof, of any such hearing; that he wes not per-
mitted to and did not offer evidence to meet any evidence presented by
the Government, nor was he in any manner informed of the character of the
evidence presented by the Government, or the names of any of the witnesses
by whom said evidence was or would be given, or of the time or place when
their testimony would be given; that he was not present at nor was he given
notice or opportunity to be present at the examination of any witnesses or
to cross-examine them or any of them.</p> 
<p>That there was no evidence offered or submitted which proved or
tended to prove the charge contained in the pretended warrant of arrest here-
in or to sustain the findings upon which the said order of deportation
was made</p> 
<p>VI.</p>
<p>That the pretended evidence or testimony of your petitioner be-
fore the said T. M. Fisher was given under the following circumstances, and
not otherwise: That the aforesaid T.M. Fisher called upon your petitioner
in the county jail of Pierce County, Washington, in the city of Tacoma, on
or about the 26th day of January, 1912, and then and there stated to your
petitioner that he, the said T.M. Fisher, desired to procure a statement
from your petitioner; that the said T.M. Fisher or Charles E. Keagy did not
then or thereafter, or at all, inform your petitioner of the purpose or ob-
ject of said examination; that the said T.M. Fisher or Charles E. Keagy did
not then or thereafter inform your petitioner that he was arrested under
and by virtue of Department Warrant 53259/150, dated January 12, 1912, is-
sued by the Acting Secretary of Commerce and Labor, in that he entered the
United States in violation of the act of Congress approved February 20,
1917, amended by Act approved March 26, 1910, towit: That the said alien
is unlawfully within the United States in that he has been found receiv-
ing, sharing in or deriving benefit from the earnings of a prostitute or
prostitutes; that this hearing is for the purpose of giving him an ample
opportunity to show cause why he should not be deported to the country
whence he came in conformity with law; nor did they or either of them make
<pb></pb>
any statement of similar import to your petitioner; nor did they or either
of them inform your petitioner that the statements made by your petitioner
upon said examination, or any part thereof, would or might be used againat
him or that said examination was had in connection with or in relation to
any warrant or charge that had been issued or made against him. That the
said T.M. Fisher or Charles E. Keagy did not, upon said examination, or at
all, state to your petitioner, "You have a right to be represented by coun-
sel if you desire; or words of similar import; that your petitioner did not
then, or at all, answer or say, "If my brother in Spokane will get a lawyer
for me, I want a lawyer; if he will not, I do not care for any;" or words
of similar import. That the said T.M. Fisher or Charles E. Keagy did not
then, or at all, say to your petitioner, "Then, if your brother in Spokane
does not see fit to retain a lawyer for you, do you waive your right to be
represented by counsel?" or words of similar import. That your petitioner
did not then, or at all, respond or say, "Yes;" or use any word or words
of similar import. That the said T.M. Fisher or Charles E. Keagy did not
then, or at all, say to your petitioner, "By your brother you mean Joe Plas-
tino." or words of similar import. That your petitioner did not then, or
at all, respond or say, "Yes, sir;" or words of similar import. That had
your petitioner been informed of the nature and object of said proceedings
and of his right to be represented by counsel, he would have procured coun-
sel for that purpose.</p> 
<p>That the pretended transcript of the examination of your peti-
tioner set forth in Exhibit C did not, as originally written, contain said
pretended questions or answers, or any of them, but that said pretended ques
tions <space></space> and each of them were written into the said
pretended record of the examination of your petitioner after the same was ori-
ginally transcribed, as more fully appears by the affidavit of John King,
hereto attached (marked Exhibit D).</p> 
<p>That your petitioner is informed by his brother, Joseph Plastino,
(whose affidavit thereto is hereto attached, marked Exhibit E) and upon in-</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>formation and belief states the fact to be that the said T.M. Fisher did
not, at any time or place, propound to the said Joseph Plastino the fol-
lowing questions, or any questions of similar nature or import:</p>
<p>Q. BY INSPECTOR FISHER. (To Joe Plastino, brother of Sam
Plastino). "Your brother, Sam Plastino, has been given a hearing to show his
right to be, or remain, in the United States. He states that he wanted an
attorney to represent him, provided you will furnish the same"?</p> 
<p>That the said Joseph Plastino did not then, or at any time,
give the following answer, or any answer of similar nature or import:</p>
<p>A. (BY JOE PLASTINO)</p> 
<p>"I am through with him for good; I will have nothing to do with
hiring an attorney for him."</p> 
<p>That the said T.M. Fisher did not inform the said Joseph Plastino
that deportation proceedings were pending against the said Sam Plastino;
that the subject of the employment of counsel for the said Sam Plastino in
said matter, or in any matter or proceeding of any kind and character, was
not then, or at any other time, mentioned to the said Joseph Plastino in
any manner or form by the said T.M. Fisher.</p>
<p>That your petitioner was never informed by the said T.M.Fisher
or at all, and never heard of the pretended refusal of his brother, Joseph
Plastino, to furnish him counsel in said proceeding.</p>
<p>VII.</p>
<p>That no action was taken by the said Department of Commerce and
Labor or by the Bureau of Immigration, or by any officer or agent thereof, or
at all, to execute said order or warrant of deportation or cause the warrant
of deportation of your petitioner, until about the 15th day of July, 1916.</p>
<p>That the order of Dan'l J. Keefe, Commissioner General of the
Department of Commerce and Labor (Exhibit B, hereto attached), directing
that "execution of the warrant of deportation should be held in abeyance
until such time as the alien is released from prison," was and is without
<pb></pb>
authority of law, and void.</p>
<p>VIII.</p>
<p>That your petitioner is now unlawfully held by the said Henry
M. White, Commissioner as aforesaid, by virtue of said order and warrants
and not otherwise; the said Henry M. White, Commissioner as aforesaid,
is about to cause the deportation of your petitioner to the Kingdom of
Italy, and will do so unless prevented from so doing by the order of
this court.</p>
<p>IX.</p>
<p>That in said proceedings your petitioner was not given a fair or
impartial trial, and the said proceedings and the said warrants and order
of deportation were and are without legal right, authority, or jurisdiction
of any kind, and are in violation of that clause of the fifth amendment of
the Constitution of the United States providing that no person shall be
deprived of life, liberty, or property without due process of law, and are
in violation of the provisions of the sixth amendment of the Constitution
of the United States that in all criminal prosecutions the accused shall
be informed of the nature and cause of the accusation, shall be confronted
with the witnesses against him, and have the assistance of counsel for his
defence; and that your petitioner's detention and imprisonment thereunder
are in violation of the Constitution of the United States and in violation
of the rights, privileges, and immunities thereunder.</p> 
<p>WHEREFORE Your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus may
issue, directed to the said Henry M. White aforesaid, or to any of his
deputies, requiring him or them to bring and have your petitioner before
this court at a time to be by it determined, together with the true cause
of his detention, to the end that due inquiry may be had in the premises
and that this court may proceed in a summary way to determine the facts
<pb></pb>
of the case in that regard, and the legality of your petitioner's im-
prisonment, restraint, detention, and deportation, and thereupon to
dispose of your petitioner as law and justice require. And your peti-
tioner will ever pray.</p> 
<p>Tolman &amp; King</p>
<p>Joseph Glasglow
Attorneys for Petitioner.</p>
<p>Sam Plastino
Petitioner.</p>
<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON
COUNTY OF KING ))) 
SS.</p>
<p>SAM PLASTINO, being first duly sworn, on
oath says: That he is the petitioner in the foregoing petition; that
he has read said petition and knows the contents thereof, and that the
same is true of his own knowledge except as to the matters therein stated
to be on information and belief, and as to those matters he believes it
to be true.</p>
<p>Sam Plastino</p>
<p>SUBSCRIBED AND SWORN TO Before me this 30th day of July, 1916.</p> 
<p>Sam C. Griffin
Notary Public for the State of
Washington, residing at Seattle, 
Washington.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>