<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0116.028"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Wiley v. Keokuk. Attorney Petitioner Response</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0116.028</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Wiley v. Keokuk. Attorney Petitioner Response</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1870-01">January 1870</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Barreme</term>
<term>Beardmore</term>
<term>Carrington</term>
<term>Christian, James</term>
<term>Hawk, Black</term>
<term>Keokuk, Moses</term>
<term>Kendall</term>
<term>Mix, Charles E.</term>
<term>Montgomery, William P.</term>
<term>Morton</term>
<term>Wiley, Albert</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Kansas</term>
<term>United States</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Wiley, Albert</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Keokuk, Moses</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Christian, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Nevison</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Rigg</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fonte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Kingman, C.F.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Douglas District Court</orgName> 
<placeName>Douglas County, Kansas</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="sab">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0116.028"/>

<p>63</p>
<p>WILEY V. KEOKUK.</p>
<p>James Christian, for defendant in error.</p>
<p>The error, if any, in overruling the challenge of the juror, was cured by the defendant himself. He removed Willis from the jury by a peremptory challenge, and did not exhaust the number of such challenges allowed him by law. Morton v. State, 1 Kan. 468. The letter or circular of Com'r Mix was no protection to Wiley in the trespass complained of. The pwer to issue such an order does not exist in the commissioner of Indian affairs, nor any other officer of this government. It is not among any of the powers of the executive department of this government. And *even though the order in question was approved by the secretary of the interior, (as is alleged,) or by the president himself, it was in flagrant violation of law, and is void. Conkl. Ex. Pow. 64, 65, 67; Little v. Barreme, 2 Cranch, 170. But it is contended that Wiley acted in good faith, and therefore is excusable in the matter of damages for doing what it might seem was his duty. Good faith is no excuse for a violation of the statues, and ignorance of the law is no defense. All are bound to know the law. "And the court cannot sanction the doctrine that the president is invested with a dispensing power which has no countenance for its support in any part of the constitution." Kendall v. U.S. 12 Pet. 613. "To enter a man's house by virtue of a nameless warrant is a most daring attack upon the liberty of the subject." Beardmore v. Carrington, 2 Wils. 244. That the defendant in error is an Indian makes no difference; his right to personal liberty and personal security in a government of law is as great as that of the president or any other citizen. Vatt. Law Nat. 4, "Preliminaries." He cannot be deprived of his rights without his consent. The defendant in error, although an Indian, a member of his tribe, born out of the limits of any of the states, not a citizen of or owing allegiance to the United States, is still a man a member of the great family of nations, and entitled, by the laws of nature, reason, and humanity, to go when and where he pleases, so that he does not interfere with the rights of others. He has the right to travel in any part of his Great Father's earthly dominions where his desires or necessities require, being unarmed and willing to pay his own expenses, form the fact *of his being a man. "Sir," said Black Hawk, the famous Sac and Fox chief, when a prisoner, and reproved by President Jackson for bringing on the war in 1831, "sir, you are a man; so am I. But fortune has placed us in different circumstances. Your people are stronger than mine. You can dictate your terms; I am your prisoner, and must submit. But I am still a man, as well as you." This manhood argument is no new idea; it has been the chief argument of man since the earliest ages. 2 Kings, viii. 13; 1 Samuel, xvii. 43. And earlier still it was said, "Let us make man in our image, after our likeness." Genesis, i. 26.</p>
<p>As to damages. This man Keokuk is a prince among his people; a chief or sachem. He is the representative man of his nation. Hi s position and standing is a legitimate fact to be taken into consideration in ascertaining the amount of damages he is entitled to recover.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
