<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0466.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In The United States Circuit Court, For The District of Washing-
 ton, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In The Matter of The Application    
 of Henry Craemer for Writ of 
 Habeas Corpus, and Relief Thereon. :
 PETITION</p>
    
<p>To The Honorable Circuit Court of The United States, for the 
 District of Washington, and to the Judges thereof;</p>
    
<p>Your petitioner, Henry Craemer, all ages and shows:</p>
    
<p>1. That he is a citizen and resident of the United States, 
 residing in the county of King, at the city of Seattle, in the
 state of Washington.</p>
    
 <p>2. That he is now against his will and without authority of
 law confined and restrained of his liberty and detained and unlaw-
 fully held in custody by William H. Moyer, Sheriff of King county,
 and, against his wish, is being held by the said Moyer under
 threats by the said Moyer, as sheriff of King county, to take the
 life of this petitioner under all alleged process and authority as 
 hereinafter more fully stated.</p>   
    
 <p>3. Your petitioner further alleges that the said threat and
attempt to take his life, which is set for and arranged to be, 
your petitioner understands, at once, and particularly in the 
month of July on the day of the 23rd, is wholly without authority
of law, without the jurisdiction of any court, contrary to the law
and contrary to the rights of your petitioner as a citizen of the 
United States under the Constitution of the United States, as will 
more particularly appear in matters hereafter stated. </p>
    
 <p>4. Your petitioner informs the court that on or about the 
 <fw>(1)</fw> <pb></pb>
 23rd day of August, 1894, he was charged by the state of Washington
 by information of three separate crimes in one count, to-wit; the
 crime of murder in the first degree, to which the penalty of death
 attached upon conviction; murder in the second degree, to which a
 penalty of not less than ten nor more than 20 years imprisonment in 
 the penitentiary attached, and the offense of manslaughter, to 
 which not less than two nor more than 10 years imprisonment in the 
 penitentiary attached.</p>

<p>That your petitioner was tried upon the said informatin upon
issue joined in the Superior Court of King County.</p>

<p>That to said issue a jury trying your petitioner did return
him guilty of no greater offense than the offense of murder in the 
second degree, and by legal construction granting inferences and 
all presumptions in favor of your petitioner as accused, finding
your petitioner guilty of no higher offense than that of manslaught-
er.</p>

<p>That the said jury in no wise found your petitioner guilty of 
murder in the first degree, to which the sentence adn penalty of 
death could be inflicted.</p>

<p>That the said verdict was rendered about the 12th day of 
 September, 1894.</p>
<p>5. That your petitioner appealed from the decision finding
your petitioner guilty of murder in the second degree, or of
manslaughter, to the Supreme Court of the State of Washington upon
errors assigned, and the said judgement was affirmed.</p>

<p>And further, upon the validity of the process under which
your petitioner was charged, to-wit; as to whether or not your
petitioner could be tried upon an information, for his life, your
petitioner appealed to the Supreme Court of the United States upon
that point and that point alone, and the said Supreme Court
<fw>(2)</fw> <pb></pb>
dismissed said appeal, returning the  said cause and all process
to the Supreme Court of the state of Washington to be dealt with
as in manner and form of the law both just and proper.</p>
    
    <p>6. That at no time after the said verdict or upon any <del>fur</del>
    further hearing of the said cause upon appeal or pending any of its
    stages was ever any death warrant issued by any Judge or Court
    authorizing or assuming to take the life of your petitioner, or
    authorizing or assuming to order that your petitioner's life be
    taken, or warranting any person, sheriff or otherwise, to take the
    life of your petitioner. Thus there was no opportunity nor
    occasion to complain in the Supreme Court of the state or any other 
    court as to the right to issue said death-warrant or the authority 
    for the same.</p>
    
<p>7. That at the time your petitioner was tried he was tried 
before the Honorable Thomas J. Humes, one of the Judges of the
Superior Court of the County of King.</p>

<p>That after the said cause had been disposed of in the Supreme
Court of the state of Washington and the Supreme Court of the
United States and returned to the Superior Court of the state of 
Washington for the execution of such process as would be legal in
the premises, the said Thomas J. Humes had ceased to be Judge - 
the said Thomas J. Humes being the only Judge who had heard the
evidence in the cause and who had presided at the trial of your
petitioner - and succeeding the said Thomas J. Humes came the
Honorable Orange Jacobs, Judge of the Superior Court of King
County, elected and qualified.</p>
    
 <p>8. That to-wit: on the <del>20th</del><add>6th</add> of February, A.D., 1897. the 
state of Washington moved that your petitioner be brought up for 
<fw>(3)</fw> <pb></pb>
judgement and for other process against him, and moved the said
Orange Jacobs, Judge, to execute a warrant of death authorizing the
taking of your petitioner's life for matters and things alleged
as was claimed in the record, to-wit: upon the said verdict, and
there was presented to the said Judge a form of death-warrant
 reciting matters and things in nowise true, in so far as the same
 assumed to recite any conviction of your petitioner of the crime of
 murder in the first degree, and your petitioner then and there 
 duly objected through his counsel to the said Honorable Orange
 Jacobs assuming to pass sentence of death upon your petitioner,
 and particularly assuming to issue a death-warrant against your 
 petitioner ordering the taking of your petitioner's life by the 
 said Sheriff W. H. Moyer on the 23rd day of April, 1897, or at 
 any time whatsoever, and duly insisted that the Court was without
 jurisdiction to make such an order; that the same was wholly in 
 excess of jurisdiction, was wholly in want of jurisdiction, and 
 wholly without the authority of law, particularly was without any
 due process of law and was in violation of your petitioner's
 rights as a citizen of the United States and of the state of 
 Washington, and particularly in violation of Article 6 of the 
 Federal Constitution of the United States prescribing that the life
 of your petitioner or any other citizen shall not be taken without
 due process of law, and particularly in violation of Article 14 of 
 the Federal Constitution of the United States specifically provid-
 ing that no state shall by law or otherwise deny to your petitioner
 the right of exemption and immunity from unjust process, and
 particularly providing and prescribing against the taking of your
 petitioner's or any other citizen's life without due process of 
law and save and except upon a due judgement and conviction upon 
which the sentence of death necessarily and as a matter of law
 absolutely followed, and that under the laws of the state of
 <fw>(4)</fw> <pb></pb>
Washington there was no authority in the said Judge Jacobs or the
said Superior Court or any Judge thereof to order the taking of the
life of your petitioner upon a construction of the process or
verdict or upon assumed construction of the law, or upon any
 pretense or authority.</p>

<p>9. That notwithstanding such objections duly presented 
before the said Judge, your petitioner was nevertheless ordered to
be executed by the said Judge Jacobs, and the said Orange Jacobs
did assume to end and did order under his hand that your petitioner 
shall on the 23rd day of April, being Friday, of the year, 1897, 
between the hours of 9 o'clock in the forenoon and 4 o'clock in the 
afternoon, be executed and his life be taken under and by authority 
of an alleged judgement in the called cause; that there was no authori-
ty for such order, non permitted by the laws of the state of
Washington, was wholly contrary to the laws of the United States,
and to the Constitution of the United States, and to the rights of 
your petitioner as a citizen of the United States.</p>

<p>10. That under the laws of the state of Washington there was 
no time allowed further to appeal the said order or cause to the 
Supreme Court of the state of Washington from the order of the said
Judge Jacobs as an original cause, as the time had expired in which 
said cause could be taken to the Supreme Court upon the wrongful
order and upon the said order and authority so exercised without
jurisdiction.</p>

<p>That upon application duly made John R. Rogers, Governor of the
state of Washington, granted a respite to your petitioner, this
prolonging your petitioner's life and staying the execution of the
death sentence for the period fo ninety (90) days, or until, to-wit
<fw>(5)</fw> <pb></pb>
the 23rd day of July, 1897.</p>

<p>That the next term of the Supreme Court of the State of
 Washington is not until the month of October, A.D., 1897, in which
there would be any authority on the part of the court by any pro-
ceedings to review the unauthorized act  of the said Judge Jacobs
and of his Honor the Judge of the Superior Court, and as there is 
no law under which your petitioner can seek any stay pending any 
attempt to seek relief from the Supreme Court of the State or from
any other source your petitioner has the only remedy left him as
a citizen of the United States of appealing to this Honorable Court
for rescue from an order seeking to take his life, upon the ground 
that the same is wholly in excess of jurisdiction and wholly void
for want of jurisdiction and without authority.</p>

<p>11. Your petitioner further shows that he has duly protested
in every wise against the action of the said Court and against the
threatened action of the said sheriff, and particularly protested
against that particular action which seeks in the manner and form
herein stated to execute and carry out an alleged conviction and 
sentence thereon of your petitioner.</p>

<p>12. That your petitioner does not seek at the hands of the
court absolute discharge unconditionally, but knowing the fact to
be that an attempt to take his life is wholly in excess of juris-
diction by or upon behalf of any court of the state of Washington,
and a wholly unauthorized act on the part of the sheriff of the
county of King or any other person, and knowing that under the law
the only offense of which your petitioner has been duly convicted
and to which sentence could legally attach is the crim of murder
in the second degree, and under the reasonable construction granted
by the law possibly only the offense of manslaughter, and under no
circumstances by any construction of the law in anywise applicable
of the crime of murder in the first degree, your petitioner seeks
<fw>(6)</fw> <pb></pb>
at the hands of the court the relief under such conditions are 
allowable; that is, that your petitioner either be permitted the 
election of accepting his sentence upon a verdict of murder in the 
second degree and that in the event of a failure on the part of 
the state of Washington to so act that your petitioner be discharg-
ed or held upon order to re-try your petitioner upon the offense 
alleged in the information, or that proceedings against your petitioner
be held void and the court of the state of Washington be 
ordered to pronounce sentence and judgement against your petitioner
as under the law appertaining to convictions of murder in the
second degree, and no other could be had in the premises, or 
that upon due hearing of the cause and upon examining the records
of the cause and the evidence in the cause, your honor will make 
an order discharging the petitioner, subject to the jurisdiction of
the state court to proceed against petitioner for such offense
only as it appears undr the law to your honor your petitioner has 
alone been convicted of and which in law and in justice alone
your petitioner could be sentenced upon.</p>

<p>13. That for due information of the court, your petitioner
respectfully announces to the court that the Journal entries and 
the records in the Superior Court of the State fo Washington in 
this cause known as number 1054 <add>be</add> by Writ of Certiorari duly certi-
fied before your Honor for spection and investigation, that the
court may be duly advised in the premises, and that your Honor
will grant unto your petitioner a Writ of Habeas Corpus commanding
your petitioner to be brought before the Court at such time and
place as to the Court shall be convenient, whereat the Court could
inquire of the matters and things alleged by your petitioner, and
that your Honor would issue a Writ of Certiorari to the Superior
<fw>(7)</fw> <pb></pb>
court of the county of King ordering to be duly certified to the
court the records of this said cause for information, particularly
the alleged information, the verdict, the judgement and the death-
warrant made in the premises, and all other journal entries and
orders in the cause, that your honor and the court may be informed
of the premises, and that upon such record and upon hearing of
the cause, such further and other order can be made as in the 
premises will be right and proper.</p>

<p>And your petitioner will ever pray.</p>

<ab>Henry Craemer
Petitioner.</ab>
<ab>Pratt &amp; Riddle
Attorneys for Petitioner.</ab>

<p>State of Washington
County of King} SS</p>
    
<p>Henry Craemer, being first and duly sworn, on oath says; that
he is the petitioner herein; that he knows the matters and things 
set forth in the petition, and of the matters and things
set forth in the petition, and of the matters of his own know-
ledge says they are true, and the other matters of law he is 
advised by his counsel that they are true, adn therefore believes
the whole of said petition to be true.</p>

<ab>Henry Craemer</ab>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 14 day of June, 1897.</p>

<ab>S.S. <unclear>Sangfard</unclear></ab>

<p>Notary Public in and for the state of Washington, residing at 
Seattle.</p>

<p>In The U.S. Circuit Court
Dist. of Wash. Northern
Division.</p>
    
<p>In Re Application of Henry
Craemer for Writ of Habeas 
Corpus, and relief thereon.</p>

<ab>PETITION.</ab>

<p>FILED June 14 1897
BY THE
U.S. CIRCUIT COURT.</p>
<ab>As Reeves Ayres Clerk.</ab>
<ab>By PM Hopkins DEPUTY.</ab>
<p> Pratt &amp; Riddle,
Attys for Petitioner.
309-310-311 Bailey Bldg.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>