<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0199.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Rudolph Tschahle v. Henry M. White. Judge Decision</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0199.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Rudolph Tschahle v. Henry M. White. Judge Decision</title>
<date when="1919-01-02">January 2, 1919</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1919-01">January 1919</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>New York</term>
<term>Montana</term>
<term>Detroit</term>

</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Tschale, Rudolph</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Moore, Ben L.</persName>
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2019-11" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="#hc.case.wa.0199.007"/>

<p>No.</p>

<p>In the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Jan 2 1919</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<p>No. 4476.</p>

<p>Filed Jan. 2 1919.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Rudolf Tschable, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Ben L. Moore, <gap></gap> Attorney for Government.</p>
<p>Ralph S. Pierce, <gap></gap> Attorney for Petitioner</p>

<p>NETERER, District Judge.</p>
<p>The petitioner is ordered deported upon the ground that he was a person likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry into the United States. He seeks relief on the ground that he has been denied a fair trial, that there is no evidence to support the charge against him, and that the order of deportation was arbitrary and unsupported by fact or law. The issue before the court is whether the petitioner was accorded a fair trial, and if there is any testimony, however slight, to suppot the order of deportation. The order is final. The testimony is very brief. It shows that the petitioner came as a passenger to the United States, landing at the Port of New York. He worked in a factory in the East for three years until the factory was closed on account of the war, and then worked for a time in a machine shop in Detroit, and then came West and worked for a railroad in Montana as laborer, and later came to the Puget Sound district. He registered under the Selective Service Act at Detroit, but did not fill out the questionnaire because, he says, "I didn't have nobody give it to me to fill out." He does not belong to the I.W.W; he did belong to the Socialist party in the East, but does not belong to that party now. There is a statement by the Inspector with relation to the petitioner which cannot be considered as evidence, and there is likewise a letter introduced, found among the petitioner's possessions, written to him by another person, but there is nothing to connect the petitioner with the endorsement of any sentiment expressed in this letter.</p>
<p>Upon the record, there is no evidence upon which to predicate the conclusion and the petitioner, therefore, was not accorded a fair hearing, and the writ should be granted.</p>

<p>Jeremiah Neterer</p>
<p>Judge.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>