<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0366.038"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Brief Opposing Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0366.038</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Brief Opposing Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1921-09-15">September 15, 1921</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-09"></date>September 1921</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fletcher Decker</term>
<term>Beeler</term>
<term>Sullivan</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Western District of Washington</term> 
<term>United States</term>
<term>Great Britain</term><!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Fletcher Decker</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>Beeler</persName>
<persName>Sullivan</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Charlotte Kolmitz</persName>
<persName>Robert C. Saunders</persName>
<persName>Tucker</persName>
<persName>Hyland</persName>
<persName>F.C. Reagan</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName></placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022" who="AS">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0366.038"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>IN THE DISTRICT OF THE UNITED STATES
WESTERN DISTRICT NORTHERN DIVISION</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE EXTRADITION
of 
FLETCHER DECKER.) ( )</p> 
<p>No.</p> 
<p>B R I E F
opposing petition for
WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS</p> 
<p>The proceedings before the commissioner were pursuant
to the Extradition Treaties between U.S. and Great Britian 
of 1842 and 1889. For these treaties, see Malloy's Treaties,
Vol.1, page 655 and 740.</p> 
<p>The present hearing being one on Habeas Corpus before
the District Court, the first inquiry is as to the scope of
review of the District Court: on a habeas corpus hearing:</p> 
<p>POWER OF DISTRICT COURT OF HABEAS CORPUS PROCEEDINGS TO REVIEW
PROCEEDINGS OF THE COMMISSIONER IS LIMITED TO DETERMINING
WHETHER THERE WAS ANY LEGAL EVIDENCE UPON WHICH COMMISSIONER
COULD EXERCISE HIS JUDGMENT AND WHETHER ANY PROBABLE CAUSE
EXISTED FOR COMMISSIONER BELIEVING PRIONER GUILTY.</p> 
<p>In re Count De Touluse Lautrec, 102 Fed 879.
Matter of Wahl, 15 Blatch. 334.
Matter of Wiegand, 14 Blatch. 370.
Ex p. Van Aernam 3 Blatch 160.
Ex p. Van Hoven, 4 Dill 415.
Terlinden vs Ames 184 U.S. 270.
Bryant v. U.S. 167 U.S. 104.
Ornelas vs. Ruiz 161 U.S 502.
Fong Yue Ting vs U.S. 149 U.S. 698.
In re Cortes, 136 U.S. 330.
Benson vs. McMahon, 127 U.S. 457.
Sternaman vs. Peck 80 Fed. 883.
In re Fowler 4 Fed. 303.
In re Veremaitre, 3 Am. L. J. N. S, 438
28 Fed. Cases No. 16,915.
In re McDonell, 11 Blatch. 170,
16 Fed. Cas. No. 8772.
In re Kaine, 10 N.Y. Leg. Obs. 257,
14 Fed. Cas. 7598.
In re Stupp 12 Blatch. 501.
Matter of Vandervelpen 14 Blatch. 137.
In re Krojanker, 44 Fed. 482.
In re Behrendt 22 Fed. 699.</p> 
<p>Fed Case 16409</p>  
<pb></pb> 
<p>In re Wadge 16 Fed. 332
Grin vs Shine 187 U.S. 191
In re Herskovitz 136 Fed. 713.
Ex parte Charlton 185 Fed. 880.
Powell vs U.S. 206 Fed. 400. 
Ex parte Schorer 197 Fed. 78.</p> 
<p>In re Herskovitz, 136 Fed. 713.</p>
<p>On petition for Habeas Corpus after proceedings
before the Commissioner.</p> 
<p>"By section 5270, already referred to, concurrent
jurisdiction is given to the serveral officers
named in the statute to issue warrants, hear exam-
inations, and to commit in extradition proceedings.
This, the, is a collateral attack upon the judg-
ment of a concurrent court. It is too well settled
to require the citation of authority that the writ
of habeas corpus cannot be used as a method or fe-
viewing proceedings as if upon error, and that judg-
ments or findings of courts of competent jurisdic-
tion cannot be set aside or avoided by this pro-
cedure because of error. Under the provisions of
the statute the commissioner had full jurisdiction
of the subject-matter, and there is no question
but what he had jurisdiction of the person of the
petitioner. I think the disclosures made at the
examination have, however, cured any defect in the
complaint."</p>
<p>Powell vs. U.S. 206 Fed. 400</p> 
<p>Defense attempted to prove absence from the foreign
country at the time of the offense charged by the way
of alibi, and alleged as error the refusal of the
commissioner to entertain the defense.</p> 
<p>"The commissioner also said orally upon the hearing,
and in his return to the writ issued from the Dis-
trict Court, that he did not disregard the testi-
mony tending to show an alib, but gave it due con-
sideration and did not believe it, and from the
whole testimony drew the conclusion that there was
probable cause to believe Powell guilty."</p> 
<p>Ex parte Charlton 185 Fed. 880.</p> 
<p>"The duty of the committing magistrate is confined 
to determining: First, whether such warrant or cer-
tificate has been issued; second, whether the of-
fense charged against the accused is extraditable un-
der the treaty; third, whether the person brought be-
fore him is the one accused of such crime; and, four-
th, whether there is probably cause for holding the
accused for trial, the evidence in that respect to
be such as, according to the law of the state in
which the accused is apprehended, would be sufficient
to commit him for trial."</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>Sternam vs Peck  80 Fed. 883.</p>
<p>"A writ of habeas corpus cannot perform the office
of a writ of error in reviewing the proceedings in
extradition before an officer authorized to enter-
tain such proceddings. It is efficent only to
reach error which is fatal to the jurisdiction of
the officer over the person of the accused, or
over the subject-matter of the accusation......
.....The evidence was not very satisfactory, and
was far from being convincing. Nevertheless, the
facts and circumstances proved authorized conflict-
ing presumptions and probabilities as to her guilt 
or innocence, and it was the province of the com-
missioner to determine theri import, and whether
they were such as to justify him in exercising
his power to commit her to custody pending the
action of the department of state."</p> 
<p>In re Stupp. 12 Blatch. 501</p> 
<p>The court issuing the writ of habeas corpus
"is not to inquire whether the legal evidence of
facts before the commissioner was sufficient or in-
sufficient to warrant his conclusion; nor, if there
was legal and competent evidence of facts before the
commissioner, for him to consider in making up his
decsion as to the criminality of the accused, is the
court, on habeas corpus, to hold the proceedings il
legal, and to discharge the prisoner, because some
other evidence was introduced which was not legal
or competent, but was held to be so by the commis-
ioner, and was considered by him on the question of
fact, or, because the court, on a consideration of
all the evidence which the commissioner considered,
would have come to a different conclusion, or be-
cause the court on an exclusion of such of the
evidence as it may think was not legal or competent,
would come on the rest of the evidence, to a dif-
erent conclusion of facts from that at which the
commissioner arrived."</p> 
<p>Grin vs Shine. 187 U.S. 181.</p> 
<p>the sufficiency of the evidence cannotbe reviewed
on habeas corpus.</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>Ex parte Schorer 197 Fed. 67.</p> 
<p>The court, after discussing the lack of proof of
intent, said:</p> 
<p>"It is always possible to conceive that the accused
might be an innocent victim of circumstances; but,
if an extradition commissioner has drawn the per-
missable inferences of guilt, it is beyond the prov-
ince of the court on habeas corpus to reject them.
We may note that the testimony given by the accused
before the commissioner, although it consisted of
denials, called for nothing more than the exercise
of the commissioner's discretion in believing it or
disbelieving it. It could not render incompetent
the other testimony, and whether it was worthy of
belief, whether the accused fairly met the incul-
pasing circumstances with which he was confronted,
was within the peculiar province of the commissioner
to determine; and such determination is not review-
able on habeas corpus."</p> 
<pb></pb>
<p>TO JUSTIFY THE COMMISSIONER IN ISSUING THE CERTIFICATE HE
NEED ONLY HAVE PROBABLE CAUSE FOR BELIEVING THE ACCUSED GUILTY.</p>
<p>Ex p. Charlton   185 Fed. 880.
U.S. vs Piaza   133 Fed. 998.
Ex p. Zentner   188 Fed. 344.</p> 
<p>U.S.<add>vs</add>Piaza   133 Fed. 998.</p>
<p>"Authorities abound which hold that it is sufficient
if the accused is held on competent legal evidence,
and, further, if probable cause exists for believ-
ing the defendant guilty of the offense charged.
The evidence need not be conclusive, nor must the
commissioner who hears the proceedings be absolute-
ly convinced of the defendant's guilt, before exer-
cising the power to commit him."</p>
<pb></pb> 
<p>THE LEGALITY OF THE EVIDENCE.</p> 
<p>Section 5271 of the Act is superseded by
SECTION 5 of the Act of 1882.</p> 
<p>3 Fed. Stats. Anno. page 90.
In re Behrendt 22 Fed. 699.
In re McPhun   30 Fed.  57.</p> 
<p>This section provides for DEPOSITIONS, WARRANTS, or
OTHER PAPERS.</p> 
<p>and makes ALL SUCH legal evidence if properly auth-
enticated showing admissability in the foreign country</p>
<p>In re Cortes.    42 Fed. 47.</p> 
<p>The court may look to the warrant of arrest for
a statement of the offense, and the prisoner can-
not object if that sufficiently informs him of the
offense.</p> 
<p>In re Behrendt   22 Fed. 699.</p> 
<p>"The certificate of the royal judge that the judicial
proceeding certified to 'is valid evidence according
to the laws existing in Prussia', reasonable inter-
preted, can mean nothing less than that, according
to the law of Prussia, such documents are valid
evidence of criminality as regards the crime charged
in the proceedings specified in the court where the
proceedings purports to be had. This is all the
evidence that is required under the first branch
of the statute; since the proceedings appear upon
the face to be acriminal one, in a criminal court."</p> 
<p>In re Krojanker  44 Fed. 482.</p>
<p>Following the Behrendt case.</p> 
<p>Terlinden vs Ames. 184 U.S.S 270.     (184 U.S. 270)</p> 
<p>In this case copies of the Penal Code of the
German Empire were attached to the complaint.</p> 
<p>In re Exeta 62 Fed. 972.     (984-5(</p> 
<p>Here, statements, in the form of depositions,
but not even appearing to have been sworn to,
were submitted. It was held that their infor-
mality was covered by the Act of Congress and
the certificate.</p> 
<p>Elias vs. Ramirez.   215 U.S. 398.</p> 
<p>Unsworn statements were admitted by reason of 
the Act and the fact that they created a probab-
ility of guilt.</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>In re Luis Oteiz vs Cortes   136 U.S. 330.</p> 
<p>Here informal papers, and ex parte depositions
were offered by the defense under the Act and
refused not because of their informality, but
because of the fact that they were offered by
the defense.</p> 
<p>Ex parte Glaser      176 Fed. 702.</p> 
<p>Following Elias vs. Ramirez. Supra.</p> 
<p>Grin vs Shine        187  U.S. 191.</p>
<p>ORAL PROOF MAY BE TAKEN IN AIDER OF
IRREGULARITY OR INSUFFICIENCY.</p> 
<p>In re Folwer     4 Fed. 303.</p> 
<p>In re Wadge      15 Fed. 864.</p> 
<p>THE CERTIFICATE OF THE DIPLOMATIC OR CONSULAR
OFFICER OF THE UNITED STATES RESIDENT IN THE FOREIGN
COUNTRY IS ABSOLUTE PROOF THAT THE PAPERS CERTIFIED
ARE RECEIVABLE IN THE FOREIGN COUNTRY AS PROOF OF
CRIMINALITY.</p> 
<p>In re McPhun 30 Fed. 57</p> 
<p>In re Wadge XXXXXX 15 Fed. 864.</p>
<p>AND THE SIGNATURE OF THE UNITED STATES VICE
CONSUL IS SUFFICIENT FOR THIS PURPOSE ALSO.</p> 
<p>In re Herres     33 Fed. 165</p> 
<p>In re Orpen      86 Fed. 760.</p> 
<p>AND THE WORDING OF THE CERTIFICATE IS SUFFICIENT
IF IT FOLLOWS THE LANGAUGES OF THE STATUTE.</p> 
<p>Grin v. Shine 187 U.S. 181.</p> 
<pb></pb>
<p>THEREFORE THE PETITIONER'S CONTENTION THAT THERE IS NO EVIDENCE
OF THE COMMISSION OF A CRIME MUST FAIL BECAUSE THERE WAS COMPETENT
LEGAL EVIDENCE BEFORE THE COMMISSIONER WHICH THE COMMISSIONER
FOUND TO CREATE PROBABALE CAUSE OF THE COMMISSION OF A CRIME BY
THE PRISONER AND HIS DECISION ON THIS POINT IS NOT OPEN TO REVIEW
BY THE DISTRICT COURT IN THIS PROCEEDING.</p> 
<p>It is next contended by the Petitioner that
THE COMMISSIONER DID NOT HAVE JURISDICTION.</p> 
<p>This contention cannot stand for the simple reason
that the Comissioner did have jurisdiction, and reference to the
papers will show that affirmatively, although it is the duty of
this court to TAKE JUDICIAL NOTICE OF THE COMMISSIONER'S AUTHORITY
AND JURISDICTION.</p>
<p>Ex parte Lane.   6 Fed. 34.</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>It is next contended by the Petitioner that
the warrant is void and illegal.</p> 
<p>This contention is unsound.</p> 
<p>THE WARRANT MUST NOT NECESSARILY SHOW ON ITS FACE THE AUTHORITY
OF THE COMMISSIONER.</p> 
<p>This was decided in Ex parte Lane.   6 Fed. 34.
(1881, Michigan, Dist. Ct. <del>6</del></p> 
<p>In this case both the complaint and the warrant
failed to show the power of the commissioner to act in extra-
dition cases. After the close of the proceedings and without
the knowledge or consent of the petitioner the complaint was
amended by interlining "extradition" to show the authority.</p> 
<p>The District Court Judge doubted the right of the
amendment and determined the case as though unamended. Then,
after reviewing the cases holding to the contrary, said:</p>
<p>"Hence, I think it should appear that the person
taking the complaint and issuing the warrant is
not only a commissioner of the court, but is one
authorized to act iin extradition cases. <del>I</del> should
be loth, however, to hold that the proceedings
were void upon this account, since I am by no means
certain but that the court, upon an application
for discharge upon a writ of habeas corpus, would
be bound to take judicial notice of the fact that
the commissioner had been <del></del> appointed for
this purpose. If a third person had been indicted
for resisting amarshal in the execution of this
warrant, I should have no doubt that the decision
of Justice Curtis would apply, and that it would 
be necessary to make a more particular averment
in the indictment."</p> 
<p>The reasonable and logical inference from this
opinion is that if the commissioner had seen fit to let the
accused go by reason of the defect in the warrant he might
have done so, but actually having the authority, and the
proceedings being otherwise regular, and there being evidence
of guilt, he acted properly; and the District Court will ig-
nore mere technicalities and take judicial notice of the fact
that the commissioner actually had authority and acted within
it by issuing the warrant.</p> 
<p>This brings it exactly within the case at bar, on 
that point.</p> 
<p>In the Lane case the Judge doubted the authority
of the Commissioner to amend. But there the amendment was
made after the close of the proceedings and without the know-
ledge of the petitioner. But in the case at bar the warrant
was amended at the opening of the proceedings and in the
presence of counsel of both parties.</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>Inasmuch as there is a conflict of authority on
this question, but has not been decided in this District or assed
upon by the Supreme Court both the question as to the validity of
the warrant and the power to amend must be open questions.</p> 
<p>The first consideration is that the Act only <del></del>
requires the Commissioner to be authorised by any of the courts
of the United States. It does not require the warrant to show
the authority its face. (Sec. 5270).</p> 
<p>The second consideration is that technicalities
will be ignored and good faith will be kept with the foreign
country.</p>
<p>In re Neely      103 Fed. 626.</p>
<p>In re Herres     33 Fed. 165 
reversing 32 Fed. 583</p> 
<p>46 ten 267</p> 
<p>In re Roth 15 Fed. 506.</p>
<p>In re Henrich 5 Blatch 414.</p> 
<p>In re Behrendt 22 Fed. 699</p> 
<p>In re Krojanker 44 Fed. 482.</p> 
<p>Grin vs Shine 187 U.S. 184.</p> 
<p>"In the construction and carrying out of
such treaties the ordinary technicalities of crim-
inal proceedings are applicable only to a limited
extent. Foreign powers are not expected to be
versed in the niceties of our criminal laws, and
proceedings for a surrender are not such as put
in issue the life or liberty of the accused. They
simply demand of him that he shall do what all 
gpod citizens are required, and ought to be will-
ing to do, viz, submit themselves to the laws of 
their country. Care should doubtless be taken
that the treaty be not made a pretext for collect-
ing private debts, wreaking individual malice, or
forcing the surrender of policitcal offenders; but
where the proceeding is manifestly taken in good
faith, a technical noncompliance with some for-
mality of criminal procedure should not be allowed
to stand in the way of a faithful discharge of our
obligations. Presumably, at least, no injustice
is contemplated, and a proceeding which may have
the effect of relieving the country from the
presence of one who is likely to threaten the peace
and good order of the community, is rather to be
welcomed than discouraged."</p> 
<p>The above case has been followed and quoted
extensively on this point.</p> 
<p>U.S. vs Piaza 133 Fed. 998.</p> 
<p>Gluckman vs Henkel 221 U.S. 508 
55 U.S. (L. Ed.) 830.</p> 
<p>"It is common in extradition cases to
<pb></pb>
attempt to bring to bear all the factitious nice-
ties of a criminal trial at common law. But it
it a waste of time. For while of course a man
is not to be sent from the country merely upon
demand or surmise, yet if there is presented,
even in somewhat untechnical form according to
our ideas, such reasonable ground to suppose
him guilty as to make it proper that he should
be tried, good faith to the demanding govern
ment requires his surrender. 2</p> 
<p>In re Herskovitz. 136 Fed. 713.</p>
<p>Ed p. Zentner 188 Fed. 344.</p>
<p>Lincoln vs Power 228 Fed. 70</p>
<p>Lincoln vs Power 241 U.S. 651.
60 L. Md. 1222.</p> 
<p>Rice vs Ames 180 U.S. 371.</p> 
<p>Yordi vs Nolte 215 U.S. 227.</p> 
<p>"A writ of habeas corpus is not like an
action to recover damages for an unlawful arrest
or commitment, but its object is to ascertain
whether the prisoner can lawfully be detained
in custody; and if sufficient ground for his
detention by by the Government is shown, he is
not to be discharged for defects in the
original arrest or commitment."</p> 
<p>U.S. vs Green  146 Fed. 766</p>
<p>AND UPON SIMILAR GROUNDS IT IS HELD THAT THE WARRANTS AND ORDERS
OF ARREST OF IMMIGRATION OFFICIALS EVEN THOUGH IRREGULAR WILL
NOT BE REVIEWED IF THE PRISONER HAD A FAIR HEARING.</p>
<p>U.S. vs Williams.  200 Fed. 538.</p> 
<p>FURTHER MORE ERRORS OF LAW CANNOT BE REVIEWED UPON HABEAS CORPUS</p> 
<p>Frank vs Mangum  237 U.S. 309
59 L. Ed. 969.</p>
<p>Ex parte Williams  138 S.W. 985
Lewis vs Nelson  56 So. 436.</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>AS TO POWER TO AMEND  SEE</p>
<p>Ex parte Lane    6 Fed. 34.</p> 
<p>In re Fergus     30 Fed. 607.</p> 
<p>IN EXTRADITION TO THIS COUNTRY THE MEANS OF OBTAINING THE
PERSON OF THE FUGITIVE ARE IMMATERIAL.</p> 
<p>Ker vs Illinois  119 U.S. 436.</p> 
<p>State vs Brewster 7 Vt. 118.</p> 
<p>Matter of LaGrave  45 How. Pr. (N.Y.) 301.</p>
<p>People vs Rowe   4 Park Crim. N.Y. 253.</p> 
<p>Hall vs Patterson    45 Fed. 352.</p> 
<p>People vs Pratt  78 Cal. 345.</p>
<pb></pb> 
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION OF
FLETCHER DECKER
FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.)()(()()(</p> 
<p>NO. 
Authorities Cited on
Behalf of Petitioner.</p> 
<p>E X T R A D I T I O N.</p> 
<p>Sufficiency of Warrant of Arrest.</p>
<p>What warrant must show upon its face.</p>
<p>In re Ferez, 8 Fed.Case.4644-</p>
<p>In re Kelley, 25 Fed. 268</p> 
<p>In re McDonnell. 16 Fed.Cas.8711.-</p> 
<p>U.S.-vs-Stowell.27.Fed.Cas.16409-</p> 
<p>Ex parte Lane.5 Fed.34-</p>
<p>Byrne's Fed.Crim.Proc.page 26.</p>
<p>19 Cyc. page 68.</p>
<p>Bishop's New Crim.Proc. Sec.187.</p>
<p>1 Cooley on Torts.page 302.</p>
<p>Anderson on Jud.Writs&amp;Process.page36
" 112</p> 
<p>COM.-vs-FAY,112 Mass.235.-<figure><p>checkmark</p></figure></p>
<p>Beeler &amp; Sullivan,
Attorneys for Petitioner.</p>
</div1> 
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>