<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0179.003.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. State of Washington. Petition. </title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0179.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. State of Washington. Petition.</title>
<date when="1913-06-19">June 19, 1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2504AlbertYoung&amp;KamasaburoSugiuro</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-06">June 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Sugiuro, B. K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Jacoby, Joseph R. H.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Washio, Shotoro</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Ito, Kayama</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Uneda, K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Sato, Hana</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>San Francsico, California</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Young, Albert H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sugiuro, Kamasaburo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>State of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Martin, Walter S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>McCelland, Robert W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Cushman, Edward E.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the United States District Court in and for the Western District
of Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the 
Petition of Albert H. Young
and Kamasaburo Sugiuro alias
B.K. Sugiurd for a writ of 
habeas corpus. } No. 2504
Petition for Writ of
Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>To the Honorable Edward E. Cushman, Judge of the above entitled
court:</p>
<p>The petition of Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro,
alias B.K. Sugiuro, for a writ of habeas corpus in the above entitled
casue respectfully shows, to-wit:</p>
<p>I.
That the defendants and each of them are unlawfully imprisoned,
detained, confined and restrained of their liberty by
Joseph R.H. Joacoby, United States Marshall in and for the Western
District of Washington, at the County Jail of King County in the
State of Washington within said district, under an alleged, pretended
and illegal commitment under process in the above entitled
court.</p>
<p>II.
That said imprisonment, detention, confinement and
restraint are illegal and in violation of the Constitution of the
United States and of the several treasties between the sovereignties
of the United States and Japan in this, to-wit: That at Seattle
within the district and court aforesaid on or about the 4th day
of December 1912, the petitioners were indicted by the
Grand Jury sitting in and for said district for an alleged violation
of the White Slave Traffic Act, that your said petitioners
were charged in that indictment, first, with a consumtated violation
of the act itself as the same is set forth in counts one and two
thereof, and secondly, with a conspiracy between themselves and
the other defendants mentioned herein to violate the said act.
That said indictment was number 2347 in the files of the
above entitled court and was in words and figures as follows, to wit:</p>
<fw>1</fw>
<pb/>
<p>"United States of America
Northern Division 
Western District of Washington } ss. No. 2347</p>
<p>The Grand Jurors of the United States of America, duly
expaneled, sworn and charged to enguire within and for the
Northern Division of the Western District of Washington, upon
their oaths, present:</p>
<p>Count I
That heretofore, <del><unclear/></del> <add>to-wit</add> on or about the 13th day of August,
A.D. 1912, one Albert H. Young, one Kamasaburo Sugiuro, alias 
B. K. Sugiuro, one Shotoro Washio, one Kayama Ito and one K. Uneda,
did wilfully, unlawfully, and feloniously and knowing transport
and cause to be transported, and aid and assist in obtaining transportation
for, and in transpoerting in Inter State Commerce, from
the city of Seattle in the State and Northern Division of Washington,
District of Washington, to San Francisco, in the State of
Californi, by means of a certain common carrier engaged in interstate
commerce, to wit: by means of the ships of the Pacific
Steamship Company, a corporation, a certain women, to-wit: One Hana
Sato, for the purpose of prostitution, whereby the said woman Hana
Ito was transported in interstate commerce from said city of
Seattle, State of Washington, to the said city of San Francisco,
in the state of California for the purpose of prostitution; contrary
to the form of the statute in such case made and provided
against the peace and dignity of the United States of America.</p>
<p>Count II.
And the Grand Jurors aforesaid, upon their oaths aforesaid,
do further present:</p>
<p>That heretofore, <add>to-wit</add> on or about the 13th day of August,
A.D. 1912, Albert H. Young, Kamasburo Sugiuro, alias B.K.
Sugiuro, Shotoro Washio, Kayama Ito and K. Uneda did wilfully,
unlawfully and feloniously, knowingly persuade, induce, entice
and coerce, and cause to be persuaded, <add>induced</add>, enticed and coercing, a certian
woman, to-wit: Hana Sato, to go from the city of Seattle, in
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
the state of Washington, and in the Northern Division, District
of Washington, to the city of San Francisco, in the state of California,
in interstate commerce, for the purpose of prostitution,
and with the intent and purpose on the part of the said Albert H. 
Young, Kamasaburo Sujiuro, alias B.K. Sugiuro, Shotoro Washio,
Kayama Ito and K., Uneda, that the said women Hana Sato should
engage in adn giver herself up to the practice of prostitution, and
that the said Albert H. Young, Kamasaburo Sugiuro, alias B.K. 
Sugiro, Shotoro Washio, Kayama Ito, and K. Uneda, did thereby
knowingly cause and <del>did</del> <add>aid and</add> assist in causing said women, Hana Sato,
to go and be transported and carried as a passenger in interstate
commerce over the steamship line of the said Pacific Coast steamship
Company, a corporation, from the city of Seattle, State of
Washington to the city of San Francisco, state of California, for
the purpose of prostitution; that the said Pacific Coast Steamship
Companh is and then and there was, as the said Albert H, Young,
<add>Kamasaburo Sugiuro, alias B.K. Sugiuro, Shotoro Washio, Kayama Ito, and K. Uneda <unclear/></add>
well know a common carrier engaged in the business of transporting
and carrying passengers in interstate commerce from the state of
Washington to the state of California, and did act in such capacity
in bringing said Hana Sato from said city of Seattlee and state of
Washington, to <add>said city</add> San Francisco in the state of California, which is
contrary to the form and statutes in such cases made and provided
and against the peace and dignity of the United States of America.</p>
<p>Count III.
And the grand jurors aforesaid, upon their oaths aforesaid,
do further present:</p>
<p>That heretofore, and on or about the 25th day of July,
A.D. 1912, one Albert Young, one Kamasburo Sugiuro, alias B.K.
Sugiuro, Shotoro Washio, Kayama Ito and K. Uneda did knowingly,
wilfully, wickedly, unlawfully, corruptly and feloniously, conspire,
combine, confederate, and agree among themselves, and with divers
other persons, whose names are to the grand jurors unknown, and
whose names for that reason cannot be herein stated, to commit an
offence against the United States, to-wit: that the said Albert H. 
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
Young, Kamasburo Sugiuro, alias S.K. Sugiuro, Shotoro Washio
Yakama Ito and K. Uneda, then and there knowingly, wilfully,
wickedly, and unlawfully, corruptly and feloniously, did conspire,
combine, confederate and agree among themselves and with divers
other persons, whose names are to the grand jurors unknown, knowingly,
wilfully, wickedly, unlawfully and feloniously, to persuade,
induce, entice and coerce, and to cause to be persuaded, induced,
enticed and coercing and to aid and assist in persuading, inducing,
enticing and coercing, and to transport and cause to be transported
and to aid and assist in obtaining transportation and transporting
a women, to-wit: one Hana Sato to go as a passengar in interstate
commerce from the city of Seattle in the state of Washington, to
the city of San Francisco, in the state of California, for the
purpose of prostitution, and with the intent on the part of the
said Albert H. Young, Kamasburo Sugiuro, alias B.K. Sugiuro,
Shotoro Washio, Kayama Ito and K. Uneda, that the said woman
Hana Sato should engage in the practice of prostitution.</p>
<p>Count IV.
And the grand jurors aforesaid upon their oaths aforesaid
do further present:</p>
<p>That during the continuance and in accordance with and
in pursuance <add>to</add> and to effect the object of, said conspiracy, the
said Albert Young, Kamasaburo Sugiuro,alias B.K. Sugiuro, Shotoro
Washio, Kayama Ito and K. Uneda, on or about the 12th day of
August A.D. 1912, did go to the ticket office of the Pacific Coast
Steamship Company, in the city of Seattle, county of King and
state of Washington, and Northern Division of the Western District 
of Washington, to arrange with the said ticket agent for transportation
and ticket from the city of Seattle, Washington to San
Francisco, California, on the steamship line of the said Pacific
Coast Steamship Company, to be used by <del>one</del> <add>said</add>, Hana Sato, and did
then and there purchase and obtain transportation and tickets,
whereby the said woman Hana Sato, was transported and carried as
a passenger in interstate commerce from the said city of Seattle
<fw>4</fw>
<pb/>
in the state of Washington, Northern Divison of the Western District 
of Washington, to the city of San Francisco, in the
state of California for the purposes of prostitution, contrary to
the form of the statute in such cases made and provided and against
the peace and dignity of the United States of America."</p>
<p>III.
That thereafter on the 9th day of December, 1912
defendants and each of them entered a plea of not-guilty upon
the said indictment; that thereafter on the 25th day of Feburary
1913 in the above entitled court within the district
aforesaid a jury was duly and regularly sworn and empaneled in
the above entitled cause and the said defendants then and there
placed on trial upon the said indictment and their plea of not-
guilty thereto; that then and there, after the said jury was
sworn, empaneled and charged, and after your said petitioners
had been placed on trial is said cause, upon motion of your said
petitioners the Government was required by said court to elect
upon which two counts it would proceed to prosecute your petitioners,
to-wit: That the court required the Government to elect
whether it would try the defendants either upon the consumated
offense as set forth in the first two counts in the indictment
or upon the conspiracy to commit and offense as set forth in the
last two counts of said indictment; that thereupon the United
States elected to try your petitioners, the defendants in said
cause, upon the first two counts of said indictment, to-wit:
Upon the counts in said indictment which charged the defendants
with the consumated offense under the said act.</p>
<p>IV.
That thereafter on the 1st dat of March, 1913, after
all the testimony in said cause had been introduced, and after
instructions by the court and arguments of counsel the cause was
submitted to the jury, and the said jury thereafter on said March
1st having duly considered the evidence, and after due deliberation
thereof, returned a verdict of not-guilty as against your petitioner
<fw>5</fw>
<pb/>
herein.</p>
<p>V.
That thereafter on the 5th day of May, 1912, the 
grand jurors sitting in and for the said court and district
returned an indictment in Cause #2471 against your petitioners
herein, which indictment is hereafter set forth in words and
figures as follows, to-wit:
"The United States of America,
Northern Division,
Western District of Washington. ss No.2471</p>
<p>The grand jurors of the United States of America duly
empaneled, sworn and charged to inquire with and for the Northern
Division of the Western District of Washington upon their oaths
presents:</p>
<p>That heretofore, to-wit: On or about the 25th day of
July, 1912, one Kamasaburo Sugiuro, alias B.K. Sugiuro, one Albert
E. Young, one Shotaro Washio, one Kyugoro Ito, and one K. Uneda
did knowingly, willfullyh, wickedly, unlawfully, corruptly and
feloniously conspire, combine, confederate and agree among themselves
and with divers other persons whose names are to the grand
jurors unknown, and whose names for that reason cannot be herein
stated to commit an offense aganist the United States, to-wit:
The said Kamasaburo Sugiuro, alias B.K. Sugiuro, Albert H. Young,
Shotaro Washio, Kyugoro Ito and K. Uneda then and there knowingly,
willfully, wickedly, unlawfully, corrputly and feloniously did 
conspire, combine, confederate and agree among themselves and with
divers other persons whose names are to the grand jurors unknown,
knowingly, willfully, wickedly, unlawfully and feloniously to
persuade, induce, entice and coerce and to cause to be persuaded,
induced, entilted and coercing and to transport and cause to be
transported a woman, to-wit: One Hana Sato to go as a passenger
in interstate commerce from the city of Seattle in the state of
Washington to the city of San Francisco in the state of California
for the purpose of prostitution and with the intent on the part
<fw>6</fw>
<pb/>
of said Kamasaburo Sugiuro, alias S.K. Sugiuro, Albert H. Young,
Shotaro Washio, Kyugoro Ito and K. Uneda that the said woman
Hana Sato should engage in the practice of prostitution.</p>
<p>And the grand jurors aforesaid upon their oaths aforesaid
do further present:</p>
<p>That after the formation of said unlawful conspiracy and
during continuance thereof and to effect the object thereof the
said Albert H. Young on or about the 13th day of August, 1912 in
the city of Seattle, county of King, state of Washington and within
the Northern Division of the Western District of Washington did
purchase from the Pacific Coast Steamship Companym, a corporation,
a ticket to be used by himself, the said Albert H. Young, in going
as a passenger in interstate commerce over the steamship line of
the said company from the said city of Seattle to the said city
of San Francisco.</p>
<p>And the gran jurors aforesaid upon their oaths aforesaid
do further present:</p>
<p>That after the formation of said unlawful conspiracy and
during the continuance thereof, and to effect the object thereof, the
said Albert H. Young, on or about the 13th day of August, 1912 did
go to the ticket office of the Pacific Coast Steamship Company in
the city of Seattle, county of King, state of Washington and in the
Northern Division of the Western District of Washington to arrange
with said ticket agent for transportation and tickets from the city
of Seattle, Washington to San Francisco, California, over the steamship
line of the said Pacific Coast Steamship Company, to be used
by said Hana Sato and did then and there purchase and obtain transportation
and tickets whereby the said woman Hana Sato was transported
and carried as a passenger in interstate commerce from the
said city of Seattle in the state of Washington and within the
Northern Division of the Western District of Washington, to the
city of San Francisco in the state of California for the purpose
of prostitution.</p>
<p>And the grand jurors aforesaid upon their oaths aforesaid
<fw>7</fw>
<pb/>
do further present:</p>
<p>That after the formation of said unlawful conspiracy
and during the continuance thereof and to effect the object
thereof the said Albert H. Young, siad Sugiuro and the said
Shotaro Washio did on or abour the 9th day of August, 1912 go from
the said city of Seattle to the city of Tacoma in the state of Washington.</p>
<p>And the grand jurors aforesaid upon their oaths
aforesaid do further present:</p>
<p>That after the formation of said unlawful conspiracy and
during the continuance thereof and to effect the object thereof
the said Albert H. Young and the said Kamasaburo Sugiuro, alias
B.K. Sugiuro, did on or about the 9th day of August, 1912 in the 
city of Tacoma, state of Washington, coerce the said Hana Sato to
go from teh city of Tacoma to the said city of Seattle; contrary 
to the form of the statute in such case made and provided and
against the peace and dignity of the United States of America."</p>
<p>VI.
That thereafter under the authority and by virtue of
the last mentioned indictment your petitioners were arrested by
said Marshall and by his brought before the above entitled court
and by said above entitled court on said day committed to the
county jail to await trial upon said indictment, and that your
said petitioners ever since have been and now are in the custody
of the said United States Marshall and are detained and imprisoned 
in the county jail at Seattle, Washington, all as aforesaid. That
your petitioners are as aforesaid unduly, illegally and wrongfully
imprisoned in the said county jail adn deprived of their liberty, which
imprisonment and deprivation of liberty are in violation of the
constitution of the United States in this, that your petitioners
are being twice put in jeopardy of life or limb for the same
offense within the fifth amendment to the <add>United</add> States Constitution;
that by reason of the former acquitial of your petitioners upon
this said offense your petitioners are as aforesaid illegally
<fw>8</fw>
<pb/>
detained and imprisoned and for said reason now bring this petition
for a writ of habeas corpus in this said cause.</p>
<p>Wherefore, your petitioners pray that a writ of habeas
corpus may issue out of and under the seal of this Honorable 
Court directed to Joseph R.H. Jacoby as the Marshall of the
United States in and for the court and district aforesaid, then
and there commanding him, the said Jacoby to forthwith bring the
bodies of Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro, alias B.K.
Sugiuro, befoe this Honorable Court as such time as the court
may direct, then and there to be dealt with according to law
and to abide such decree or order as this Honorable Court may make
in the premises.</p>
<ab>Albert H. Young
Kamasaburo Sugiuro
Petitioners.</ab>
<ab>Walter S. Martin and
Robert W. McCelland
Attorneys for petitioners.</ab>
<pb/>
<p>1x No. 2504</p>
<p>In the United States District Court
for the
Western District of Washington
Northern Division</p>
<p>In the matter of the
Petition of Albert H. Young
and Kamasaburo Sugiuro alias
B.K. Sugiuro for a writ of
habeas corpus.</p>
<p>Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>Filed in teh 
U.S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington,
JUN 19 1913
Frank L. Crosby, Clerk.
By EML Deputy.</p>
<p>Robert W. McCelland and
<del><unclear/>, Wardall &amp; Martin</del>
Walter S. Martin
Attorneys for petitioners</p>
<p>#805 Leary Bldg
540-1-2 New York Block
Seattle</p>
<pb/>
<p><add>District</add> Court of Washington
County of King} ss.</p>
<p>Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Suguiro <add>each for himself and not one for the other</add> being first duly sworn
on oath says: Yjat he is the petitioner
in the above entitled actions: That he has read the foregoing
petition
knows the contents thereof and <del><unclear/></del> the same <del>to be</del> <add>is</add> true.</p>
<ab>Albert H. Young
Kamasaburo Sugiuro</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 19th day of June 1913
Walter S. Martin
Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, counties of Seattle, Washington.</p>
<figure/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>