<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0222.011">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Francis Stephen Medcraf vs. Frank T. Hodge. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0222.011</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Francis Stephen Medcraf vs. Frank T. Hodge. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-09">September 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>










</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Francis Stephen Medcraf</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Frank T. Hodge</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>George D. Emery</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Frank P. Helsell</persName>
<persName>Alfred H. Lundin</persName>    
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-04" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN RE APPLICATION OF 
FRANCIS STEPHEN MEDCRAF 
FOR WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS )
No. 3038.
Filed September 23, 1915.</p>
<p>George D. Emery, For Petitioner.</p>
<p>Alfred H. Lundin, Prosecuting Atty. 
Frank P. Helsell Asst. " " ) For State.</p>
<p>NETERER, District Judge:</p>
<p>The petitioner alleges that he is unlawfully detained
and restrained of his liberty by the Sheriff of King County,
Washington, upon a judgment of conviction for violation of the 
provisions of Sections 8412-8425 Remington &amp; Ballinger's Codes
and Statutes of Washington, he was being charged with practicing
dentistry for a fee in the State of Washington, without having
first filed for record and recorded in the office of the Auditor
of the County wherein he then and there practiced, to-wit,
King County, a certificate from the Board of Dental Examiners 
of the State of Washington, authorizing him to so practice as 
provided by law. He alleges that at the age of thirteen he 
was regularly apprenticed to a practicing dentist in London,
England, and served his apprenticeship the full term of five
years; that he "worked as dental assistant" to a surgeon 
dentist at Athens, Greece, for the term of two years, and as 
dental mechanic in the regular study and practice of that profession; 
that he returned to London "for further study and prosecuted
such study in dental surgery for six months" under William
Lombardi, under whom he served his apprenticeship; that in 1896
he was engaged in the office of Dr. Waldo Royce, dentist at 
Tunbridge Wells, England, a graduate of Harvard University, for 
eight months, as general dental assistant; that thereafter he 
was employed by Mr. James Shillcock, at Cannes, France, for five
months; and afterward entered the office of William Lombardi,
<fw>--1--</fw>
<pb/>
at London, and studi<add>ed</add> and practiced dental surfery for five 
months, and then, at Nice, France, acted as general assistant
and continued in that practice for the term of six months;
and in 1898 served for four months as dental mechanic at Mile 
End Road, London, and then returned to Nice, France, where he 
was employed for seven months in the practice of general 
dental work; and, in 1899, acted as general dental mechanic for 
four months in the office of Isador Clifford, in London, who 
treated "the then Prince of Wales, who is now the King of 
England"; did further assistant dental work in 1900, at Nice,
France, and in 1901 returned to London and opened an office
where he continued the practice of dentistry for two years; and
then, on account of ill health, removed to Alberta, Canada,
where he practiced dentistry for five years, and in February,
1908, removed to Seattle, Washington, "where he has continued
the practice of dentistry undisturbed until the issu<del>e</del> <add>ance</add> of the
warrant of arrest herein complained of." That before beginning
the practice of dentistry in Seattle, Wash. for license 
to practice, <add>he</add> "tendered the legal fee and offered himself for
examination pursuant to law, and in all things complied with 
the requirement of the statutes in such cases made and provided,
save only that he did not present any diploma from any
college of dentistry whatever for the reason that he did not 
possess one and does not now possess any, having obtained his 
profession, learning and skill at the places, by the practice
and study, and in the manner hereinbefore set forth." That the 
State Board of Dental Examiners refused to receive the application
of petitioner, and refused to grant him any licesne; and 
further states that he is qualified to practice dentistry and 
is willing to pay the fees, and sets forth in the petition the
sections of the act complained of, and alleges that the provisions
contravene Section 1 of Article 14 of the amendments to the 
Constitution of the United States, and Section 7 of Article 1
<fw>--2--</fw>
<pb/>
of the Constitution of the State of Washington, and Section 3
of Article 1 of the State Constitution.</p>
<p>Section 8416, Rem. &amp; Bal. Codes of Washington, in so far 
as pertinent, reads:</p>
    <p>"Any person *****seeking to practice dentistry
    in the State of Washington****shall file his or her 
    name, together with the application for examination
    with the Secretary of the State Board of Dental 
    Examiners, and at the time of making such application
    shall pay to the Secretary of the Board a fee of 
    $25.00 and to present him or herself at the first 
    regular meeting thereafter of said Board to undergo
    examination before that body.</p>
    <p>No person shall be eligible for such examination 
    unless he or she shall present to said Board his or 
    her diploma from some dental college in good standing
    and shall give satisfactory evidence of his or her
    rightful posession of the same; PROVIDED, this 
    section shall not apply to persons engaged in the 
    practice of dentistry at the time of the passage of this 
    act who are bona fide citizens of the State of 
    Washington.*****"</p>
<p>The act further provides for the issuance of a certificate and
the record thereof in the Auditor's office and a penalty for the
violation of the provisions of the act, and <del>then</del> Section 8424
defines dentistry as follows: "All persons shall be said to be 
practicing dentistry within the meaning of this chapter, who 
shall, contrary to this act, for a fee or salary or other reward,
paid either to himself or to another person for operations or 
parts of operations of any kind, treat diseases or lesions of 
the human teeth or of jaws or correct malpositions thereof."
The underscored portion of the section of the statute 1 is attacked.
These various constitutional provisions can be discussed 
together. Section 1, Article 14 of the amendments to the
Constitution of the United States, provides:</p>
    <p>"*****nor shall any State deprive any person of 
    life, liberty or property without due process of law, 
    nor deny to any person within its jurisdiction the 
    equal protection of the laws."</p>
<p>Article 5 of the Constitution of the United States:</p>
    <p>"*****No person****shall be deprived of life,
    liberty or property without due process of law."</p>
<p>Section 12, Article 1 of the Constitution of Washington:</p>
    <p>"No law shall be passed granting to any citizen
    or class of citizens, or corporation, other than
<fw>--3--</fw>    
<pb/>    
    municipal, privileges or immunities which, upon the
    same terms, shall not belong equally to all citizens
    or corporatins."</p>
<p>Section 7, Article 1:</p>
    <p>"No person shall be deprived of life, liberty 
    or property without due process of law."</p>
<p>It is strenuously urged on behalf of the petitioner 
that since the profession of dental surgrey or dentistry is a 
profitable employment and an honorable profession, and oflarge
importance to the petitioner as a means of earning a livelihood,
and to the public in that it gives it efficient service, that
the act transgresses the several provisions of the Constitution
of the State and United States, in that i t deprives the petitioner,
without due process of law, of that which to him is property
and which enables him to provide for himself and his family, and
that is not within the police power of the State.</p>
    <p>Mr. Justice Gray, in Leisey v. Hardin, 135 U. S. 127, in
    speaking of the police power, said:</p>
    <p>"It is that power which is characterized as that 
    inherent power essential to the very existence of civil 
    society and the safeguard of the inhabitants of the State
    against disorder, disease, poverty and crime."</p>
<p>Courts cannot place precise limits upon the police power of the
State. Each case must be controlled by the facts peculiar to its
situation and condition, but the exercise must be reasonable as 
distinguished from arbitrary or capricious, and when no 
discrimination between persons or classes upon any matter pertinent to 
the legal purpose of the law appears, it is not in contravention 
of any rights protected by the constitutional provisions, even 
though it may emphasize the condition or situation upon one more
that upon another because of the pecuniary situation. The mere
fact of discrimination because pecuniary situation of itself
does not make the law subject to legal criticism. The right to
<fw>--4--</fw>
<pb/>
enjoy life, liberty, property and the pursuit of happiness is 
secured to everyone under the State and Federal Constitutions,
and any act which deprives a man of the right to labor or 
restricts his liberty or capacity to earn wages over and beyond 
any deprivation of all others does not afford such person the
equal protection of the law. This right and liberty, however, 
is not unlimited, and if a restriction is placed upon all alike, 
that right is not invaded. The State Court, in State ex rel 
Thompson v. State Board, 48 Wash. 29, held the act in issue to 
be within the police power of the state and not in contravention
of any constitutional provision, and at page 293 said:</p>
    <p>"The statute makes the same requirements of all
    applicants for examination. No favored or preferred
    classes are created or recognized. An applicant who
    holds a diploma must also pass an examination. Rightful
    possession of his diploma does not of itself authorize
    him to practice, or entitled him to a license. The 
    requirement for both diploma and examination as a test
    of knowledge<del>i</del> is not such an unreasonable or arbitrary 
    one as to invalidate the statute. The right to determine
    what requirements must be met by an applicant is 
    within the exclusive province of the legislature. This 
    statute was considered in the case of In re Thompson,
    36 Wash. 377, 78 Pac. 899, in which it was attacked as
    unconstitutional and was sustained by this court. Without
    further discussion, we now adhere to the ruling then 
    made."</p>
<p>The same act was construed by the same court, In Re Thompson,
36 Wash. 377. Judge Mount, at page 380, said:</p>
    <p>"If we are correct in our conclusion that the 
    legislature, in the exercise of its police power, has
    authority, under the state and federal constitutions, 
    to regulate the practice of dentistry within the state 
    by reasonable rules, it follows that the legislature 
    may provided that an applicant must be possessed of a 
    diploma from some dental college in good standing.
    There is nothing unreasonable in this requirement, nor
    in the other requirements named in the act. Such
    diploma is evidence of the ability of the applicant to 
    practice dentistry. It is not conclusive of such ability,
    and the dental board may, therefore, provide
    reasonable rules for determining the actual ability of 
    the applicant."</p>
<p>The Supreme Court, in Reetz v. Michigan, 188 U. S. 505,
at page 506, said:</p>
    <p>"The power of a state to make reasonable provisions
    for determining the qualifications of those engaging
    in the practice of medicine and punishing those who 
    attempt to engage therein in defiance of such statutory
    provisions, is not open to question. Dent v. West 
<fw>--5--</fw>    
<pb/>    
    Virgina, 129 U. S. 114; Hawker v. N. Y., 170 U. S.
    189."</p>
<p>Justice Field, in Dent v. West Virginia, 129 U. S. 
114, at page 122, said:</p>
    <p>"The power of the State to provide for the general 
    welfare at its people authorizes it to prescribe all
    such regulations as, in its judgment, will secure or 
    tend to secure them against the consequences of 
    ignorance and incapacity as well as of deception and
    fraud. As one means to this end it has been the 
    practice in different states from time immemorial to exact
    in many pursuits a certain degree of skill and learning
    upon which the community may confidently rely, their 
    possession being generally ascertained upon an examination
    of parties by competent persons, or inferred from 
    a certificate to them in the form of a diploma or 
    license from an institution established for instruction
    on the subjects, scientific and otherwise, with which 
    such pursuits have to deal. The nature and extent of 
    the qualifications required must depend primarily upon
    the judgment of the State as their necessity. If 
    they are appropriate to the calling or profession, and
    attainable by reasonable study or application, no 
    objection to their validity can be raised because of their 
    stringency or difficulty. It is only when they have
    no relation to such calling or profession, or <del>are</del>
    unattainable by such reasonable study and application,
    that they can operate to deprive one of his right to 
    pursue a lawful vocation."</p>
<p>and Justice Day, in Watson v. Maryland, 218 U. S. 173, at page
177 said:</p>
    <p>"In such statutes there are often found exceptions
    in favor of those who have practiced their callings for 
    a period of years. In the Dent case, supra, an exception
    was made in favor of practitioners of medcien who 
    had continuously practiced their profession for ten 
    years prior to a date shortly before the enactment of 
    the law. Such exception proceeds upon the theory that
    those who have acceptably followed the profession in the 
    community for a period of years may be assumed to have
    the qualifications which others are required to 
    manifest as a result of an examination before a Board of 
    Medical experts."</p>
<p>and at page 178:</p>
    <p>"Before a law of this kind can be declared violative
    of the 14th amendment as an unreasonable classification
    of the subjects of such legislation because of the 
    ommision of certain classes, the court must be able to say
    that there is no fair reason for the law that would not
    require with equal force its extension to others whom 
    it leaves untouched."</p>
<p>Justice Holmes, in Collins v. Texas, 223 U. S. 288, in
reviewing the act of the legislature establishing a Board of
medical examiners in which it provided as a condition precedent
to examination that they must have graduated from a medical
<fw>--6--</fw>
<pb/>
school "whose entrance requirements and courses of instruction
are as high as those adopted by the better class of medical 
schools in the U. S. whose course of instruction shall embrace
not less than four terms of five months each", plaintiff being
an osteopath, who claimed that he was deprived of his property
without due process of law and denied the equal protection of 
the law, at page 296, said:</p>
    <p>"The state constitutionally may prescribe 
    conditions to such practice considered by it to be 
    necessary or useful to secure competence in those who 
    follow it. We should presume, until the Texas courts
    may otherwise, that the reference in par. 4 to the 
    diploma of a reputable and legal college of medicine
    and the confining in par. 7 of examination to graduates
    of reputable medical schools use the words 
    medicine and medical with the same broad sense as in par.
    13 and that the diploma of the plaintiff in error
    would not be rejected merely because it came from a 
    school of osteopathy. In short, the statute says, if 
    you want to do what it calls practicing medicine, you
    must have gone to a reputable school in that kind of
    practice."</p>
<p>The Supreme Court of Minnesota, in determining the 
constitutionality of anact which provided that "any person who 
shall desire to begin the practice of dentistry in the State 
after September 1, 1899, shall make application for examination
to the Board of Examiners****and shall undergo an examination", 
and further that "in order to be eligible for such examination
such person shall present to said Board his diploma from some 
dental college in good standing and shall give satisfactory 
evidence of his rightful possession of the same, provided also
that the Board may, in its discretion, admit to examination such 
person as give satisfactory evidence of having been engaged in
the practice of dentistry for ten years prior to the date of the 
passage of this act, in State v. Vanderlens, 43 N. W. 789, at 
page 790, said:</p>
    <p>What particular objections of a constitutional 
    character the appelant makes to this section, are, it
    is somewhat difficult to determine from his brief. We
    infer, however, that he claims the section to be
    objectionable because no matter how well qualified by learning
    and skill or experience one may be, he has no absolute
    right to be examined by the board unless he has a 
    diploma from a dental college of good standing, such good
<fw>--7--</fw>    
<pb/>    
    standing to be determined by the Board, and this he
    claims to be discrinination between the rich and poor, 
    because one may be pecuniarly able and another not 
    able to attend a dental college. The mere fact of 
    discrimination in such a law is not objection to it.
    Requiring a certain degree of learning and skill as
    a condition of being allowed to practice is 
    discrimination between those who have and those who have not
    that degree of learning and skill--between those who
    are able and those who are not able to acquire it.
    If there were discrimination between persons or classes
    upon any matter not pertinent to the legal purpose 
    of the law, to-wit, to secure fitness and competency 
    in those who shall per permitted to practice, it would
    be objectionable. As for instance, if it were as to 
    place of birth, color or religious belief. The requirement
    of a diploma from some college or learned society, 
    in order to practice medicine has been inserted in the 
    laws of many states, and questioned in but few. In 
    Mass. a law required the practitioner to have been
    licensed by the Medical Society or been graduated a Dr.
    in medicine at Harvard University. This was held 
    constitutional in Hewitt v. Charier, 16 Pick. 356. The 
    statute of Nevada (1875) require a medical education 
    and a diploma from some regularly chartered medical
    school. This was held constitutional in Ex parte
    Spinney, 10 Nev. 323. As the fact of having graduated
    and received a diploma from a school or college
    devoted to teaching the particular science, medicine, 
    surgery or dentistry, bears directly upon the persons
    qualification to practice, we have no doubt the 
    legislature might have made that the sole test. That this
    statute allows, in the discretion of the Board, ten
    years practice prior to the passage of the act as a 
    substitute for the diploma of a college, furnishes
    no objection on constitutional groundsto the act."</p>
<p>The Supreme Court of Kentucky, in Webster v. State Board
of Health, 113 S. W. 415, at page 416, said:</p>
    <p>"The statute under consideration is a wise and
    beneficent exercise of the police power of the 
    commonwealth, enacted for the purpose of protecting the
    people of the state from imposition by empirics and
    quacks. It does not seek to prevent any honorable 
    man or woman from practicing the profession of 
    medicine. It only requires that they shall show, by a
    satisfactory examination before the State Board of 
    Health that they are qualified. There is no
    suggestion in the petition that the Board is acting
    arbitrarily or that it unlawfully seeks to prevent the 
    appellant from obtaining a certificate, and we are 
    not entitled, in the absense of such allegation, to
    indulge in any presumption against its fairness. It 
    is the nigh duty of the Board to protect the health and
    safety of the public by requiring every applicant for 
    a certificate to practice medicine to first show his
    qualifications. It is not necessary to demonstrate 
    the constitutionality of the act. Such legislation 
    has been uniformly held as an exercise of the police
    power of the state by our own court and other courts
    throughout the land."</p>
<fw>--8--</fw>
<pb/>
<p>This act, however, predicated the qualifications upon a diploma
from a reputable medical college </p>
































</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>