<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0116.032"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Wiley v. Keokuk. Wiley v. Keokuk</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0116.032</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Wiley v. Keokuk. Wiley v. Keokuk</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1870-01">January 1870</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Keokuk, Moses</term>
<term>Wiley, Albert</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Kansas</term>
<term>Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Wiley, Albert</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Keokuk, Moses</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Christian, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Nevison</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Rigg</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fonte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Kingman, C.F.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Douglas District Court</orgName> 
<placeName>Douglas County, Kansas</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="sab">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0116.032"/>

<p>67</p>
<p>WILEY V. KEOKUK</p>

<p>asked laid down a much more limited rule, and consequently ought not to have been given.</p>
<p>4. On a motion for a new trial it was insisted that the verdict was against the law and the evidence; and two reasons are urged in support of the position: First, that the evidence did not show a state of facts that would authorize a recovery against Wiley. Let us see: Wiley was agent for the Sac and Fox Indians, of which the tribe Keokuk was chief. Com'r Mix had directed that no delegation from any of the tribes should visit Washington, as there was no appropriation to pay their expenses. This letter, as was one from Supt. Murphy, was read by Wiley to Keokuk and others on the sixteenth of November Keokuk and four others of the tribe started for Washington, without license so to do. They were overtaken by Wiley, at Lawrence, on the next day. Wiley on that day went before a United States commissioner for the district of Kansas, and made a complaint in writing, under oath, charging "that Keokuk, a Sac and Fox Indian of the Sac and Fox Reserve, in the county of Franklin, in the district and state of Kansas, did on the twenty-second of November, 1868, leave said reserve, and did disobey the orders of the United Staes commissioner of Indian affairs, and the [*109] order of other agents of the United States to him *given," and asking that Keokuk be apprehended and dealt with according to law. On this affidavit a warrant was issued, and Keokuk arrested by the United States marshal and brought before the commissioner. Wiley employed counsel, and testified in the case; and thereupon the  the commissioner decided that Keokuk should give bail for his appearance at the next term of the United States court for the district of Kansas, and directed the marshal to take him into custody. Keokuk refused to give bail, and was taken to jail, and kept there till he was released upon habeas corpus. This is a sufficient outline of the testimony in the case to understand what is deemed necessary to say on the point under consideration. The complaint made by Wiley charges no offense on the part of Keokuk; neither did the warrant or mittimus describe any offense known to he law. The substance of the complaint is stated above, and the warrant and mittimus generally follow it; though in this case the mittimus is more verbose, as though the commissioner felt it necessary to say something more than that Keokuk had left the reserve and was traveling to Washington, to justify his act in sending him to jail. Still, no offense is charged known to any system of law of which we have any knowledge. The facts are so barren as not to lay the foundation for jurisdiction. The affidavit, warrant, and mittimus afford ample evidence that no criminal charge was preferred or passed upon, nor a sufficient pretense of one to challenge judicial discretion; and this conclusion sweep away the ground on which the decisions rested, to which the plaintiff in error refers in his brief.</p>
<p>The second reason urged why the verdict should have been [*110] set aside is that "the plaintiff below was an Indian, *and as such was subject to the power and right of the United</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
