<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0241.033"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Typed Submission to Court</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>

<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0241.033</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Typed Submission to Court</title>
<date when="1885-08-25">August 25, 1885</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1885-07">July 1885</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Brown, E.M.</term>
<term>Campbell, A.</term>
<term>Dolan</term>
<term>Frances</term>
<term>Hoppe, Ernest</term>
<term>Kelly</term>
<term>Lockwood, Henry</term>
<term>Miller, F.C.</term>
<term>Reich</term>
<term>Walker, Charles</term>
<term>Walker, Helen</term>
<term>Walker, M.A.</term>
<term>Ward, G.A.</term>
<term>Whittem</term>
<term>Wintermute</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term>Port Townsend</term>
<term>Tacoma, Pierce County, Washington Territory</term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Walker, M.A.</persName>
<persName>Walker, Charles</persName>
<persName>Walker, Helen</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Campbell, A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court For The Western District of Washington Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="#sab">transcribed, encoded</change> 
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0241.033"/>

<p>4</p>
<p>1601 1/2</p>

<p>At 10:20 a.m., yesterday morning, the preliminary hearing in the case of The Territory vs. M.A. Walker, et. al, was continued before Justice Campbell. The defense introduced its witnesses.</p>
<p>The first witness was Jailor G.A. Ward, who testified to accompanying Mrs. Helen, Walker, one of the defendants, to her house, to secure some clothing.</p>
<p>Mrs. Frances Foresting testified that she was the mother of Mrs. Helen Walker; and that she was at the residence on the morning of the 15th. She then named those persons who were present at that time, and what was done there. She said: We had beer there and drew in from the keg into a tin bucket, which stood on the table, and from this the beer was poured into the glasses; neither Mrs. Whittem, the little girl or he s lf drank any beer; the others drank from seven to eight glasses; the parties went away about 12 o'clock; M.A. Walker was not present at the party; he was at Port Townsend with Harry Lockwood; he came in that evening about ten minutes after the party had left; he mu <del></del> ave arrived at the house before the Hunters reached home; when Walker arrived Mrs. Walker, Charles and myself were sitting up and smoking; none of us had gone to bed; no person went in or went out of the house after M.A. Walker came up.</p>
<p>Cross-examined: M.A. Walker went to Port Townsend with Harry Lockwood; said where he was going before he started, but did not say how long he would be gone; he said he intended to stay if he got work; he did not know how long he would be gone, as he expected to get work; did not expect him that night; the party left about 12 o'clock; we had not time-piece; Mrs. Whittem left before the others; bade her good-night; the rest of the party all started together; we said "good-bye" to each other; Lockwood spoke to my daughter, saying if he was locked out he would like to come back and stay all night; saw A.M. Walker about ten minutes after the party left; we did not stay up longer than ten minutes; eat and smoked; Mrs. Hunter and Mrs. Walker went to the spring about twenty minutes before the party got ready to leave, and returned just before Mrs. Whittem left; we have no clock; I guessed at the time; would estimate Walker's return to have been ten minutes after; we all sat down by the stove and talked over his visit to Port Townsend;  it was about 12 o'clock wehn he came in; we talked about the party, saying we ahd a good time; Walker did not ask who was there; told him Mrs. Walker had said Lockwood could come back if locked out at home; Charles Walker lives with us; A.M. and Charles Walker saw wood and play the fiddle; Charles is a foundryman and steam fitter; have not been at jail, and was not allowed to talk with defendants; I heard no unusual noise that night; there were no Jogs at the house that night; heard no barking; Lockwood did not come back to the house; have been acquainted with Lockwood for about nine months; he used to come into the house at times and lay down; one morning at 5 o'clock he came in, lay down and got warm; there is a path leading up the bank near  the house; do not know whether a person could pass the road, and might come up the bank; know the path was used; it is too steep to permit of my going up and down the bank ; my daughter has gone up and down the bank path; never heard of any trouble between Lockwood and Walker; would be likely to have heard of it if there had been any; Lockwood has said that he thought as much of Si, (that is the name by which we call M.A. Walker), as though he were a brother, and Walker often said the same of Lockwood; know of no trouble occurring between Walker and his wife; on that morning (16th) was awake, and heard the engine stop at about 2 o'clock; they were all in bed at this time, and had been in bed about an hour and a</p>
<p>half; heard no noise excepting the stopping and starting of the engine; there was not a great while between the stopping and starting of the engine; heard Kelly call, and describe the man and the dog; the daughter asked what kind of a man; Kelly described the dog; Mrs. Walker woke up her husband and said she thought it must be Lockwood; I am sure she woke up her husband; Charles slept tight; they wanted me to go down and look at the body, but I did not want to go down; they (the Walkers) dressed hastily and went down, the time elapsing between walking and going down being five or six minutes; Walker went down town tat morning and told Lockwood's friend <unclear></unclear> (L's) being unover; Mrs. Walker stand at the house; she explained to me how Lockwood had been run over, saying he was al <unclear></unclear> I did not want to see the body; heard Kelly's first call, and then second call; my daughter awoke and answered; the Walker house is about 12x14 feet; there are two beds at it these trunks, one stove; there was one set of dancers on the floor at one time; there was room enough for one <del></del> trunk and the small bedstead had been put outside the house to make room; Charles slept on the floor; Lockwood was cheerful when he went away; did not think he had drank to excess; talked with defendants about the matter before they were arrested; we were all sorry it had happened; heard no voice on the track before the engine stopped;; heard it coming; it might be that I could not have heard voices if talking on the track; Mrs. Whittem went away before the rest of the party; she carried a lantern; the other party had one lantern which I gave them myself, as it was one I borrowed from the Dolans; the ladies of the Dolan party came together, at about 8 o'clock, the men came about half an hour afterwards; after the party, when M.A. Walker came, I was talking to Charles; Mrs. Walker had been straightening out things after the party was over, and then she sat down with us and smoked; we all smoked; smoked two pipes before retiring; can smoke two pipes out in less time than ten minutes; went to bed within twenty minutes after Walker's arrival; know there are 60 seconds in a minute; do not know how many minutes there are in an hour; in stating the time which elapsed I have given it according to my judgement; am not very familiar with Mrs. Walker's handwriting; I might know it if I saw it [here witness was shown a slip of paper containing some written matter;] that is not her handwriting; am positive of it; have seen her handwriting.</p>
<p>Mrs. Whittem called: On the night of the 16th of July I went to Walker's between 6 and 7 o'clock, which is half an hour fast; it was 12:30 actual time when I reached my house; left Walker's about fifteen minutes pas 12 o'clock.</p>
<p>Cross-examined: Have not talked with any one in regard to matters connected with this trial since I was a witness yesterday; my memory is good except when I am frightened.</p>
<p>Dr. Reich was called to testify as to his opinion of the blood-stained cloths.</p>
<p>The court then took a recess till 1:30 p. m.</p>
<p>At 1:30 o'clock the court reconvened.</p>
<p>Dr. Reich was recalled and cross-examined.</p>
<p>Dr. F.C. Miller, Dr. E.M. Brown and Dr. Wintermute were then called and testified in regard to the cloths found.</p>
<p>Dr. Miller cross-examined: Saw body of Lockwood at undertaker's; the wound in forehead had a three-cornered appearance, and looked as if made by some blunt instrument, or by striking; heard Thompson's testimony in court; saw the wounds on body, except <unclear></unclear> in back of the head; saw <unclear></unclear> it remarked that it looked  as though the head had been struck by a blunt instrument, and spoke about the clothes on the body not showing much blood; either there was good drainage, or else the body was not bleeding touch; theirs were no indications of the <unclear></unclear> been dragged; it would have been possible for the body to have fallen in the position found in; a drunken man could fall so, and the body could so say along-ide the wrack; examined the place where the man was killed; it might be possible for the body to have fallen in the position found in; a drunken man could fall so, and the body could so day alongside the wrack; examined the place where the man was killed; it might be possible for a man to be thrown into the position indicated by being struck by an engine; body was in an unnatural position.</p>
<p>This closed the testimony for defense, and of the evidence of the preliminary hearing.</p>


<p>Territory of Washington 
County of Pierce} ss</p>
<p>M.A. Walker being first duly sworn says that he has heard the foregoing statements read, knows the contacts thereof, and that the sauce contain the substance of all the testimony taken before A. Campbell. Esq. Justice of the peace in &amp; for Pierce County, Wash. Terr. on its 21. 22. and 23rd days of July, 1885. at the preliminary examination of <unclear></unclear> charged with the mender of Wm Lockwood</p>
<p>MA Walker</p>
<p>subscribed and swoon &amp; before me this 25th day of August 1885.</p>
<p>Ernst <unclear>Hoppe</unclear>
Astary <unclear>Prsblier</unclear>, Pierce Con. W.T.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
