<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0268.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ernest Hutchinson v. City of Seattle. Petition.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Tecca, Lauryn" xml:id="lnt">Lauryn Tecca</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0268.001</idno>
<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ernest Hutchinson v. City of Seattle. Petition.</title>
<date when="1904-04-12">April 12, 1904</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1904-04-12">April 12, 1904</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Battle Creek, Michigan</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hutchinson, Ernest</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>City of Seattle</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Carroll, Carroll A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C.H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> 
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#lnt">transcribed and encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>  

<body>
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT OF THE NINTH CIRCUIT IN AND 
FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of 
Ernest Hutchinson
for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>To the Honorable C.H. Hanford, Judge.</p>  

<p>The petition of Ernest Hutchinson respectfully represents to your honor.</p>

<p>I.</p>
<p>Your petitioner is a citizen of the United States, and of the 
State of Michigan, having his home and domicile in the city of Battle 
Creek in the State of Michigan, where he is engaged in the business
of general <del>advertising</del> merchandising and <del>merchandising</del> advertising and in manufacturing for and
selling to the trade in the Unites States "Buyer's Stamps", otherwise
called "Trading Stamps".</p>

<p>II.</p>
<p>That your petitioner is a memberof the firm of Hutchinson and 
Hutchinson, doing business under the name and style of "The National
Stamp Co.", and which said company has its principal place of business
in the said City of Battle Creek in said State of Michigan.</p>

<p>III.</p>
<p>That the purposes and objects of said company are:</p>
<p>To buy, sell, and exchange merchandise; to do a general merchandise and 
<del>general</del>advertising business; to print, issue and circulate advertisements;
 to make and carry out contracts with corporations and individuals;
 to advertise their business by special and useful devices; to give
merchandise in echange for Buyers' Stamps, commonly known as "Trading 
Stamps" and which said stamps are to be due bills, certificates or
vouchers to be sold by the said company, and to be redeemed by it in 
merchandise, according to it contracts, rules and regulations.</p>

<p>IV.</p>
<p>That said "Buyers' Stamp" is issued by and as a due bill of
said National Stamp Co. and is reduced by said company in exchange
for merchandise at the store or place of business of the said company
 in the City of Seattle or any other city, town or place in the
Unites States where said company has an office or is doing business as aforesaid.</p>
 <pb></pb>   

 <p>V.</p> 
<p>That said stamps of said company are sold to the trade at the
rate of fifty cents and a hundred and are given by the trade or merchant
as a cash discount to each purchaser, one stamp to each ten cents
represented in the purchase and whcih said stamps are redeemed by
said stamp company in merchandise at its place of bsuiness at room
81, Hinckley Block in said city of Seattle; and that said stamps are 
used only as a means of advertising the business of petitioners and
of the merchants using the same, as a medium of co-operation and exchange 
for value.</p> 

<p>VI.</p>
<p>Petitioner attaches hereto and makes part hereof a stamp book
used in the said bisiness of petiutioner marked Exhibit "A", which said
exhibit "A" is for the convenience and information of the people doing
business with said stamp company and the merchants using said stamps and
which said book explains the method of obtaining, using and redeeming
said stamps.</p>

<p>VII.</p>
<p>Petitioner attaches hereto and makes part hereof, marked Exhibit
"B", a true and correct copy of the said ordinance No. 6036, under
which petitioner was apprehended and is now unlawfully deprived of
his liberty, property and constitutional rights.</p>

<p>VIII.</p>
<p>Petitioner attaches hereto and makes part hereof, marked Exhibit 
"C", a true and correct copy of the complaint, filed against petitioner
and upon which he is unlawfully held and deprived of his liberty and 
which said complaint is founded upon said ordiance No. 6036.</p>

<p>Wherefore, your petitioner demurs to said complaint and for cause
of demurrer alleges:</p>
<p>1st: That the information and complaint against petitioner charges no
offense or crime, because</p>
<p>2nd: The said ordinance No. 6036 under which petitioner is deprives</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>of his liberty and upon which said complaint is founded is unconsti-
tutional and void in this, to-wit:</p>
<p>a. That said ordinance is against public policy.</p>
<p>b. That said ordinance is in restraint of trade and commerce between
the people of this State.</p>
<p>c. That said ordinance is in restraint of Inter-State trade and
commerce</p>
<p>d. That said ordinance is special legislation and wrongfully, unlawfully
 and unreasonably discriminates against the lawful business affairs of petitioner. </p>
<p>e. That said ordinance unlawfully, wrongfully and unconstitutionally
deprives petitioner of his liberty and right to fully contract and 
carry on lawful business, trade and commerce. </p>
<p>f. That said ordinance unlawfully, wrongfully and unconstitutionally
prohibits and restrains petitioner from engaging in lawful business
and takes away and destroys property without due process of law.</p>
<p>g. That said ordinance imposes an unreasonable and unjust burden
upon petitioner and upon trade and commerce, and is in violation of 
his constitutional rights.</p>
<p>h. That said ordinance is in violation of the Constitution of the
State of Washington and of the United States; and that the City Council
of the City of Seattle has no power or authority to enact said ordinance
 and the legislation of the State of Washington has not given
and cannot give such power or authority to said city council or any
city council.</p>
<p>i. That said ordinance impairs and interferes with petitioner's right
to engage in lawful business.</p>
<p>j. That said ordinance unlawfully interferes with petitioner's right
to engage in lawful business.</p>
<p>k. That said ordinance is oppressive, discriminating, prohibitory
and unreasonable. </p>

<pb></pb>

<p>IX.</p>
<p>That your petitioner is unlawfully restrained of his liberty by 
the Chief of Police, Seattle, at the City Hall
in the said City of Seattle. </p>

<p>X.</p>
<p>That said Chief of Police, Seattle, pretends to and does
hold petitioner a prisoner and unlawfully deprives and restraines
petitioner of his liberty and constitutional rights under and by virtue
of a pretended complaint and judgment based upon said unconstitutional 
and void ordinance, No. 6036.</p>

<p>Your petitioner therefor prays that a Writ of Habeas Corpus may
issue, directed to the said Chief of Police, Seattle, commanding
him that he have the body of the said Ernst Hutchinson by him imprisoned 
and detained, together with the time and cause of said imprisonment
and detetion, before Hon. C.H. Hanford, Judge of aforesaid Court,
at the United States Court, cor. 4th Ave. and Marian St., in the City
of Seattle, County of King, State of Washington, at on the 
day of 1904, to do and receive what shall then and
there be considered or ordered concerning the said Ernst Hutchinson,
in pursuance of the statute in such case made and provided.</p>
<p>Dates this 12th day of April A.D. 1904</p>

<p>Carrol A. Carroll</p>
<p>Attorneys for Petitioner</p>

<pb></pb>



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>