<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0116.029"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Wiley v. Keokuk. Kansas Reports</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0116.029</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Wiley v. Keokuk. Kansas Reports</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1870-01">January 1870</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Allen</term>
<term>Beardmore</term>
<term>Bruce</term>
<term>Carrington</term>
<term>Crunchley</term>
<term>Harvey</term>
<term>Hewlett</term>
<term>Horne</term>
<term>Huckle</term>
<term>Keokuk, Moses</term>
<term>Leeman</term>
<term>Marrest</term>
<term>Mix, Charles E.</term>
<term>Money</term>
<term>Rawlins</term>
<term>Wiley, Albert</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Kansas</term>
<term>United States</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Wiley, Albert</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Keokuk, Moses</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Christian, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Nevison</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Rigg</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fonte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Kingman, C.F.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Douglas District Court</orgName> 
<placeName>Douglas County, Kansas</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="sab">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0116.029"/>

<p>64</p>
<p>KANSAS REPORTS</p>
<p>The action is ex delicto, for a tor, a wrong, or injury to the person, wherein we claim exemplary damages, on the ground that there was malice and oppression in the trespass complained of. Wiley admits in his answer that he made the affidavit that caused the plaintiff to be arrested; that he gave evidence against him on the examination. He employed counsel to prosecute for the alleged offense on the preliminary farce, and before the district judge on the haveas corpus, and he is liable to respond in exemplary damages. Sedg. Dam. 35. I beg to call attention to a fw cases found in the books where juries, exercising the powers instrusted to them by the law, have rendered verdicts that have stood the test of judicial investigation, and the sanction and approval of mankind. In Beardmore v. Carrington the *jury gave $1,000 damages for six days' detention in a private house. In Huckle v. Money, 2 Wils. 205, the jury gave $300 for six hours' imprisonment. In Leeman v. Allen, Id. 160, the jury gave $300 damages for two hours' restraint on the street and in a private house. In none of these cases was the plaintiff stigmatized by being put into the common prison, like a murderer or thief. In Merrest v. Harvey, 1 Marsh. 139; 5 Taunt. 442, the jury gave $500 damages in trespass; Bruce v. Rawlins, 3 Wils. 61, $500, for searching his house; Grey v. Sir Alexander Grant, 2 Wils. 252, a little assault and battery, $200 were allowed; Hewlett v. Crunchley, 5 Taunt. 277, an arrest, on a false charge, of a few hours, $2,000 damages were allowed. And not one of these cases was set aside as being excessive.</p>
<p>There was no error in the instructions given, and none in refusing those asked by defendant below.</p>

<p>KINGMAN, C.J. The first error alleged occurred in selecting a jury. The juror was challenged for cause, on the ground that he had once already served on a jury as a talesman on the trial of a cause at the same term of the court. The court overruled the challenge. This was error. Civil Code, 270. It appears that after the juror had served as a talesman he had been called to serve as a regular juror for the term, in place of a juror excused. This made no difference. The law remained the same; the challenge should have been allowed. The beneficent objects of the section could not be frustrated by placing a man on the regular panel who cold not serve on a jury if challenged. The object of *the law is to get rid of professional jurors,--a most pestiferous set, as every lawyer knows; and this could not be done away with by a sheriff or court by putting such a juror on the regular panel. The juror was afterwards challenged peremptorily by plaintiff in error, and thus removed from the jury. The record does not show that the defendant exhausted his peremptory challenges. These facts bring the case directly within the ruling of this court in the case of Morton v. State, 1 Kan. 468. "By this means the defendant seems effectually to have relieved himself from the grievances of which he complained," and the case will not be reversed for an error of the court which the party cures by his own action.</p>
<p>2. The next error claimed is that the court erred in the charge to</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
