<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0148.018">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Marie Le Fevre, Yvonne Le Fevre, &amp; Georgette Normand v. M. Angelique. Appeal</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Hidalgo, Emily" xml:id="eh">Emily Hidalgo</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0148.018</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Marie Le Fevre, Yvonne Le Fevre, &amp; Georgette Normand v. M. Angelique. Appeal</title>
<date when="1903">December 10, 1903</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1903-03"></date>March 1903</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Ross</term>
<term>Gilbert</term>
<term>Morrow</term>
<term>Ekiu, Nishimura</term>
<term>Sing, Lem Mon</term>
<term>Yo, Fok Youngs</term>
<term>Yamasaka</term>
<term>Monckton, Frank D.</term>
<term>Ayres, A. Reeves</term> 
<term>Walthew, H.M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>LeFevre, Marie</persName>
<persName>LeFevre, Yvonne,</persName>
<persName>Normand, Georgette</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>M. Angelique</persName>
<persName>Lavin, James P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Gill, H. C.</persName>
<persName>Hoyt, H. B.</persName>
<persName>Frye, Herman S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Cushman, Edward E. </persName>
<persName>Frye, Jesse A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, Cornelius H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>District of Washington, Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#eh">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0148.018"/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT OF APPEALS, 
FOR THE NINTH CIRCUIT.</p>

<p>JAMES P. LAVIN, Immigrants Inspector,
and SISTER M. ANGELIQUE, Sister Superior 
of the House of the Good Shepherd,
Appellants,
vs.
YVONNE LE FEVRE, GORGEETTE NORMAND,
and MARIE LE FEVRE,
Appellees.}
</p>

<p>No.948.</p>

<p>Appeal from the United States Circuit Court for the District
of Washington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>Habeas corpus proceedings were instituted by counsel on behalf
of the appellees in the Superior Court of the State of Washington
for King County, alleging their illegal detention at Seattle 
by the appellant Sister Superior M. Angelique of the House of 
the Good shepherd, said detention being by authority and request
of the appellant James P. Lavin, United States Immigrant Inspector,
After the service of the writ of habeas corpus upon the Sister Superior,
the appellants petitioned the United States Circuit Court
for the District of Washington, Northern Division, for the removal
of the proceedings to the Circuit Court. Thereupon a writ of certiorari 
was issued to the State Court, and the proceedings removed
to the Federal court.</p>

<p>Thereafter, the appeallants made a return and answer to the 
petition for habeas corpus, showing that the appellant James P.

1.

<pb/>

Lavin was a revenue officer and immigrant inspector for the Collection 
District of Puget Sound; that the appellees were natives
of the Republic of France; that the appellant Lavin had theretofore,
in the discharge of his duties as such officer, removed the 
appelles from the steamship "Rosalie" upon its arrival at Seattle 
from Victoria, British Columbia, from which port they had been 
brought to Seattle; that said removal was for the purpose of investigating
whether they were immigrants properly entitled to enter
the United States; that a board of special inquiry was convened,
consisting of the treasury and revenue officers, in accordance
with the law and the regulations of the Treasury Department, to 
determine the eligibility of the appellees to land in the United
States; that upon such investigation it had been found and determined 
that appellees had, within one year prior thereto, been imported
into the United States at the port of New York form France,
for the purpose of prostitution; that it had been further found
and determined that each of them was a pauper and likely to become
a public charge; that it had been further found that immediately
prior to their having been taken and removed from said vessel;
that upon such findings it had been determined that concluded by 
said board that the appellees were not lawfuly entitled to be in 
or enter the United States, and that they should be deported and
returned to the country to which they belonged and from whence
they came. Thereafter the facts and findings of said board of 
special inquiry were forwarded to the Secretary of the Treasury 
for the purpose of having the question of the country and port to 
which the appellees should be deported and returned, detemined by 

2.

<pb/>

said Secretery; that while said question was pending before the 
Secretary of the Treasury, the court made an order and judgment,
finding the facts and causes of detention of the appellees by the 
appellants as set forth in the return, and finding further that
the only action warranted by the goverment and its officers upon 
the facts found was the deportation and return of the appellees to 
Victoria, British Columbia, at the expense of the steamer bringing 
them to this country; and thereupon the court entered an order and 
judgment according.Thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury 
issued his warrant, directing the appellees James P. Lavin, Immigrant 
Inspector, to arrest the appellees and remove them to the 
port of New York for deportation to France. Upon the receipt of 
said warrant the appellant made a supplemental return, showing
the fact of the issuance of such warrant, and petitioned the court
to modify its order and judgment by striking out so much thereof 
as required the appellant to return the appellees to the steamship
that brought them to Seattle, "to be by said vessel at its own expense
returned to Victoria, British Columbia", leaving the appellant 
Lavin free to carry into effect the warrant of the Secretary 
of the Treasury. Upon a hearing upon this supplemental return and 
petition, the court found that the appellees had only been temporarily 
removed from the steamer bringing them to Victoria, for the 
purpose of examination as to their fitness as immigrants by the 
Treasury officials, and that the only action warranted under the 
law was the refusal to the appellees of the right to land in this 
country, and the only country to which they could be lawfully returned 
upon the refusal of the right to land was the country from
which they has come immediately prior to such rejection, to wit, 
to British Columbia. The court found that the appellees, not having 
landed in this country, and not having been found here, were 
not subject to deportation by warrant of the Secretary of the 

3.

<pb/>

Treasury to the county to which they belong and from which they 
originally came, to writ, France. The court thereupon denied the 
petition for a rehearing and modification of the judgment, and ordered 
and directed the appellant James P. Lavin, Immigrant Inspector, 
to carry into effect the original order and judgment of 
this court. From these orderes and judgments the present appeal is
prosecuted by the United States Attorney, for and in behalf of the 
Immigrant Inspector and the Sister Superior of the House of the 
Good Shepherd.</p>

<p>Jesse A. Frye, U.S. Attorney, and Edward E. Cushman, Assistant 
U.S. Attorney, for the Appellants.</p>

<p>H.C. Gill, H.B. Hoyt, and H.S. Frye, Attorneys for the 
Appellees.</p>

<p>Before GILBERT, ROSS, and MORROW, Circuit Judges.</p>

<p>MORROW, Circuit Judge, delivered the opinion of the court;</p>

<p>The errors relied upon by the appellants are; First, that
the question of the deportation of the appellants was within the 
judgment and the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Tresury,
and not within the jurisdiction of the Circuit Court. Second, 
that after assuming jurisdiction, the court erred in determining,
contrary to the determination of the Secretary of the Tresury, 
that the appellees should be return to British Columbia, and not 
to France.</p>

<p>The court below found the cause of the detention of the appellees

4.

<pb/>

to be as set forth in the return of the appellants to the 
writ of habeas corpus. This retun showed that the executive officers
of the Goverment had upon investigation determined that 
the appellees were alien immigrants, and belonged to a class of 
persons excluded by law from coming to the United States; that upon 
such investigation it was found and determined that said immigrants
had within one year prior thereto been imported into the 
United States at the port of New York from France, for the purposes
of prostitution; that each of them was liable to become a public
charge; that immediately prior to being taken from the vessel 
that brought them to Seattle they had left the United States and 
gone to Victoria, from which place they were returning to the 
United States.</p>

<p>The deportation of alien immigrants of the class to which 
appellee belongs, in provided for in Sections 10 and 11 of the Act
of March 3, 1891 (26 Stats. 1086), as follows:</p>

<p>"That all aliens who may unlawfully come to the United
States shall, if practicable, be immediatly sent back on the vessel 
by which they were brought in. The cost of their maintenance 
while on land, as well as the expense of the return of such aliens,
shall be borne by the owner or owners of the vessel on which such 
aliens came."</p>

<p>"That any alien who shall come into the United States in 
violation of law may be returned as by law provided, at any time 
within one year thereafter, at the expense of the person or persons,
vessel, transportation company, or corporation bringing such 
alien into the United States, and if that cannot be done, then at 
the expense of the United States."</p>

<p>5.</p>

<pb/>

<p>The supplemental return of the Immigrant Inspector shows
that the Secretary of the Tresury had issued his warrant directing 
the Immigrant Inspector to arrest the appellees and remove 
them to the port of New York for deportation to France. it has 
been repeatedly held that the excutive officers of the Goverment
have exclusive jurisdiction to determine the right of an alien immigrant
to land and come into the United States. Nishimura Ekiu
v. United States, 142 U. S. 651, 660; Lem Mon Sing v. United
States, 158 U.S. 538; Fok Young Yo v United States, 185 U.S. 296,
305; The Japanese Immigrant Case, 189 U.S. 86. It is equally 
clear that these officers have jurisdiction to carry their judgement 
into execution in the manner provided by law. United States 
v. Yamasaka, 100 U.S. 404. But whether, in deporting an alien 
Immigrant, they are proceeding according to law, is a judicial 
question, and may be inquired into by the court upon writ of habeas 
corpus. The court below had jurisdiction, therefore, upon the 
supplemental return of the Immigrant Inspector, to inquire into the 
legality of the warrant of deportatiom; but we think the findings
of the court that the facts in the retun, disposed of the question. If the 
appelles were alien immigrants who had been imported into the port 
of New York from France within one year, and their absence from the 
United States just prior to their arrival at Seattle was only 
temporary, as the finding of facts indicates, them their deportation 
to France would appear to be, under the circumstances, according to 
law.</p>

<p>The judgment of the Circuit Court is modified, with instructions
to vacate its order of deportation, discharge the writ
of habeas corpus, and remand the appellees to the custody of the 
Immigrant Inspector.
(ENDORSED;) Opinion. Filed November 2, 1903, F.D. Monekton, Clerk.</p>

<pb/>

<p>I, Frank D. Monckton, clerk of the United States Circuit Court of Appeals, for the 
Ninth Circuit, do hereby certify the foregoing to be a full, true and correct copy of the 
opinion in the cause entitled James P. Lavin, Immigrant Inspector, 
and Sister M. Angelique, Sister Superior of the House of the Good
Shepherd, Appellants, vs. Yvonne Le Fevre, Georgette Normand, and 
Marie Le Fevre, Appellees, No. 948, as the same remains of record 
in my office.</p>

<p>ATTEST any hand and the seal of said Circuit Court of Appeals, at San Francisco,
Californi, this 10th day of December A.D.  1903</p>

<p>F.D. Monekton, Clerk.</p>

<figure></figure>

<pb/>

<p>united Sttes Circuit Court 
of Appeals
For the Ninth Circuit</p>

<p>Jas P. Lavin
vs. 
Yuonne Le Fevre</p>

<p>Opinion U.S. G
G. of appeals</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U.S. Circuit Court, 
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JAN 7 1904
A.REEVES AYRES, Clerk
HMSStatiherd Deputy</p>

<p>Clerk</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>