<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0150.001.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>George Hawkins v. The United States of America. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J" xml:id="sjs">Salma Silva</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0150.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">George Hawkins v. The United States of America. Petition</title>
<date when="1902-11-05">November 5, 1902</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1902-11">November 1902</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Daniel, Reese P.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Alaska</term>
<term>Washington</term>
<term>McNeil's Island, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hawkins, George</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>The United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Fenton, James E.</persName>
<persName>Grigsby, Melvin</persName>
<persName>Allen, John B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Wood, Joseph K.</persName>
<persName>McGinn, John L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
<persName>Moyes, Arthur H.</persName>
<persName>Morro, William W.</persName>
<persName>Fuller, Melville W.</persName>
<persName>Moore, Alfred S.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The United States Circuit Court</orgName>
<placeName>District of Washington, Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<ab>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT, IN AND FOR THE DISTRICT OF 
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</ab>

<ab>In the Matter of the Application of George Hawkins for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</ab>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE C.S.HANFORD, JUDGE OF THE ABOVE ENTITLED COURT.
The petition of George Hawkins respectfully shows to your Honor;</p>

<ab>I.</ab>

<p>That he is now imprisoned and restrained of his liberty by the
Warden of the United States Penitentiary at McNeil's Island in the State
of Washington;</p>

<ab>II.</ab>

<p>That the cause of pretense of the restraint of your said petitioner,
according to the best of the knowledge and belief of the petitioner,
is as follows;- That on the 23rd day of January, A.D. 1901. your
said petitioner was indicted by the Grand Jury in and for the Second
Division, District of Alaska, for the crime of robbery, a certified copy
of which said indictment is hereto annexed, marked "Exhibit A" and made
a part of this petition.</p>

<ab>III></ab>

<p>That thereaftr such proceedings were had and taken in the said
United States District Court in and for the District of Alaska, Second
Division, upon said indictment that the said petitioner was tried upon
and convicted of the charge contained in said indictment, and thereafter
such proceedings were had and taken in the said United States District
Court in and for the District of Alaska, Second Division, that your said
petitioner was by the judgment of the said United States District Court.
in and for the District of Alaska, Second Division, sentenced to be confined
in the United States Penitentiary at McNeil's Island, in the State
of Washington, for a period of fifteen years; that thereafter such proceedings
were had and taken in said United States District Court, in and
for the District of Alaska, Second Division, upon the said judgment and
sentence that the Honorable Arthur H. Moyes, Judge of the United States
District Court, in and for the District of Alaska, Second Division, issued</p>

<pb/>

<p>a committment upon said judgment and sentence, a certified copy of which
committment is hereto annexed, marked "Exhibit B" and made a part hereof.
That thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in the said United 
States District Court, in and for the District of Alaska, Second Division,
that said petitioner prosecuted a writ of error from that said judgment
and sentence to the United States Circuit Court of Appeals, in and for
the Ninth Circuit; that thereafter such proceedings were had and taken
in the said United States Circuit Court of Appeals that an application
was made for and on behalf of your said petitioner to have your said
petitioner admitted to bail pending the hearing and determination of the 
cause of your said petitioner upon said writ of error in the said Circuit
Court of Appeals; that thereafter such proceedings were had and taken
upon said application to have your said petitioner admitting to bail, that
the Honorable Wm. W. Morrow as Circuit Judge, and one of the Judges of
the said Circuit Court of Appeals, made an order in the said cause of
your said petitioner then pending in the said Circuit court of Appeals
upon said writ of error, that a supersedeas be granted therein and that
your petitioner furnish or cause to be furnished a bond in the sum
of Five Thousand Dollars, conditioned according to law, subject to the
approval of the United States District Judge for the District of Washington,
or the Judge or acting Judge of the District Court for the
District of Alaska, Second Division, and that upon the approval of said
bond your said petitioner be admitted to bail pending the determination
of said writ of error, or until the further order of the said United
States Circuit Court of Appeals; that thereafter such proceedings were
had and taken in the said United States Circuit Court of Appeals that
the sad bond of your said petitioner was reduced to the sum of Three
Thousand Dollars, conditioned as aforesaid and to be approved as aforesaid;
<del>and</del> but your said petitioner alleges that by reason of his being without
friends and unacquainted in the State of Washington, he was unable to
furnish the said bond pending the determination of his said cause upon
said writ of error; that therafter such proceedings were had and taken
in the said United States Circuit Court of Appeals, upon said indictment,
and upon record in said cuase, that the said United States Circuit Court</p>

<pb/>
<p>of Appeals did on the 5th day of June, A.D., 1902, reverse the said
judgment and sentence and remand the said cause for a new trial; that
thereafter such proceedings were had and taken in the said cause upon
said indictment, that the said Circuit Court of Appeals issued a mandate
in said cause, a certified copy of which said mandate is hereto annexed,
marked "Exhibit C" and made a part hereof, which said mandate from the
Circuit Court of Appeals in the said cause was filed with the Clerk of 
the United States District Court, in and for the District of Alaska,
Second Division, on the 31st day of July, 1902, that thereafter such proceedings
were had and taken in the said United States District Court, in
and for the District of Alaska, Second Division, that on the 14th day of
October, A.D. 1902, the Honorable Alfred S. Moore, Judge of the United
States District Court, in and for the District of Alaska, Second Division,
made an order admitting the said petitioner to bail in the sum of Three
Thousand Dollars, a certified copy of which said order is hereto annexed,
marked "Exhibit D" and made a part hereof; that thereafter such proceedings
were had and taken upon the said indictment in said cause, that on
the 14th day of October, A. D., 1902, the Honorable Alfred S. Moore,
Judge of the United States District Court, in and for the district of
Alaska, Second Division, made an order fixing the said cause upon said
indictment, for trial for the first Monday in September, A.D., 1903. a
certified copy of which said order is hereto annexed, marked "Exhibit E"
and made a part hereof.</p>

<ab>IV.</ab>

<p>That your said petitioner alleges that his said imprisonment
and restraint is illegal, and that said illegality consists in this;</p>

<p>A.-That the said judgment and sentence of the said United States
District Court, in and for this District of Alaska, Second Division,
having been reversed, and your said petitioner having been granted a new
trial by the said United States Circuit Court of Appeals, the said 
committment issued upon the said judgment is illegal, void and of no force
or effect, and in truth and fact your said petitioner is not confined or</p>

<pb/>

<p>imprisoned by the said Warden of the said United States Penitentiary at
McNeil's Island, under and by virtue of any legal or valid process, issued
on any final judgment of a Court of competent jurisdiction.</p>

<p>B.-That your said petitioner has not been granted a speedy trial
upon said indictment, and is deprived of his liberty without due process
of law.</p>

<p>C.-That by reason of your said petitioner's illegal restraint and
confinement in said United States Penitentiary at McNeil's Island, in
the State of Washington, and without the jurisdiction of the said United
States District Court in and for the District of Alaska, Second Division,
your said petitioner has been denied and deprived of the right and opportunity
to procure bail upon said indictment.</p>

<p>D.-That under and according to the laws of the District of Alaska
now in force, the Sureties upon bail after indictment, are required to
qualify and justify before a magistrate of this District of Alaska, and
to make oath among other things that they are residents and inhabitants
of the district of Alaska; and your said petitioner alleges that he is
wholly unacquainted with any of the residents and inhabitants of Alaska
save and except those residing at Nome in the Second Division, District
of Alaska, and that he is without friends or acquaintances in the State
of Washington, and that navigation between McNeil's Island in the State
of Washington, where your said petitioner is now restrained of his
liberty, and Nome, in the district of Alaska, where your said petitioner
could obtain bail, is now closed, and owing to the close of navigation
and the lack of other means of transportation your said petitioner cannot
now be taken to Nome in the District of Alaska for trial upon said indictment
before the 15th day of June, 1903; that by reason of the aforesaid
facts, and by reason of the failure of the United States to comply
with the said mandate of the said Circuit Court of Appeals, and remand
your said petitioner to the said town of Nome in the Second Division,
District of Alaska, for a new trial, your said petitioner has been deprived
of the opportunity to obtain and has been and is unable to obtain
bail upon said indictment; that your said petitioner is in ill health and</p>

<pb/>

<p>unless he is granted his liberty and released from confinement, will be
in great danger of loosing his life.</p>

<p>Wherefor your said petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus may be granted, directed to the
said Warden of the United States
Pentientiary at McNeil's Island, in the State of Washington, commending
him to have the body of your said petitioner before this Honorable Court
at the time and place therein to be specified, to do and receive what
shall then and there be considered by your Honor concerning him, together
with the time and cause of his detention, and the said writ; and that 
your said petitioner may be restored to his liberty and discharged from
custody.</p>

<ab>George Hawkins</ab>
<ab>PETITIONER.</ab>

<ab>James E Fenton</ab>
<ab>ATTORNEY FOR PETITIONER.</ab>

<ab>State of Washington
County of King.</ab>

<ab>ss.</ab>

<p>I, James E. Fenton, being duly sworn says;- That I am the
Attorney of record for the above named petitioner, George Hawkins; that
I have read the foregoing petition, know the contents thereof and the
allegations are true as I verily believe; that I make this verification
in behalf of the said petitioner for the reason that all the material
allegations in the said petition are within my personal knowledge.</p>

<ab>James E Fenton</ab>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 5th day of November, 1902.</p>

<ab>Reese P Daniel</ab>
<ab>Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</ab>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>