<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN
DIVISION</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Petition of K. Gregory, M. Aloshin, I. Riaboff, P, Neanlin, I. Erelin, L.
Orloff, G. Yakimoff, P. Yakimoff, aliens, for a WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>
<p>No. 2646
RETURN TO PETITION AND WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>
<p>TO THE HONORABLE JUDGE JEREMIAH NETERER, JUDGE OF THE ABOVE ENTITLED COURT:</p>
<p>Comes now Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration, at Seattle, now for answer to the Writ of
Habeas Corpus ussued herein, and for answer to the petition filed herein, for said Writ, states as
follows:</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>That he denies each and every allegation set forth in the petition for said writ, save and except
what is herein-after specially admitted.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>That he admits the allegations set forth in the first paragraph of the petition ending at the
words "Commissioner of Immigration".</p>
<p>III.</p>
<p>As to the allegations set forth in the second paragraph, he admits those ending at "twenty years
of age" in line eleven.</p>
<p>As to the rest of the allegations in said paragraph, he
<pb></pb>
has not knowledge or information thereof sufficient to form a belief and therefore denies the same.</p>
<p>IV.</p>
<p>As to the allegations in the third paragraph, he admits those ending at the words "free will" in
line eighteen; and as to the other allegations set forth in said paragraph, he has not knowledge or
information thereof sufficient to form a belief and therefore denies the same.</p>
<p>V.</p>
<p>As to the allegations set forth in the fourth paragraph, he admits those ending at the word
"Russia" in line twenty-three; and as to the matter set forth in line twenty-four of said paragraph,
he has not knowledge and information thereof sufficient to form a belief and therefore denies the
same.</p>
<p>VI.</p>
<p>As to the allegations set forth in the fifth paragraph, he has not knowledge and information
thereof sufficient to form a belief and therefore denies the same.</p>
<p>VII.</p>
<p>As to the allegations set forth in the sixth paragraph, he admits that the petitions were not
held upon process issued by a United States or state court; alleges that there is a valid and lawful
reason for the detention of your petitioners, as hereinafter appears by the affirmative matter set
forth in the seperate answer.</p>
<p>VIII.</p>
<p>As to the allegations set forth in the seventh paragraph, he denies each and every allegation
thereof, save and accept what may be admitted by the matter set forth in the seperate answer
hereinafter appearing.</p>
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>