<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the United States District Court, in and for the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Ching Hing, for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus } No. 2857
Motion</p>
<p>Comes now John J. Sullivan, as attorney for petitioner
Ching Hing, and respectfully prsents to this Hon. Court; that
a petition was presented to this Hon. Court in the month of
October, 1914, praying that a Writ of Habeas Corpus, be issued
alleging that petitioner was confined and imprisoned and restrained
of his liberty and that said restraint was illegal,
and thereupon set out facts in said petition, to bear out his
said statements, adn that said matter coming on for hearing
on the 16th day of Octobfer, 1914, at which time a continuance
was granted by this Hon. Court through Judge Neterer, ordering
a commission to issue to Thomas G. Lewis, of Washington D.C.,
authorizing him to take the depostition of Lewis F. Post, and
Corry M. Stadden, both of Washington, D.C. That said Lewis
F. Post refuses to answer the said interrogaories, wehereupon
an order was directed by the District Court, in and for the
District of Columbnia, commanding Lewis F. Post to show cause
why he should not answer the said interrogatories; that this
matter is now pending, and that petitioner can not present his
case in proper form until this matter is determined, and whereupon
a bond in the sum of Fifteen Hundred (1500) Dollars, to
await any Judgment or Order of this Court upon and in relation
to said application for Writ of Habeas Corpus, now pending in
this Court. This motion is based upon the facts hereinabove 
presented to this Court, and by the records and files in this
Court.</p>
<ab>John J. Sullivan</ab>
<pb/>
<p>State of Washington
County of King } ss</p>
<p>John J. Sullivan, being first duly
sworn, on oath deposes and says: That he is the Attorney for
the Petitioner Ching Hing; that he has read the foregoing 
Motion, and believes the dame to be true and meritorious in
law.</p>
<ab>John J Sullivan</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 2 day of March, 1915.</p>
<ab>Adam Beeler
Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>