<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0176.008.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Marie Miler v. United States of America. Brief.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0176.008</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Mary Miler v. United States of America. Brief.</title>
<date when="1913-05-03">May 3, 1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Adminstration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of
Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno>2457MarieMiler</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-05">May 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Miller</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Bassani, Angelo</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Marchetti, Roger</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Polet, I. G.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Patrosini, Vincent</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>DeBruler, Ellis</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Chadney, William H.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Jackson, California</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Butte, Montana</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Ellis Island, New York</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>San Fransico, California</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Miler, Mary</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wright, Elias A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wright, Sam A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Brockway, E. B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington Judicial Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States, in and for the
Western District of Washinton, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of Marie Miler
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. } No. 2457</p>
<p>Petitioner's Brief.</p>
<p>The petitioner in this case, Marie Miler, was on or
about the 7th day of January,m 1913, arrested under and by virtue
of a warrant issued by the Secretary of Commerce and Labor on
ground that she was a member of one of the classes of aliens
required to be deported under the laws of the United States, to-
wit: That the alien was connected with a house of prostitution
and practiced prostitiution and derived benefits therefrom after
she had entered the United States, such conduct being in violence
of the Act of Congress of Feburary 20th, '07, and amended by the
Act apporved March 26th, 1910. That thereafter said Marie Miler,
on or about January 13th, was givenn a purported
hearing before Thomas M. Fisher, Inspector of Immigration, stationed
at Seattle, Washington. That at said hearing the said
Marie Miler was not represented by counsel, although she had
employed one Roger Marchetti to represent her at that hearing,
and also had paid him a reasonable fee for his services in that
matter, and relying upon his assurance she presumed that all
the proceedings is reference to her examination were regular
and that her rights would be protected by the said Roger
Marchetti.</p>
<p>It appears from the return of the Honorable Ellis 
DeBruller, respondent in this action, that the said Roger Marchetti
did not at said hearing on January 13th, 1913, or at any other
hearing or hearings subsquent thereto appear in behalf of the
said Marie Miler, nor inform her of the fact that he would not
appear, notwithstanding she had paid the said Roger Marchetti
a reasonable fee for his services and had relied upon him to
<pb/>
defend her in said deportation proceeding.</p>
<p>By reason of the foreging this Honorable Court can
readily see that it was utterly impossible for the said
Marie Miler to controvert any of the evidence produced by the Immmigration
officers, upon which they based their findings, as a ground
for ordering her deportation to Austria.</p>
<p>Marie Miler insists, as alleged in her petition, that
the affidavit of Angelo Bassani, I. G. Polet and Vincent
Patrosini are absolutely falso in every particular, and that if
she had had an opportunity of producing evidence to controvert
the said affidavits, it<del><unclear/></del> would have been possible for her to
establish the falsity of each of the said affidavits in their 
entirety, but owing to the fact that the said Roger Marchetti
failed to properly conduct her defense in this case, as aforesaid,
it was impossible for her in said proceeding before Immigration
officers to do so.</p>
<p>It appears from the record that the Immigration officers
did notify Roger Marchetti of the hearing and the record
also discloses his assurances and attitude in reference thereto,
but the record does not show that his failure to appear and his
promises in reference thereto were ever communicated to Marie
Miler, and as a matter of fact they never were, and for that
reason the Immigration officers were at fault and mislead the
said Marie Miler in reference to her rights. The least that 
they could havee done would have been to notify her that her attorney
was not exerting himself in her behalf so that she might
have been enabled to have procured other counsel and this
establish the falsity of the purported affidavits as above stated,
and also introduced evidence which would have proven her innocence
beyond question.</p>
<p>It was not until the 13th of April, 1913, that the
said Marie Miler was informed of the exact status of the proceedings
against her and until after she had employed additional
counsel to sue out the writ of Habeas Corpus in this section, and
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
at which time <add>the</add> order of deportation had already been issued with
directions to the respondent in this case to send her to Ellis
Island, New York, tehre to await her deportation to Austria.</p>
<p>The Court can readily see that owing to this fact it 
was impossible for the petitioner, Marie Miler, to make application
to the Secretary of Commerce and Labor to permit her to
submit additional evidence or permit her to appeal from the decision
of the respondent in this case to his superior, as, in
the meantime, she would have already been sent on her way to
Ellis Island.</p>
<p>On the question of the inability or the prevention of
the alien immigrant from appealing the case,
In re Morrow, 86 Federal, 117,
and also the cause of
Lavin vs. LaFevre, 125 Federal, 693,
are in point. from a careful reading of these cases it would
appear that the statutees regarding immigration and deportation
evidently contemplates to appeal from the subordinate officers to
the Secretary of the proper department, and where she is prevented
from presenting her case to that tribunal <add>of</add> review it does
not seem to be within the intent of Congress that the decision
of the subordinate officers shall be final.</p>
<p>In regard to Agelo Bassani's affidavit, and in fact
the affidavits of all the Italians, Polet, and Petrosini, we think
it no more than a fair statement that this Honorable Court should
carefully consider their contents. The affects of these affidavits 
are unqualifedly denied by Marie Miler throughout her
entire testimony before the Inspectors, and wihtout the assistance
and advice of counsel it would seem that the story, as told by 
Marie Miler and also her husband on their examination, was entirely
trustworthy and entitled to a great deal of weight.</p>
<p>The attention of this Court is especially called to
the affidavit of Angelo Bassani wherein he states that is was
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
not until in May, 1912, that he first met Marie Miler, record
page 32. It appears from the testimony of Marie Miler herself
that affiant had met the said Marie Miler and her husband in Butte
Montana, serval month previous and had advised them at that 
time to come to Seattle, but that they had disregarded his advice and had gone to the State of California instead.</p>
<p>Strenous effort was made on the part of the Inspector
of Immigration at the hearing to establish the fact that Marie
Miler had conducted herslef in an imporper manner in the State
of California and also in Butte, Montana, prior to her arrival
in the State of Washington, but upon the testimony of the alien
herself it appears that she was wholly unable so to do. In
fact, from communications which the Department received from California,
as appears on pages 17-18 of respondent's return to
this writ, that both Mr. Miler and this petitioner were conducting
themselves in a very orderly manner, Mr. Miler being emplouyed
in a mine at Jackson, California, while this petitioner was
engaged in washing for the men employed in the mine. Mr.
William H. Chadney, Immigration Inspector at San Francisco,
Californiam as appears from his letter, pages 17-18 Respondent's
return, made very caregul inquiry in regard to Marie Miler's
conduct while in that State and informed the officers in charge here
that after careful inquiry he was assured that this alien had
conducted herself in a proper and orderly manner while within
that State.</p>
<p>The court will observe throughout all of the
testimony introduced by the Government to establish a case
against Marie Miler, that not one of the witnesses identified
the Petitioner only by the means of a photograph. This is just
for the purpose of calling the Courts attention to the question
of the suffaciency of the identity of the Petitioner in this case.</p>
<fw>No. 4</fw>
<pb/>
<p>One of the Italians, I.G. Polet, who made an
affidavit against the Petitioner, stated that he had onlymet
Marie Miler once, and from his affidavit, (page 33, rec.)
the Court can readily see the circumstances under which that
meeting took place, and can, for itself judge as to whether
it would be possible for anyone under similar circumstances
to identify a person soley from a photograph picture shown
to them some three months later. The same question may be
raised in regard to each and every one of the affidavits 
introduced against the Petitioner. The foregoing, we think,
contains a fair statement of the facts of this case.</p>
<p>To anticipate the chief question which will be
raised by the Hon. Ellis DeBruler in this case will be that
this Court has no jurisdiction to question the findings of
the Secretary of Commerce and Labor entered herein, and that
the findings of such Secretary is conclusive upon this
hornorable Court, <add>but</add> so far as we have been able to determine, a
writ of habeas corpus has never been refused to a petitioner
when it appeared that the Secretary's of Commerce and Labor
findings and order abased thereon were made upon evidence
which was not aqudate to support the Secretary's conclusion,
and that the alien, woing to that fact, was not given a fair
hearing. In the late case of
Zakonaito Vs. Wolf, 33, U.S. Supreme
Court Reporter, 311
the last decision of the U.S. Supreme Court in reference to
the deportation of aliens for the same reason that the
Petitioner in this case has been ordered deported, we find
the following statement: "The findings of the Secretaries
of Commerce and Labor for the deportation of an alien are
not subject to review by the Court, if thee evidence was
aquedate abnd sufficent to support the Secretary's conclusion,
and that alien was given a fair hearing."
<pb/>
from the foregoing statement, it would seem that the
aquedacy and sufficency of the evidence to support the
Secretary's conclusion as to whether the alien was given a 
fair hearing, was considered a judicial question, and would
be inquired into by writ of habeas corpus, as was done in 
the above cited case.</p>
<p>It was announced in the case of
Lavin Vs. Le Fevre, 125 Federal, -693
that the question as to whether the executive officers of the
Government in deporting an alien immigrant are proceeding
according to law, is a judicial question which might be inquired
into under habeas corpus proceedings. We fully realize
that the sufficency and aquedacy of the evidence in this
case might be well considered to be one of fact, but the
regularity of the Secretary's of Commerece and Labor action in
ordering Petitioner deported upon this evidence is one of
law, and can be inquired into by this Court under habeas
corpus.</p>
<p>The question as to whether the alien has been given
a fair hearing is reviewable by the courts as announced in
the case from this judisdiction
DeBruler Vs Gallo, 184 Federal, 566.
With all due respect to the Inspectors of Immigration who
conducted the hearing of the Petitioner in this case, we think
it is not more than fair to staqte that from the record as
produced herein, that this Petitioner has not been given a
fair hearing, is that she has not, at any time, been able to 
introduce any evidence to contradict the perjured affidavits
of the four Italians herein on file, and so, as she alleged
in her petition, <del>and</del> <add>for the</add> writ of habeas corpus that a conspiracy
to get rid of her and acquire her property existed on the
part of her own countrymen who made the affidavits against her.</p>
<fw>No. 6</fw>
<pb/>
<p>To think that if this honorable Court assumes jurisaduction
in this matter, and permits the Petioner to establish the
real facts in regard to the matter, that it will noe be the
Petitioner whom the Immigration Officers would be asking to
deport, but that they will order a wholesale deportation
of the real parties who are actually engaged in the business
which the Petitioner is charge to be engaged in. The
Petitioner desires to call the Courts attention to the case of
Chin Lou Vs. <add>SOC</add> U.S. Page 8
on the question of when a court will assume jurisdiction in
habeas corpus proceedings. We fully realize that this is a 
case which, of course, involves the Chinese Exclusion Act,
but yet, what was said by the Supreme Court of the U.S. in
that case is strictly applicable to this case on the question
as to when a court would, and should assume jurisdiction,
and determine as to whether or not petitioners had had a fair 
opportunity to produce the evidence they desired. We find
this suggestion made by the Court in this case, "if the
Petitioner was not granted a fair opportunity to produce their
evidence, or a fair though summary hearing, the case can 
proceed no futher." Those facts were the foundation of the
jurisdiction of the District Court, and we will admite, for
the sake of argument, that so far as we have been able to 
determine, such seems to be the law in deportation cases,
but we respectfully submit thaqt this court will be justified
in finding that this Petitioner has not had a fair opportunity
to produce the evidence that she desired, not wholly,
perhaps, due to any fault of the Commissioner of Immigration
Inspector until after the order of deportation has issued
from the Secretary of Commerce and Labor. That her attorney,
Roger Marchetti, has failed to produce the evidence which
Petitioner has been ready and willing to produce at all times.</p>
<fw>No. 7</fw>
<p>In the Chin Lou case above, we also find the following 
statement I. "the decision of the department is final",
but that is based wholly on the pre-supposition that the
decision was after a hearing in good faith, although summarily
informed." The Court recognises throughout the entire decision 
that in order to preserve the rights of a citizen, or one who 
is a bona fide resident of this country, although an alien,
that something must be done, and that, in such a case, this
something must be done by the courts, and it naturally
devolves upon them to intervene, as they did in that case.</p>
<p>If, on the hearing for the application for the writ
Marie Miler is unable to satisfy this court that she is not
entitled to reamin in this country, and that the evidence which
she alleges to be false, and in aid of the conspiracy to get
rid of her to acquire her propety, the of course we would
have no reasonable ground for complaint. But, under the
present status of the case, it would seem that she has been 
denied the right and opportunity of protecting her property
and personal rights in this proceeding, and we respectfully
submit that after this court has carefully considered the
Petitioner's application herein, and considered the suffecincy
of evidence and the surrounding circumstances, then in all
fairness to the Petitioner herein, although an alien, that
this honorable court will be justified in finding that she is
entitled to be released, on her application herein.</p>
<ab>Respectfully submitted
Elias A. Wright
Sam A. Wright
atty for petitioner</ab>
<fw>No. 8.</fw>
<pb/>
<p>2x No. 2457</p>
<p>In the
District Court
of the United States
For the Western District
of Washington
Northern Division</p>
<p>In Re Marie Miler
Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Brief</p>
<p>Filed in the 
U.S. District Court
Western Dist. of Washington
May 3 1913
Frank L. Crosby. Clerk.
By EML Deputy.</p>
<p>Elias A. Wright
Sam A. Wright
Attorney for Marie Miler</p>
<p>629-31 Burke Building
Seattle</p>
<pb/>
<p>Service of within Brief
and receipt of copy admitted this 
3rd Day of 
May 1913</p>
<ab>EB Brockway
Attorney for <gap reason="blank"></gap></ab>
<p> We hereby designate Room No. <gap reason="blank"/>
Building
<gap reason="blank"/>
Street
<gap reason="blank"/>, Washington
as the place where all subsequent papers
herein, expect writs and process
may be made upon the <gap reason="blank"/>
herein, and consent that service of all
subsequent papers herein, expect writs 
and process, may be made as the place
hereinabove, designated upon the said
<gap reason="blank"/>
Dated <gap reason="blank"/> 191<gap reason="blank"/>
attorney </p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>