<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0154.007"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0154.007</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">October 14, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date></term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Clifford, Peter A.
Long (Clifford, Williams), Grace E.
Clifford, Alice B.
Burt. J.  J.
White, W. H. 
DeLang, James
Hanford, C. H.
Ayres, A. Reeves
Matthew, H. M.
Herice, Deevnay 
Fuller, Melville W.  
Hopkins, C. B.
Stringer, John
Heade, Matthew H.
Tallman, Boyd J.
Humphreys, William P.
Allison, William B.
Norris, George E.
Huxston, R. I.
Koepfli, C. A.
Brewster, J. M.
Moor, A. N. 
Drake, James C.
Wright, B. O. 
</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Georgetown, King County, Washington
San Francisco, San Francisco County, California
Seattle, King County, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Clifford, Peter A.</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Long (Williams, Clifford), Grace E.
Williams, Herbert O.</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>White, W. H.
Burt, J. J. 
Steiner, G. E.
Sweeney
French
</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>
Humphreys, William P.</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.
Tallman, Boyd J.</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0154.001"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->

<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL CIRCUIT,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner. 
vs
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.</p>

<p>No.
A N S W E R .</p>

<p>Come now the respondents by their attorneys Sweeney and
Steiner and answering petitioner's petition for habeas corpus allege:</p>

<p>That on or about the 20th. day of January, 1904, petitioner,
Peter A. Clifford filed in for the Superior Court of the State of Wash-
ington, for King County in the cause numbered 41727, entitled
"Peter A. Clifford, petitioner, vs Herbert O. Williams and Grace
E. Williams, respondents", praying for a writ of habeas corpis
to bring the body of Alice B. Clifford before said Superior Court
to abide such order as said Court may direct, a copy of which said 
petition is hereto attached marked "Exhibit A", and hereby reffered
to and made a part hereof; that thereupon in response to said petition
a writ of heabeas corpus was issued returnable before the Honorab;e
George E. Norris, one of the judges in the above entitled court.
which said writ is hereto attached and marked "Exhibit B" and is
hereby referred to and made a part hereof; that respondents there-
upon appeared in said action and filed their answer or return to
said petition which said answer or return is hereto attached and
marked "Exhibit C" and is hereby referred to and made a part hereof;
that in obedience to said writ, the body of said Alice B. Clifford
was produced on the 22nd day of Janurary, 1904, before the said Court, where upon the said cause was
referred to by his Honor, George E. Norris to the Honorable Boyd J.
Tallman, also one of the judges of the aforesaid Superior Court, and
continued to January 25, 1904, at which time and place the body of
said Alice B. Clifford was produced before his Honor, Boyd J. Tallan
and a full and complete hearing had on said petition. That
at said hearing, evidence was introduced by the petitioner and re-
spondents and the cause argued at length by counsel for petitioner
and respondents, and at the conclusion of said hearing, the Court,
being fully advised in the premises, made an order sustaining the validity of the decree of adoption; dissolving said
writ of habeas corpus and demanding said infant, Alice B. Clifford to the care,
custody and control of respondents, which said order is hereto at-
tached, marked "Exhibit D" and is hereby referred to and made a
part hereof; that the parties in said cause number 41727 were
identical with the parties in this cause; that the subject matter
in controversy was identical; that the facts at issue in said cause
number 41727 and in this case are identical and that no new facts
have since arisen; that the petition in said cause umber 41727 and 
in this cause are identical with the exception of slight and imma-
terial variations; that the subject matter at issue in this cause
has been and the facts involved were fully and finally adjudicated
in said cause number 41727, by his Honor, Boyd J. Tallman, Judge of
the Superior Court, State of Washington, for King County, and the
status of said infant, Alice B. Clifford was thereby fixed and es
tablished, and the custody of said infant awarded to respondents
herein.</p>

<p>That by reason of said writ of habeas corpus in number
41727 and the proceedings had therein. and the full and final ad-
judication thereof petitioner is estopped from further questioninh
respondents rigt to the custody of said infant, Alice B. Clifford
by reason of said former adjudication.</p>

<p>That respondents claim the rightful custody of the said
infant, Alice B. Clifford by reason of the aforesaid adjudication.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, respondents pray that the writ of habeas corpus
issued herein may be dissolved and the said infant, Alice B. Clifford
be remanded to the custody of respondents.</p>

<p>Further answering the petitioner's petition herein re-
spondents allege:</p>

<p>That on or about the 12th, day of November, 1903, respondenta
petitioned the Superior Court of the State of Washington, for King
County, in cause number 5262, entitled "In the matter of the adoption
of Alice B. Clifford, an infant, by Herbert O. Williams and Grace
E. Williams, his wife, "for permission to adopt said child, Alice B.
Clifford as their own. That thereafter, such proceedings were had
that a decree of adoption was entered by said Supreme Court adjudging
thatfrom and after said date, said infant, Alice B. Clifford should
to all legal intents and purposes, be the child of petitioners
respondents herein the same as if she had been born to them in
lawful wedlock, and that the name of said child be changed to Alice
B. Williams, a copy of which decree is hereto attached and marked
"Exhibit E", which decree is hereby referred to and made a 
part hereof, and by virtue of which respondents have the custody 
of said infant now known as Alice B. Williams, and claim to be her
rightful custodians.</p>

<p>Respondents further allege that petitioner did on or about
the 5th, day of June, 1904, file a petition in said cause number 5262,
praying that the decree of adoption therein made and entered be
set aside and held for naught, which said petition is now pending in 
said Superior Court.</p>

<p>Further answering the petitioner's petition herein re-
spondents hereby refer to and make a part hereof their said answer
in said cause number 41727, attached hereto and marked "Exhibit C",
as fully and completely as if said answer was here repeated.</p>

<p>Wherefore, having fully answered petitioner's petition,
respondents pray that the writ of habeas corpus heretofore issued
herein be dissolved and said infant, be remanded to the custody of
respondents and that said respondents be awarded their coats here-
in.</p>

<p>Sweeney Steiner
Attorneys for respondents</p>

<p>United States of America, )
District of Washington, ) SS.
Northern Division. )</p>

<p>Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams being first duly
sworn on oath, depose and say: that they are the respondents in the
above entitled cause; that they have read the foregoing answer, know
the contents thereof and the same is true. </p>

<p>Herbert O. Williams
Grace E. Williams
Subscribed and sworn to before me this 10 day of June, 1904.
G. E. Steiner
Resides in Seattle, WA the Notary Public, residing Seattle Wash</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>