<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>United States District Court
Western District of Washington
Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus for
Gwoo Shee Ah Look. } No. 2647
Filed April <gap reason="blank"/>, 1914.</p>
<p>Wilbur &amp; Spencer of Portland, Ore.,
A. L. Clark, or Portland Ore.,
Jesse A. Frye, of Seattle, Wash., 
For Petitioner.</p>
<p>Clay Allen, U.S. District Attorney,
Geo. F. Fishburne, Assistant District Atty. 
For Respondent.</p>
<p>Neterer, District Judge.</p>
<p>A writ of habeas corpus was issued in this case on the 13th 
day of January, 1914, upon the application of the petitioner, to
which return has been made. The return shows that on the 5th day
of November, 1913, a warrant for arrest of Gwoo Shee Ah Look was
issued, and she was taken into custody. It would appear that a 
general raid was made on November 4th, 1913, of the city of Portland
by the police officers of the city, and the petitioner
together with some other women were arrested. A report was
made to the immigration commissioner of the arrest of the petitioner,
and she was taken into custody under the warrant above
stated and given a hearing. On the same day the commissioner
was advised by Mr. Clark, representing the firm of Wilbur &amp;
Spencer, laywers, that they had been retained on behalf of
Gwoo Shee Ah Look, and desired to consult with her. This request 
was denied, as were also the subsquent requests which were
made practically every day until after the 17th day of November when
all of the testimony against the petitioner had been taken, except
that on November 10th a conference was permitted. On the 17th
the attorney for the petitioner was told over the phone to prepare
to present such evidence as he desired by way of affidavits
and the same would be forwarded with the report to the secretary
of labor. At the close of the petitioner's examination on
November 10th, she was advised:</p>
<fw>1.</fw>
<pb/>
<p>"Q. Do you desire to designate any attorney or representative
to appear for you at this hearing. A. I wish to notify Wong
On, Manager of the Kwong Man Yun Comapny in this city. Q. Do 
you know him personally. A. My husband knows him, I do not
know him."</p>
<p>This party was not advised, nor was counsel for petitioner
permitted to be persent at this hearing. <add>The petitioner does not
understand nor speak English.</add></p>
<p>The record discloses that the order of deportation was based
upon the testimony of two policemen who made the raid, which testimony
shows that they had the petitioner under surveillance for
some two or three weeks, and they had watched the room in which t
she was arrested in this building and had seen men go in and out 
of the room; that on the 



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>