<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0267.006.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>In the Matter of the Application of L.J. Urann for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. Return.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Stapleton-Deno, Zoe L." xml:id="zlsd">Zoe L. Stapleton-Deno</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0267.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">In the Matter of the Application of L.J. Urann for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. Return.</title>
<date when="1905">1905</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington.</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1905-07">July 1905</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>L.J. Urann</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Morris Wolf</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>L.C. Smith</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Vince H. Faben</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Kenneth Mackeeboh</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Ninth Circuit Court of the United States</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#zlsd">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>FORM NO. 282
RETURN ON SERVICE OF WRIT.</p>

<p>United States of America</p>
<p>Western DISTRICT OF Washington ss:</p>
    
<p>I hereby certify and return that I served the annexed Writ of Habeas Corpus
on the therein-named Morris Wolf, agent
of the state of Massachusetts
by handing to and leaving a true copy thereof with Morris Wolf
personally
at Seattle in said District on the 1st day of 
July, A.D. 1905</p>
    
<p>C.B. Hopkins
U.S. Marshal.</p>
    
<p>By Fred M. La<unclear>ihe</unclear></p>
    
<p>Marshal's Fees
Service $2.00
Mileage $0.12
$2.12</p>
    
<p>7-279</p>

<pb/>

<p>FORM NO. 282</p>
<p>RETURN ON SERVICE OF WRIT.</p>

<p>United States of America,
Western District of Washington} ss:</p>

<p>I hereby certify and return that I served the annexed Writ of Habeas Corpus
on the therein named L.C. Smith, Sheriff of 
King County, Washington,
by handing to and leaving a true copy thereof with Oscar Wise, Deputy Sheriff
of King County Washington personally
at Seattle in said District on the 1st day of
July, A.D. 1905</p>

<p>C.B. Hopkins
U.S. Marshal.</p>

<p>By Fred M. La<unclear>ihe</unclear></p>

<p>Marshal's Fees
Service $2.00
Mileage $0.12
              $2.12</p>
<p>7-270</p>

<pb/>

<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE NINTH CIRCUIT,
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of 
L.J. Urann
for a WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>

<p>No. 1313</p>

<p>RETURN.</p>

<p>To the Honorable C.H. Hanford, Judge of the above entitled Court:</p>

<p>Come now L.C. Smith, sheriff of King county, Washington, and 
Morris Wolf, agent of the State of Massachusetts, upon whom were
a served copies of a writ of habeas corpus in the above entitled
matter, and in obedience to said writ make the following return and
show to this honorable court:</p>

<p>That the petitioner L.J. Urann is now in the custody of L.C.
Smith, sheriff of King county, Washington, and that the detention 
of said petitioner is lawful in this:</p>

<p>That said L.C. Smith, sheriff of King county, Washington acting
in the public service and not otherwise, did, on the 1st day of
July, 1905, take into custody the petitioner herein upon a warrant
of arrest issued by Albert E. Mead, governor of the State of Washington,
and directed to Morris Wolf, agent of the State of Massachusetts,
wherein and whereby said Morris Wolf was directed to take
the said L.J. Urann, wherever he might be found in the State of
Washington, and transfer him to the line thereof and return him to
the jurisdiction of the superior court of Suffolk County, Commonwealth
of Massachusetts.</p>

<p>Hereto there is attached and made a part of this return a copy
of said warrant of arrest issued by Elbert E. Mead, governor of the
State of Washington.</p>

<p>Having shown to this honorable court that said petitioner L.J.</p>

<pb/>
<p>Urann is held by due and lawful process, your orators nevertheless
now produce before this honorable court the body of L.J. Urann
in compliance with the direction of writ of habeas corpus, and 
pray this honorable court that said writ be now denied, and that the 
petitioner may be held under said warrant issued by the governor 
of the State of Washington hereinabove referred to.</p>

<p>L.C. Smith
Morris Wolf
Respondents</p>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON,
County of King.} ss.</p>

<p>L.C. SMITH and MORRIS WOLF, being first
first duly sworn, each for himself, and not one for the other, says:
That he is the respondent in the foregoing return; that he has read 
the same, knows the contents thereof, and believes the same to be.</p>

<p>L.C. Smith
Morris Wolf</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before
me, this third day of July, 1905.
Kenneth Mackeeboh
Notary public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at 
Seattle in said state.</p>

<pb/>

<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.
STATE OF WASHINGTON.</p>

<p>Executive Department.</p>

<p>TO ALL TO WHOM THESE PRESENTS SHALL COME GREETING:</p>

<p>WHEREAS, It has been represented
to me by His Excellency WILLIAM L. DOUGLAS Governor of the 
State of Massachusetts that LOUIS L. URANN stands charged in said 
State with the crime of Larceny committed in the County of Suffolk
in said state and is a fugitive from the justice of said State and
has taken refuge in the State of Washington;</p>

<p>AND WHEREAS, the said Governor of the State of Massachusetts
has pursuant to the constitution and laws of the United States demanded
of me that I cause the said Louis J. Urann to be arrested and 
delivered to Morris Wolf, agent authorized to receivedhim into
his custody and convey him back to said State of Massachusetts</p>

<p>AND WHEREAS, said representation and demand are accompanied 
by affidavits, indictments and warrant whereby the said Louis J. 
Urann is charged with the said crime and being a fugitive from the
justice of said State and having taken refuge in the State of Washington,
which are certified by said Governor of Massachusetts to be 
duly authenticated.</p>

<p>NOW THEREFORE, I, A.E. MEAD, Governor of the State of Washington, 
do hereby authorize and empower MORRIS WOLF the agent named 
in said demand to take the said Louis J. Urann wherever he may be 
found in this State, and transfer him to the line thereof at the
expense of The State of Massachusetts.</p>

<p>And I hereby command all civil officers within the said State
of Washington to afford alll needful assistance for the execution of 
this warrant.</p>

<p>IN TESTIMONY WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand
and caused the Seal of the said State to be 
affixed at Olympia, this first day of July, 
A.D. 1905.
(Signed) Albert E. Mead</p>

<p>(SEAL)</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>