<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0088.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0088.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Type of document</title>
<date when="1887">1887</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1887">1887</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McKay, Alice</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, Della</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020-05" who="#lkw">encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#nl">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Mr. JOHN KEEVIN, a witness called on behalf of the respondent after being duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>Q. [Gilman] Where do you reside? A. In Belltown.</p>

<p>Q. How long have you had in your custody this child Mary McKay? A. About five years and three months.</p>

<p>Q. Under what circumstances did she come to you? A. I got her at the sisters.</p>

<p>Q. How did you happen to get her from the sisters? A. Well, the sisters sent word by Mrs. Lattimer if she knew any one--</p>

<p>RONALD: We object.</p>

<p>The COURT: Overruled: exception allowed.</p>

<p>Witness: If she knew any one that would take the child, that would act as a mother and father to the child, that she would guarantee that she would get papers in a few days, and we took the child under that condition.</p>

<p>Q. Did <sic>Mrrs.</sic> McKay ever visit you afterwards? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Well, now, state what occurred when she visited you? A. She came about a week or eight days after we got the young-one, and she was very glad to see the child had a good home. She said I will be here in a week or couple of days and I will leave the papers with you or the Sisters.</p>

<p>Q. Did she consent at that time to your taking the child as your own? A. She said she would leave all the transactions with the Sisters. Then we did not see her again for eight or nine months.</p>

<p>Q. How often did she come after that? A. Well, after that we commenced to have trouble with her.</p>

<p>Q. What trouble? A. Lawsuit.</p>

<p>Q. What was done in that lawsuit? A. I think that was the time.</p>

<p>Q. What was done in that lawsuit? A. The child was given by Judge Greene to us, and we had possession still.</p>

<p>Q. Given by Judge Greene to you? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Have you any children of your own? A. No sir.</p>

<fw>[Keevin, D-EX. <gap/> 21. <gap/> 76--124.</fw>

<pb/>

<p>Q. Given by Judge Greene to you? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Have you any children of your own? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. How do you regard this child? A. Well, I <sic>prvide</sic> for the child the same as my own.</p>

<p>Q. Have you the same affection for it that you would for your own child?</p>

<p>A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. You have had children of your own? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. What are your means Mr. Keevin? A. Well, I work at Mason work, laboring, teaming, sometimes.</p>

<p><sic>ZQ</sic> Are you able to support this child in comfort? A. I consider I am sir.</p>

<p>Q. What are the feelings of the child toward you and Mrs. Keevin? A. Well I expect the child is a good young one.</p>

<p>Q. Is it like other children, the same as your own children would be? A. Yes.</p>

<p>Q. Is Mary going to school? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Where does she go to school? A. To the school in Belltown</p>

<p>Q. Attending the public schools? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know anything about the character of this woman McKay? A. No sir, I do not, only hearsay.</p>

<p>-------0-------</p>

<p>CROSS-EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>Q. [Ronald] You are not the father of this child? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Is it Mrs. McKay's child is it? A. Yes, I suppose  so.</p>

<p>Q. She wants the child, dont she? A. I <sic>gusess</sic> so.</p>

<p>Q. She has asked for it several times? A. Well, I dont know she asked for <sic>iat.</sic></p>

<p>Q. Even had you arrested once for cruelty to the child? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. You say Judge Greene gave it to you? A. Well, he says I was a fit <del>and</del> person to take charge.</p>

<p>Q. Did he not say that he would <del/> not make an order at that time giving the child to the mother, is not that all he said? A. He said she was not fit person, she had no means.</p>

<p>Q. Did he not further say that that woman was to see that child whenever she wanted to and if he ever heard---</p>

<p>A. Yes, he said if she <sic>p</sic> behaved herself as a lady.</p>

<p>Q. Did you ever refuse her after that? A. I did.</p>

<p>Q. What did you refuse her for? A. Because she did not come as a decent woman should come.</p>

<p>Q. How did she come? A. She came drunk.</p>

<p>Q. You are certain of that? A. I am certain of that.</p>

<p>Q. You are certain that she came drunk?? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. You know when a person is drunk? A. Yes, I saw the black eye on her at the time.</p>

<p>Q. You did not give it to her? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You say the reason Judge Green refused to give her the child was because <sic>ushe</sic> was poor and was not able to support her? A. I suppose according to her means and character Her husband was away, there was no one to provide at that time except herself.</p>

<p>Q. She was a <sic>pooer</sic> woman? A. Yes sir.</p>

<fw>[Keevin, C-EX. <gap/> 76--131.</fw>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>