<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0148.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. State of Washington. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Hidalgo, Emily" xml:id="eh">Emily Hidalgo</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0148.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. State of Washington. Petition</title>
<date when="1903">Febuary 14, 1903</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Lavin, James P.</term>
<term>Angelique, M.</term>
<term>Hanford, Cornelius H.</term>
<term>Crushman, Edward E.</term>
<term>Normand, Georgette</term> 
<term>Fevre, Marie Le</term>
<term>Fevre, Youve Le</term>
<term>Cushman, Edward E</term>
<term>Avres, A. Reeves</term>
<term>Statishem, HMS</term>
<term>Gay, Wilson R.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hauford, C.H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0148.001"/>

<p>1078 INRE: PETITION of JAMES P. LAVIN &amp; SISTER M. ANGELIQUE of the HOUSE of the GOOD SHEPARD for 
WRIT of CERTORIARI</p>

<p>1078 INRE: PETITION of JAMES P. LAVIN &amp; SISTER M. ANGELIQUE of the HOUSE of the GOOD SHEPARD for 
WRIT of CERTORIARI</p>

<p>Reproduced at the National Archives at Seattle</p>

<p>(Action to Remove a Habeas Corpus Case to US Circuit Court)</p>

<pb/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition
of James P. Lavin, Immigrant Inspector
and Sister Superior of the House of 
the Good Shepherd, for a Writ 
of Certiorari} 
No.
Petition.</p>

<p>To the Hon. Cornelius H. Hanford, Judge of the above entitled 
Court for the District of Washington-:</p>

<p>Comes now James P. Levin and Sister M. Anquelique, by Edward E. Crushman,
Assistant United States Attorney, and respectfully ahows the Court:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That prior to the commencement of the suit hereinafter mentioned,
the said James P. Lavin was, and still is an <add>revenue</add> officer in the Tresury
Department, to-wit, an Immigrant Inspector, for the District of Puget
Sound Collection District; that hertofore,in the discharge of his duties
as such officer, on the 9th day of Febuary, 1903, he temporarily 
removed from the "Rosalis" a steuse ship, upon its arrival in Seattle,
form the foreign port of Victoria, Youve Le Fevre, Marie Le
Fevre and Georgette Normand, for the purpose of determining and investigating 
whether they were immigrants properly entitled to enter the United 
States; that thereafter, a Board of Inquiry was convened of the 
Tresury officials and Revenue officers according to law and the regulations
of the Tresury Department, to investigate and determine the leigibility 
of the above named immigrants to land and enter the United States
that upon such investigation, it was found and determined that said 
immigrants had within one year prior therto been imported into the United
States, at the port of New York, from France, for puposes of prostitution.
It was further found and determined that each one of them was
liable to become a public charge. It was further found that they had

<pb/>

immediatly prior to being taken from said vessel for such purpose by 
your petitioner, left the United States and gone to Victoria, from which
place they were returning to the United States; that upon this state of 
facts it was found and determined that they were not lawfully entitled 
to be in or enter the United States, and that they should be deported
and returned to the country from whence they came; that said matter was
held under advisement by the Tresury Department and said officers, pending 
a determination and order as to whether they should be deported to 
Victoria in the Province of Canada or the Republic of France, and that pending 
such determination your petitioner, James P. Lavin, as such officer, 
was and still is detaining and restraining of liberty each of 
said immigrants above named <add>By express <unclear></unclear> &amp; diction of the section of the <unclear></unclear></add> and as they are women, said petitioner has
delegated the office of their detention and restraint to your petitioner
Sister M. Angelique, and that she has been and is<del></del> so restraining them
of their liberty, acting under and by authority of <del></del> your petitioner,
James P. Lavin. That heretofore, to-wit, on the 13th day of Febuary,
1903, in the Superior Court of the State of Washington for the County of 
King, an action and suit <del>is</del> <add>was</add> commenced on the part of saidx immigrants,
Yourve Le Fevre, Marie Le Fevre and Georgette Normand, against
your petitioner, Sister M. Angelique, so acting as aforesaid, under color
of her aforsaid office, by authority of the laws of the United
States and the regulations of the Tresury Department and <add>and dircetin or</add>your petitioner
James P. Lavin.That your petitioer, Sister M. Angelique, has been 
served with proces, to-wit, a writ of habeas corpus, in said suit, entitled,
"In the Matter of the Application of Yuonne Le Fefre, Mari Le
Fevre and Georgette Normad," and being numbered 38028 in said Court;
that there has not been as yet any trial or final hearing of said suit.
Your petitioners therefore praythat in persuance of the laws of the 
United States that the said suit so commenced in the said Superior Court
of the State of Washingotn for the County of King may be removed therefrom

<pb/>

into this Honorable Court for trial, and therupon proceed as a 
cause originally commenced in the same, and that a writ of certiorari
in this behalf issue from this Honorable Court to the said Superior 
Court of the State of Washington for the Couty of King.</p>

<p>Edward E Cushinw
Assistant United States Attorney</p>

<p>United Statesof America
District of Washington} SS.</p>

<p>James P. Lavin, being first duly sworn, on oath deposes and says:
That he is the petitioner above named, and the matters hereinabove set
forth in said petition are true in substance and in fact.</p>

<p>James P. Lawin</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 13 day of Febuary, 1903.</p>

<p>C.H. Hauford
U.S. Disthict Judge</p>

<p>I, EdwardE. Cushman, Assistant United States Attorney, herby certify
that as a counsel for the petitioners I have examined the proceedin
the State Courttherin mentioned, and carefullyinquired into all
matters set forth in the said petiion, and belive them to be true.</p>

<p>Edward E Cushinw
Assistant United States Attorney</p>

<pb/>

<p>Due and full service of within
acknowledge this day 
of, 189
Attorney for</p>

<p>FORM NO.499
NO.1078</p>

<p>IN THE <unclear></unclear> COURT
OF THE UNITES STATES 
FOR THE 
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
Northern Division.</p>

<p>THE UNITED STATES
VS.
por the petiion of Lavin
et al for Gestionari</p>

<p>Petition</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U.S. Circuit Court 
DIST. OF WASHINGTON
FEB 14 1903
A.REEVES AVRES, Clerk
HMS Statishem Dep.</p>

<p>WILSON R. GAY,
UNITED STATES ATTORNEY,
SEATTLE, WASHINGTON</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>