<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0448.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Jeremiah Mangan v. John H. McGraw. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Ham, Bethany R." xml:id="brh">Bethany R. Ham</name>


</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0448.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Jeremiah Mangan v. John H. McGraw. Petition</title>
<date when="1889-05">May 1889</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives</repository>
<collection>King Frontier Justice</collection>
<idno>Case No 6867</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1889-05">May 1889</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Dilman, L. W.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
<term>Skagit Couny, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Mangan, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>McGraw, John H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, Cornelius H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>King County</orgName>
<placeName>Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-06" who="#brh">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0448.001"/>

<p>
FILE
No. 6867
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
In the District Court of the Third Judicial District of Washington Territory. Holding terms at Seattle in and for King County. 
In the Matter of the application NO.....
Of Jeremiah Mangan for a writ of Habeas Corpus.
John H. McGraw, Respondent -              PETITION.
</p>
<p>
To the Honorable C. H. Hanford Chief Justice of Washington Territory, and Judge of the above entitled Cour. 
Your petitoner Jeremiah Mangan respectfully represents to your Honor.
</p>
<p>
           I-
That your petitioner is restained of his liberty in the County Jail of King County Washington Territory, by one John H. McGraw Sheriff of said King County
</p>
<p>
           II-
That the cause or pretense of such x restraint according to the best knowledge and belief of your petitoner is as follows, to wti;- That the said John H. McGraw pretended and claims to be holding and restraining him of his liberty, and confines him in the Jail aforesaid by virture of a certain paper writing, claimed and pretended by the said John H. McGraw to be a commitment from one, D. L. March, a pretended Justice of the Peace of Skagit County, Washington Territory. A true copy of which said paper writing and pretended commitment is hereunto annexed and <del></del> marked exibit "A" and made a part of this petiton.
</p>
<p>
         III-
That said restraint of your petitoner is illegal for the following reasons;- That said pretended commitment is directed to and Constable and the keeper of the County Jail of Skagit County Washington Territory; and the said John H. McGraw has no right or
</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>
authority by virtue thereof to restrain your petitoner of his liberty; that it does not appear from said commitment that said Jeremiah Mangan has committed any crime or offence whatsoever, or that there is just cause to fear, or that it appeared to said so called Justice of the Peace that there is just cause to fear that any offence might be commited by said Jeremiah Mangan, nor does it appear by said commitment or otherwise that he is confined in the County Jail of King County by virtue of any order of the County Commissioners of said Skagit County, or that he said John H. McGraw has any right or authority whatsover to restrain your petitioner of his liberty.
<unclear>Rochester Larnis Dilman</unclear> attys for Petitioner
</p>
<p>
Territory of Washington)
                       )ss-
    County -of- King )
    Jeremiah Mangan, being first duly sworn upon his oath deposes and says tha the is the petitoner in the foregoing petiton; tht he has read the same, knows the contenst thereof and believes the same to be true. 
<del>L. W. D</del> Jeremiah Mangan
Subscribed and sworn to before me this .... day of May, A. D. 1889.
L. W. Dilman
Notary Public in and for Washington Territory-
</p>



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>