<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0365.025">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John Matthews v. Henry M. White. correspondents</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0365.025</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">John Matthews v. Henry M. White. correspondents</title>
<date when="1921-01">January 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-01">January 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fisher, Thomas M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Matthews, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>U.S. DEPARTMENT OF LABOR
Immigration Service</p>

<p>37012/600           Seattle, Washington,
                 still in the possession of the alien at the
time of hearing.</p>

<p>After arriving in the United States he proceeded to Alaska, where
he worked approximately two months before his arrest. He was convicted in
the United States District Court, Third Division of Alaska, on a charge
of sending obscene matter through     January 15, 1921.</p>

<p>SUMMARY AND FINDINGS
In the case of John Matthews.</p>

<p>The alien was arrested on a departmental warrant, charging that
he had been sentenced subsequent to the passage of the act of February 15,
1917, to imprisonment for a term of one year or more, because of conviction
in this country of a crime involving moral turpitude, committed within five
years after his entry into the United States, and with the additional charge
that he was a person likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry.
The alien was not represented by counsel.</p>

<p>The record shows that he is 28 years of age; that he was born in
Ukrainian, Austria, and that he claims to have landed at either St. Johns,
N.B., or Halifax, N.S., he could not be positive which, in either the year
1906 or 1907, sailing from Antwerp, Belgium, on the SS "Montezuma", his
destination at a that time, according to his story, being New York; that he
proceeded to New York, remained there a short while, and returned to
Canada, going to Montreal, thence to Ottowa; that he lived in Canada
continuously until August 31, 1919 when he applied for admission to the
United States at the port of Victoria, B.C., and was admitted as a
visitor, paying head tax, and being given head tax refund receipt
No.14188.    This receipt was  the mail, and was sentenced May 4, 1920,
to serve a term of one year in the Federal Penitentiary at McNeil Island.</p>

<p>After considering the testimony adduced in this case I find that
John Matthews is an alien, that he entered the United States through the port
of Victoria, B.C., August 31, 1919; that he was at the time a person likely
to become a public charge, and that he has been sentenced subsequent to the
passage of the act of February 5, 1917, to imprisonment for a term of one
year or more, because of his conviction in this country of a crime involving
moral turpitude committed within five years after his entry to the United
States, and I therefore respectfully recommend that he be ordered deported to
the country whence he came, or of which  he is a citizen or subject, in
conformity with law.</p>

<p>The alien's description is as follows,
Age 28 years; height 5'61/4, weight 189 pounds; hair dark
brown; eyes hazel gray, complexion medium.</p>

<p>Thomas M. Fisher
Immigrant Inspector</p>

<pb></pb>
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>