<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0485.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Harry Smith and Barney Slomen v. United States. Petition. </title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Byrd, Samantha." xml:id="slb">Samantha Byrd</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0485.003</idno>
<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Harry Smith and Barney Slomen v. United States. Petition.</title>
<date when="1916-07-01">July 1, 1916</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1916-07-01">July 1, 1916</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>John H. Boyle</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Smith, Harry</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Slomen, Barney</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, J. G.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Sullivan, J. J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Martin, Winter S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court</orgName> 
<placeName>Western District of Washington Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#slb">transcribed and encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>  

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE UNITED SATES DISTRICT COURT, IN AND FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, Plaintiff, vs. Barney Slomen, Defendant. No. 3375 PETITION.</p>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE JEREMIAH NETERER, JUDGE OF THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT OF THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION:</p>

<p>Your petitioner, Barney Slomen, respectfully shows that he, the said Barney Slomen, is unlawfully imprisoned, detained and restrained of his liberty by John H. Boyle, the United States Marshall of the Western District of Washington, at the county jail in the City of Tacoma, County of Pierce, State of Washington; that the said impricorment, detention, confinement and restraint in illegal, and that the illegality thereof consists in this, to-wit: That on or about the 28 day of March, 1916, the grand jury of the aforesaid district duly and regularly returned and presented unto the court an indictment in words and figures, as follows, to-wit: "Having in his possesson certain grains of morphium, a derivative of opium and cocoa leaves":<add>that the same</add> does not constitute an offense against the laws of the United States. And each and every charge so set out in said indictment is made a part of this petition, as if set out <unclear>in henc verbe</unclear>.</p>

<p>That your petitioner was arrested on said indictment and was arraigned thereon; that your petitioner entered his plea of not guilty to the facts set out in said indictment; that on or about the 23rd day of May, your petitioner was tried and convicted in said court on said indictment, so the facts therein set forth; that on the 5 day of June, 1916, your</p>

<pb/>

<p>petitioner was by the court sentenced to serve five months in the Pierce County jail, and that your petitioner was thereafter, and is now, confined in said Pierce County jail; that the judgment and sentence of the court is null, illegal and void, and of no effect, for the reason that the acts charged in said information do not constitute any crime or offense against the Government of the United States.</p>

<p>That the acts charged and proved against your petitioner do not consitutute any crime or offense against the Government of the United States.</p>

<p>Your petitioner further alleges that he had not a fair and impartial trail before the said court; that there is no evidence in the records to sustain the judgment that the court rendered againt your petitioner, and ordered him confined in the Pierce County jail without any authority of law.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus may be granted, directed to the United States Marshall, as aforesaid, commanding him to have the body of said Barney Slomen before your Honor at the time and place therein specified, to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by your Honor concerning him the said Barney Slomen, together with the time and cause of his detention, andthat the said Barney Slomen may be restored to his liberty.</p>

<p>Barney Sloman Petitioner</p>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON COUNTY OF KING ss</p>

<p>BARNEY SLOMEN, being first duly sworn, on oath desposes and says: That he has read the foregoing Petition, knows the contents thereof, and that the same is true of his own knowledge, excepting the matters therein stated on information adn belief, and as to those matters, he believes them to be true.</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn before me Barney Slomen this 1 day of July, 1916.</p>

<p>Adam Beele Notary Public for the State of Wasington, residing at</p>

<pb/>

<p>Let the Writ issue returnable before me at the court room of the United States District Court at the Federal Bldg., Seattle, State of Washington, on the 3rd day of July, 1916, at the <unclear></unclear> hour of said day.</p>

<p>Jeremiah Neterer Judge.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>