<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0189.011">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Charles Jackson v. Henry M. White. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0189.011</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Charles Jackson v. Henry M. White. Complaint</title>
<date when="1918-11-14">November 14, 1918</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1918-11">November 1918</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>W.P.Callahan</term>
<term>S.J.Burford</term>
<term>Trent Dozier</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Denmark</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Mt. Vernon, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Jackson, Charles</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2019-11" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.189.010"/>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of CHAS. JACKSON for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>No. 4356 Complaint</p>
<p> The complainant, Charles Jackson, appearing by Ralph S. Pierce his attorney, complains to the court and alleges and petitions as follows:</p>
<p>1.</p>
<p> That at all times hereinafter mentioned, complainant was, and still is, a subject of Denmark, lawfully domiciled in the United States of America; that he is not restrained of his liberty on any charge or conviction of crime, nor on any process issued on any final judgement of a court of competent jurisdiction, nor on any warrant committment, or other proceess issued on any indictment or information, nor on any order or warrant of committment oherwise than as herinafter specified.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p> That on or about the 20th day of January, 1918, the complainant was arrested by an Immigration Inspector of the United States on a warrant of arrest issued by the Secretary of Labor of the United States, wherein the complainant is charged with being an alien and with having entered the United States without the inspection contemplated by law, and that he was at the time a member of the inadmissable classes in that he was suffering from a loathsome and dangerous disease, and that at the time he was a person likely to become a public charge, and further, that at the time of his entry he was affiliated with an organization which advocated or taught the unlawful destruction of property, and that on the 25th day of January, 1918, pursuant to the mandate of said warrant, the complainant was taken before W.P.Callahan, an immigration inspector of the United States at Seattle, Washington, and given a hearing for the purpose of inquiring into the merits of said charges; that at a later date, and on the 15th day of June, 1918, the complainant was taken before a special board of inquiry consisting of S.J. Burford, Trent Dozier and W.P. Callahan at Mt. Vernon, Washington, for the purpose of inquiring further into the merits of said charges.</p>
<p> That at said hearing the said complainant was denied the right of counsel, and that his counsel was commanded to leave the room where such hearing was being held. That subsequently the complainant was examined as a witness, and that in response to questions propounded to him, stated that he was 37 years of age, that he had entered the United States in June 1917, and that he had been a member of the I.W.W. for a period of six months; that the complainant was asked at said hearing if he believed in the teachings of the I.W.W., and answered "No, none of them at all; I am finished with the I.W.W. for all time to come." That he was asked if any other laboring man would have asked him if it was a good organization to belong to, <del>that</del> <add>if</add> he would have told him "Yes," and that he answered "I would have told him that it was up to him to find our, and that I never advocated to nobody to join."</p>
<p> That the complainant was further questioned as to his financial condition, and that the record shows that at the time of the hearing he had $100.00 in cash; that he had in his possession a bank book of the bank of Montreal, Vancouver Branch, No.1880-B, showing a balance on September 27, 1917, of $777.80, and also a bank book of the Scandanavian American Bank of Seattle, Washington, showing deposits in the sum of $265; that said questions and answers were reported by a stenographer employed by the United States Department of Labor, and were subsequently transcribed and introduced in evidence against the complainant in substatnion of the charges contained in the warrant of arrest hereinbefore referred to, together with a great many other questions and answers having no bearing upon, and in no manner material to said charges, and that the said transcript constitutes the only evidence ever introduced against the complainant in substantiation of said charges.</p>
<p> That at no time was complainant questioned as to whether he had ever advocated or talked the unlawful destuction of property or anything else, or even whether he believed in such unlawful destruction except as above indicated, nor was he questioned about his ability to work and support himself or about the likehood of his becoming a public chage at the time of his entry into the United States or at any other time, except as above indicated, nor was an evidence of any character offered or received upon any of said questions except as above indicated; that thereafter, and on the 2nd day of October, 1918, a warrant was issued by the Department of Labor of the United States, ordering <del>that</del> the deportation of the complainant on the ground that he was a person likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry into the United States.</p>
<p>III.</p>
<p> That the complainant is now and ever since the 2nd day of October, 1918, has been continuously restrained of his liberty in the United States Immigration Detention Station of Seattle, King County, Washington, by Henry M.White, United States Commissioner of Labor, stationed at Seattle, under the pretended authority of the warrant of deportation issued by the Secretary of Labor as herinabove alleged, and not otherwise, and that said restraint is illegal for the following rwasons.to-wit:</p>
<p> That on the hearing conducted to inquire into the charges upon which the complainant is restricted of his liberty, and by which he has been ordered deported above referred to, no evidence whatsoever was introduced to sustan the charge that the complainant was a person likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry into the United States, and that there was no evidence upon which the Secretary of Labor of the United States could make an order directing that the complainant be deported from the United States or any other order in any manner restraining the complainant of his liberty, and that the order herinabove referred to made by the Secretary of Labor is entirely arbitrary, and wholly void.</p>
<p> That the complainant is informed and believes that there are only two copies of the testemony introduced on the hearing of the charges of which he is restrained of his liberty, and that one of said copies is in the possession of the Secretary of Labor of the United States at Washington D.C., and the other in the possession of Henry M.White, Commissioner of Labor of the United States, at Seattle, Washington. That complainant demanded a copy of said evidence, in order that he might attach the same to this petition, but his demand therefor was refused by said Henry M.White. That complainant is a common laborer and a result of his long confinement and the deprivation of his usual means of support, he is unable, by reason of his poverty, to pay for the preparation of such a copy, but deponent is informed by his attorney, and believes that if the said Henry M.White is required to produce the transcript of said evidence, now in his possession, and make the same a part of his return herin, or exhibit the same to court, the verity of complainant's allegations in relation thereto will clearly appear therefrom.</p>
<p> Wherefore, complainant prays an order directing the Clerk to issue out of and under the seal of this court, a writ directed to Henry M.White, Commissioner of Labor of the United States, stationed at Seattle,Washington, requiring him to produce the body of complainant in the above entitled court, before the Hon.Jeremiah Neterer, a judge thereof, on the   day of November, 1918, at   o'clock in the   noon, and that he then and there show cause, if any he has, why the complainant should be further restrained of his liberty, and further directing that said Henry M.White also then and there produce, properly authenticated under his seal, a copy of the testimony t aken at the hearing held pursuant to the mandate of the warrant of arrest issued by the Secretary of Labor, pursuant to which complainant Charles Jackson, is restrained of his liberty by said Henry M.White.</p>
<p>State of Washington County of King</p>
<p>ss</p>
<p> Charles Jackson, being first duly sworn, says: That he is the complainant in the above entitled action; that he has read the foregoing complaint, knows the contents therof, and that the same is true to his knowledge.</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 14 day of November, 1918.</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Wash, residing at Seattle</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>