<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0364.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Tsunetaro Machida v. Luther Wedin</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0364.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Tsunetaro Machida v. Luther Wedin</title>
<date when="1922-09-05">September 5, 1922</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1922-09">September 1922</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Machida, Tsunetaro</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Wedin, Luther</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Horner, Thomas R.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>United States of America, ss:</p>

<p>The President of the United States of America,</p>

<p>To the Honorable the Judges of the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</p>

<p>Greeting:</p>

<p>Whereas, lately in the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division, before you, or some of you, in <del>a cause between</del> the matter of Tsunetaro Machida, on Habeas Corpus, No. 6190, an order Discharging Writ of Habeas Corpus was duly filed on the 26th day of September, 1921, which said order is in the words and figures following, to-wit:</p>

<p>"In this matter, petition for a writ of habeas corpus having heretofore been filed and order havingbeen granted requesting Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration, to show cause why a writ of habeas corpus should not be issued herein, and the writ having been issued on the 19th day of September, 1921, and the court having considered the evidence and having heard the argument of counsel thereon;</p>

<p>"It is ordered, adjudged and decreed that the said writ of habeas corpus be, and it is hereby, discharged, and that the petitioner remain in the custody of the said Henry M.White, Commissioner of Immigration.</p>

<p>"Done in open court this 16th day of September, 1921,</p>

<p>"JEREMIAH NETERER, Judge."</p>

<p>which said Order is of record and fully set out in the said matter in the office of the Clerk of the said District Court, to which record reference is hereby made and the same is expressly made a part hereof,</p>

<pb/>

<p>as by the inspection of the Transcript of the Record of the said District Court, which was brought into the United States Circuit Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit by virtue of an appeal prosecuted by Tsunetaro Machida, as Appellant, against Luther Weedin, as Commissioner of Immigration at the Port of Seattle, Washington, for the United States Government, as Appellee, agreeably to the Act of Congress in such cases made and provided fully and at large appears:</p>

<p>And Whereas, on the 5th day of September in the year of our Lord One Thousand Nine Hundred and Twenty-two the said cause <gap></gap> came on to be heard before the said Circuit Court of Appeals on the said <gap></gap> Transcript of the Record and upon the stipulationof counsel for the respective parties for the dismissal of the appeal herein, and was duly submitted:</p>

<pb/>

<p>On Consideration Whereof, It is now here ordered, adjudged and decreed that the appeal in this cause be, and hereby is dismissed.</p>

<p>(September 5, 1922.)</p>

<p>You, Therefore, are Hereby Commanded</p>

<p>That such further proceedings be had in the said cause as according to right and justice and the laws of the United States ought to be had, the said appeal notwithstanding.</p>

<p>Witness, the Honorable William Howard Taft, Chief Justice of the United States, the 5th day of September, in the year of our Lord One Thousand, Nine Hundred and Twenty-two and of the Independence of the United States of America the One Hundred and Forty-seventh.</p>

<p>F.D. Monckton,</p>
<p>Clerk of the United States Circuit Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit.</p>

<p>By Paul P. <unclear></unclear></p>
<p>Deputy Clerk.</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 3821</p>

<p>United States Circuit Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit</p>

<p>Tsunetar Machida,</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>Luther Wedin, as Commissioner of Immigration at the Port of Seattle, Washington.</p>

<p>Mandate</p>

<p>B.8 #2-Page 319.</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Sep 12 1922</p>

<p>F. M. Harshberger</p>
<p>By <gap></gap> Deputy</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>