<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0433.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Physicians Certificate</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0433.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Physicians Certificate</title>
<date when="1888-06-20">June 20, 1888</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1888-06-20">June 20, 1888</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>PHYSICIAN'S CERTIFICATE
[Form prescribed by the Superintendent of the Hospital]</p>

<p>TERRITORY OF WASHINGTON
County of Yakima         } ss</p>

<p>W.F. Morrison and J.O. Clark being duly sworn,
certifies each for himself, that he is a legally qualified physician; that at the request and in the presence of Hon J.A. Navarre, Probate Judge of Yakima County, he has heard the
testimony of the witnesses, and carefully examined the said James A. Balch in reference to the charge
of insanity, and <add></add> find that .... he is insane. <del></del>
The further facts appertaining to said case, as nearly as can be ascertained, are set forth in the
<del>following questions and</del> answers to the following questions- 
W.F. Morrison M.D.
J.O. Clark M.D.</p>

<p>QUESTIONS.</p>

<p>1. Name: James A. Balch     2. Age? about 57
3. Place of birth? Indianana    4. Married or Single? Married
5. If children, how many, and the age of the youngest? about 8 7 years
6. If female and married, maiden name, and name of husband? . . . . .
7. What State last from. and how long in W.T.? About 12 years in Territory
8. What occupation. Farming and landscaping
9. What evidence have you of the presence of insanity? Halucinations regarding
corporations and religion
10. Is there homicidal, suicidal or incendiary diposition? ///
11. Is the case a recent one, having occured within twelve months last past? Yes according
to his statements.
12. When did this attack first appear? about three months ago
13. Is this the first attack? If not, when did others occur, and what their duration? Do not know
14. Is the disease increasing, decreasing or stationary? Stationary
15. Are there rational intervals? if so, do they occur periodically? . . . . . 
16. Is there any permanent hallucination? If so, what is it? Religion
<del>17. Is there any permanent delusions? If so, what is it?</del></p>

<pb></pb>

<p>17. In what way is the accused dangerous to be at large? Deep Destruction
18. Is there a disposition to injure others? If so, is it directed especially to relatives, and is it from sudden passion or premeditated? . . . . .
19. If suicidal, is the propensity now active, and in what way? . . . . .
20. Is there a disposition to filthy habits, destruction of clothing, furniture, etc? . . . . .
21. Any relation, including grand-parents and cousins being insane? . . . . .
22. Any peculiarities of temper, habits, disposition, or pursuits before the attack - any predominant passions or religious impressions? yes --
23. Been intemperate in the use of ardent spirits, wine, opium or tabacco in any form? . . . . .
24. Suffered from epilepsy, suppressed secretions, eruptions, discharges, or sores, or injured on the head? No
25. Any change in the physical health since the attack? . . . . .
26. The supposed cause of insanity? . . . . .
27. Of what class of insanity. Mania, melancholia or dementia? Dementia
29. What treatment has been pursued, and with what effect : Don't know
30. Name or post-office address, of relative or friend? Hattie M. Balch (wife)
<unclear>Syle Klickertal</unclear> Co W.T.</p>

<p>W.F. Morrison M.D.
J.O. Clark M.D.</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 20th day
of June A.D. 1883</p>

<p>J.A. Navarre, Probate Judge</p>

<pb></pb>
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>