<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, FOR THE WESTERN 
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of Application
of K. Gregory, M. Aloshin,
I. Riaboff, P. Neanlin, I. 
Emelin, L. Orloff, G. Yaki-
moff and P. Yakimoff for a 
WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS</p>
<p>No. 2646
ASSIGNMENT OF ERROR</p>
<p>Comes now Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, for the United
States Government, the respondent and appellant in the above entitled cause, by Clay Allen, United
States Attorney for the Western District of Washington, and George P. Fishburne, Assistant United
States Attorney for said District, and says that in the record and preceedings in the cause and in
the order and judgement of discharge, dated the 27th day of January, 1914, and field and entered in
the Clerk's office February 2, 1914, and in the decision of the Court, made and filed the 27th day
of January, 1914, there is manifest error in this, to-wit:</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in issuing the Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in assuming jurisdiction of the case.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>III.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in holding that he had jurisdiction and power to discharge the petitioners,
K. Gregory, M. Aloshin, I. Riaboff, P. Neanlin, I. Emelin, L. Orloff, G. Yakimoff and P. Yakimoff,
when the records show they had previously had a hearing before the Immigration Board, which had
rendered a decision excluding their admission and which decision was affirmed by the Secretary of
Labor.</p>
<p>IV.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in finding that said petitioners were not "likely to become a public
charge".</p>
<p>V.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in finding that he or any court has a right to say what are the matters to
be taken into consideration by the Immigration Board in determining what aliens are "likely to
become a public charge".</p>
<p>VI.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in findinng that the Immigration Board exceeded its authority in excluding
the said petitioners on the ground that they are "likely to become a public charge", because it
based its decision upon reasons not within the act.</p>
<p>VII.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in setting aside the decision of the Immigration Board, affirmed by the
Secretary of Labor, that the said petitioners were "likely to become a public charge".</p>
<p>VIII.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in holding that the Immigration Board exceeded its authority in its
decision, affirmed by 
<pb></pb>
the Secretary of Labor, that the said petitioners should be excluded because they were "likely to
become a public charge".</p>
<p>IX.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in finding that the courts had power to intervene where the Immigration
Board exceeded its authority, if the decision was already affirmed by the Secretary of Labor.</p>
<p>X.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in not finding that said petitioners had a hearing according to the Act, and
that therefore the Immigration Board and the Secredtary of Labor did not exceed their authority in
holding that said petitioners should be excluded because they were "likely to become a public
charge".</p>
<p>XI.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in not holding that seeing and questioning the said petitioners by the
Immigration Board was such taking of testimony as would exclude the courts from reviewing the
decision of the Immigration Board, affirmed by the Secretary of Labor, holding that the said
petitioners should be excluded on the ground they were "likely to become a public charge."</p>
<p>XII.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in finding that the Immigration Board excluded the said aliens as "likely to
become a public charge" upon facts and reasons not within the Immigration Act.</p>
<p>XIII.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in finding that the Immigration Board excluded the said aliens on grounds
not set forth in the Act.</p>
<p>XV.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in rendering the decree discharging the said petitioners from the custody of
the officers of the United States and restoring them to their liberty.</p>
<p>XVI.</p>
<p>That the Court erred in not holding that the decision of the Immigration Board, affirmed by the
Secretary of Labor, that the said aliens were"likely to become a public charge", was a decision on a
question of fact that could bot be reviewed or reversed by the Court.</p>
<p>WHEREAS, Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, respondent and
appellant herein, prays that his assignment of errors be entered upon the record in this cause, and
that upon the hearring of this appeal it may be adjudged by the United States Circuit Court of
Appeals for the Ninth Circuit that the order and judgement, dated January 27, 1914, and entered
February 2, 1914, be in all things reversed, set aside and held for naught, and that it be adjudged
and decreed that the applicants, K. Gregory, M. Aloshin, I. Riaboff, P. Neanlin, I. Emelin, L. Orloff, 
G. Yakimoff and P. Yakimoff, be remanded to the custody of the respondent herein to be further dealt
with according to law.</p>
<p>Dated at Seattle, February 4th, 1914</p>
<p>Clay Allen
United States Attorney.</p>
<p>George Fishburne
Assistant United States Attorney.</p>

<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>