<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0272.001.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Columbia George v. Charles B. Hopkins. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Czapla, Ethan P" xml:id="epc">Ethan Czapla</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0272.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Columbia George v. Charles B. Hopkins. Petition</title>
<date when="1906-02-24">February 24, 1906</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno>1390ColumbiaGeorgeIndian</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1906-02">Febuary 1906</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Salem, Oregon</term>
<term>Umatilla Indian Reservation, Oregon</term>
<term>McNeil's Island, Washington</term>

</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>George, Columbia</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Hopkins, Charles B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Slater, R. J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Frye, Jesse A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#epc">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>No. 1390</p>

<p>
In the Circuit Court
of the United States for the
Western District of Washington</p>
<p>
In the Matter of the Application
of Columbia George for a Writ of
Habeus Corpus</p>
<p>
Petition</p>
<p>
Filed in the U.S. Circuit Court
Western Dist. of Washington
FEB 24 1906
A. Reeves Ayres, Clerk
P.M. <unclear>Hapkins, Dep.</unclear></p>
<p>
Service of Papers in this case may be made upon
R.J. Slater
Pendleton, Oregon
Attorneys for Petiioner</p>

<pb/>

<p>In the Circuit Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Columbia George for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. No1390. Petition</p>

<p>To the Honorable Judges of the Circuit Court of the United States, for the Western District of the State of Washington</p>

<p>The petition of Columbia George respectfully shows:
       That Columbia George is unlawfully imprisoned, detained, confined and restrained of his liberty by CB Hopins, United States
       Marshall for the Western District of the State of Washington, at the Penitentiary of the United States, at McNeil's Island in the
       said District and State.</p>

<p>That the said imprisonment, detention and confinement and restraint are illegal, and that the illegality thereof consists in this, to-wit;</p>

<p>That on or about the 21st day of November, AD, 1901 the said Columbia George was indicted, tried and convicted in the Circuit Court
       of the United States for the District of Oregon, of the crime of murder in the first degree, and by recommendation of the jury in ther verdict,
       he was by said Court sentenced to imprisonment for life, and under said conviction and sentence he was thereafter confined to the Oregon
       State Penitentiary at Salem, Oregon, and was thereafter by order of the Attorney General of the United States, transferred to the custody of
       CB Hopkins, said United States Marshall for the Western District of the State of Washington, and is now in his custody at the United States
       Penitentiary as above alleged</p>
       
<pb/>

<p>That said indictment and conviction were based upon the following facts, to-wit, that the said Columbia George is a full blood Indian, and that
the person murdered was a  full blood Indian, and the said rime was comitted upon the Umatilla Indian Reservation in the State of Oregon,
and that the said Columbia George was a tribal Inidan belonging to the Cayuse band of Indians and resided upon said Reservaation, which facts
it was claimed by the United States Court in and for the District of Oregon in said case, but the facts were, and the record in case shows:
</p>
      
<p>That the said Columbia George is and was at the time said crime was committed a full blood Indian and was at said time an allottee of land in severalty
upon said Reservation under an Act of Congres approved March 3rd, 1885, and had received from the United States Government a Trust Patent for said land, by
reason of which facts he was at said time a citizen of the United Staes, and of the State of Oregon and entitled to all the rights, privileges and immunities
thereof, and was subject to the laws of the State of Oregon, and the said Circuit Court of the United States for the District of Oregon by reason thereof
had no jurisdiction in said matter.</p>
       
<p>Wherefore, Your petitioner prays that a Writ of Habeus Corpus may be granted, directed to the said C B Hopkins, commanding him to have the body of Columbia George
before your Honors at a time and place therein to be specified, to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by your Honor concerning him, together
with the time and cause of the detention of the said Columbia George, and said Writ; and that he may be restored to his liberty.</p>
       
<p>Dated, this 24th day of February, 1906.</p>
       
<p>R.J. Slater
       Attorney for Petitioner</p>
<pb/>

<p></p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>