<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">
<pb/>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES
DISTRICT COURT FOR THE
WESTERN DISTRICT OF 
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN 
DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE
UNLAWFUL DETENTION OF
SEVENTY-THREE HINDOOS.</p>
<p>MEMORANDUM BRIEF OF 
PETITIONERS. 
REPLY BRIEF.</p>
<p>HERBERT W. MEYERS 
ATTORNEY AT LAW
430-431-432-433 PIONEER BUILDING
PHONE MAIN 1278 
SEATTLE, WASH.</p>
<p>MERCHANTS PRINTING CO., TIMES BLDG., SEATTLE</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE WESTERN
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION, MAY TERM, 1913.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE UNLAWFUL
DETENTION OF SEVENTY-
THREE HINDOO ALIENS.
: : : 
NO. 2532. 
BILL OF EXCEPTIONS.</p>
<p>BE IT REMEMBERED: That in the May term, 1913, came
the seventy-three Hindoo aliens into the said court and im-
pleaded the United States of America in a certain petition for
writs of habeas corpus on the ground of the unlawful detention of
the said aliens; a show cause order was issued out of the United
States District Court and in due time the United States made a
return from said order and petition for writs of habeas corpus,
admitting and denying allegations in the petition, and the United
States further tendered the record as taken before the Immigration
Department; a hearing was had on the 18th day of August,
1913, and the same was continued until the 26th day of August,
1913, and the court took the matter under advisement; the court
thereupon rendered a verbal opinion, after which a rehearing was
asked for by the petitioners, and the matter came on for hearing
on the petition of the aliens on the 16th day of September, 1913,
after which, on September 27, 1913, the court signed and filed
an order refusing to grant the writs and discharging the govern-
ment on the show cause order, to all of which petitioners excepted
as herein set forth:</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>-I-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in refusing to grant the writs 
of habeas corpus and in refusing to release the aliens.</p>
<p>-II-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in refusing to release the 
aliens on the hearing on the show cause order on the ground that
the government's return was not sufficient.</p>
<p>-III-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in refusing to release the
aliens and failing to grant the writs prayed for on the
rehearing.</p>
<p>-IV-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in holding the decision of the
Immigration Department final and in failing to examine the evidence.</p>
<p>-V-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in refusing to find that the
petitioners had been deprived of their constitutional rights under
Articles V, VI, VIII, and XIV of the Amendments to the Constitution
of the United States.</p>
<p>-VI-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in not holding that the second
examination at Seattle was improper.</p>
<p>-VII-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in refusing to hold that the
examination at Manila was sufficient.</p>
<p>-VIII-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in refusing to find that the
warrants of arrest were not faulty and contrary to law.</p>
<p>-IX-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in refusing to find that the 
examination was not fair and impartial.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>-X-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in refusing to find that the
Immigration Department violated the Act of February 20, 1907.</p>
<p>-XI-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in failing to find that the
Immigration officals transcended the bound of their authority.</p>
<p>-XII-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in failing to find that the
warrants were issued contrary to law, and the entire proceeding
was in direct violation of the Act of February 20, 1907.</p>
<p>-XIII-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in failing to find that the
Immigration officals had abused their authority and discretion</p>
<p>-XIV-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in failing to find that the
second examination was improper, after a previous proper 
examination.</p>
<p>-XV-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in failing to find that the
aliens had never become public charges and had never entered the
country unlawfully and were, therefore, not properly held under
the Act of February 20, 1907.</p>
<p>-XVI-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in refusing to find that there
was no proper, material or substantial evidence showing the aliens
to come within the confines of the Act of February 20, 1907.</p>
<p>-XVII-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in refusing to find that the
aliens had been properly examined and passed by an Immigration
Board at Manila.</p>
<p>-XVIII-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in failing to find that the
petitioners had had no hearing on the ground of exclusion.</p>
<p>-XIX-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in refusing to find that the
aliens were not amenable to the law.</p>
<p>-XX-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in failing to find that the
positive proof furnished by the aliens as to their proper landing 
in Manila was sufficient to overcome any presumption as outlined
in Rule 14 of the Immigration Act.</p>
<p>-XXI-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in failing to find that Section
20 of the Immigration Act was mandatory.</p>
<p>-XXII-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in failing to find that the
Immigration authorities had not complied with Rule 22 of the
Immigration Act.</p>  
<p>-XXIII-</p>
<p>The learned judge erred in failing to find that Section 
25 of the Immigration Act had no application to the cases of
these aliens.</p>
<p>-XXIV-</p>
<p>And to each and every of the rulings of the court 
to which objection was made and exception was noted, as herein-
before set forth, the petitioners now, within the time prescribed
by law, present this bill of exceptions as to each and every of
<pb></pb>
the rulings on objections as aforesaid, move the court to sign 
the same, to have the same force and effect as if each and every
of said exceptions had been separately signed and sealed, and
thereupon the petitioners pray that this bill of exceptions may 
be signed and sealed and made a part of the record according to
the form of the statute in such case made and provided, which
is done accordingly this 8th day of October, 1913.</p>
<p>Jeremiah Neterer
District Judge.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>2x No. 2532.</p>
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE
UNITED STATES FOR THE WESTERN 
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, 
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE UNLAWFUL
DETENTION OF SEVENTY-
THREE HINDOO ALIENS.</p>
<p>BILL OF EXCEPTIONS.</p>
<p>Received a copy of
the within this
8th day of October,
1913 
E B Brockway
Asst Dist Atty </p>
<p>FILED IN THE
U.S. DISTRICT COURT,
Western Dist. of Washington
NORTHERN DIVISION.
OCT 23 1913.
FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk,
By Emy Deputy</p>
<p>HERBERT W. MEYERS 
ATTORNEY AT LAW
430-431-432-433 PIONEER BUILDING
PHONE MAIN 1278
SEATTLE, WASH.
MERCHANTS PRINTING CO., TIMES BLDG., SEATTLE</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>