<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>In Re: Ex Parte - Donald Kerracher - Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Banse, AD" xml:id="ab">AD Banse</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0270.009</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">In Re: Ex Parte - Donald Kerracher - Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="2022-06-13">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">2022-06-21</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName> Donald MC Kerracher</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName> C.B. Hopkins</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>C.H. Hanford</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p> In Re. Ex Parte: 
    Donald MC Kerracher,
    Petitioner. No. 1328 </p>
<p> Motion to Dismiss and Quash the Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p> To the Honorable Cornelius H. Hanford, </p>
<p> Comes now Jesse A. Frye, United States 
    Attorney for the Western District of Washington, appear-
    ing for the United States of America intervening herein, and
    for Charles B. Hopkins, United States Marshal aforesaid, upon the petition, 
    writ and return herein moves that the writ of habeas corpus heretofore 
    issued herein be quashed and dismissed, on the following grounds to-wit: </p>
<p> I. 
    That said writ was improvidently issued, </p>
<p>II. 
    That it appears from the petition, writ and return
    herein that the said petitioner, Donald McKerracher, is 
    in the legal custody of Charles B. Hopkins, United 
    States Marshal for the Western District of Washington. </p>
<p> III.
    That it appears from said petition, writ and return 
    that the said petitioner, Donald McKerracher, was sentenced
    to five years imprisonment in the United States Penitent-
    iary on McNeil's Island, Washington, on the 14th day 
    of January 1902, by the Honorable Judge of the United 
    States District Court for the Distrcit of Washington,
    and that on the 15th day of January 1902 in pursuance of
    said sentence the said petitioner was placed in the 
    custody of the United States Marshal for  the then 
    District of Washington, was placed in the United States 
    penitentiary on McNeil's Island, Washington, where
    said petuitoner has since been confined in pursuance
    of said sentence.</p>
<pb/>
<p> IV. 
    That it appears from said petition, writ and 
    return, that the said sentence so imposed by the said 
    court as aforesaid has not expired by law, and will 
    not expire until the 14th day of April 1906.</p>
<p> V. 
    That is is established by the petition, writ and 
    return, that the petitioner, Donald McKerrracher, is not
    entitled to the be discharged at this time from the custody 
    of the said United States Marshal for the Western 
    District of Washington, that said sentence so imposed
    as foretold has not expired according to law.</p>
<p> Jesse A. Frye.
    Unired States Attorney for 
    the Western District of Washington. </p>

<pb/>
<p>  Due and timely service of the within motion, and the receipt
    of a true copyh thereof, acknowledged this 20th day of September 1905. </p>
<p> Metcalfe and Jurey, Attorneys for Petitioner. </p>
<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>