<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR
THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
Northern Division.

IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION
OF LEE FONG FOR A WRIT OF 
HABEAS CORPUS.

J. M. Wiestling, for the Petitioner.
Ellis D. Buller, for the Respondent.

Gilber, Circuit Judge. 

The petitioner, Lee Fong, was arrested and detained in the 
custody of the Chief of Police of the City of Seattle, upon the
charge that he had violated the provisions of Section 6 of Ordinance
710 of the City of Seattle, approved Feb. 6, 1886, entitled: An ordinance
regulating the establishment and maintainance of public laundries 
and public wash-houses within the limits of the City of Seattle"
Those portions of the ordinance which are pertinent to the present
inquire read as follows:  "Sec. 2. It shall be unlawful for any
person or persons to conduct or maintain a public laundry or wash-house
within the city of Seattle without having first obtained a 
certificate signed by the health officer of the city of Seattle that
the premises are properly and sufficiently drained and that all proper
arrangements for carrying on the business without injury to the sanitary 
condition of the neighborhood have been complied with, also a
certificate signed by the chief of the fire department of the City

(1)

<pb/>

of Seattle that the stoves, washing and drying apparatus and the
appliances for heating smoothing irons are in good condition, and
that their use is not dangerous to the surrounding property, from
fire, and that all proper precautions have been taken to comply
with the provisions of the ordinances of the city then in force making
regulations concerning the erection and use of buildings and for
the protection of property from injury or destruction by fire".

"Sec. 3. It shall be the duty of the health officer, also
of the chief of the fire department, respectively, upon application
from any person or persons proposing to open or conduct the business
of a public laundry within the City of Seattle to inspect the premises
in which it is proposed to carry on said business, or in which said
business is being carried on, with a view to ascertain whether the
said premises are provided with proper drainage and sanitary appliances,
also whether the provisions of the ordinances of the city then
in force making regulations concerning the erection and use of buildings 
and for the protection of property from injury or destruction
by fire, have been complied with, and if found in all respects satisfactory,
then to issue to such person or persons the certificates
provided for in section 2 of this ordinance. No charge whatever
shall be made or compensation or fee collected or received for the
performance of any of the services required by the provisions of this
ordinance in the inspection of premises or the issuance of a certificate,
but all such services shall be performed free of charge".

"Sec. 6. It shall be unlawful, from and after the passage
of this ordinance, for any person or persons to establish, maintain
or carry on a laundry within the corporate limits of the City of Seattle
without having first obtained the consent of the common council,
except the same be located in a building constructed either of brick

(2)

<pb/>

or stone, and covered with a metal roof". The petitioner alleges in
substance that an application was made by John Miller, the petitioner's 
lessor, to the City of Seattle for a permit to change premises No.
1410 East First Street into a laundry; that there were submitted therewith
builder' specifications for said change, expressly designating
that the same were to be used for laundry purposes; that said application
and specifications were examined by the building inspector of
the City of Seattle and were duly approved and a permit was granted 
authorizing the proposed change; that at the time when said laundry
permit was granted, the health officer of the City of Seattle, after
inspecting said premises, on June 18, 1902, gave his official certificate
stating that "permission is given to John Miller to build a 
laundry at 1410 East First Street, he having complied with the said
ordinance"; that pursuant to said respective permits, the petitioner
expended upwards of $600 in making said changes and converting said
building into one suitable for laundry purposes; that at the conclusion
of said work, on Aug. 2, 1902, the health officer of Seattle
executed a certificate, certifying that he had inspected the premises
and found them properly and sufficiently drained and that proper
provisions had been made for sanitary conditions. That on July 30,
1902, the city inspector of plumbing for said city certified that the
plumbing in said building had been inspected, completed, and found
to be in accordance with the ordinance of the City of Seattle; that
notwithstanding these facts, certain persons made petition to the
common council of the City of Seattle against having at the designated
place a "Chinese laundry", and requested the council to withold their
consent for the same; that the petitione was indorsed: "A remonstrance
against erecting a Chinese laundry at No. 1410 East First Street",
and was referred to a committee of the council who, without giving the
petitioner a hearing, reported a recommendation that the council

(3).

<pb/>

refuse to grant its consent to said laundry, which report was adopted
by the council. It appears from these allegations that the reason
why the council withheld its consent to the maintainance of the
petitioner's laundry was that it was to be a Chinese laundry. The 
petitioner contends that by said action of the council a discrimination
unfavorable to him was made, for no reason save that he is a 
Chinaman, and that his arrest and detention are unlawful for the 
reason that they contravene the provisions of the 14th amendment in
that they deprive him of his liberty and property without due process
of law and deny him the equal protection of the laws. It is clear
that Sec. 6 of the ordinance above quoted gives to the common council
of the City of Seattle the arbitrary power to withhold permission
from any person or persons to conduct a laundry within the coporate
limits of the city unless it be located in a building constructed
of brick or stone and covered with a metal roof. That such an
ordinance is unlawful has been decided by the Supreme Court, in Yick
Wo v. Hopkins, 118 U.S., 356, as well as in several decisions at the
Circuit. Referring to the ordinance in that case, which was similar
to that which is under consideration in the case at bar, the court
said: "It does not prescribe a rule and conditions for the regulation
of the use of property for laundry purposes, to which all similarly
situated may conform. It allows without restriction the use for
such purposes of buildings of brick and stone; but, as to wooden
buildings, constituting nearly all those in previous use, it divides
the owners or occupiers into two classes, not having respect to their 
personal character and qualifications for the business, nor the
situation and nature and adaptation of the buildings themselves, but
merely by an arbitrary line, on one side of which are those who are 
permitted to pursue their industry by the mere will and consent of the

(4)

<pb/>

supervisors, and on the other those from whom that consent is withheld 
at their mere will and pleasure..... The ordinance, therefore, also
differs from the not unusual case, where discretion is lodged by law
in public officers or bodies to grant or withhold licenses to keep
taverns, or places for the sale of spirituous liquors, and the like,
when one of the conditions is that the applicant shall be a fit
person for the exercise of the privilege, because in such cases the
fact of fitness is submitted to the judgment of the officer, and 
calls for the exercise of a discretion of a judicial nature."

But it is contended that the doctrine of the Yick Wo case
is modified by the more recent decision of the Supreme Court in
Gundling v. Chicago, 177 U.S.,  183. In that case it was held that
an ordinance authorizing the issuance of licenses to persons to sell
cigarettes and forbidding their sale without license was constitutional,
but the ordinance differs from that in the Yick Wo case and
from that which is under consideration in the present case in that
it required that the applications for license be accompanied by evidence 
that the applicant was a person of good moral character and
reputation and required that the application and the evidence
accompanying the same should be submitted by the commissioner of 
health, together with his own opinion concerning the propriety of
granting such a license, to the may and that if the mayor should
be satisfied that the applicant was of good moral character and 
reputation, and suitable to be intrusted with the sale of cigarettes,
the license should issue upon the execution of a bond with sureties.
The court pointed out the distinction between that case and the
Yick Wo case and alluded to the fact that the ordinance in the Yick
Wo case was held to be illegal and violative of the 14th amendment,
because with reference to the subject upon which it touched, "it
conferred upon the municipal authorities arbitrary power at their
will and without regard to discretion in the legal sense of the term,

(5)

<pb/>

to give or withhold consent as to persons or places for carrying
on a laundry with reference to the competency of the persons applying
or the propriety of the place selected. It was also held
that there was a clear and intentional discrimination made against
the Chinese in the operation of the ordinance, which discrimination
was founded upon the difference of race and was wholly arbitrary and
unjust". 

It is contended also that the present case may be 
differentiated from the Yick Wo case by reading into the terms of 
Sec. 6 of the ordinance the provisions of Sections 2 and 3, but that
contention cannot be sustained. Sections 2 and 3 make general proovisions
regulating the license and maintenance of the laundry business 
and require arrangements to secure sanitary conditions, drainage, protection
against fire and official inspection of the premises. They
are generl provisions applicable to all laundries whether in wooden
buildings or brick or stone buildings with metal roofs. Sec. 6 is 
a distinct and separte grant to the council of arbitrary power to 
withold from any or all persons at will permission to maintain any
laundry not located in a building constructed of brick or stone and 
covered with a metal roof. With the violtion of that ordinance
and that ordinance alone, the petitioner is charged. The business
of conducting a laundry, while it is subject to the police power of
a municipal corporation, is not in itself a public nuisance and cannot
be made such by the mere declaration of a city ordinance. If the
petitioner is to be deprived of the right to use his property in the
prosecution of a legitimate business, not dangerous or injurious to
oters, he can only be so deprived by a judgment of competent authority,
pronounced in the exercise of a judicial discretion so vested
as to observe due process of law and afford him the equal protection
of the laws.

Upon the allegations of the petition, th <add>writ</add> must issue as 
prayed for.

<unclear>Wm B. Gilbert</unclear>

<pb/>

1036 Tx

US Circuit Court
Dist of Washington.

In re
Lee Fong.
Habeas Corpus.

Opinion of
Wm B Gilbert.
Judge.

FILED IN THE
U. S. CIRCUIT COURT,
DIST OF WASHINGTON.

SEP 25 1902
A. REEVES AYRES, CLERK

HM Walthew Dep. 


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>