<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0000.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1891">1891</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-09" who="#lkw">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

"In the Superior Court of the State of Washington, for King
County.

The State of Washington, Plaintiff.
vs
Adolph Krug and Henry Fihrman, Defendants.

Number 864.
Indictment.

Adolph Krug and Henry Fuhrman are accused by the Grand
Jury of the State of Washington, in and for King County, said state, 
by this indictment of the crime of using public money in order to
make a profit out of the same, and for purposes not then and there 
authorized by law, committed as follows:

That on the 2nd day of July, 1892, the said Adolph Krug
then and there being and at said time was a city officer, to-wit:
the duly elected, qualified and acting city treasurer of the City
of Seattle, in the County of King, State of Washington, and being
then and there charged under the provisions of the charter and the
amendments thereto of the said city of Seattle, the said charter
being commonly known as the Freeholder' charter, with the receiving
and safe keeping of all moneys belonging to and the property of
the said city of Seattle; the said city of Seattle then and there
being a municipal corporation duly organized and existing under and
by virtue of the laws of the Territory (now state) of Washington,
and as such officer and city treasurer as aforesaid, the said
Adolph Krug was then and there by virtue of his said city office
entrusted with the sum and amount of $10,000.00 in lawful money,
for safe keeping, the same being public money belonging to and the 
property of the said city of Seattle, and which said money was under
the care, custody and control of the said Adolph Krug as such officer
and city treasurer as aforesaid, and the said Adolph Krug, officer
and city treasurer as aforesaid on the 2nd day of July, 1892 in said
King County, State of Washington, unlawfully, feloniously and in a 
manner not authorized by law, did use the said $10,000.00 public
money as aforesaid, of the value of $10,000.00 in lawful money,
in order to make a profit out of the same and for a purpose then
and there not authorized by law; and the said Henry Fuhrman then
and there at the time aforesaid, the said Adolph Krug in the manner
and form as aforesaid unlawfully and feloniously did aid, counsel,
abet and assist,

Contrary to the form of the statute in such cases made
and provided and against the peace and dignity of the state of
Washington.

Dated at Seattle in the county and state aforesaid, this
the 23rd day of October, 1893.

John F. Miller.

Prosecuting Attorney. "

(3)

<pb/>

which indictment is alleged to be framed and founded under
Section 57 of the Code of Washington, known as the Second
Volumbe of Hill's Code.

That upon the said indictment there was a trial had before
jury of the County of King, and the jury in that said cause,
Number 864 rendered a verdict of guilty.

That upon the said verdict an alleged judgment was rendered
against the defendant by one of the Judges of the Superior 
Court of King County, in words and figures following, to-wit:

IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON FOR THE COUNTY OF
KING.

Monday March 26, 1894.

The State of Washington,
864
vs
Adolph Krug, impleaded with
Henry Furhman,

Motion denied,
Sentence, etc.

And now this cause comes on for further hearing on defendant's 
motion to set aside verdict and for a new trial, pursuant to continuance,
thereof, the State appearing by the Prosecuting Attorney,
John F.Miller, and defendant appearing in person and by his Counsel,
Messrs. Lewis, Gilman &amp; Fishback. And now upon due consideration 
thereof said defendant's motion for a new trial is denied, to
which ruling defendant excepts and the exception is allowed, defendant
thereupon moves the court for arrest of judgment; which motion
on consideration thereof is denied. Exception taken by defendant
is allowed.

And now upon motion of the Prosecuting Attorney the said defendant,
Adolph Krug, is brought before the bar of the court to be 
sentenced.

And no legal cause being shwon or appearing to the court why
judgment should not be pronounced upon the defendant, the court
sentences the said defendant, Adolph Krug, to be punished by confinement 
at hard labor in the Penitentiary of the State of Washington
for a term of Seven (7) years and to pay all costs of this action
Defendant's counsel therupon give notice in open court 
of their appeal from the verdict and the judgment of this court to
the Supreme Court of the State of Washington. And the Court fixes
and determines the amount of defendant's Appeal Bond in the sum of
$5.000.00

<pb/>

which judgment was rendered on the 26th day of March
1894.

V1.

That the said alleged judment is still in existence.
That the same has been appealed from to the Supreme Court of
the State of Washington, and the said judgment affirmed, and is
now in existence and in force and full effect. That under said
judgment the said Moyer assumes to imprison and to keep imprisoned
and to have imprisoned in the penitentiary of the State of
Washington this petitioner, and now threatens and continues to
threaten to seize the body of this petitioner from his present
imprisonment and convey him to further imprisonment, to-wit:
to the penitentiary of the state of Washington, where he is
to be held for the petiod of Seven years.

V11.

That the imprisonment of this petitioner by the said
Moyer, or any other person, under the said alleged judgment
and proceeding would wholly be contrary to petitioner's right
as a citizen of the United States, and particularly in violation
of your petitioner's rights as a citizen of the United States,
contrary to the laws of the United States, in violation of the
Constitution of the United States and directly against the
special right and immunity and exemption from imprisonment
without due process of law, as provided by the Constitution of
the United States, in behalf of this petitioner as a citizen of
the United States; all of which more particularly appears in
the following, detailed, manifested and exhibited to the Court,
viz:

V111.

That the Constitution of the United States prescribes
in Article VI., that "No person shall be held, etc., to answer

(5)

<pb/>

the charge of an infamous crime without due process of law
###". And the further provision that "Such person when held
or attempted to be held shall by indictment be informed of the
nature and cause of the accusation". That this provision was in
pursuit of the Common Law and meant that the facts and circumstances 
of the charge shall be presented to the defendant in
complete detail, that he may understand the same and prepare to
defend himself with the same detail essential to meet the charge
against him.

1X.

That the State of Washington when admitted into the
Union was admitted by express contract in the Enabling Act
that the Constitution of the State of Washington should not be
repugnant to or inconsistent with the Federal Constitution.
That in view and in pursuit of this provision and mandate, 
the Constitution of the state of Washington did provide and 
does now provide and at all times hereinafter state it was
provided that "In Criminal prosecutions the accused shall have
the right ### to demand the nature and cause of the accusation 
against him; to have a copy thereof, etc.", being Section
22 of the Constitution.

X.

That notwithstanding such provisions, this petitioner was
arraigned upon the form of alleged indictment hereinbefore stated
and immediately in the Superior Court demurred to the same upon
the ground that it did not state the facts nor inform him of the 
nature and cause of his accusation; that the Code of Washington
provided that in all criminal offenses, being the laws of
Washington, and in all informations or indictments, the information
or the indictment must contain ### a statement of the acts
constituting the offense, in ordinary and concise language,
without repetitions, and in such a manner as to enable a person of

(G)

<pb/>







</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>