<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0451.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>A. A. De Meules v. John H. McGraw. Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Ham, Bethany R." xml:id="brh">Bethany R. Ham</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0451.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">A. A. De Meules v. John H. McGraw. Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1889-08-16">August 16th, 1889</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives</repository>
<collection>King Frontier Justice</collection>
<idno>Case No 7071</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1889-08">August 1889</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Faskie, Stewart</term>
<term>Harmon, H. T.</term>
<term>Hopkins, R. M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
<term>Slaughter, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>De Meules, A. A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>McGraw, John H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, Cornelius H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>King County</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-06" who="#brh">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0451.002"/>

<p>
Territory of Washington
County of King ss.
In the District Court of the 3rd Judicial District of Washington Territory, holding term at Seattle for said County of King. In chambers,
</p>
<p>In the matter of the application of A. A. De Meules for a writ of Habeas Corpus. 
Petition</p>

<p>
For Hon. C. H. Hanford Judge of the District Court of the 3rd Judicial District of Washington Territory</p>

<p>Your petitioner A. A. De Meules respectfully shows that he is unlawfully imprisoned, detained, confined and restained of his liberty by behalf of McGraw Sheriff of King County W. T. and Stewart <unclear>Faskie</unclear>, Jailor of King County W. T. at the County Jail in said King County, W. T. at Seattle.</p>

<p>That the said detention imprisonment confinement</p> 
<pb></pb>
<p>and restraint are illegal; and that the illegality thereof consists of this to wit that the Justice of the Peace who tried the said cause and sentenced this said petitioner at Slaughter King Co. Washington Territory. had no jurisdiction over either the person herein or of the offence committed, if any offence was committed, because said Justice was not enformed by any authority of law whithin to issue process agaisnt or try said Deft. because he had not an authority of Justice of the Peace for Slaughter. Preceint King County where law offence was alledged to have been committed tried sued that said <add>warrant of</add> commitment shows the same and that said Justice of the Peace had no authority of law to either try <unclear>couriet</unclear> or sentence this from petitioner under the laws of Washington Ter. and that your petitioner is detained</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>and restrained of his liberty without any warrant or process of law.</p>
<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus may be granted, directed to the said John H. McGraw and Stewart Faskie commanding them to have the body of A. A. De Meules known in the warrant of committment as John Doe, before your honor forthwith to so and receive what shall there and then be considered by your honor concerning him in this behalf and that from petitioner may be restored to his liberty.

Dated Aug 16th 1889, 
+ A. A. De Meules</p>
<p>
Territory of Washington
County of King ss.
a. a. De Meules being duly sworn deposes and says that he is the petitioner named in the foregiving petition subscribed by him, that he has</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>heard the foregiving petition read, and knows the contents thereof and that the statements therein mean he believes to be fine L
x A. A. De Meules

Subscribed and sworn before me this 16th day of Aug 1889,
Julius Rochester
Notary Public for Washington Territory.</p>

<p>
Let a writ of Habeas Corpus issue as prayed for returnable before me August 20th 1889 at Ten o'clock A.M. 
C. H. Hanford 
Judge </p>

<pb></pb>
<p>7071
In the Matter of the application of a. a. De Meules for a writ of Habeas Corpus

FILED
R M Hopkins 
Clerk.
H. T. Harmon
 Deputy Clerk.
</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>