<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0208.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ichitara Matsutsuyu v. Henry M. White. Order to Show Cause</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0208.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ichitara Matsutsuyu v. Henry M. White. Order to Show Cause</title>
<date when="1919-12-02">December 2, 1919</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1919-12">December 1919</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Matsutsuyo, Ichitara</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wardell, Ray M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Moore, Ben L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-01" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>50B-7-475</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Dec 2, 1919</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>

<p>By. <gap></gap> Deputy</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 4918</p>

<p>Order Directing Henry M. White to Show Cause Why Habeas Corpus Should Not Issue.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Ichitara Matsutsuyo to be Released on Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>This cause coming on to be heard upon the petition of Ichitara Matsutsuyu for Writ of Habeas Corpus, and it appearing from the petition that said Petitioner is entitled to an order requiring respondent, Henry M. White, United States Commissioner of Imigration at Seattle, to show cause why the Writ of Habeas Corpus, as prayed for, should not be granted and petitioner discharged from custody; and the Court being duly advised in the premises, it is hereby ordered and decreed that said Henry M. White, as commissioner of Imigration at Seattle be, and he hereby is, required to be and appear before the above Court on the <del>8th</del> <add>6th</add> at <del>two</del> in the forenoon of said day, then and there to show cause, if any he has, why the Writ of Habeas Corpus should not issue in said cause, the relief therein prayed for be granted and the petitioner, Ichitara Matsutsuyu be discharged from custody.</p>

<p>It is further ordered and decreed that pending the return of this show cause order, the said Henry M. White be, and he hereby is enjoined and restrained from removing the petitioner, Ichitara Matsutsuyu from the city of Seattle to any place beyond the jurisdiction of this Court, the purpose of this order being to keep the said petitioner, Ichitara Matsutsuyu safely in detention at Seattle or such other place within this district as may, by law, be required so that he may be produced in person before this Court on the day heretofore mentioned in this Order.</p>

<p>IT IS FURTHER ORDERED that the Marshal of this Court serve this restraining order forthwith.</p>

<p>Done in open Court this 2nd day of December,1919.</p>

<p>Jeremiah Neterer</p>
<p>United States District Judge.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>