<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0172.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>D.A. Hatfield v. Robert T. Hodge. Petition.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0172.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">D.A. Hatfield v. Robert T. Hodge. Petition.</title>
<date when="1912-02-06">Feburary 2, 1912</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno>2082DAHatfield</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1912-02">Feburary 1912</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Sickles, D. K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Sickles, W. K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Stark, Allen</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>VanBlaricon, L. P.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>McGraw, James E.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Workman, George W.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Murphy, John E.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hatfield, D. A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Hodge, Robert T.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>McBride, A. J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Murphy, John F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney-defendant">
<persName>Caldwell, Hugh W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington Territory</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-09" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States for the
Northern District of Washington.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of D.A. Hatfield for a writ of 
Habeas Corpus.</p>
<ab>2082</ab>
<p>The said petitioner, D.A. Hatfield, most respectfully shows
to said above entitled court, and to the Hon. C. H. Hanford, one of
the Judges thereof, as follows:</p>
<p>That your said petitioner, D.A. Hatfield, is unjustly, wrongfully and illegally deprived of his liberty by Robert Hodge, as sheriff
and ex-officio jailer of King county, Washington, and is unlawfully
confined in the jail of King county, Washington, in the City
of Seattle, King county, Washington, by the said Robert Hodge, aforesaid,
without due process of law and in controvention
of the fifth amendment to the consitution of the United States.</p>
<p>That the cause of such illegal imprisonment and detention
as aforesaid is as follows:</p>
<p>That about June 16th, 1911, your petitioner was informed
against by the prosecuting attorney in and for King county, Washington, by an information duly signed, verified and filed in words and figures as follows:
In the superior court of the state of Washington, </p>
<p>For King County,
Satate of Washington,
Plaintiff,
-vs-
D.A. Hatfield and 
George W. Workman,
Defendants. } No. 5880.</p>
<p>Information</p>
<p>I, John F. Murphy, prosecuting Attorney in and for the county
of King, State of Washington, come now here in the name of and by
the authority of the state of Washington and by this information
<fw>1</fw>
<pb/>
do accuse D.A. Hatfield and George W. Worman, and each of them, of 
the crime of attempting to escape from prison, committed as follows,
towit:</p>
<p>He, said D.A. Hatfield in the county of King, State of Washington
on the 12th day of May, 1911, was confined and held in a prison, to wit, the King County jail, located in the city of Seattle, in said
county adn state, on a charge, conviction, and sentence of felony,
towit, forgery in the first degree, theretofore duly made, rendered
and impored against him in cause numbered 5589 in the superior
court of the state of Washington for King county, asn was then and there confined and held in said prison on a charge of felony, towit,
forgery in the first degree, theretofore duly made against him
in cause numbered 5622 in said superior court, and he, said George W. Workman was then and there confined and held in said prison on
a charge, conviction and sentence of felony, towit, carnal knowledge 
of a child, duly made rendered and imposed against him in cause 
numbered 5779 in said superior court. And they, said D.A. Hatfield
and George W. Workman, and each of them, while then and there being
so confined and held in said prison, did then and there wilfully,
unlawfully and feloniously and by force, attempt to escape from
said prison by obtaining from outside said prison, through means
which are to the prosecuting attorney unknown, acid, saws and blow
pipe, and by then and there using and attempting to use said acid
blow pipe and saws in sawing and cutting the iron bolts and bars
of said prison, for the purpose of making an aperture therein,
through or by means of which they, or either of them might escape.</p>
<p>Contrary to the state in such case made and provided, and 
against the peace and dignity of the state of Washington.</p>
<ab>John F. Murphy,
Prosecuting Attorney</ab>
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
<p>State of Washington,
County of King, }ss</p>
<p>Hugh M. Caldwell, being first duly sworn, on oath says
that he is deputy prosecuting attorney in and for the county of
King, state of Washington; that he has read the foregoing information, 
knows the contents thereof, and believes the same to be true.</p>
<ab>Hugh M. Caldwell.</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 16th day of June, 1911.</p>
<ab>D.K. Sickles,
Clerk Superior Court of King county,
State of Washington, by W.K. Sickles,
Deputy.</ab>
<p>Witnesses for the state:
Robert T. Hodge
Allen Stark.
L.P. VanBlaricon.</p>
<p>Filed June 16th, 1911,</p>
<ab>D.K. Sickles, Clerk.</ab>
<p>That thereafter, your petitioner was duly tried on said charge
attempted to be set forth in said information and was found guilty
by a jury and thereafter was sentenced by said superior court
to be confined in the pententiary of the state of Washington, for
a period of not less than two years, which said judgment and sentence
was sustained and affirmed by the Supreme Court of the state
of Washington, and the said Robert T. Hodge, Sheriff and jailer as
aforesaid threatens to deliever your petitioner to the agents of
the state of Washington, for the purpose of convaying him to the
pententiary at Walla Walla. That if there is any other <add>legal</add> cause of
the dentention and imprisonment of your petitioner than that set
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
forth, your Petitioner is not informed thereof, but if there is any other casue of detention, the same is unjust and unlawful.</p>
<p>That the illegality of said unlawful imprisonment and detention
as claimed by your petitioner mherein may be more particularly
state and described, as follows:</p>
<p>That siad infromation attempting to charge your petitioner 
with the offense of attempted escape from prison does not state
or charge a crime against the laws of the state of Washington,
and is null and void and cannot become the basis of a valid
judgment for the reason that that the said information fails to 
show that that at the time of the commission of the alleged pretended
offense, your petitioner was in lawful custody, and fails to
show that your petitioner was imprisoned by virtue of a written
committment. That under our system of criminal jurisprudence
"no person can be deprived o his liberty on accounty of some"
"criminal charge against him except by virtue of some <del>written</del>"
"Written authority therefor, except in causes where the accused may"
"be arrested before any warrant has been issued. But even in cases"
"where the accused may be arrested withour warrant, he must be immediately"
"taken before a maristrate, and a complaint filed against"
"him, and a warrant issued wherewith to hold him, or the custody"
"of him would become unlawful."</p>
<p>Wherefore, your Petitioner prays that a Writ of Habeas Corpus
be issued herein and that upon a hearing thereon, your Petitioner
be discharged.</p>
<ab>D.A. Hatfield
Petitioner.</ab>
<ab>AJ McBride
Atty for Petitioner
406 Eplor Block
Tel. Francis 2114.</ab>
<fw>4</fw>
<p>State of Washington,
County of King, SS.</p>
<p>D.A. Hatfield, who being duly sworn on his oath says he
is the Petitioner named in the within and foregoing petition for
a writ of Habeas Corpus; That he has read the same and knows the
contencts thereof, and that the allegations and statements therein
contained are true in substance and in fact.</p>
<ab>DA Hatfield</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this Fifth dat of Feburary, 1912.</p>
<ab>James E. McGraw
Notary Public for the state of
Washington, residing at Seattle.</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>