<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0241.018"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Summary of Case</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>

<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0241.018</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Territory of Washington v. Walker et al. Summary of Case</title>
<date when="1885-07-17">July 17, 1885</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1885-07">July 1885</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Hughs, W.</term>
<term>Lockwood, William Morrell</term>
<term>McCoys, Mare</term>
<term>Walker, Charles</term>
<term>Walker, M.A.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places">
<term></term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Walker, M.A.</persName>
<persName>Walker, Charles</persName>
<persName>Walker, Helen</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Campbell, A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court For The Western District of Washington Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="#sab">transcribed, encoded</change> 
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0241.018"/>

<p>Adj- Friday July 17th '85</p>
<p>H.B. Lockwood: sworn: Am a labourer: and a brother of the deceased: his name Wm Morrell Lockwood saw him last upon last Tuesday afternoon he accomplished me to the wart as I was going to Port Townsend with M M.A. Walker: M Walker and I returned on the Olympian <del>with Mr. Walker</del> Thursday night heard <del>the boat</del> some of the boat officers say that "fora wonder the boat is on time tonight": do ot think that it was much after ten when boat got in: stores were open on Pacific Av when we came up: we walked up the Pacific Ar. hell rather last and reached a point newly opposite the Halded house before boat Hotel Tusses passed us the runner for the Western Hotel (Billy) asked us to ride. But we refused: went straight home: did not stop anyplace, but to get a drink of water at the top by Mare McCoys store: then proceeded directly home: I left Mr Walker at 19th &amp; Jefferson near M Hughes feed store: should judge that it was before 11.30 when I left Mr Walkers company: don't think it would take much over half an hour to walk from wharf to that point as we walked: I then went home: saw nothing more of Mr Walker: he took the man road up toward where the Weiller house stood. Soon after the 4th of July write came into our room we were sleeping together and asked me where my revolver was: I kept in the washstand drawer and he went there and took it cut and then came to bed I was in bed at the time: he told me that the Walker boys were after him and asked me to tell them if they came to the house that he had been in bed an hour or so that</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
