<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0154.006"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0154.006</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">October 14, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date></term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Clifford, Peter A.
Long (Clifford, Williams), Grace E.
Clifford, Alice B.
Burt. J.  J.
White, W. H. 
DeLang, James
Hanford, C. H.
Ayres, A. Reeves
Matthew, H. M.
Herice, Deevnay 
Fuller, Melville W.  
Hopkins, C. B.
Stringer, John
Heade, Matthew H.
Tallman, Boyd J.
Humphreys, William P.
Allison, William B.
Norris, George E.
Huxston, R. I.
Koepfli, C. A.
Brewster, J. M.
Moor, A. N. 
Drake, James C.
Wright, B. O. 
</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Georgetown, King County, Washington
San Francisco, San Francisco County, California
Seattle, King County, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Clifford, Peter A.</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Long (Williams, Clifford), Grace E.
Williams, Herbert O.</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>White, W. H.
Burt, J. J. 
Steiner, G. E.
Sweeney
French
</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>
Humphreys, William P.</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.
Tallman, Boyd J.</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0154.001"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->

<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, NINTH JUDICIAL CIRCUIT,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN
DIVISION.</p>

<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
Vs
Herbert O. Williams and 
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
No.
R e p l y . </p>

<p>Comes now the Petitioner herein and replying to the answer
of the respondents herein, replies as follows:</p>

<p>Said Petitioner denies that by any reason of the writ of habeas
corpus in Number 41787, or of any proceedings, or of any adjudica-
tion of the Superior Court of the County of King, State of
Washington, or of any Judges thereof, referred to in the answer of
respondents, or by reason of any thingtherein, or any proceedings
between the parties hereot, or any other persons or parties, he is 
estopped from further questioning any right or rights claimed by 
said respondents, or either of them, as to the custody of said
child, Alice B. Clifford.</p>

<p>And in further reply said Petitioner avers and alleges:</p>

<p>That upon the hearing of said proceeding in said Superior
Court and before the Honorable Boyd J. Tallman, the Judge before
whom said hearing of said habeas corpus proceeding was had, said
Petitioner presented and put in evidence a copy of the judicial
records and proceedings of the Superior Court of the City
and in the notion granting the divorce referred to in his petition herein
County of San Francisco, State of California, 
authentioated a provided i Section 905 of the Revised Statutes 
of the United States, and claimed the right to the custody of
said child upon the ground that is was being imprisoned and
detained by respondents, and each of them, in violation of Article
exemplified and
IV, Section 1 of the United States and Section 905 of the Revised
Statutes of the United States, and demanded that in pursuance of
said provision of said Constitution and said provision of said
Revised Statutes if the United States, full faith and credit to
said records of said Superior Court of California should be given
by said Court of Washington and the respondents herein, and that
said child should be released from the imprisionment and detention
by said respondents, and each of them, and delivered into the
custody of your Petitioner, to be by him taken back to the juris-
diction of said Court of California; but said Superior Court of
 Washington refused, and it appears upon the face of the records and
proceedings of said Superior Court of Washington, in said habeas
corpus proceedings therein, that said Court refused, to give any
faith or credit to the records or proceedings of the said Court of
California; and your Petitioner sets up and claims under said
Article IV, Section 1, of the Constitution of the United States,
and said Section 905 of the Revised Statutes of the United States,
that said record and proceedings of said Superior Court of Wash-
ington in the application therein for a writ of habeas corpus should
be disregarded by this Court and held to be of no force or effect
whatever.
 </p>

<p>Further replying to the answer of the respondents herein, as
to the adoption of said child by proceedings in Number 5262 of
said Superior Court of the State of Washington, said Petitioner
avers and alleges that by reason of the facts set out in his
petition herein, said child at the time said adoption proceedings
were commended and had, and ever since, has been, a resident of and
at all of said time had and yet has her domicile in the State of
California, and that the facts of such residence and domicile and
her being a ward of said Superior Court of California and subject
to the control and jurisdiction thereof, were made to appear before
the said Superior Court of Washington when said proceedings for
the adoption of said child were taken and had therein, and said
domicile and said wardship of said child appear upon the face of
the records and proceedings of said Superior Court of said State of
Washington in the matter of the adoption of said child, which
consist of a petition by the respondents herein to be allowed to
adopt said child, a copy of which is hereto attached marked
"Exhibit A" and made a part hereof, a written consent to the
adoption of said child, a copt of which is hereto attached, marked
"Exhibit B" and made a part hereof, and an order for the adoption
of said child, a copy of which is attached to the answer of the
respondents herein marked "Exhibit E", and which is hereby
referred to and made a part hereof, and of them alone; but
nevertheless the said Court of Washington refused to give any
faith or credit to the said records or proceedings of said Court
of California, and made and entered said order allowing said
adoption of said child; and your Petitioner hereby sets up and
claims that under said Article IV, Section 1 of the Constitution
of the United States and Section 905 of the Revised Statutes
thereof, said order allowing said adoption is void, and of no
force or effect.</p>

<p>And further replying as to the now pending in the
Superior Court of the State of Washington in and for the County of
King to set aside said order of adoption, said Petitioner alleges
that said proceeding is nothing more than to have expunged from
the records of that Court an order claimed by said Petitioner to 
be void and of no affect, and presents to reason why this appli-
cation should be denied, abated or continued</p>

<p>And further replying to Exhibit C of respondents' answer,
reffered to and adopted by them as a portion of their answer 
herein, said petitioner denies, as alleged in Parahraph IX thereof,
that no notice whatever was served upon them, or either of them, or
that they, or either of them, received no information as to the
change of the decree of the Court of California as to this custody
of said child; and on the contrary alleges that eight days' notice of the 
motion to modify the decree was given and served upon William P.
Humphreys. Esq., who was and yet is the attorney of record for
Grace E. Williams in the action wherein said decree was made and
entered.</p>

<p>Futher replying to Paragraoh I of the affirmative defense of respondents' Exhibit C
adopted as a portion of their answer herein, said Petitioner
alleges and avers that all of thematters and things therein set up
and alleged were set upp ad alleged in the complaints in actions
brought by Grace E. Williams, as Grace E. Clifford, against your
Petitioner in the said Court of California, wherein your Petitioner
was granted a divore from her, and all of such matters and things
were adjudged and decreed by said Court against her and in favor
of your Petitioner, and are barred by the judgments therein, one
which is the judgment granting said divorce; and further
replying as to the matters and things set out in said paragraph,
said Petitioner avers and alleges that they are beyond the jurisdiction of
this Court upon this application, and are solely and exclusively
within the jurisdiction of said Superior Court of California.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, Petitioner objects to the consideration by this
Court of any of the matters or things set out in this answer of
the respondents herein, and respondents are notified hereby that
upon the calling of this matter for hearing herein Petitioner will
move the Court for judgment upon the pleadings herein, and for the
granting of the prayer of his Petition herein; and in the case of the
Court's refusal to grant said motion Petitioner will then offer
evidence in support of his Petition herein, and of this Reply.
W H White
J. J. Burt
Attorneys for Petitioner.</p>

<p>State of Washington, )
County of King. ) ss.</p>

<p>J. J. Burt, being duly sworn, says; That he is one of the
attorneys for the Petitioner in the above entitled matter or
proceeding; that he has read the foregoing reply of the Petitioner
therein and knows the contents thereof, and that he verily believes
the same to be true. </p>

<p>Deponent further says that the reason he makes this affidavit
is that said Petitioner is absent from the State of Washington, and
in the State of California, and also that deponent is better in-
formed as to the facts stated in said reply than is the said
Petitioner.</p>

<p>J J Burt</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 15th day of June, A. D. 1904.</p>

<p>William B Allison
Notary Public in and for the State of
Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

<p>Exhibit A</p>

<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, FOR KING COUNTY.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Adoption of Alice B. Clifford, an infant, by
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams, his wife,</p>

<p>No.
Petition.</p>

<p>To the Hon. Boyd J. Tallman, one of the Judges of the above
entitled court:</p>

<p>The petition of Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams,
his wife, respectfully shows;</p>

<p>1. That petitioners Herbert O. Williams and Grace E.
Williams are and ever since the 15th day of August, 1903, have
been husband and wife, and are residents of Seattle, King County,
Washington.</p>

<p>a. That your petitioners desire to adopt as their own an
infant female child named Alice B. Clifford, and to change the
name of said child to Alice B. Williams.</p>

<p>3. That the parents of said child, Peter A. Clifford and
his then wife, Grace E. Williams, were divorced by decree of the
Superior Court of San Francisco County, California, on the 20th
day of May, 1908, and that said decree by its terms awarded the
carem custody and control of said infant to its mother Grace E.
Clifford, now Grace E. Williams.</p>

<p>4. That said Peter A. Clifford and his then wife, Grace E.
Clifford, have ever since the issuanceof said decree, and for a
long time prior thereto, lived separate and apart, during all
of which time said infant, Alice B. Clifford, has been and now is
in the care, custody and control of its said mother, Grace E.
Williams.</p>

<p>5. That said Grace E. Williams and said infant, Alice B.
Clifford are residents of King County, Washington.</p>

<p>6. That your petitioners are persons of good oral
characterm industrious habits, and good prospects in life, of the
ages of 31 years and 32 years respectively, are amply able to 
provide a suitable home for said child, and are in every respect
fit and proper persons to be entrusted with the moral ad other
character of said child, and to make a reasonable provision for
its future usefulness and happiness in life. </p>

<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioners pray that by order of this court
said infant, Alice B. Clifford, shall from and after the date of
such order be deemed to all legal intent are purposes the child
of your petitioners, Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams,
and that said child be rendered capable of inheriting the estate
of your petitioners and each of them, and that the name of said
child be changed to Alice B. Williams.</p>

<p>Herbert O. Williams
Grace E. Williams</p>

<p>Sweeney and Steiner,
Attorneys for petitioners.</p>

<p>State of Washington
County of King.</p>

<p>Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams being first duly
sworn on oath say, each for himself, that they are the peti-
tioners above named, and that they have read the foregoing
petition, know the contents thereof, and that the same is true.</p>

<p>Herbert O. Williams
Grace E. Williams</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 18th day of Nov. 1903.
G. E. Steiner,
Notary Public in and for the State of Washington,
residing at Seattle.</p>

<p>Exhibit B</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Adoption of Alice B. Clifford, an infant, by
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams, his wife,</p>

<p>No.
Consent to Adoption.</p>

<p>State of Washington
County of King.</p>

<p>I, Grace E. Willia,s being first duly sworn say: That I am
the mother of Alice B. Clifford, the infant child mentioned in
foregoing petition of Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams,
his wife; that I was divorced from Peter A. Clifford, the father
of said child, in San Francisco County, California, on or about
the 20th day of May, 1902, and that the court in granting the
divorce awarded the care, custody and control of said
child; that I hereby consent to the adoption of said child, Alice
B. Clifford, by Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams, the
foregoing petitioners, and that the name of said child be changed
to Alice B. Williams.</p>

<p>Grace E. Williams</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 12th day of Nov. 1903.
G. E. Steiner
Notary Public in and for the State of Washington,
residing at Seattle.</p>

<p>ORIGINAL.
No. 1204 Tx</p>

<p>In the United States
C I R C U I T Court
FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN Division</p>

<p>Peter A. Clifford, 
Petitioner,
vs.
Herbert O. Williams and 
Grace E. Williams, 
Respondents.</p>

<p>R E P L Y . </p>

<p>FILED IN THE
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. of WASHINGTON.
JUN 15 1904
A. REEVES AYRES Clerk
HM Matthew
Deputy
W. H. White and
J. J. Burt,
Attorneys for Petitioner</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>