<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0162.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ray Raymond v. Territory of Washington. Testimony of Joseph Bradshaw</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
<name n="Hidalgo, Emily" xml:id="eh">Emily Hidalgo</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0162.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ray Raymond v. Territory of Washington. Testimony of Joseph Bradshaw</title>
<date when="1886-06-29">June 29, 1886</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Bradshaw, Joseph</term>
<term>Finch, James</term>
<term>May, Johnny</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Spokane County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Raymond, Ray</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Peel, J. J. L.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>        
<change when="2021-09" who="#lkw">review</change> 
<change when="2021-06" who="#eh">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0162.001"/>

<p>Joseph Bradshaw sworn</p>

<p>I knew the person that was
that his name was James Finch I 
<unclear>him</unclear> after he was shot I heard the report 
of the shot the fellow that was with 
me said <del>what is that</del> it's a shot 
we went over there Montgomery was with 
me saw the man lying on the floor
Policeman was inquiring who he was told 
him I knew him We left Colfax
together when I first entered I saw 
the two girls <add>now</add> sitting here (identifies them)
I asked who shot him, <del>y</del> probably
less than 5 minutes after the shot I got 
there Policeman was there when I got 
there, Next I see Policeman
had hold of the prisoner and he 
was leading her back and forth 
inquiring for he that and one thing 
and another, I looked at the man 
and saw he was wonded and 
could hardly breathe kinda excited 
me I did not take much notice 
to what was going on was watching 
him, Saw the Wound was on the right 
side of the neck near the collar bone</p>

<p>On turning round from looking 
at the man saw a Woman lying on 
the floor did not understand what 
she said when she came up, dont 
remember what she said she wanted 
to see Man that was dying

<pb/>

Policeman led her up their by the Arm
Kinda rung her hands and think 
she said is he dead or is he <del>dying</del> going 
to die at that next I see her she 
back right up, and was lying on the 
floor supposed, to be fainting 
(Show Diagram) Body laid with 
his shoulder across the threshold of the 
mines door Saw him after he 
was dead was with him when he 
died was the same James Finch 
I was with before</p>

<p>Cross Ex</p>

<p>Have known Jim about three months 
knew him first at Colfax the only 
name I knew by was Jim until
after his death and <del><unclear></unclear></del> <add>since that I recollected</add>
<del>Colefax <unclear></unclear></del> <add>of his name being called James Finch</add></p>

<p>Had been with him in the evening 
prior to the shooting between 10 &amp;
11 OClock seperated from him at 
the Brewery across from Mr. Barney
Smith, was under under the influence 
of liquor when he left me drinking
considerable not so bad so what he 
could get along all right told 
him he had better quit drinking 
or he would get into trouble did not 
come into town with him. First time
I saw him day preceeding the shooting
along in the evening after dark

<pb/>

<del>Think</del> I heard him say he had passed 
through Spokane Falls, don't know 
Johnny May <unclear> Leiss</unclear>, don't know if he 
were with deceased. Have seen this 
man drunk before  He was accustomed 
to getting drunk when when he could 
obtain Liquor He was a harmless Man 
when drunk or sober when I knew 
him One would think from his 
manner if they did not know him 
that he was a bad man although 
he was harmeless He had a pillow 
under his head when I saw him I think
when I got there they where putting a pillow
under his head, did not notice 
who it was helped move him down 
the Halll when pillow was put under his 
head when pillow was put under his 
head that he was laying across the 
threshold of the mines door, dont 
know who brought the pillow, dont 
know that the deft helped to place pillow 
under his head or not <del></del>
The man was lying in between the two
doors with pillow under his head when 
she requested policeman to see him 
they had not removed him there </p> 

<p> She apeared very Much distressed
about his condition <del> She was </del> I did 
not hear or see her ask any one to 
help him when she went with the 
Policeman <del></del> when She said O is he going 

<pb/>

to die, It was asked of no one in particular
I did not hear any one answer the 
Woman I saw on the floor was <unclear><!-- name? --></unclear>
<unclear></unclear> was past the entrance to the Parlor in 
the Hall I remember that I saw 
her fall dont know whether she fell 
or not Called to the Policeman and 
said she better put her in the Cooler </p>

<p>I did not think she was in a 
swoon was the reason I spoke so 
I did not <add>know</add> what her condition was</p>

<p>The Policeman had her by the arm 
leading around after she came to</p>

<p>I did not believe in it so I paid 
no attention I saw something done to 
bring her to I saw water slashing around 
there I drank two glasses beer that 
night I had been in the saloon that 
evenign a good deal I correct this statement 
I had not been in saloons a good deal</p>

<p>The first of the evening I went to the 
temperance lecture - the first saloon I 
visited was I Cannot tell I might have 
been in all of them was not in all of 
them was not in 5 or six probably 
four Drank in the Brewery when we 
had a quart of Beer <del>me</del> and the Man 
that got killed, There were four of 
us to drink it one glass was spilled 
I drank two half glasses - drank 
nothing from that time until I heard the 
shot about two hours <del> prior</del> subsequent 

<pb/> 

thats all I drank in the evening  might 
have drank some in the afternoon </p>

<p>In the other saloons went in and heard 
Music, Music in two of them only </p>

<p> In Saloon where no music we went in and
right out again</p>

<p>Redirect</p>

<p>Wounded Man was moved farther into the hall 
just past the door, I did not notice when 
the doctor <del></del> came prisoner was lying on the 
floor in the hall about where the dead 
man was lying just beyond the door that 
leads into the Parlor I saw the Prisoner 
lying on the floor and she was lying partly
on her side and they were throwing water 
on her directly I saw her up &amp;
a Policeman had hold of her she 
probably lay there a half minute 
did not fall heavy, went in the other 
room when she got up, thought 
she was putting on, I thought to many 
motions, I did not hear her say any 
thing, she made a few more few 
kicks laid on her side a second 
or two they got her up and took her 
in the other room was afraid she might 
get away Policeman had her by the arm 
wanted to get her hat or some clothes to go to 
the Cooler, did not hear Policeman say 
anything to her before she fell on to the floor</p>

<p> Took four of us to drink the Beer 
there was a fellow Came up that was 

<pb/>

Standing near the Bar Had been to 
the temprance lecture did not have
any affect on me</p>

<p>Recross</p>

<p>I did not see her fall</p>

<p>Laid there about half Minute did not 
look at my watch Know how long a 
half minute is have held my breath 
one minute looked at my watch 
while so doing didnt hold my breath 
or my tongue while she was down</p>

<p>After she <add>got through</add> put water on
her face she lay there a few seconds 
it might have been less half miute</p>

<p>I was standing near the mans feet
I kept an eye on her to see that she 
did not get away</p>

<p>Redirect </p>

<p> Did not see her fall she just
kinda rolled over on her side with her 
head toward the other end of the wall 
did not see her go down to the floor</p>

<p>Joseph Branshaw</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me on this 
June 29 th 1886 </p>

<p>JJL Peel</p>

<p>Justice of the Peace</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>