<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>In Re: Ex Parte - Donald Kerracher - Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Banse, AD" xml:id="ab">AD Banse</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0270.00</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">In Re: Ex Parte - Donald Kerracher - Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="2022-06-13">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">2022-06-21</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName> Donald MC Kerracher</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName> C.B. Hopkins</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>C.H. Hanford</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

          
<div1 type="case">

<p>  In the United StatesCirtuit Court, For the Ninth Judicial Circuit,
    Western District of the State of Washington, Northern Division. </p>

<p> In Re. Ex Parte: 
    Donald MC Kerracher, 
    Petitioner. No. 1328</p>
<p> Exceptions. </p>

<p> Comes now the United States of America and Charles
    C. Hokpins, United States Marshal for the Western 
    District of Washington, respondents in the above en-
    titled matter, by Jesse A. Frye, United States Attorney
    for the Western District of Washington, and duly
    except to the order of disacharge made and entered in 
    the above entitled matter on the 20th day of Sep-
    tember 1905, for the reasons and upon the grounds
    following, to wit:   </p>


<p> I. 
    That Court erred in finding that the petitioner,
    Donald Mc Keeracher, was wrongfully restrained of his liberty, </p>

<p> II. 
    The Court erred in finding that the petitioner, 
    Donald Mc Kerracher, was unlawfully held in custody by
    the United States Marshal for the Western District of
    Washington. </p>

<p> III. 
    The Cout erred in holding and finding that the 
    petitioner, Donald Mc Kerracher, was unlawfully held
    in custody by the Warden of the United States Penitent-
    iary on McNeil's Island, Washington.  </p>

<p> IV.
    The Cout erred in holding and finding that the
    terms of imprisonment of the petitioner, Donald Mc Kerr-
    acher, had expried as provided by law. </p>

<p> V. 
    The Court erred in ordering and adjusting that the
    petitioner, Donald Mc Kerracher, was entitled to be
    discharged from the cusotdy of the United States
    Marshal for the Western District of Wahsington. </p>

<p> VI.
    The Court erred in ordering and directing the 
    United States Marshal for the Western District of 
    Washington to discharge said petitioner, Donald 
    Mc Kerracher, from custody and imprisonment.</p>

<p> VII. 
    The Court erred in ordering and directing that the 
    petitoner, Donald Mc Keeracher, be discharged from 
    the United States penitentiary on McNeil's Island, 
    Washington. </p>

<p> VIII. 
    The Court erred in ordering the petitioner, Donald
    Mc Keeracher, to be released from the custody of
    the officers of the United States.  </p>

<p> IX. 
    The Court erred in releasing and discharging the
    petitioner, Donald Mc Keeracher, from the custody of
    the officers of the United States and restoring him to
    his liberty.</p>

<p> X.  
    The Said order of discharge is not supported
    by the law controlling in the premises, </p>

<pb/>

<p> XI. 
    That said order of discharge is contrary to the 
    facts in the premises. </p>

<p>  XII. 
    That said order of discharge is not warranted by,
    nor supported by, the facts, nor by the law in the 
    premises, but is contrary thereto. </p>

<p> Dated this 20th day of September 1905. </p>
<p> Jesse A. Ayres, United States Attorney. </p>

<pb/>
<p>  Due and timely service of the within Exceptions, and the
    receipt of a true copyh thereof, acknowledged this 20th day of September 1905. </p>
<p> Metcalfe and Jurey, 
    Attorneys for Petitioner. </p>

     

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>