<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0214.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Kichitaro Kubota and Ise Kubota v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0214.005</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Kichitaro Kubota and Ise Kubota v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1920-09-04">September 4, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-09">September 1920</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Akiyoshi, T</term>
<term>Joseph Perkins</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
<term>Japan</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Kubota, Kichitaro</persName>
<persName>Kubota, Ise</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Gallagher, John P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-03" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>No. 5556</p>

<p>Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>In the matter of the petition of Kichitaro Kubota and Ise Kubota, his wife, for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE JUDGES OF THE ABOVE ENTITLED COURT:</p>

<p>The petition of Kichitaro Kubota and Ise Kubota, his wife respectfully represents as follows:</p>

<p>That the said Kichitaro Kubota came to the United States on or about the first day of February 1911 as a sailor. That from said date he continuously resided in the United States of America up to on or about the first day of January 1919 when he left the United States of America upon a visit. That during practically all of said period of about eight years he resided in the city of San Francisco, California; that he was engaged there in the hotel business and now owns there a one-half interest in the hotel business., and restaurant.</p>

<p>That while in Japan on his said visit he married his present wife Ise Kubota and attempted to gain a passport back to the United States, but that some delay was caused in the issuing of said passport and he was not able to return immediately.</p>

<p>That he arrived from his visit in Japan in the United States on or about the first day of July 1920 and after a hearing and examination before the United States Commissionerof Immigration at the Port of Seattle and a Board of Special Enquiry convened for that purpose, your petitioners herein were excluded from the United States for the reason that Kichitaro Kubota never had a legal residence in the United States and that no passport should have been issued for his return to the United States, also</p>

<pb/>

<p>that they are parties liable to become a public charge.</p>

<p>That an appeal was taken from such decision to the Secretary of Labor, who on or about the 18th day of August 1920 dismissed, refused and denied said appeal.</p>

<p>That your petitioner Kichitaro Kubota is a duly domiciled alien having resided in the United States continuously for approximately eight years before returning to Japan. That he is the owner of property in the United States of America. That upon going to Japan he intended to return to the United States and that the delay of the Government in issued passport. That he is able to support himself and wife, having in his possession or under his control money and securities of the value of $400. <add>and <unclear></unclear> $2000</add> That he has a regular and lawful occupation, to-wit the occupation of conducting a hotel and restaurant and as a hotel-and restaurant keeper, and that his earnings generally average about the sum of $200 per month.</p>

<p>That your petitioners were denied a just and fair hearing but were arbitratily excluded and denied admission, because of prejudice and in utter disregard of the testimony and that petitioners now have in their possession other and additional proof showing their residente in the United States in addition to the submitted before the board of special enquiry, and that the board of special enquiry which heard the case of your petitioners was not legally constituted.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE your petitioners pray that a writ of Habeas Corpus may issue herein to the said Henry M. White, U.S. Immigration Commissioner for the Port of Seattle, commanding him that he do produce your petitioners before this court together with the cause of their detention and that upon hearing your petitioners be discharged and be permitted to land and be admitted into the United States of America and for such other and further relief</p>

<pb/>

 <p>as to the court may seem just and proper in the premises.</p>

<p>Kichitaro Kubota</p>
<p>Ise X Her Mark Kubota</p>
<p>Petitioners.</p>

<p>United States of America</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>County of King</p>

<p>SS:</p>

<p>KICHITARO KUBOTA and ISE KUBOTA his wife, being duly sworn according to law say:</p>

<p>That they are the petitioners above named; that the foregoing petition has been explained and interpreted to them and that the facts therein stated are true as they verily believe.</p>

<p>T. Akiyoshi witness to her mark</p>
<p>Joseph Perkins</p>

<p>Kichitaro Kubota</p>
<p>Ise X Her Mark Kichitaro</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 4th day of September, A.D 1920.</p>

<p>John P Gallagher</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington residing at Seattle.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>