<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0358.009">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>George Kotros v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0358.009</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">George Kotros v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1920-01-11">January 11, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-01">January 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Kato, Gin</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Myers, H.A.P</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</p>

<p>No. 5778</p>

<p>Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of GEORGE KOTROS for a writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>To the Honorable Judges of the above-entitled court:</p>

<p>Your petitioner respectfully represents and shows:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That he is a citizen of the Kingdom of Greece. That in the year 1912 he emigrated to the United States and landed in the City of New York and was duly admitted into the United States; that immediately thereafter he came to the State of Washington, and ever since said time has been and now is a resident of said states.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>That on the 21st day of June, 1920, petitioner was arrested under and by virtue of a warrant issued by the Assistant United States Secretary of Labor, which warrant charged petitioner with the following:</p>

<p>(a) That he procured or attempted to procure or import a prostitute or person for the purpose of prostitution, or other immoral purpose.</p>

<p>(b) That he entered the United States for an immoral purpose.</p>

<p>(c) That he was a person likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry.</p>

<p>(d) That he entered without inspection.</p>

<p>III.</p>

<p>That thereafter petitioner was given a purported hearing before one of the United States inspectors at the United States Immigration Station at Seattle, Washington; that thereafter the proceedings against this petitioner were forwarded to the Secretary</p>

<pb/>

<p>of Labor, at Washington, D.C. That thereafter, and on or about the 15th day of December, 1920, a purported order was signed and made by Louis F. Post, Assistant Secretary of Labor, by the terms of which petitioner herein was ordered to be deported to the Kingdom of Greece.</p>

<p>IV.</p>

<p>That ever since the arrest of this petitioner as aforesaid, (except a very short period of time during which petitioner was at large under bail) he has been and is now detained and imprisoned in the United States Immigration Station at Seattle, Washington, by Henry M. White, United States Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle.</p>

<p>V.</p>

<p>Your petitioner further alleges and shows that his detention and imprisonment as aforesaid is illegal, in this, to-wit:</p>

<p>FIRST: That in said proceedings for the deportation of this petitioner he was not accorded a fair hearing, because:</p>

<p>(a) The evidence adduced against petitioner consists of the evidence of this petitioner and of one Mary Merkovich, and the evidence of said Mary Merkovich was taken in the absence of this petitioner and without his consent;</p>

<p>(b) That letters and documents of a highly damaging character were introduced and used in said deportation proceedings, none of which was identified or sworn to.</p>

<p>(c) That petitioner was compelled in said proceedings to be a witness against himself, contrary to the provisions of Article 5 of the Amendments to the Constitution of the United States.</p>

<p>SECOND: There was no evidence adduced in said deportation proceedings to support any of the charges contained in the warrant of arrest aforesaid; and the charges set forth in said warrant are untrue.</p>

<p>THIRD: That the executive immigration officer abused their discretion in recommending and ordering the deportation of this petitioner, because the evidence shows that the only thing done by petitioner was an attempt to marry the said Mary Merkovich, heretofore referred to, and to whom this petitioner had been engaged, and to continuously support her and her two children.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, to be relieved of said unlawful detention and imprisonment your petitioner prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus, to be directed to the said Henry M. White, United States Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, may issue in his behalf, so that your petitioner may be forthwith brought before this Honorable Court to do, submit to, and receive what the law may direct. And your petitioner will ever pray.</p>

<p>George Kotros</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>

<p>United States of America</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>County of King</p>

<p>SS</p>

<p>GEORGE KOTROS being first duly sworn, deposes and says: that he is the petitioner named in the foregoing petition; that he has heard the same read: and that he knows the contents thereof and the allegations therein set forth are true.</p>

<p>George Kotros</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 11th day of January, 1921.</p>

<p>Margarete B <unclear>Lerise</unclear></p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle</p>

<p>No. 5778</p>

<p>District Court of the United States</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>In re application of GEORGE KOTROS for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District County</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Jan 12 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<p>H.A.P. Myers</p>
<p>1160 Empire Building,</p>
<p>Seattle, Washington</p>

<p>Attorney for Petitioner</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>