<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0253.002"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Davis v. Davis. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0253.002</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Davis v. Davis. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1888-11-27">November 27, 1888</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1888-11"></date>November 1888</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Davis, Maggie</term>
<term>Davis, Nelson</term>
<term>Davis, Sarah M.</term>
<term>Langford, William G.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Colfax, Washington Territory</term> 
<term>Whitman County</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Davis, Nelson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Davis, Sarah M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Brown</persName>
<persName>Chadwick</persName>
<persName>Sullivan</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Langford, William G.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court For The First Judicial District Court</orgName> 
<placeName>Colfax, Whitman County, Washington Territory</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020" who="#sab">encoded, transcribed, edited.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0253.002"/>

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF WASHINGTON TERRITORY AND FOR THE FIRST JUDICIAL DISTRICT THEREOF HOLDING TERMS AT COLFAX IN WHITMAN COUNTY, IN SAID TERRITORY.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION "  PETITION FOR WRIT
OF NELSON DAVIS FOR THE CUSTODY "     OF HABEAS CORPUS
OF MAGGIMDAVIS A MINOR CHILD</p>

<p>TO THE HON. WILLIAM G. LANGFORD,
JUDGE OF THE ABOVE ENTITLED COURT AND ASSOCIATE JUSTICE OF THE SUPREME COURT OF WASHINGTON TERRITORY:-</p>

<p>The Petition of Nelson Davis, respecfully shows;- 
That petitioner and Sarah M. Davis inter-married at Columbia County, Washington Territory, on the 23rd day of July, 1874 and ever since have been and now are husband and wife; and are now and have been for several years preceding this Petition, residents of Whitman County, Washington Territory.</p>
<p>That the issue of said marriage is one child, Maggie M Davis, of the age of eleven years.</p>
<p>That in the County of Whitman, Territory of Washington, on the 19th day of November, 1888, the said Sarah M. Davis, disregarding the solemnity of her marriage vews, and that duties and obligations as a wife, wilfully and without cause, deserted and abandoned, and still continues to desert and abandon, wilfully and without cause, your Petitioner, and to live separate and apart from him, without any sufficiant cause or any reason, and without his consent and against his will.</p>
<p>That at the time the said Sarah M. Davis deserted and abandoned your Petitioner, as aforesaid, she wrongfully, surreptitiously, and without any cause or excuse took the said minor child, from the home and custody of your Petitioner, and wrongfully and without any cause or excuse keeps the said child from the custody and home of your Petitioner, and refusesto deliver said child to the custody of your Petitioner or to allow you Petitioner to excercise any control over her whatever though your Peitioner is abundantly able to</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>