<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>In Re: Ex Parte - Donald Kerracher - Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Banse, AD" xml:id="ab">AD Banse</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">In Re: Ex Parte - Donald Kerracher - Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="2022-06-13">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">2022-06-21</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName> Donald MC Kerracher</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName> C.B. Hopkins</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>C.H. Hanford</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


<div1 type="case">



<p>  In the United States Cirtuit Court, For the Ninth Judicial Circuit, Western District of the State of Washington, Northern Division. </p>

<p> In Re. Ex Parte: Donald MC Kerracher, Petitioner. </p>

<p> Praceipe for Transcript</p>
<p> Filed in the U.S. Circuit Court, Western Dist. of Washington. Sept 18 1905. Clerk by Deputy A. Reeves Ayres. A.N. Moody Dep. </p>

<p> In the Circuit Court of the United States for the Western District of the State of Washington, Northern Division. </p>
<p> In Re. Ex Parte:  </p>
<p> Donald Mc. Kerracher, </p>
<p> Petitioner. </p>
<p> No. 1328</p>
<p>  Assignment of Errors.</p>
<p> Comes now the United States and Charles B. Hopkins, United States Marshal for the Western Distrcxit of Washington, appelants in the above entitled proceeding, by their attorney, Jesse A Frye, United States Attorney for the Western Distrcit of Washington, and in connection with their appeal herein say; that in the record and proceeding in the above entitled matter and in the order and judgement rendered and entered herein on the 20th day of September 1908, there is manifest error, in this, to-wit:  </p>

<p> I.  That Court erred in finding that the petitioner, Donald Mc Keeracher, was wrongfully restrained of his liberty, </p>

<p> II. The Court erred in finding that the petitioner, Donald Mc Keeracher, was unlawfully held in custody by the United States Marshal for the Western District of Washington. </p>

<p> III. The Cout erred in holding and finding that the petitioner, Donald Mc Keeracher, was unlawfully held in custody by the Warden of the United States Penitentiary on McNeil's Island, Washington.  </p>

<p> IV.The Cout erred in ordering and directing the United States Marshal for the Western District of Washington to discharge said Donald McKerracher from custody and imprisonment. </p>

<p> V.  That The Court erred in ordering and adjusting that the petitioner, Donald Mc Keeracher, was entitled to be discharged from the cusotdy of the United States Marshal for the Western District of Wahsington. </p>

<p> VI.  That the Court erred in ordering and directing the United States Marshal for the Western District of Washington to discharge said Donald McKerracher from custody and imprisonment.</p>

<p> VII. That The Court erred in ordering and adjusting that the petitioner, Donald Mc Keeracher, be discharged from the United States penitentiary on McNeil's Island. </p>

<p> VIII.  That The Court erred in ordering and adjusting that the petitioner, Donald Mc Keeracher,  from the custody of officers of the United States. </p>

<p> IX.  That The Court erred in ordering and adjusting that the petitioner, Donald Mc Keeracher,  from the custody of officers of the United States and restoring him to his liberty.</p>

<p> X.  That the Court erred in entering the order and judgement of September 20, 1905, in the premises, discharging the petitioner, Donald McKerracher, from the custody of the United States officers and restoring him to his liberty, for the reason that said order and judgement is not supported by the law in the premises, and that said order and judgement of discharge is contrary to law.  </p>
<p> Wherefore, the United States Marshal for the Western Distrcit of Washington, and the United States of America, appellants, pray that their assignment of errors be entered upon the record in this proceeding:  </p>
<p>  And they further pray that, upon the hearing of this appeal it may be adjusted by the United States Circuit Court of Appeals  for the Ninth Circuit, that the order and judgment in this proceeding made and entered on the 20th day of September 1905 be in all things held in naught, and that the petitioner, Donald McKerracher, be remanded to the custody of the United States Marshal for the Western District of Washington, and that he be imprisoned in the United States penitentiary on McNeill's Island, State of Washington, and there held until his term of sentence expires according to law. </p>
<p>  Jesse A Frye</p>
<p> United States Attorney for the Western District of Washington, and Attorney for Appellees. </p>

<pb/>
<p>  Due and timely service of the within Exceptions, and the receipt of a true copy thereof, acknowledged this 20th day of September 1905. </p>
<p> Metcalfe and Jurey, Attorneys for Petitioner. </p>
<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>