<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0224.009">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Lewis Johnson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>John M. Boyle</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Hammond and Hammond</persName> 
<persName>George R. Tennant</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Winter S. Martin</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court, For the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#AS">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p><unclear></unclear> GARNETT called as a witness being first 
sworn, testified as follows: 
</p> 
<p>MR GRANT: In this matter Your Honour the Police have laid a 
charge against Mr Garnett of receiving stolen property, and
now they propose to enquire as to the property he received.
I would ask that none of this evidence be used against him</p> 
<p>MR KENNEDY: That certainly will go and further than that I am
prepared to say this, if Mr Garnett turn out King's Evidence -
I don't want to make any promise - but it goes as a matter 
of course e...</p> 
<p>COURT: You understand that any evidence you may give will not be
used against you.</p> 
<p>QUESTIONS by MR KENNEDY:</p> 
<p>123 Q. Mr Garnett what is your occupation? A. Barber.</p>
<p>124 Q. Do you know Lewis Johnston? A. Yessir</p> 
<p>125 Q. On or about the 4th of June, that would be about two
weeks ago yesterday, did you have occasion, or near then, to
see him? A. I don't remember the date, but I had occasion to
see him</p> 
<p>126 Q. Do you remember what day it was? A. No sir I do not.</p> 
<p>127 Q. You don't remember whether it was Sunday or Monday?
A. No I don't remember</p> 
<p>128 Q. It was about two weeks ago? A. It might be, possibly be</p> 
<p>129 Q. Where and under what circumstances did you see him then? 
A. Johnston came to me one evening and said to me he wanted
me to keep some money for him; so I said "alright", so I got
an envelope out of the coset and I gave it to him and he
put some money on it. So when I had taken the money I said
"what are you doing with so much money?"</p> 
<p>130 Q. How much money was it? A. I don't know</p> 
<p>131 Q. You are evidently impressed with the amount of it; 
were there a number of bills? What impressed you? A. Well 
I really thought he had possibly seventy, eighty, or one hun-
dred dollars, something like that. That was just my idea. 
It might have been ten thousand dollars, I... 
<pb></pb> 
<unclear></unclear> 
132 Q. I saw that there was a roll of bills, was there? A. Yes.
So I said "what are you doing with so much money?" He said 
"I just beat" - no, he said "I just been over and beat some
Bohunks out of some money" I said "it is pretty good for 
you" So I put the money in the safe. And I was going home
that morning about 3:30 and I met him on the Powell Street 
playgrounds.</p>  
<p>133 Q. 3:30 in the afternoon? A. 3:30 in the morning. He said
"I want you to come back and give me two fifty dollar bills"
Well I was under the impression he was going back to play
again, and I said to him "if I were you I would not be
foolish" I said "you have done very well already".</p>
<p>134 Q. You had a conversation with him, Mr. Garnett, and eventually
did you give him any more money? A. Well yes. So he came on 
back....</p> 
<p>COURT: Cout out those long conversations</p> 
<p>A. I have got to tell you right.</p> 
<p>COURT: Look here Garnett simply answer the questions.</p> 
<p>A. I said "yes"</p>
<p>135 Q. You gave him some more money? A. Yes</p> 
<p>136 Q. How much did you give him? A. Two fifty dollar bils</p> 
<p>137 Q. Did that leave any balance in your hands at all? A. Yes sir</p> 
<p>138 Q. How much? I don't know</p> 
<p>139 Q. Didn't you ever look at it at all? A. No I never looked 
at the money</p> 
<p>140 Q. Did you see the denomination of any of bills that were
left in your hands? A. I didn't see the denominations but
I know there were two one hundred dollar bills.</p>
<p>141 Q. Then eventually did he get the money from you, all of it, 
the balance? A. Yes sir</p> 
<p>142 Q. Did you never count the balance of it at all? A. No sir 
I did not</p>
<pb></pb> 
<p>143 Q. Do you remember when, what day that would be that he got
the balance of the money? A. That was three or four days 
later.</p> 
<p>144 Q. You could not tell me the day of the week? A. I am not 
positive. I think it was around Sunday, Monday or Tuesday.
One of those days near the first of the week.</p> 
<p>145 Q. Have you any way of estimating from the amount of money
you gave him at one time and another, and any monies that he
gave you, have you any way of estimating approximately how much
was in your hands from him? A. I cannot estimate how much 
money there was because I didn't know the denomination of all
the bills. </p> 
<p>146 Q. Was anything left for your trouble? A. Two hundred 
dollars; not for my trouble; he owed me some money.</p> 
<p>MR KENNEDY: I am only asking you that question because I want to
get some idea of how much money this man had.</p> 
<p>147 Q. I show you now a photograph which has already been produced 
in these proceedings as Exhibit "A", do you recognise that
photograph? A. Yes</p> 
<p>148 Q. Who is that? A. That is Lewis Johnston. Just let me see
one moment</p> 
<p>149 Q. That is the man to whom you have been referring? A. Yes</p>
<p><unclear>H.J.S</unclear></p>
</div1> 
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>