<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>United States District Court
Western Division of Washington
Northern Division</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application 
of Ching Hing for a Writ of Habeas
Corpus } No. <del>2875.</del> 2857
Answer to Petition</p>
<p>Comes now John J. Sullivan, attorney for the Petitioner,
Ching Hing, in answer to the petition of G.P. Fishburne, Assistant
United States Attorney for the Western District of Washington, and
states, alleges and answers as follows:</p>
<p>That the matter therein set up by said G.P. Fishburne,
is outside the record and can not be reviewed or taken connisance of
by this Court, for the reason that if said Secretary of Labor did
review the record and affirm the decision of the Commissioner of Immigration,
in relation to the above entitled case on November 13, 1914,
that the same was done while this Court had jurisdiction of the subject
matter and of the petitioner herein and after a rule to show
cause had served upon Lewis F. Post, Assistant Secretary of Labor
under seal of the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia, Honorable
Ashley M. Gould, Justice, to show cause why he should not be directed
to make full and direct response to interrogrations propounded under a
stipulation issued by Honorable Jeremiah Neterer, Judge of this Court,
authorizing Thomas G. Lewis, Commissioner, to take said depositions;
and in further answer, Ching Hing, through his attorney, respectfully
informs the Court that no opportunity was given Counsel informing him
when said alleged hearing was had, or that he he be given permission to
appear before Honorable Secretary and present argument in behalf of
sadi alien and petitioner, Ching Hing; and that the said action of the
Secretary, if there was such an action, was arbitrary and contrary to
Law and oversteps the due procedute of this Court.</p>
<p>Wherefore, Ching Hing, through his attorney, John J.
Sullivan, respectfully prays that the petition of G.P. Fishburne,
Assistant United States Attorney, be denied, and this Court procede to
<pb/>
hear the Writ upon its merits, after the determination of the Supreme
Court in and for the District of Columbia, on the question now pending
before Honorable Justice Ashley M. Gould.</p>
<p>Beeler &amp; Sullivan
Attys for Petitioner
Ching Hing</p>
<p>The United States of America
Western District of Washington
Northern Division } ss</p>
<p>John J. Sullivan, being first duly sworn on
oath, deposes and says: That he is attorney for the petitioner herein;
that he has read the foregoing Answer to Petition, knows the contents
thereof, and believes the same to be true.</p>
<ab>John J. Sullivan
Subscribed and sworn to before me this 21st day of April, 1915.</ab>
<ab>Adam Beeler</ab>
<figure><ab>Notary Public State of Washington
Notary Public
Jan. 3, 1913</ab></figure>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>