<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0272.011.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Columbia George v. Charles B. Hopkins. Petition Exhibit A.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Czapla, Ethan P" xml:id="epc">Ethan Czapla</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0272.011</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Columbia George v. Charles B. Hopkins. Petitioner's Exhibit A.</title>
<date when="1893-03-27">March 27, 1893</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno>1390ColumbiaGeorgeIndian</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1893-03">March 1893</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>McKinley, William</term>
<term>McKean, F.M.</term>
<term>Brush, C.H.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Umatilla Indian Reervation, Oregon</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>George, Columbia</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Hopkins, Charles B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Slater, R.J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Frye, Jesse A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C.H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#epc">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Petitioners Exhibit "A"</p>

<p>The United States of America.</p>

<p>To all to whom these Presents shall come, Greeting:</p>

<p>Whereas, there has been deposited in the General Land Office of the United States a schedule of allotments of land, dated
       March 27, 1893 from the Acting Commissioner of Indian Affairs, approved by the Acting Secretary of the Interior April 12, 1893,
       whereby it appears that under the provisions of the Act of Congress approved March 3, 1885 (23 Stats.,340) Pa-no-tal-Kan-it, or
       George, an Indian residing upon the Umatilla Reservation, Oregon, has been alloted the following described land, to-wit: The 
       N.E.1/4 of the S.E.1/4 and the S.E.1/4 of the N.E.1/4 of Section 6 in Township 1 North, and the N.1/2 of the N.E.1/4 of section 20
       in township 2 north of Range 30 E. of the Willamette Meridian in Oregon, containing 166 acres.</p>

<p>Now, Know Ye, That the United States of America, in consideration of the premises and in accordance with the provisions of the 
       first section of said Act of Congress of the 3d March 1885, HEREBY DECLARES that it does and will hold the land thus allotted
       (subject to all the restrictions and conditions contained in said first section) for the period of twenty-five years, in trust for the sole
       use and benefit of the said Pa-no-tal-Kan-it, or George, or in the case of his decease, for the sole use of his heirs, according to the 
       laws of the State of Oregon, and that at the expiration of said period the United States will convey the same by patent to said Indian,
       or his heirs, as aforesaid, in fee, discharged of said trust and free of all charge or incumbrance whatsoever.</p>

<p>In Testimony Whereof, I, William McKinley, President of the United States of America, have caused these letters to be made Patent
       and the seal of the General Land Office to be hereunto affixed.</p>

<p>SEAL. Given under my hand at the City of Washignton this sixteenth day of September, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight
       hundred and ninety-nine, and of the Independence of the Untied States the one hundred and twenty-fourth.</p>

<p>By the President, William McKinley
       By the F.M. McKean, Secretary</p>

<p>Recorded Vol. 2, p. 371. C.H. Brush, Recorder of the General Land Office.</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>