<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>K. Gregory et al. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0182.059</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">K. Gregory et al. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Henry White</term>
    <term>Frank Crosby</term>
    <term>Clay Allen</term>
    <term>G.F. Fishburne</term>
    <term>Parker</term>
    <term>Kalina</term>
    <term>K. Gregory</term>
    <term>M. Aloshin</term>
    <term>I. Riaboff</term>
    <term>P. Neanlin</term>
    <term>I. Erelin</term>
    <term>L. Orloff</term>
    <term>G. Yakimoff</term>
    <term>P. Yakimoff</term>
    <term>Jeremiah Neterer</term>

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Parker</persName>
    <persName>Kalina</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Petition of
K. GREGORY, et al.,
For a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>No. 2646.
Filed Jan., 1914.</p>
<p>ON MOTION FOR DISCHARGE. Motion Granted.</p>
<p>Parker and Kalina        For Petitioners</p>
<p>Clay Allen, U.S. Attorney,
G.F. Fishburne, Assist. U.S. Atty. For Respondent.</p>
<p>NETERER, District Judge.</p>
<p>K. Gregory and seven others filed a petition praying a writ of habeas corpus alleging that they
are in good faith seeking admission into the United States to make the United States their permanent
home; that they do not come within any of the classes prohibitecd admission. A show cause order was
issued and the Commissioner of immigration made return setting forth, in substance, that the
petitioners sought admission and were held for special inquiry by the immigrant inspector and a
board of special inquiry was organized as provided by law, and:</p>
<p>"That on December 23, 1913, after a full hearing, (A duplicate report of which appears in the
immigration files of this cause and is marked "Exhibit A" and made a part of  this Return they Board
decided to reject the aliens on the ground that they were persons who were likely to become a public
charge, for the following resons:</p>
<p>first: Because they are common or farm laborers and there is no work for them in the United
States.</p>
<p>second; Because they have but a limited amount of money, insufficient to maintain them during the
winter.</p>
<p>third: Because there are 800 to 1000 Russians unemployed in Seattle, and thousands of other
nationalities in the same condition, and reports from the Interior are to the effect that the supply
of common labor is far in excess of demand.</p>
<p>fourth: That any addition to the unemployed should be gaurded against, and alien laborers should
not be permitted to enter the United States at this time." <add>That the petitioners appealed to the
Secretary of Labor who affirmed the decision of the board of special inquiry</add>.</p>
<p>The petitioners move that they be forthwith discharged for the reasons:</p>
<p>"(1) That the return shows that they are detained and restrained of their liberty for unlawful
reasons and contrary to the statutes in such chases made and provided; (2) that the Special
examining board and the Secretary of Commerce and Labor and said Commissioner exceeded their
authority and jurisdiction; (3) that the alleged reasons for detainging said petitioners are
<pb></pb>
irrelevant, immaterial and not sipported by evidence, and are frivolous and sham; (4) that said
petitioners had all the personal qualificatiosn required of them by the statutes, and to entitle
them to immediate and unconditional discharge."</p>
<p>This court held in In re Moola Singh, 207 Fed. 780, that the jurisdiction of this court is
limited to ascertaining whether the petitioners were denied a hearing, and if a hearing has been
accorded, the court is precluded from a re-examination of the issue presented merely because it is
contended that the conclusion of the immigration officers based upon the testimony was wrong. In the
Moola Singh case a trial was had, and the conclusion of the examining board was that the aliens be
excluded from admission under the laws of the United States. The conclusion of the board found
delinquency in the personal qualifications of the applicants which brought them within the exclusion
provisions of the act. This court cannot examine into the testimony produced upon the hearing in
this case beofre the special examining board, nor enter upon a re-examination of the facts. This
court is bound by the facts as found by the board of special inquiry. Do the facts as found bring
the petitioners within the provisions of the exclusion provisions of the act? Are the petitioners
qualified to enter under the findings of the baord, and is the act of the board beyond its
jurisdiction, and does the personal candition of the applicants, as found, preclude their exclusion.</p>
<p>Sec. 1 of the Immigration Act, of Febuary 20, 1907, reads:</p>
<p>"That there shall be levied, collected and paid a tax of four dollars for every alien entering
the United States."</p>
<p>Sec. 2 of the Act provides who are to be excluded, amon whom are "persons likely to become a
public charge." Sec. 10 of the Act provides:</p>
<p>"That the decision of the baord of special inquiry, hereinafter provided for, based upon the
certificate of the examining medical officer, shall be final as to the rejection of aliens affected
with tuberculosis or with a loathsome or dangerous contagious disease, or iwth any mental or
physical disability which would bring such aliens within any of the classes excluded from admission
to the United States under section two of this Act."</p>
<p>Sec. 24 fo the Act provides:</p>
<p>"...Immigration officers shall have power to administer oaths, and to take and consider evidence
touching the right of any alien to enter the United States, and where such action is nec-
<pb></pb>
essary to make a written record of such evidence.</p>
<p>A provision for the punishment of any persons who shall knowingly or wilfully give false oaths or
swear to any false statement is made, and it is also provided that the decision of such officer in
admitting an alien shall be subject to challenge by any other officer, and such challenge shall
operate to take the alien whose right to land is challengedd before a baord of special inquiry for
its investigation. It is further provided:</p>
<p>"Every alien who may not appear to the examining immigrant inspector at the part of arrival to be
clearly and beyond doubt entitled to land shall be detained for exaamination in relation thereto by
a board of special inquiry."</p>
<p>"Sec. 25...All hearings before bards shall be separate and apart from the public...and the
decision of any two of the baord shall prevail; but either the alien or any dissenting member of
said baord may appeal...to the secretary of labor...that in every case where an alien is excluded
from admission into the United States under any law or treaty now existing or hereaftr made, the
decision of the appropriate immigration officers, if adverse to the admission of such alien shall be
final, unless reversed in appeal to the secretary of labor."</p>
<p>Under Sec. 2, an alien "likely to become a public charge" is excluded; and under Sec. 25, the
decision of the board of special inquiry is final where the alien is by law excluded. The findings
and conclusions of the board with relation to the petitioners, however, eliminate all physical and
mental deficiencies as legislated against. Shall it be said, under such a record, that the examining
baord can exclude an alien upon the conclusion that he is "likely to become a public charge," when,
upon the facts found and reasons given, the applicant is not brought within the provisions fo the
act excluding him from admission?</p>
<p>In the findings made there is no disqualification personal to the applicants, nor any objection
made because of inability to conform to new conditions and relations. They are not excluded by the
provisions of the act. The reasons govien do not exclude them under the act. These reasons are
proper subjects for the consideration of Congress, but they do not authorize the temporary
supsension of the Immigration Act, which the adoption of these findings will do. The laws and
principles upon which our government rests forbid the exercise of arbitrary power. Immigration
officers must act within the powers give. Courts have power to
<pb></pb>
intervene where they exceed their authority.</p>
<p>Ex parte Saraceno, 182 Fed. 955;
Lewis v. Frick, 189 Fed. 146;
In re Feinkoff, 47 Fed. 447;
Ex parte Hoerna, 176 Fed. 479;
In re O'Sullivan, 31 Fed. 447;
Inited States v. Martin, 192 U.S. 1,</p>
<p>The petitioners are discharged; bu, if within then days after the filing of this decision, the
respondent appeals, the petitioners must give recognizance with sufficient surety in like sum of
$250 each, conditioned to appear and answer the judgment of the appellate court in accordance with
Supreme Court Rule 34.</p>
<p>Jeremiah Neterer</p>

<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>