<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0449.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Jeremiah Mangan v. King County. Commitment</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Ham, Bethany R." xml:id="brh">Bethany R. Ham</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0449.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Jeremiah Mangan v. King County. Commitment</title>
<date when="1889-06-19">June 19th, 1889</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives</repository>
<collection>King Frontier Justice</collection>
<idno>Case No 6991</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1889-07">July 1889</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Mangan, Flora E.</term>
<term>Hopkins, R. M.</term>
<term>Harmon, H. T.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Skagit County, Washington</term>
<term>King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Mangan, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Dwelley, J. F.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-06" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0449.001"/>
<p>
United States of America
Territory of Washington
County of Skagit    ss.

To the Sheriff or any constable and the keeper of the jail of said Skagit County and the keeper of the jail of King County Wash. Ter. the jail of said King County being the place provided by the Commissioner of Skagit County for keeping prisoners from said Skagit County.
</p>
<p>
Wheras at a Justice's Court held are the 15 day of June A. D. 1889 at my Office in said Skagit County for the trail of Jeremiah Mangan for threatening to commit the Offense hereinafter stated, the said Jeremiah Mangan was convicted of having on the 2nd day of February A. D. 1889 in said Skagit County threatened to set fire to and burn the dwelling house of one Flora E Mangan situate in said Skagit County; And whereas it fully appeared to said court and said court found that there is just cause to fear that said Jeremiah Mangan will set fire to and burn the dwelling house of said Flora E Mangan situate in said Skagit County; And whereas the said court did adjudge and determine that the said Jeremiah Mangan should enter into a recognizance with sufficient penalties in the sum of one thousand dollars to keep the peace and be of good
</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>behavior towards all the people of the Territory and Especially toward the said Flora E Mangan for the terms of one year from the 15th day of June A. D. 1889: And whereas the said Jeremiah Mangan has neglected and refused to enter in to such recognizance has made default in sending in to the same; Therefore you the said Sheriff or Constable are hereby commanded in the name of the United States of America forthwith to convey and deliver the said Jeremiah Mangan to the said keeper and you the said keeper are hereby commanded to receive the said Jeremiah Mangan with your custody in said jail and him then safely keep for the space of one year from the 15th day of June 15th A. D. 1889 or until he shall enter into such recognizance or thence be discharged by due course of Law.
Dated at Skagit County
this 19th day of June 1889
J F Dwelley
Justice of the Peace</p>

<p>
6991
Territory of Washington
vs
Jeremiah Mangan
Commitment

Filed July 20, 1889
R. M. Hopkins 
Clerk
By H. T. Harmon
Deputy
</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>