<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0180.014.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Affadvit.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0180.014</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Affadvit.</title>
<date when="1913-06-03">June 3, 1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2628AlbertYoung&amp;KamasaburoSugiura</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-06">June 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Ito, K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fisher, Thomas M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Tsumori</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Saito, Hana</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Umeda, K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Washio, Shotaro</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Kodama, S.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Nakada</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Gardner</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Sacramento, California</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Fresno, California</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Young, Albert H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sugiuro, Kamasaburo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Myers, H. A. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>McClellan, R. W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Johnstone, Walter L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, G. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>Exhibit "B"
Statement of K. Ito, Made at San Francisco Cal.,
June 3, 1913
K. Ito sworn by Immigrant Inspector, Thom, M. Fisher.</p>
<p>Q What is your name? A K. Ito</p>
<p>Q When did you first become connected with that house at 1020 Stockton
St? A About June last year.</p>
<p>Q How much of that house did you control? A The part known as
1020B</p>
<p>Who did you buy from A Tsumori</p>
<p>In buying did you buy in your own name or the name of your wife?
A My wife's name</p>
<p>Q When you bought that house was this girl, Hana, an inmate of it?
A She had been there but had ran away before that time.</p>
<p>Q That house was a house of prostitution was it not? A Yes.</p>
<p>You had known Hana and <del>Saito</del> Washio before that had you not?
A Yes</p>
<p>Q How long before that? A About 3 years but not together, they had
been together about four months.</p>
<p>Q Were you living in that house when Hana went away with Saito?
A No I was living at 528 Pine St.</p>
<p>Q You knew about them going away together? A Yes</p>
<p>Q You were called into a consulation in regard to a settlement? 
A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Who else was called in? A Umeda, Hana, Saito, Washio and myself</p>
<p>Q What was the agreement reached? A It was agreed that Saito was
to pay either $1300.00 or $1500., I forget which, to Washio, Saito
owed some money at some stores also and it was agreed that he was to
take Hana to Sacramento or Frseno for two weeks and make that money.
Umeda adn I guaranteed the payment of that money.</p>
<p>Q They didn't return in two weeks did they? A No.</p>
<p>Q You found they had gove north did you not? A Yes</p>
<p>Q Did you get together then and take steps to try to locate Hana and
Saito?</p>
<p>Q Washio came to us and said we had guaranteed for them and it was
up to us to produce the woman or pay so we did all we could to locate
them.</p>
<p>Q Then you went to the Burne Agency and paid them for two days work
in Seattle locating Hana did you not? A A man named S. Kodama and
Washio went there and paid them $40. I didn';t go with them at that
time.</p>
<p>Q Then Umeda went to Seattle, didn't he, to look for Hana? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q He didn't locate her? A No.</p>
<p>Q After he came back Washio went up there? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Washio sent you a wire that he had then located in Tacoma didn't he?
A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Sent you this wire? (Showing wire) A Yes.</p>
<p>Q When you got that what did you do? A Umeda and I employed Nakada
to go with us to Burne people. I had received a latter from Washio
asking me to get a warrant for Hana in Umeda's name. we asked the
Burns people about it and they told us we couldn't get the kind of a
warrant we wanted, we could get one for larceny, we weanted a warrant
just to get them back here.</p>
<p>Q Did you wire or write Washio that you couldn't get the warrant?
A We told him by wire the same day we went to the Burns people.</p>
<fw>12</fw>
<pb/>
<p>Q What did you say in that wire? A That we couldn't lend our name
to a warrant of that kind.</p>
<p>Q How did you send that wire? A Western Union Addressed to Washio
in care of the Great Northern Hotel.</p>
<p>Q Did you get a letter from Washio after that? A No.</p>
<p>You got a wire from him? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q This one? (Showing telegram dated August 9, 1912) A Yes</p>
<p>Q What did you understand by "please have all arrangements made"
A I understood that to mean to arrange so there would be no trouble
at this end between Saito and Washio and people interested.</p>
<p>Q It was already understood beforehand that if Washio got the girl
she was to be brought back to that house was it not? A Yes</p>
<p>Q Then you got this wire also from Washio? (Showing wire dated
Aug. 13, 1913) A Yes after I got that wire my wife and I went to the
boat and met them.</p>
<p>Q Did you at the time know that Young and Sugiura were coming?
A No I didn't, I met them for the first time at the dock.</p>
<p>Q . There was a little trouble at the dock between Saito and some one
else was there not? A Yes, Saito and I had some trouble.</p>
<p>Q Then the party went right to your house at 1020 Stockton St?
A Yes</p>
<p>Q How long did Young and Sugiura stay there? A About half an hour.</p>
<p>Q What did they have to say? A they told me that Washio had agreed
with them thay they should be paid for bringing the girl down and
thay they had found Washio hadno money and they wanted mr to
raise the money and give it to them.</p>
<p>Q Did they say how much money they were to get? A They said
Washio had agreed to give them $800., I told them I didn't agree to
give them the money and it was up to them to get it from Washio.</p>
<p>Q What wlse did Young, Sugiura or Washio say at that time? A Young
and Sugiura said the agreement with Washio was to pay them $800. for
bringing the girl down here but that things didn't go just right so
they were willing to settle and take $400. and wanted me to pay them that. Sugiura said he had posed as an interpreter and that
Young has possed as an Immigration officer and the woman believeing
them $800. to take the chances of bringing this woman here to a house
of prostitution and that they wanted their money. They told me later
that they had been to see Mr. Gardner of the Immigration offices and
had fixed things with him so there would be no trouble but that we
must come through with the money to them. Young and Sugiura went to
the Imperial hotel, Washio and Hana stayed in my house. The next day
I think it was, Umeda and I were sent for by Young and Sugiura and
went to the Imperial Hotel to see them, Young and Sugiura and
their agreement with Washio and said they couldn't wait for their
money and must get back to Seattle and that Umeda and I must raise the
money for them. Later in the day Young and Sugiura came to my house 
Umeda was present also, and there I paid them $200. and later I paid
them $50. more.</p>
<p>Who did you pay this money to? A I handed it to Umeda who passed
it over on the table, Sugiura picked it up and handed it to Young.</p>
<p>Q Did you see Young and Sugiura after that? A They came the next
day and said it was alright for Hana to practice prostitution as they
had fixed it with the immigration officers, they had told us at first
not to let her do business for a while as they were afraid if we did
there would be trouble for all of us, that was the last I saw of them.</p>
<fw>13</fw>
<pb/>
<p>Q After that Hana practiced prostitution in that house didn't she?
A Yes</p>
<p>Q You after wrote a letter to Sugiura didn't you? A yes</p>
<p>Q Is this the letter? (showing letter) A Yes</p>
<p>Q What do you mean when you say in that letter "what did you tell the
Immigration officers about Hana"? A They had told me that they had
fixed things in regard to Hana doing business and the Japanese News
Paper had printed an article and I wanted to know how he had fixed
things and what he has told them when he fixed it, after the News
Paper article Nakada phoned me to come to his office, I went there
and he told me that the Immigration officers would be after Hana that
night or the next morning and told me to get her out of the house,
Umeda was there with me, and we got the woman out of the house,
took her to a lodging-house on Keaney St., near the City Hall, the
house from which she was arrested. The next day Nakada came and told
me that the United States Marshal was after myself and Umeda and that
we had better hide out, he said "I can fix it if you will come through"
I asked him to fix it and he told me to give him $50. and he would
fix it <del><unclear/></del> so I would be out of California as far as the
officers knew. I paid him two $20. and one $10. in gold, then he
told me, this $50. you give me is not all for me, I have to buy
cigars for the Marshals and give them a piece of it beside.</p>
<p>Q Was there anyone present when you gave him that money? A No, I 
showed the money to Umeda and told him what I was going to do with
it, I forgot to tell you that when we were at the Burns Agency Nakada
told us he could get a United States warrant for Hana for $250. The
next day after I gave Namasa the $50. Nakada and a Marshal came to
my house after Hana, Nakada said the Marshal wants Hana and if you
don't produce her he will hold you until she is produced. I told him
I couldn't stand for that and Nakada asked me where she was, I told
him "I hid her on your instructions, you told me to hide her", finally
Umeda took the Marshal to the room and showd him Hana. After my
wife was taken to Seattle Nakada told me he would find out about the
Seattle case and wanted me to pay him $25. I paid him $15.</p>
<p>I certify the foregoing is a true and full transcript of the
atenographic notes made by me at the time statement was ade.</p>
<ab>Thos. M. Fisher
Immigrant Inspector</ab>




</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>