<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0267.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Stapleton-Deno, Zoe L." xml:id="zlsd">Zoe L. Stapleton-Deno</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0267.001</idno>
<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">IN THE MATTER OF AN APPLICATION OF L.J. URANN FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS. Petition.</title>
<date when="1905-07-01">July 1st, 1905</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1905-07"></date>July 1905</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>L.J. Urann</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Morris Wolf</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>L.C. Smith</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Vince H. Faben</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Ninth Circuit Court of the United States</orgName> 
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#zlsd">transcribed and encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>  

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0267.001"/>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE 9th CIRCUIT, WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF AN APPLICATION OF L.J. URANN FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.} PETITION.</p>
<p> TO THE HONORABLE, THE JUDGE OF THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES
IN AND FOR THE 9th CIRCUIT COURT, WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON;</p>
<p>The petition of L.J. Urann respectively shows as follows, to-wit:</p>
    
<p>I.</p>
<p>That the petitioner is unlawfully imprisoned, detained and confined
and restrained for his liberty by L.C. Smith, Sheriff of King
County Washington and Morris Wolf, Agent of the State of Massachusetts,
and that he is confined in prison under the direction of the
said L.C. Smith as Sheriff of King County, Washington and Morris 
Wolf as Agent of the State of Massachusetts, against his will and
contrary to the law.</p>
    
<p>II.</p>
<p>That the said imprisonment, detention and restraint are illegal 
and that the illegality thereof consists in this, to-wit: That the
said petitioner is held without due process of law or any process
whatever; that no sufficient warrant or attachment of person has
ever been issued out of any court of this State or any other State
or Commonwealth of the United States.</p>
    
<p>III.</p>
<p>That the cause or the pretended cause of the restraint, imprisonment,
detention and confinement of said petitioner, to the
<pb/>

best of his knowledge and belief, is a pretended charge of crime
alleged to have been committed under the laws of the State of 
Massachusetts but that said alleged charge is no crime against the
law of the State of Massachusetts and that said pretended charge is 
one of larceny, wherefore in truth and in fact the said charge was
laid with spite and founded upon malice and laid for the purpose of
extortion and extorting money from the petitioner and that the said
charge was made for the purpose of collecting a sum of money due
upon a civil debt and that the said complaining witness never had
any intention of prosecuting this petitioner for crime but has
simply resorted to the process of for the purpose of forcing a collection
and not otherwise.</p>
    
<p>IV.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further alleges that his imprisonment is
illegal, unjust and in violation of the provisions of the laws of
the United States, Sec. 5278 Revised Statutes, in the following
particulars:</p>
<p>That this petitioner is not a fugitive from justice from the
State of Massachusetts and no demand has been made upon the executive
authority of this State by the Govonor of Massachusetts for
his apprehension as such, and your petitioner had committed no
crime punishable under and by virtue of the laws of the Commonwealth
of Massachusetts or the laws of the State of Washington;</p>
<p>That the purported or pretended demand, if any, made upon the
Govonor of the State of Washington was not accompanied by a copy
of any indictment found against your petitioner, duly certified by
the executive authority of the State of Massachusetts to be authentic.</p>
    
<p>WHEREFORE Your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus 
may be granted and issued directed to the said L.C. Smith and
Morris Wolf commanding them to have the body of your petitioner
before your Honor at a time and place therein to be specified to
<pb/>
    
do and receive what is then and there considered by your Honor 
concerning the petitioner, together with the time and cause of his 
detention, and said writ: and that he may be returned to his liberty.</p>
<p>Dated this 1st day of July, 1905.</p>
    
<p>L.J. Urann 
by Vince H. Faben his attorney
Petitioner.</p>
 
<p> Vince H. Faben
 Attorney for Petitioner.</p>
   

<p>State of Washington
County of King. - ss.</p>

<p>Jno. G. Gray on his oath being duly sworn says:
I am one of the attorneys for the petitioner named in the
foregoing petition; that he has read the same and knows the contents
thereof; and the statements therein are true as he verily
believes; that he makes this verification on behalf of the 
petitioner for the reason that the exigencies of the matter will
not permit same being made by petitioner.</p>
    
<p>Jno. G. Gray</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 1st day of July, 1905. </p>
    
<p>John C. Burnam
Notary Public in and for the State of 
Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>
<pb/>
    
<p>No. 1313</p>
    
<p>In the United States Circuit Court
for the 
Western District of Washington
Northern Division</p>
    
<p>In the Matter of the 
Petition of 
L.J. Urann
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
    
<p> Petition</p>
    
<p>FILED IN THE
U.S. Circuit Court,
Western Dist. of Washington.</p>
    
<p>Jul 1 1905</p>
    
<p>A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk</p>
    
<p><unclear>H.M. Matthew</unclear>
Dep.</p>
    
<p>Service of papers, except in process, in this cause may be made upon
Vince H. Faben</p>
<p><del>GRAY&amp;BURNAM</del>Vince H. Faben</p>
<p>Attorney<del>s</del> for Petitioner</p>
<p>50<del>268-10</del>MUTUAL LIFE BUILDING</p>
<p><del>PHONES, SUNSET MAIN 1302, IND. A 1844</del></p>
<p>SEATTLE, WASH.</p>

 <p>THE IVY PRESS, SEATTLE.</p>
 
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>