<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0000.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1891">1891</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-09" who="#lkw">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE, THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, DISTRICT
OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION OF
ALBERT FREDERICH FOR A WRIT OF 
HABEAS CORPUS.</p>

<p>THE COMPLAINT OF ALBERT FREDERICH RESPECTFULLY SHOWS THAT
HE IS NOW A PRISONER CONFINED IN THE STATE PENETENTIARY OF THE
STATE OF WASHINGTON, AT WALLA WALLA IN THE SAID STATE IN THE CUSTODY
OF <gap></gap> WARDEN OF SAID PENETENTIARY.</p>

<p>THAT HIS IMPRISONMENT IS BY VIRTUE OF A WARRANT <del>and judgment</del> A COPY OF
WHICH IS HERETO ATTACHED AND MARKED EXHIBIT "A" <add>"and B"</add>, AND NOT OTHER-
WISE; AND THAT THIS COMPLAINANT IS INFORMED BY HIS COUNSEL MESSRS
TYLER &amp; TYLER AND VERILY BELIEVES THAT HIS IMPRISONMENT IS ILLEGAL
AND THAT SUCH ILLEGALITY CONSISTS IN THIS TO-WIT</p>

<p>THAT COMPLAINANT WAS DULY INDICTED BY THE GRAND JURY OF KING
COUNTY, STATE OF WASHINGTON, ONE THE 17 DAY OF July
1891 FOR THE MURDER OF ONE JULIUS SCHERBRING, AND UPON SAID IN-
DICTMENT, HE WAS DULY ARRAIGNED, PLEADED NOT GUILTY WAS TRIED BY 
A JURY WHO FOUND HIM GUILTY OF MURDER IN THE FIRST DEGREE ON THE
26th DAY OF September 1891</p>

<p>THAT COMPLAINT MOVED SAID COURT FOR A NEW TRIAL WHICH WAS
DENIED, AND THERE UPON SAID COURT SENTENCED THIS COMPLAINANT TO BE 
HUNG.</p>

<pb/>

<p>THAT THEREUPON THIS COMPLAINANT APPEALED TO THE SUPREME COURT
OF SAID STATE FROM SAID JUDGMENT AND FROM THE ORDER OF SAID COURT
DENYING HIM A NEW TRIAL.</p>

<p>THAT UPON SAID APPEAL SUCH PROCEEDINGS WERE HAD IN SAID 
SUPREME COURT, THAT SAID COURT REVERSED, ANNULLED AND SET ASIDE THE
SAID JUDGMENT AND REMANDED SAID CAUSE TO THE SUPERIOR COURT WITH
INSTRUCTIONS TO THE SAID COURT TO SENTENCE THIS COMPLAINANT WITHOUT
ANY OTHER TRIAL OR VERDICT OF A JURY, AS FOR MURDER IN THE SECOND
DEGREE.</p>

<p>THAT ON THE 16TH DAY OF JUNE 1891 THIS COMPLAINANT WAS BROUGHT
BEFORE SAID SUPERIOR COURT. ADJUDGED TO BE GUILTY OF MURDER
IN THE SECOND DEGREE BY SAID COURT,BY DIRECTION OF SAID SUPREME 
COURT, AND SENTENCED TO IMPRISONMENT IN THE STATE PENETENTIARY OF 
THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, FOR THE TERM OF TWENTY YEARS.</p>

<p>THAT COMPLAINANT IS ADVISED BY HIS COUNSEL, AND VERILY BEL-
IEVES THAT HE HAS BEEN SINCE THE 16TH DAY OF JUNE,1892, AND IS 
NOW DEPRIVED OF HIS LIBERTY WITHOUT DUE PROCESS OF LAW, IN VIOLAT
ION OF THE XIV. AMENDMENT TO THE CONSTITUTION OF THE UNITED STATES.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, YOUR COMPLAINANT PRAYS THAT A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS
MAY ISSUE FROM THIS HONORABLE COURT COMMANDING THE SAID</p>

<p>WARDEN OF THE STATE PENETENTIARY OF WASHINGTON TO
HAVE THE BODY OF YOUR COMPLAINANT BEFORE THIS HONORABLE COURT, AT
SUCH TIME AS TO THE COURT SHALL SEEM MEET. THAT THIS HONORABLE
COURT ADJUDGE THE IMPRISONMENT OF YOUR COMPLAINANT TO BE ILLEGAL
AND DIRECT HIM TO BE DISCHARGED AND YOUR COMPLAINANT AS IN DUTY
BOUND WILL EVER PRAY ETC.</p>

<p>Albert Friedrich</p>
<p>COMPLAINANT.</p>

<pb/>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON,
COUNTY OF WALLA WALLA;</p>

<p>ALBERT FREDERICH BEING DULY SWORN DEPOSES AND SAYS: THAT
HE HAS READ THE FOREGOING COMPLAINT AND KNOWS THE CONTENTS THEREOF
AND THE SAME IS TRUE OF HIS OWN KNOWLEDGE.</p>

<p>Albert Friedrich</p>

<p>SUBSCRIBED AND SWORN TO BEFORE ME THIS 15 DAY OF JULY,
1892.</p>

<p>J<unclear></unclear></p>

<p>NOTARY PUBLIC IN AND FOR THE 
STATE OF WASHINGTON, RESIDING
AT WALLA WALLA.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>