<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0213.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Taichi Hiura v. Henry M. White. Memo of Points and Authorities.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0213.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Taichi Hiura v. Henry M. White. Memo of Points and Authorities.</title>
<date when="1920-08-28">August 28, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-08">August 1920</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hiura, Taichi</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Kiefer, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-02" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>No. 5487.</p>

<p>In the United States District Court for the Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of Hiura, Teiichi, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus,</p>

<p>Memo of Points and Authorities.</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Aug 28 1920</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<p>James Kiefer</p>
<p>for Petitioner.</p>
<p>Suite 327 Colman Bldg.</p>
<p>Seattle</p>

<p>Copy of within <unclear>memorandum</unclear> received and service of same acknowledged this 28 day of August, 1920</p>

<p>Robt. C. Saunders,</p>
<p><del>For</del> U.S. Atty</p>

<pb/>

<p>No.5487.</p>

<p>Memo of Points and Authorities.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of Hiura, Teiichi for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Section 17 of the Immigration Act of Feb. 5, 1917, provides:</p>

<p>"That each Board of Special Inquiry shall consist of three members who shall be selected from such of the immigrant officers in the service as the Commissioner General of Immigration with the approval of the Secretary of Labor, shall from time to time designate as qualified to serve on such Boards."</p>

<p>The Board in the instant case appears to have been composed of two inspectors and stenographer. We submit that this does not constitute a legal Board.</p>

<p>U.S. vs. Redfern, 180 Fed. 500.</p>

<p>The statue uses the term officer. We submit that a stenographer is not an officer.</p>

<p>A pension agent's clerk is not an official of the United States so as to disqualify him from membership in the state legislature.</p>

<p>State vs. Mason, 55 N.E.167.</p>

<p>A clerk in the office of the Supervisor of Internal Revenue under Revised Statutes Sec. 3160 is not an officer of the United States and as such required to take the Oath of Office prescribed by Section 1756 R.S. U.S.</p>

<p>Hedrick vs. U.S. 16 Ct. Claims, page 88-100.</p>

<p>U.S. vs. Schlierholz, 137 Fed. 616,</p>

<p>Martin vs. U.S. 168Fed. 198.</p>

<p>U.S. vs. Haas, 167 Fed. 211</p>

<pb/>

<p>If the Board was illegally constituted as we contend it was,it was without power to hear or determine the matter, and this sets the whole matter at large, and the court will determine the status of the petitioner upon the record both as to law and fact.</p>

<p>U.S. vs. Smith, 124 U.S. 525. 31 L. ed.534</p>

<p>The deportation of the petitioner was ordered by the Board of Special Inquiry upon an order which is a little difficult to understand. It reads as follows:</p>

<p>"In my opinion the agreement with Japan in regard to the issuance of return certificates only applies to legal residents, and that the passport issued to this applicant was issued to him through a misunderstanding of the facts in connection with his surreptitious entry; that the passport should not have been issued and the applicant is without a proper passport entitling him to come to the United States. I move to reject for that reason, and also for the further reason that he is a person likely to become a public charge.</p>

<p>Mr. Hunter: I second the motion.</p>

<p>Miss Mullen: I make it unanimous."</p>

<p>Just what authority the Board of Special Inquiry possesses to sit as a court of error and appeal to review the issuance of a passport, is not clearly apparent.</p>

<p>It would seem that that portion of the order may be disregarded as beyond the powers of the Board. The passport is merely evidence of the right of the party named in it to enter the country. It is not final or conclusive. It will be observed that the Board merely holds that the authority issuing the passport issued it irregularly because of a misunderstanding of the facts. That error is to be corrected by the issuing authority and not by the Board of Special Inquiry.</p>

<pb/>

<p>action of the Board is a thinly veiled expression of their resentment at being unable to locate the petitioner in the country within the time during which he could have been deported.</p>

<p>The rights of the petitioner as here contended for are sustained in U.S. vs. Martin, 193 Fed. 795.</p>

<p>Sprung vs. Martin, 182 Fed. 330.</p>

<p>U.S. vs. Nakashima, 160 Fed. 842.</p>

<p>Taylor vs. U.S. 207 U.S. 120. 52 L. ed. 130.</p>

<p>It is respectfully submitted that the writ should be granted and the petitioner permitted to land.</p>

<p>James Kiefer</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>