<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0369.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Teramoto Sadashige v. T.W. Lynch. Return</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0369.005</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Teramoto Sadashige v. T.W. Lynch. Return</title>
<date when="1921-11-10">November 10, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-11">November 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Teramoto Sadashige</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Lynch, T.W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Martin, Winter S.</persName>
<persName>Wardell</persName>
<persName>Allen</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Faulkner, Judson</persName>
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-08" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>No. 6361</p>
<p>Return</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of TERAMOTO SADASHIGE for a writ of habeas corpus</p>

<p>TERAMOTO SADASHIGE Petitioner,</p>
<p>vs</p>
<p>T.W.LYNCH, Acting Commissioner of Immigration,</p>
<p>Respondent.</p>

<p>To the Honorable Jeremiah Neterer, Judge of the District Court of the United States, for the Western District of Washington.</p>

<p>Now comes the respondent, T.W. Lynch, Acting United States Commissioner of Immigration, for the District of Washington, with headquarters at the port of Seattle, Washington, and for answer to the writ of habeas corpus in the above entitled matter, says that he here produces the said TERAMOTO SADASHIGE, the person named in the petition for said writ, in obedience to the command and direction thereof; and for further return and answer to said writ avers that he is detaining in his custody the said TERAMOTO SADASHIGE for deportation from the United States, as an alien Japanese person not entitled to admission under the laws of the United States, under and by virtue of an order of the Secretary of Labor of the United States, issued to him, the said respondent, said order being in the words and figures following, to wit:</p>

<p>1</p>

<pb/>

<p>55106/52</p>
<p>Seattle.</p>

<p>October 25, 1921.</p>

<p>In re: Sadashige Teramoto.</p>

<p>MEMORANDUM</p>

<p>Submitted with letter of Commissioner at Seattle, Brief of Atty., Board Minutes, etc.</p>

<p>Whatever domicile this alien had in the United States was illegal, he having first entered in violation of law, without the inspection required under the Immigration Act and was not then in possession of a proper passport. The fact that he is now returning to the United States to resume his domicile does not entitle him to consideration. He is now without a proper passport, does not appear upon the manifest of the vessel as a seaman, but is reported as a stowaway.</p>

<p>The Bureau concurs in the recommendation that he be EXCLUDED.</p>

<p>For the Commissioner General:</p>

<p>F.H.Larned</p>
<p>Special Assistant.</p>

<p>JWB</p>

<p>So ordered:</p>
<p>THEODORE G. RISLEY,</p>
<p>Theodore G.Risley, Acting Secretary.</p>

<p>-----</p>

<p>Respondent attaches hereto the original record, decision and exhibits, both on the hearing before the board of special inquiry at Seattle, Washington, and the hearing on appeal to the Secretary of Labor, which papers constitute a part of this return.</p>

<p>And now the respondent having fully answered, prays that said writ may be discharged.</p>

<p>TW Lynch</p>
<p>Acting United States Commissioner of Immigration.</p>

<pb/>

<p>The United States of America</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>SS</p>

<p>T.W. Lynch, being first duly sworn, on his oath deposes and says:</p>

<p>That he is the acting commissioner of immigration named in the foregoing return; that he has read the said return and knows the contents thereof; and that he believes the same to be true.</p>

<p>TW Lynch</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 10th day of November, 1921.</p>

<p>DL Young</p>
<p>Notary Public</p>

<p>SEAL:</p>

<p>3</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 6361</p>

<p>In the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Teramoto Sadashige for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Return</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Divison</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Nov 12 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>