<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0184.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Harry Gong vs. United States. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0184.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Harry Gong vs. United States. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1000">1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">November 1913.</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Barbour, J. H.</term>
<term>Chong, Go</term>
<term>Dook, Louie</term>
<term>Gum, Chin</term>
<term>Gwai, Yip</term>
<term>Harms, L. A.</term>    
<term>Hoy, Lee Dai</term>
<term>Leen, Mon Ah</term>
<term>Look, Gwoo Ah</term>
<term>Oi, Lin</term>
<term>Lowe, Herman</term>
<term>Ning, Sum</term>
<term>Poon, Leong</term>
<term>Post, Louis F.</term>    
<term>Sheong, Go</term>
<term>Smith, Wilfred F.</term>
<term>Tung, Lee</term>
<term>Wise, J. M.</term>    
<term>Wong, Go</term>
<term>Yow, Yut</term>
<term></term>

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>China</term>
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
<term>Visalia, California</term>
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Harry Gong</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>United States District Court, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
    <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>"Exhibit B"</p>

<p>Record of hearing held at Immigration Office, Portland, Oregon,
November 11, 1913, in the case of YUT YOW, arrested on Departmental
warrant reading as follows:</p>
<p>"Arrow Yut Yow; Mon Ah Leen; Ah Sing,
alias Gwoo Shee, alias Gwoo Ah Look; and
Chin Gum, alias Chin Yew Gim.
Louis F. Post,
Acting Secretary."</p>

<p>Hearing conducted by Inspector in Charge J. H. Barbour. 
Herman Lowe, Chinese Interpreter,
Wilfred F. Smith, Stenographer.</p>

<p>YUT YOW, duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>Q What are all your names? A Yut Yow; Ah Sing; Lim Quai; I 
belong to the Go family.</p>
<p>Q Were you ever known as Yip Yut Yow? A I do not remember now;
I registered as Yip Yut Yow.</p>
<p>Q Did you ever have a certificate of residence? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Do you know the number? A I don't remember.</p>
<p>Q Where is that certificate now? A It was burned up in the fire 
in San Francisco.</p>
<p>Q Yut Yow, you have been arrested on Department's telegraphic warrant
dated November 6, 1913, charging that you are an alien adn that you 
were a prostitute at the time of your entry, and that you entered 
the United States for the purpose of prostitution or other immoral
purpose, and that you have been found practising prostitution
subsequent to your entry into the United States; that you are lawfully
within the United States in that you have been found employed
by, in, or in connection with a house of prostitution.
You will now be given a hearing, and aforded an opportunity, to
show cause, if any there be, why you should not be deported in 
conformity with the law. It is your privilege to nominate an 
<fw>YUT YOW (1)</fw>
<pb/>
attorney or representative to appear in your behalf, and said 
attorney or representative will be admited to the hearing and given
success to all the evidence adduced in your case, in due course adn
in compliance with the Immigration Laws and Regulations pertaining 
thereto. Furthermore, it is your privilege to be released from 
custody upon furnishing bonds with approved security in amount of four
thousand dollaws.</p>

<p>Warrant read and explained to alien.</p>

<p>Q How old are you? A Forty-five.</p>
<p>Q. Where were you born? A In San Francisco.</p>
<p>Q. Where in San Francisco? A Hop Hing Building.</p>
<p>Q Street and number? A Jackson Street, I do not remember teh 
number.</p>
<p>Q How long have you know that you were born in San Francisco?
A My father told me when he left for China after I was married.</p>
<p>Q What is your father's name? A Go Chong.</p>
<p>Q What is your mother's name? A Lin Oi.</p>
<p>Q Did you ever have any brothers or sisters? A One older brother,
Go Sheong.</p>
<p>Q Where is he now? A He is dead.</p>
<p>Q WHere was he born? A In San Francisco.</p>
<p>Q Have you ever been in China? A No.</p>
<p>Q Where you registered in K.S.19 or 20? A K.S.20, I think.</p>
<p>Q Where did you get your certificate of residence? 
A I do not remember.</p>
<p>Q Have you any record of the number of that certificate?
A No.</p>
<p>Q. Is your picture on that certificate? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q When did you last see that certificate? A A long time ago.</p>
<p>Q Do you remember, when applying for that certificate of residence, 
being asked Where you were born? A I said I was born in 
San Francisco.</p>
<fw>YUT YOW (2)</fw>
<pb/>
<p>Q Do you remember being asked when you came to the United States first?
A I don't remember.</p>
<p>Q By what name were you known on that certificate of residence? A
I don't remember.</p>
<p>Q Who is there in the United States thatknows that you were born in
this country? A Only one, Go Wong.</p>
<p>Q. Where is he? A He is living somewhere in Portland.</p>
<p>Q How did he learn of your birth in this country?
A He has been to San Francisco.</p>
<p>Q Is he related to you? A He is a distant relative of my father.</p>
<p>Q. How old is he? A Sixty odd years old.</p>
<p>Q What is his occupation? A He is a laborer.</p>
<p>Q Is there any one in the United States except Go Wong who knows
anything about your birth or birthplace?
A I don't know of any other.</p>
<p>Q What is your present occupation? A Iam a seamstress.</p>
<p>Q Are you a prostitute? A No.</p>
<p>Q Did you not admit at the time of your former examination on the 4th
instant that you were a prostitute? A I don't remember that I did.</p>
<p>Q Isn't it a fact that you have been following the life of prostitution
for a great many years? A No.</p>
<p>Q Are you married  A Yes.</p>
<p>Q To whom? A I am not married now; I was married,</p>
<p>Q Where is your former husband? A He went to China.</p>
<p>Q Was he born in China? A I don't know where he was born.</p>
<p>Q What was his occupation? A He was a laborer.</p>
<p>Q You have never been married but once? A Only once. </p>
<p>Q Is it true that at the time of your arrest you were found in your 
room on North Fourth Streer at four o'clock in the morning with a 
man not your husband? A He was a friend of mine; that was all.</p>
<p>Q What was he doing in your room? A He was visiting me there.</p>
<p>Q What was that man's name, if you know? A Sum Ning.</p>
<p>Q How long have you known him? A I don't know how long.</p>
<fw>YUT YOW (3)</fw>
<pb/>
<p>Q Had he ever visited you before? A He has seen me before; he is
a friend of my husband's.</p>
<p>Q Do you know what a prostitute is? A No.</p>
<p>Q Who supports you? A I make my own living by sewing.</p>
<p>Q Did you apply for a duplicate certificate of residence in K.S.30?
A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Do you know who your lawyer was? A I don't remember the name 
of my lawyer.</p>
<p>Q Who were your witnesses at the time, if you know?
A Leong Poon; he is in China now.</p>
<p>Q Was Louie Dick one of your witnesses? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Was Lee Dai Hoy one of your witnesses? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Didn't you state at that time that your certificate was stolen from
you in Visalia, Cal.? A I don't remember.</p>
<p>Q Did you ever know a Chinaman by the name of Yip Gwai?
A Yes; he used to live in SanvFrancisco.</p>
<p>Q Did he sign or witness your application for an original certificate 
of residence? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Were you ever known as Lin Gwai? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q. Have you a scar over the right eyebrow, on the right eyelid, 
and on the right side of your neck? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Do you wish to designate any one to act as counsel or representative 
for you? A Notify ON Lee Co., this city.</p>
<p>Q Any particular person? A The manager of the store, Lee Tung.</p>
<p>Q Do you wish to say anything in your own behalf? A No.</p>
<p>Q Have you understood the interpreter? A Yes.</p>

<ab>(Signed by mark) Yut Yow her x mark</ab>

<ab>Witness to mark:
(Signed) H. Lowe.</ab>

<p>I hereby certify that the foregoing is a true and correct 
transcript of testimony taken by me in shorthand.</p> <ab>W.F.Smith,Stenographer</ab>
<fw>YUT YOW (4)</fw>
<pb/>
<p>Same place, November 17,1913.</p>

<p>Questions by Inspector in Charge Barbour.
L. A. HARMS, duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>Q What is your name? A L.A.Harms.</p>
<p>Q What is your position? A Sergeant of police, City of Portland, 
State of Oregon.</p>
<p>Q How long have you been on the police force? A Nearly seven years.</p>
<p>Q Can you identify this photograph (of Yut Yow)? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q. Whose photograph is that? She first gave me the name of Ah Sing;
her name is Yut Yow.</p>
<p>Q. When and where did you first see this woman? A I have known 
Yut Yow for several years; for the past year, probably longer, I 
have known her to be a prostitute. We arrested her about two weeks
ago on the second florr of a building on the southwest corner of 
Fourt and Flanders Streets, this city.</p>
<p>Q Under what circumstances did you see her at that time? A We were
investigating that place, knowing that there were Chinese prostitutes 
up there, about two or three weeks before the arrest was made; we were
up there three or four times, Officer Wise and myself.</p>
<p>Q State briefly what you saw on the occasion of these investigations
so far as your observation is limited to this woman. A In the
first place we had information from different sources that there
were Chinese prostitutes up there. We watched the place on several
different occasions, and saw Chinese going up there <del>unclear</del> 
in the rooms that the women were in. We went up and talked to the 
women the best we could. At different times we found different men 
in this woman's room. Finally, about 4:30 in the morning, November
4th, we went up there with the purpose of making her arrest, and we
found a Chinese in bed with her.</p>
<p>Q Did you have warrant for the arrest of that woman at that time?
A Yes, for vagrancy and indecent and immoral acts.</p>
<fw>YUT YOW (5)</fw>
<pb/>
<p>Q In your capacity, experience and observation as a police officer in
the Chinese quarter on North Fourt Street, Portland, what have
you found to be the reputation of the place out of which this woman
was arrested? A It has the reputation of being a bawdy-house,
where Chinese prostitutes ply their trade.</p>
<p>Q Are there families living in the same building with these women? 
A Yes, in the same building, but not in that particular section;
they are mostly on the third floor.</p>
<p>Q Is it your experience that Chinese prostitutes and Chinese
families dwell in the same building without any particular notice 
of each other? A Yes, in some instances.</p>
<p>Q Is this case one of the instances that you speak of? A Yes.</p>
<p>Q Are you satified that this woman is a common prostitute? A I am.</p>
<p>Q Do you base your belief upon information and observation? A Yes.</p>
<ab>(Signed) L. A. Harmes.</ab>
    
<p>Questions by Inspector in Charge Barbour.
J. M. WISE, duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>
<p>Q What is your name? A J. M. Wise.</p>
<p>What is your position? A Police officer, City of Portland.</p>
<p>Q How long have you been such? A Nearly two years.</p>
<p>Q Can you identify this phtograph (of Yut Yow)? A Yes, Yut Yow;
she first gave me the name of Ah Sing.</p>
<p>Q When, where and under what circumstances did you first see this
woman? A I have known her about a year. The first time I saw
her was when I arrested her in bed with a Chinaman up on Second
Street, on the charge of conducting and opium joint, because they
were smoking opium and she claim it was her room.</p>
<p>Q Has she been known to you here as a common prostitute? A Yes
I have caught her with a number of other Chinamen since. Along
<fw>YUT YOW (6)</fw>
<pb/>
about the 20th day of October, this year, I found her in room 17 of 
a building on the southwest corner of Fourth and Flaunders streets,
this city.</p>
<p>Q Under what circumstances did you see her there? A Investigating 
the place, gaining evidence as to this place being a house of 
prostitution and as to this woman's practising prostitution.</p>
<p>Q Did you arrest this woman? A Yes, on the 4th day of November,
about 4:30 in the morning.</p>
<p>Q Upon what charge did you arrest her? A Vagrancy and committing 
indecent and immoral acts.</p>
<p>Q Under what circumstances did you find this woman on the morning you
arrested her? A There was a Chinaman in bed with her. </p>
<p>Q Did she offer any explanation as to the situation in which she was
found at the time of the arrest? A She did not.</p>
<p>Q How did you gain your knowledge as to this woman's being a common
prostitute? A By observation and finding men in her room on
different occasions.</p>
<p>Q What if you know, is the general reputation of the quarters in which
you found this woman at the time of arrest? A That particular 
part of the building has the reputation of being a bawdy-house.</p>
<p>Q How many and what class of women are in that particular part of the 
building, if you know? A At that time there were five Chinese 
prostitutes and two Japanese prostitutes.</p>
<p>Q Are there other Chinese residing in that same building? A Yes, 
but not in that part of the building.</p>
<p>Q Are there apparently respectable Chinese families living in that
building? A Yes, though quite a ways off from that part of the building.</p>
<p>Q Do you find in your experience that the so-called respectable elements
of Chinese have any scruples against living in the same building with 
prostitutes? A They live in the same building, but they don't 
associate together.</p>
<fw>YUT YOW (7)</fw>
<pb/>
<p>Q Are you satisfied from your observation extending over a period of 
about a year that this woman is a prostitute? A Yes.</p>

<ab>(Signed) J. M. Wise</ab>

<p>I hereby certify that the foregoing is a true and correct 
transcript of testimony taken by me in shorthand.</p>
<ab>W. F. Smith,
Stenographer.</ab>
    
<fw>YUT YOW (8)</fw>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>