<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0364.015">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Tsunetaro Machida v. Luther Wedin. Bill of Exceptions</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0364.015</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Tsunetaro Machida v. Luther Wedin. Bill of Exceptions</title>
<date when="1921-12-20">December 20 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-12">December 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Machida, Tsunetaro</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Wedin, Luther</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Horner, Thomas R.</persName>
<persName>Judd, Edward</persName>
<persName>Lonergan, Pierce</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>United States District Court, Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>No. 6190.</p>

<p>Bill of Exceptions</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Tsunetaro Machida, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>BE IT REMEMBERED, that heretofore the petitioner petitione the said United States District Court for a writ of habeas corpus on the <del></del> ground that the imprisonment, confinement, restaint and order of detention of said petitioner was illegal and not according to law; that the Government made return that the petitioner wasbeing held under and by virtue of a finding of <del>Henry M. White, Immigration Commissioner;</del> <add>The Secretary of Labor</add> that ms said petitioner has become apublic charge within five years after his entry into the United States from causes not affirmatively shown to have arisen subsequent thereto, and that he waslikely to become a public charg at the timeofhis entry into the United States; that the petitioner then replied denying the facts set forth in said return; that all said above described pleadings are apart ofthe record of this action and hereby are made a part of this bill of exceptions; that on the 26th day of September 1921, this Honorable Court, having previously heard the petition and <del>mm</del> the arguments of counsel and having made his decision and filed the same with the Clerk, signed a judgment affirming the decision of said <del>Immigration Commissioner</del> <add>Secretary of Labor</add>, denying the petition of the petitioner, and remanding thepetitioner to the immigration authorities for deportation in accordance with theorder of deportation heretofore issed.</p>

<p>Counsel asked the Court to rule:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That the warrant of arrest of the petitioner as shown by the record was illegal and not based upon facts sufficient in law or in fact to justify the issuanceof the same, which the court refused to do.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>That the letters, statements and documents from the officials inspectos and Commissionerof the United States were not proper evidence not being under oath, being hearsay, and not admissable under the rules of law.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Dec 29 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<pb/>

<p>III.</p>

<p>That the petitioner was not a public charge in the meaning of t statute on immigration in such case made and provided; which the court refused to do.</p>

<p>IV.</p>

<p>That thepetitioner was not likely to become a public charge at the timeof his entry into the United States; which the court rfused to do.</p>

<p>That this Honorable Court having signed a judgment discharging the writ of habeas corpus and remanding the petitioner to the custody of theunited States Immigration Department for seportation, and the petitioner having appealed from said decision and judgment of this court to the United States Circuit Court of Appeals for the Ninth Judicial Circuit, and having filed such petition for appeal and an assignment of errors and said appeal having been allowed and citation issued, as appears by the record;</p>

<p>Thereupon, the petitioner, Tsunetaro Machida, tenders this his bill of exceptions to the actions, rulings and judgment of the court and the refusal to rule in theparticulars above set out, to have the same effect as if each and every such exception had been separately signed and sealed, which are now signed and made a part of the record herein.</p>

<p>Dated thisL6th day of December1921.</p>

<p>TSUNETARO MACHIDA; Petitioner,</p>
<p>BY Thos R. Horner and Edward Judd.</p>

<p>BILL OF EXCEPTIONS ALLOWED:</p>
<p>Jeremiah Neterer</p>
<p>Judge.</p>

<p>Copy of thisbill of exceptionsreceived and due service acknowledged this 20th day of December 1921.</p>

<p><unclear>Judeau</unclear> F. <unclear>Falknor</unclear></p>
<p>United States Attorney.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Dec 20 1921</p>

<p>F. M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>

<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>