<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p> State of Missouri, St Louis County. </p>

<p> To the Hon John W. Colvin </p>
<p> Judge of the Law Commissioners 
Court St Louis Co </p>

<p> The petition of William Johnson 
Respectfully shows </p>
<p> That on the 9th day of August 1854 
your petitioner was committed to the Jail 
of StLouis County aforesaid by the name of John Johnson suspected of 
being a slave by a warrant <sic> under the 
under the </sic> hand of P.W. Johnstone Esq 
then a Justice of the Peace of the aforesaid 
County. that your petitioner was born in 
the <del> City </del> County of St Louis aforesaid of a free 
mother, and never has been claimed as 
a slave by any person whomsoever. That 
your petitioner hath applied to John Hemp-
stead keeper of the jail of said county, in 
which your petitioner is imprisoned for leave 
to take a copy of the comitment so as to an-
nex the same herto, but said Hempstead 
refused to allow your petitioner so to do. That 
your petitioner is ready to establish his free-
dom by satisfactory proof and that the 
suspicion of his being a slave is utterly 
groundless. that Petitioner is illegally im-
prisoned &amp; detained in the jail of St Louis 
County by said Hempstead and the ill-
egality of said imprisonment consists 
in your petitioners being so detained 
on the charge of being a slave and 
a runaway whereas in truth &amp; in fact he is a 
free person of color. Your petitioner 
being so illegally arrested and de-

tained in prison prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus 
may issue directed to said John 
Hempstead requiring him to produce the 
body of your petitioner before your Honor 
and on the truth of the above allega-
tions appearing that he may be dis-
charged-- </p>

<p> Burke &amp; Gloves</p>
<p> Attys for Pettioner </p>

<p> William Johnson the above petitioner 
being duly sworn on his oath says that 
the foregoing petition and the matter 
therein set forth are true </p>
<p> William his X mark Johnson </p>

<p> Sworn to and subscribed 
Oct 11th 1854 before me </p>
<p> Jno W Colvin Law Com </p>


<p> Ex Parte </p>
<p> William Johnson </p>

<p> Pet for Hab. Corp. </p>

<p> Filed 11th Oct 1854 </p>
<p> Jno W. Colvin </p>

