<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0182.059">
    
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>K. Gregory et al. Type of document</title>
                <principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
                    <name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
                    <name n="Bruha, Ashley S" xml:id="asb">Ashley Bruha</name>
                    
                </respStmt>
                <sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
                <sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
            </titleStmt>
            
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2022</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Produce the Body</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0182.059</idno>
                
                <availability>
                    <licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
                    <p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title level="m" type="main">K. Gregory et al. Civil</title>
                    <date when="1914-01">January 1914</date>
                    <note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
                        <collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
                        <idno>2646KGregoryEtAl</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Case Papers</term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="original" n="type">
                    <term>Civil</term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="original" n="term">
                    <term><date when="1914-01">January 1914</date></term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Henry White</term>
                    <term>Frank Crosby</term>
                    <term>Clay Allen</term>
                    <term>G.F. Fishburne</term>
                    <term>Parker</term>
                    <term>Kalina</term>
                    <term>K. Gregory</term>
                    <term>M. Aloshin</term>
                    <term>I. Riaboff</term>
                    <term>P. Neanlin</term>
                    <term>I. Erelin</term>
                    <term>L. Orloff</term>
                    <term>G. Yakimoff</term>
                    <term>P. Yakimoff</term>
                    <term>Jeremiah Neterer</term>
                    
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
                    <term>Seattle, Washington</term>
                </keywords>
                
            </textClass>
            
            <particDesc>   
                <listPerson>            
                    <person role="petitioner">
                        <persName>K. Gregory</persName>
                        <persName>M. Aloshin</persName>
                        <persName>I. Riaboff</persName>
                        <persName>P. Neanlin</persName>
                        <persName>I. Erelin</persName>
                        <persName>L. Orloff</persName>
                        <persName>K. Yakimoff</persName>
                        <persName>P. Yakimoff</persName>
                    </person>
                    <person role="defendant">
                        <persName>Henry White</persName>
                    </person>
                    <person role="attorney_petitioner">
                        <persName>Parker</persName>
                        <persName>Kalina</persName>
                    </person>
                    <person role="attorney_defendant">
                        <persName>Clay Allen</persName>
                        <persName>GF Fishburne</persName>
                    </person>
                    <person role="judge">
                        <persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
                    </person>
                </listPerson>
                
                <listOrg>
                    <org>
                        <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
                        <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
                    </org>
                </listOrg>   
            </particDesc> 
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>         
            <change when="2022-02" who="#asb">transcribed and encoded</change>
        </revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>K. Gregory and seven others filed a petition praying a writ of habeas corpus alleging that they
are in good faith seeking admission into the United States to make the United States their permanent
hom; that they do not come within any of the classes prohibited admission. A show cause order was
issued and the Commissioner of Immigration made return setting forth, in substance, that the
petitioners sout admission and were held for special inquiry by the immigrant inspector and a board
of special inquiry was organized as provided by law, and:</p>
<p>(Copy parg. 3 of "Further and Separate Answer.)</p>
<p>The petitioners move that they be forwith discharged, for the <unclear>fo</unclear> reason
<add>(1)</add> that the return shows thtat they are detained and restrained of their liberty for 
unlawful reasonas and contrary to the statutes in shuch cases made and provided; (2) that the
special examining board and the Secretary of Commerce and Labor and said Commissioner exceeded their
authority and jurisdiction; (3) that the alleged reasons for detaining said petitioners are
irrelevant, immaterial and not support by evidence, and are frivolous and sham; (4) that said
petitioners had all the personal qualifications required of them by the statutes, and to entitle
them to immediate and unconditional discharge.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>jurisdiction of this court is limited to ascertaining whether the petitioners were denied a
hearing, and if a hearing has been accorded, the court is precluded from a re-examination of the
issue presented, merely because it is contended that the conclusion of the immigration officers
based upon the testimony was wrong. In the Mooa Singh case a trial was had, and the conclusion of
the examining board was that the alien be excluded from admission under the laws of the United
States. The conclusion of the board found delinquency in the eprsonal qualifications of the
applicants which borught the withint the exclusion provisions act. This court connot examine into
the testimony produced upon the hearing in this case before the special examining board, nor enter 
upon a re-examination of the facts. This court is bound by the facts as found by the board of sepcia
inquiry. <add>and the facts as found being the qualifications under the provision of the exclsion
act.</add></p>
<p>Are the petitioners qualified to enter under the findings of the board, and is the act of the
Board beyond its jurisdiction, and does the personal condition of teh applicants, as found, preclude
their exclusions?</p>
<p>Section 1 of the Immigration Act, of Feb. 20, 1907, reads:</p>
<p>"That they shall be levied, collected and paid a tax of $4 for every alien entering the United
States."</p>
<p>Sec. 2 of said act, <add>provides who are excluded anyone who are "perceived likely to become a
public charge"</add></p>
<p>Section 10 of the act provides:</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>A right of appeal from the decision of this board is denited by the provisions of Sec. 25 of the
act, as follows:</p>
<p>"But nothing in this section shall admit of any appeal in the case of an alien rejected as
provided for in Sec. 10 fo this act."</p>
<p>Sec. 24 of the act provides:</p>
<p>"...Immigration officers shall have power to administer oaaths, and to take and consider evidence
thouching the right of any alien to enter the United States, and where such action is necessary to
make a written record of such evidence."</p>
<p>A provision for the punishment of persons who shall knowingly or wilfully give false oaths or
swear to any false statement is made, and it is also provided that the decision of such officer in
admitting an alien shall be subject to challenge by in other officer, and such challenge shall
operate to take the alien whose right to land is challenged before a board of special inquiry for
its investigation. If is further provided:</p>
<p>"Every such alien who may not appear to the examining immigrant inspector at the port of arrival
to be clearly and beyond doubt entitled to land shall be detained for examination in relation
thereto by a board of special inquiry."</p>
<p>"Sec. 25...All hearings before boards shall be separate and the decision of any two of the baord
shall prevail; but either the alien or any dissenting member of said board may appeal
<pb></pb>
to <unclear>q</unclear> the secretary of labor.....that in every case where an alien is excluded
from admission into the United States under any law or treaty now existing or hereafter made, the
decision of the appropriate immigration officers, if adverse to the admission of such alien shall be
final, unless reversed on appeal to the secretary of labor."</p>
<p>Sec. 26 provides:</p>
<p>"That any alien liable to be excluded because likely to become a public charge, or because of
physical disability other than tuberculosis or a loathsome or dangerous contagious disease may, if
otherwise admissible, nevertheless be admitted in the discretion of the Secretary of Labor upon the
giving of a suitable and proper bond or undertaking,</p>
<p>Under Sec. 26 "An alien likely to become a public charge is excluded", and under Sec. 25, the
decision of the board of special inquiry is final. While the findings of the board with relation to
the petiitoners seem to eliminate all physical and mental deficiencies legslated against, by the
conclusions which follow in the construction of this statute, in the absence of an expressed or
implied intent as to the meaning of the prase "liable to become a public charge, <add><unclear>w
it</unclear></add> be <add>said</add> that the expression should apply to one or more of the other
specific reasons or cause for exclusion or all of them taken together, and which have not developed
to the stage to specifically identity <add>on</add> be off sufficient emphasis to demonstarte
physical or mental condition, In the consideration of Sec. 26 fo this act making "liable to become a
public charge" a specific objection in connection with all of the other specific grounds for
exclusion fo the applicant, the conclusion would seem to be by this expression, <add>that</add> the
immigratn officers are authorized to take into consideration the general conditions as applied to
the applicant, his ability to meet conditions and perform such labor as the new environment and
circumstances require, his ability to amalgamate and conform to the
<pb></pb>
</p>



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>