<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0185.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>George Alexander Mirianon vs. John Boyle and R. de Label-Mahy. Criminal</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0185.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1914">1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-01">January 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>



</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>George Alexander Mirianon</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>John Boyle</persName>
<persName>R. de Label-Mahy</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
    <placeName>Seattle, Washington.</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT, FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT
OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application 
of George Alexander Mirianon
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.
PETITION OF 
GEORGE ALEXANDER
MIRIANON.
2663</p>
<p>Comes now George Alexander, Mirianon, a resident of France 
and respectfully makes this application for a Writ of habeas corpus,
and alleges as follows:</p>
<p>I.
That George Alexander Mirianon is imprisoned and restrained
of his liberty by John Boyle and R. de Lobel Mahy, Vice Counsul
of France, at the Port of Seattle, State ofWashington, and by the
United States Marshal or one of his deputies under and by virtue 
of either or both of them, under the illegal and unlawful charge 
as your petitioner is informed and believes and so states the fact 
to be, that he has been guilty of insubordination to his superior 
officer while on the French Bark, Gender Faidherbe, and guilty
of conduct prejudicial to the good order of said vessel, and that
he should be taken and placed on the French Bark, Anna de Bretagne,
now lying at Ballard, Port of Seattle, and deported and carried 
on said vessel to the Republic of France.</p>
<p>II.
That said imprisonment and confinement and restraint as
aforesaid, is illegal, unlawful and wrongful and arises from the
following facts:</p>
<p>III.
That your petitioner arrived at the Port of Seattle on a voyage from France on teh 25 day of Dec, 1913,
and was charged by said R. de Lobel-Mahy of the following charges,
to-wit: That he had been guilty of insubordination to a 
superior officer while on board the French bark, General Faidherbe,
<pb/>
and that he was guilty of conduct prejudicial to the good order 
of said vessel.</p>
<p>IV.
That pursuant to said compalint, your petitioner was brought 
before the Hon. A. C. Bowman, U. S. Commissioner, and testimony
was given by R. de Lobel-Mahy, Vice Counsul of France relative
to said charges as hereinabove stated.</p>
<p>V. 
That upon hearing the testimony of said R. de Lobel-Mahy
Vice Counsul of France <del>and</del> A. C. Bowman, U. S. Commissioner made
an Order, directing the Marshal of said Western Division of Washington
and the Master of the French Bark, Anne de Bretagne, to deport
and carry said George Alexander Marianin to France on said 
vessel.</p>
<p>VI.
That your petitioner is informed and believes and so states 
the facts to be that said Marshal of theWestern District of Washington,
Northern Division and said R. de Lobel-Mahy, or any of their 
agents acting <del>theoughtor</del> through, under or for them and the Master
of the French Bark, Anne de Bretagne, are about to deport and return
the daid George Alexander Marianon to the Republic of France
in violation of the treaty relations between the United States and 
France and in violation of the constitution of the United States,
in that said Petitioner is being deprived of his liberty without 
due process of law</p>
<p>This petitioner further states that the said R. de Lobel-
Mahy was not present on said Bark, General Faidderbe a nd that he
has no knowledge of any of the acts of your petitioner while on 
said boat, and that siad U. S. Commissioner did not have a rigt to 
make any Order on the testimony of said R. de Lobel-Mahy, and furthermore, 
your petitioner states that the Order of said U. S. Commissioner 
to said Marshal of the Western District of Washington and to 
the Master of the French Bark, Anne de Bretagne, which your petitioner
makes a part of this petition, does not state any specific
<pb/>
date on which said Petitioner had been gulty of said acts as
charged. By reason thereof, said return and deportation is illegal
and invalid, and wrongfully issued.</p>
<p>VII.
<del>THE</del> Petitioner further states that the said Bark <add>wherein</add> the said
R. de Label-Mahy and said Marshal of the W. District of Washington
or any of their agents acting through of under them, intend to 
place this petitioner is the Anne de Bretagne, and that said Bark
is a sailing vessel and will take a period of from 3 to 9 months 
to return to France and your petitioner states that under the facts 
as presented to this Court by said R. de Label-Mahy, said Marshal
of the Western Division of Washington, or any person or persons 
acting by, under or through them, have no right to return said
petitioner to France as aforesaid.</p>
<p>VIII.
Petioner further states that his return would be unlawful,
illegal and contrary to the treaty relations between the United 
States and France and inviolation of the constitution of the United
States, in that it would deprive your petitioner of his liberty
without due process of law.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE YOUR PETITIONER PRAYS THAT a Writ of Habeas Corpus
be granted <del>through</del> <add>to</add> the said John Boyle, U. S. Marshal for the Western
District of Washington and to his deputies or any of them
and to said R. de Label-Mahy, Vice Counsul of France, and to such
person acting by, through or under them, commanding them and each 
of them to have the body of said George Alexander Mirianon before 
your Honor at a time and place therein to be specified, to do and 
receive what shall thenand there be considered by your Honor concerning
him, together with the time and cause of his detention and said
writ, and that he may be restored to liberty and that said Vice
Counsul be directed to return this petitioner to France by direct
route and not by the route as planned out and set forth in this
petition.</p>
<p>Dated this 20 day of January, 1914.</p>
<ab>John J. Sullivan - Atty for Petitioner</ab>












</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>