<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0490.012">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ng Kwack Kang v. King County. Brief of United States</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Daoud, Mariam M." xml:id="mmd">Mariam M. Daoud</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0490.012</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ng Kwack Kang v. King County. Brief of United States</title>
<date when="1916-01-08">January 8th, 1916</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno>Case No 3157</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1916-01">January 1916</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>White, Henry M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Kang, Ng Kwack</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, Adam</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay</persName>
<persName>Moodie, Albert</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
<person role="clerk">
<persName>Crosby, Frank L.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>King County</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#mmd">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0490.012"/>

<p>
United States District Court
Western District of Washington
Northern Division

In re petition of
Ng Kwack Kang
for Writ of Habeas Corpus

#3157
Brief of United States.

Statement of the Case.
Ng Kwack Kang applied for admission at Seattle as
the son of an American-born Chinese residing in Boston.
The Immigration authorities denied him admission because
the alleged relationship was not established. Petition
for writ of habeas corpus was then filed, embracing many 
charges, among which the following legal points are noted:
I. The function of habeas corpus is to test the 
legality of confinement, and unless that appears contrary
to law the writ should not be granted.
In the instant case petitioner is held for
deportation as a rejected chinese alien who applied for
admission, the authority for custody being a Department
of Labor warrant the validity of which is not attacked.
This warrant is based on the rejection made by the immigration
officials at the port of entry, affirmed on 
appeal to the Department of Labor. In chinese cases it 
has been construed proper, upon habeas corpus, to enquire
into the question of fairness of hearing and abuse of
discretion by the examining immigration officils and in
the event no fault is found on those scores, to remand
the petitioner for deportation.
U.S. vs Ju Toy,
49 L Ed 1040 et seq.
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
II. If the hearing was fair and no abuse of discretion
appears, the writ must be dismissed.
The power to admit, exclude, or expel aliens
has been confided entirely to the political department
of the government, except in the single instance of 
hearings before United States Commissioners on deportation
charges filed against chinese unlawfully found in the
country. In such cases an appeal to the District Court,
with trial de novo, is authorized. Sec. 13, Act 13 Sept
1888, ch. 1015. The case of aliens who have not landedm
and all other cases, being political matters of the highest 
order, are confided to the executive department of the
government, and its action, if fair and free from abuse
of discretion is final. The entire record in petitioners 
case is on file herein for examination on those points.

In re Ng Key Tung #2897, Neterer J, 1-21-15
Ex parte Moola Singh, 207 F 708, Neterer J
In re Chin Quock Wah #2971, Neterer J 5-10-15
In re Tang Tun, 168 F 488; aff. 56 L Ed 606
White vs Gregory 213 F 768
Zakonaite vs Wolf 57 L Ed 218
Nishimura Ekiu vs US, 35 L Ed 1146
Ex p. Hidekuny Iwata 219 F 610
Ex p. Bun Chew 220 F 387
In re Can Pon 168 F 479
In re D Charlie Mark 179 F 292
US vs Chin Yow 208 8
US vs Ju Toy 49 L Ed 1040
In re Gin Fung 100 F 389
In re Tsuie Shee and Quan You_G_, 325-15

Section 8, Act 13 Sept 1888, page 15 Chinese
Exclusion Laws pamphlet; and Sec. 7 of Act 5 May 1892,
page 21 same pamphlet, are the legal basis for Rule 9-b
of the immigration department, which reads:
"The lawful wife of an American citizen of the chinese 
race may be admitted for the purpose of joining her 
husband; and the lawful children of such a citizen partake 
in his citizenship and are therefore entitled to admission.
In every such case, convincing evidence of citizenship and 
relationship shall be exacted."
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
Under this rule the immigration officials at
Seattle made the rejection, not being convinced of the 
relationship claimed. Upon appeal, the Secretary of 
Labor affirmed the rejection, and this is final. The
record also fails to show convincing evidence of citizenship

Sections 22, 23, and 38 of the Immigration Act
of Feb 20 1907 as amended, pages 13, 14, 17, pamphlet laws,
contain further authority for the rules and regulations of
the Department of Labor. These rules bear on chinese 
cases, in as much as the law requires a chinese to first 
pass the requirements of this law before being examined
under the exclusion act.

In the Tang Tun case 168 F 488, at p. 496 it is
said: "Under such circumstances we do not understand, in
view of the law as declared by the Supreme Court I'
n the cases hereinbefore referred to, that ANY
court is authorized to review the action of the 
Department of Commerce and Labor in the matter of
admitting or weighing evidence, or to consider
whether the conslusions drawn by its officers
were right or wrong."

This Tang Tun case has been affirmed by the Supereme Court
in 56 L Ed 606, and is a leading case. It leaves no 
doubt that where there was a fair hearing and no abuse of 
discretion appears, the prisoner will be remanded. The
recent case of Ex parte Lam Pui, 217 F 456, cited in brief
of petitioner, clearly states that the court will not 
weigh the evidence, but will see if there is any evidence 
upon which the immigration officials could act.

Even if the conclusions of the immigration board 
are incorrect, the court has no authority in the absence
of denial of fair hearing or abuse of discretion. U.S. 
vs. Li Chiong, 217 F 45, C. C. A.
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
This rule is also laid down in te following cases:
US vs Uhl, 215 F 573, C C A (citing many cases)
Ex parte Bun Chew, 220 F 387
US vs Sin Tuck 48 L Ed 917
US vs Ju Toy 49 L Ed 1041 (citing many cases)

Several of the cases above cited point that abuse of 
discretion must not be presumed from the record submitted,
from visual facts at the hearing that the testimony is a 
fabric of lies. This clearly means that so long as
the immigration authorities act fairly and determine the 
matter conscientiously they will be sustained on habeas
corpus. In the Iwata case, 219 G 610 it is said-
"....it must be shown that the proceedings were
manifestly unfair; that the action of the executive
officers was such as to prevent a fair investigation;
or that there was a manifest abuse of the discretion
committed to them by sttute. In other cases the
order of the executive officers within their authority
of the statute is final."

In both the Ju Toy case and the D Charlie Mak case
above cited the appellate courts have positively stated 
that the decision of the executive officers is final even 
in cases involving claims of citizenship, and that they 
would not analyze the nature of the right of a person (to
land) presenting himself at the frontier for admission.
The right claim by petitioner herein is only a treaty or 
statutory right, governed by the qualifications imposed by
the statutes therefor made and provided, which makes the 
decision of the executive officials final. 28 Stat. L 390;
applied in US vs Gin Fung 100 F 389.

III. Petitioner cannot try out his right to land in 
this or any other court, and the only evidence admissible
on the habeas corpus hearing is that having a material 
bearing on Point II above.
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
IV. The appeal was heard and passed on by the
Assistant Secretary of Labor, acting as Secretary of Labor,
which is in compliance with law.

In the brief of petitioner it is claimed that 
the Secretary of Labor personally should have heard the 
appeal. This is not the law. This court should take
judicial notice in the abolute sense of the signature
of Louis F. Post, Assistant Secretary of Labor, acting as
Secretary, and not accept any evidence of such judisically
noticed point.
Act 4 Mch 1913, 37. Stat. L. 376. sec 2,
In re Chin Quock Wah #2971, Neterer J, 5-10-15
Hannibal Bridge Co. vs U.S., 221 US 194-206
Sec. 177, 178, 179 Revised Statutes.
Van Fleet on Collateral Attack,pp. 46-54.
McDowell vs U.S., 159 US 596
Ball vs. U.S., 140 U.S. 118
In re Hanning, 139 U.S. 504, 605-7
Hussey vs Smith, 99 U.S. 20
Ex parte Powers, 129 F 985
Keyser vs Hitz, 133 U.S. 138
N.Y. and Md.L.R.R.Co., vs Winans, 58 U.S. 30
In re Jem Yuen, 188 F 350
U.S. ex rel Calamia vs Redfern, 180 F 506
Wigmore on Evidence, Sec. 2576
Jones on Evidence, Sec. 109

V. Upon appeal from an order dismissing the writ,
a chinese petitioner is not entitled to bail.
Act May 5, 1892, Sec. 5. 27 Stat. L. 25.
Found on page 19 Chinese pamphlet laws,
with cases
Rule 33 Circuit Court of Appeals
In re Jem Yuen, 188 F 350
In the last cited case the court says: "I am unable 
to doubt that Congress intended to forbid admission to the
country upon bail."

The writ should be dismissed and the petitioner remanded
to the custody of the immigration officials.
<signatures>Albert Moodie</signatures>
Assistant U.S. Attorney

Seattle, January 8, 1916
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
No. 3157 
In the District Court
of the United States
for the
Western District of Washington.
Northern Division.

In re petition of Ng Kwack Kang 
for Writ Habeas Corpus.

Brief of
United States.

Clay Allen, U.S. Atty.,
Albert Moodie, Asst. U.S.A.
</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>