<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0473.002"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla" xml:id="mg">Mikayla Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0473.005</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">September 2, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date>29 July 1899</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Denning, J. Henry
Mason, William
Miller, John F.
Nordstrom, Charles W.
Lewis, James Hamilton
Jacobs, Orange
Spencer, W. C.
McBride, W. P.
Ellanerth, P. C.
Hart, John B.
Calhoun, C. V.
Willard, Rufus S.
Marion, A. B.
Bories, Emil
McElroy, James F.
Ayres, A. Reeves 
Walthew, H. M.
Hanford, C. H.
Ashley, M
Moors, A. N.
Van de Vanter, A. T.
Van de Vanter, A. D.
McKenney, James H.
Owrigher, B.
</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington
Washington D.C.
Seattle, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Nordstrom, Charles W.</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>State of Washington</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>James Hamilton Lewis .</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>John F. Miller</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jacobs, Orange</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court Northern Division</orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.473.005"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->

<p>United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington.</p>

<p>In the application of
Charles W. Nordstrom for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus etc.,</p>

<p>vs.</p>

<p>No. 784</p>

<p>Praecipe</p>

<p>To the Clerk of the above Entitled Court:</p>

<p>You will please issue Four certified copies of the 
order refusing to grant the writ herein and
allowing an appeal; and, also, Four certified
copies of the citation issued herein</p>

<p>James Hamilton Lewis</p>

<p>Notice--Attorneys will please endorse their own Filings. Rule 47.</p>

<p>no. 784</p>

<p>United States Circuit Court
District of Washington.</p>

<p>In the application of
Charles W. Nordstrom
for Habeas Corpus 
etc.,</p>

<p>Prcaecipe</p>

<p>Filed July 29 1899 189 </p>

<p>A. Reeves Ayres </p>

<p>Clerk</p>

<p>H.M. Walthew</p>

<p>Deputy Clerk</p>

<p>Jas. Hamilton Lewis,
For Petitioner.</p>

<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,</p>

<p>Northern Division.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of
Charles W. Nordstrom for a Writ of
Habeas Corpus, Appearing by his next,
Friend, J. Henry Denning.</p>

<p>No. 784</p>

<p>N O T I C E.</p>

<p>To the Hon. A. T. Van de Vanter, sherif of King County, State of 
Washington:</p>

<p>You will please take notice hereby that Charles W. Nordstrom,
now in your custody, duly petitioned the Circuit Court of the United
States for a Writ of Habeas Corpus seeking relief thereunder, and,</p>

<p>Whereas, the said writ and relief was denied, and</p>

<p>Whereas, said petitioner duly moved for the right of appeal and
for the transfer of his whole cause to the Supreme Court of the United
States, and</p>

<p>Whereas, the said cause came on for argument as to the granting
of the said appeal and the transfer of the whole cause to the appellate
Court, and was heard upon the 29th day of Juy 1899, by the Hon.
C. H. Hanford, Circuit Judge, and,</p>

<p>Whereas, after hearing said application, an order of appeal was 
duly granted, and the said cause was so ordered transferred to the
Supreme Court of the United States, a full copy of said proceedings
ad the order allowing said appeal, being duly certified, is hereunto
annexed for your information and advice.</p>

<p>And, whereas, under the Revised Statutes of the United States,
being the law of the United States, particularly, Section 766 of the 
said Revised Statutes of the United States, reads as follows, to-wit:</p>

<p>Sec. 766 "Pending the proceedings on appeal in the 
cases mentioned in the three preceding section, and until final judg-
ment therein, and after final judgment of discharge, any proceedings
against the person so imprisioned or confined or restrained of his 
liberty, in any State Court, or by or under the authority of any
State, for any matter so heard and determined, under such writ of
Habeas Corpus, shall be deemed null and void."</p>

<p>And whereas, the Supreme Court of the United States In Re Jugiro
140 U. S. 295, construing the said section, defined the same to mean
"in cases where the applicant was held in custody under the authority
of a state court or by the authority of a State to stay the hands of 
such court or State while the question as to whether his detention was
in violation of the Constitution, laws or treaties of the United 
States was being examined by the courts of the United States having
jurisdiction in the premises;" which sad decision is more fully
referred to in the case on In Re M'Kane, 61 Fed. 205, where it was
held to mean that until final decision in the Supreme Court f the 
United States no disturbance of the condition of the prisoner as he
was at the time of the denying of the writ can be in anywise had: </p>

<p>Therefore youa re hereby notified that you are to hold posession
or custody of the said petitioner, Charles W. Nordstrom, now in your 
keeping at the City of Seattle, County of King, State of Washington,
in such manner as to your discretion shall seem meet and proper, in
nowise assuming for any cause to execute any sentence of death
whatsoever upon the said petitioner, Charles W. Nordstrom, and you
will be duly notified of any other proceedings in the premises.</p>

<p>You will please govern yourself accordingly.</p>

<p>Respectfully,</p>

<p>Jas. Hamilton Lewis
Attorney for Petitioner.</p>

<p>United States of America, )
District of Washington, :ss
C o u n t y of K i n g. )</p>

<p>M. ASHLEY, being first duly sworn, on oath deposes and
says: That at all the times herein and hereafter mentioned, I was,
and am now, a citizen of the United States of America, and of the
District of Washington, and a resident of King County, in said District
of Washington, above the age of twenty-one (21) years.</p>

<p>That at Seattle, King County, State of Washington, on the 31st
day of July, A.D. 1899, I duly served the within Notice upon A. T.
Van de Vater, Sheriff of King County, State of Washington, he being
the respondent and appellee in said within Notice named, by delivering
to and leaving with said A. D. Van de Vater, Sheriff of King County,
State of Washington, a true copy of said within Notice.</p>

<p>That at Seattle, King County, State of Washington, on the 31st
day of July, A. D. 1899, I duly served the within Notice upon James F.
McElroy, Es., Prosecuting Attorney for King County, State of Washing-
ton, on behalf of the State of Washington, said State of Washington
being the respondent and appellee in said within Notice named, by
Prosecuting Attorney for King County, State of Washington, a true copy
of said within notice. </p>

<p>M Ashley</p>

<p>Subscried and sworn to before me this 32st dau of July, A.D. 1899.</p>

<p>J Henry Denning
Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, DISTRICT OF </p>

<p>WASHINGTON,Northern Division.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of
Charles W. Nordstrom for a Writ of
Habeas Corpus, Appearing by his next,
Friend, J. Henry Denning.</p>

<p>No. 784</p>

<p>ASSIGNMENT OF ERRORS</p>

<p>Comes now the petitioner and assigns as error committed by
the Court in the above entitled cause at the time of the hearing of
the same, as follows:</p>

<p>I</p>

<p>That the Court erred in declining and refusing to issue the
Writ of Habeas Corpus upon the record of the above named cause.</p>

<p>II</p>

<p>That the Court erred in refusing to issue an order to show
cause why the Writ should not issue in the above named cause.</p>

<p>III</p>

<p>That the Court erred ub refusing to make an order restraining
proceedings pending the hearing of the Petition for the Writ of Habeas
Corpus in the above named cause.</p>

<p>James Hamilton Lewis
Attorney for the Petitioner.</p>

<p>No. 784</p>

<p>In the Circuit Court</p>

<p>OF THE</p>

<p>UNITED STATES</p>

<p>District of Washington, Northern Division</p>

<p>In The matter of the application
of Charles W. Nordstrom for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus,
appearing by his next
friend J Henry Denning</p>

<p>Assignment of Errors</p>

<p>Filed this 31st day
of July 1899
A Reeves Ayers Clerk.
By A.N. Moors Deputy.</p>

<p>JAS. HAMILTON LEWIS</p>

<p>Attorney for Petitioner</p>

<p>Office--FIFTH FLOOR, PIONEER BLOCK</p>

<p>Corner First Ave. and James St. SEATTLE, WASH.</p>

<p>Received copy of the within
and service of the same admitted this
day of 189
Attorney for</p>

<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, ss:</p>

<p>The President of the United States of America,</p>

<p>To the Honorable the Judges of the Circuit
Court of the United States for the
District of Washington</p>

<p>GREETING:</p>

<p>Whereas, lately in the Circuit Court of the United States
for the District of Washington, before you
or some of you, in a cause entitled In the matter 
of the application of Charles W. Nordstrom
for a writ of habeas corpus, appearing
by his next friend, J Henry Denning, No.
784, wherein the order of the said Circuit 
Court, entered in said cause on the 29th
day of July, A.D. 1899, is in the following
words, viz;</p>

<p>"In the Circuit Court of the United States, District of Wash-
ington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of CHARLES W. NORDSTROM for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus, Appearing by His Next Friend, J. Henry 
Denning. No. 784. Order.</p>

<p>This cause coming on for hearing upon the petition of petitioner
for a writ of habeas corpus, the court, being advised upon the peti-
tion and upon hearing counsel for petitioner, deies and refuses to
grant the said writ; to which ruling of the court petitioner excepts.
Exception allowed.</p>

<p>Petitioner thereupon gives notice that he appeals from the said
ruling of the court and from the whole and every part thereof and
appeals his said petition and his said cause and the whole and each
and every part thereof to the Supreme Court of the United States,
holding terms at the city of Washington, District of Columbia, and
to the next regular term thereof, and particularly appeals from the
said ruling of the said court denying and refusing to grant the said
writ of habeas corpus.</p>

<p>Which said appeal is here and now allowed.
Done in open court this 29th day of July, 1899.</p>

<p>C. H. HANFORD.</p>

<p>District Judge.</p>

<p>as by the inspection of the trancript of the record
of the said Circuit
Court, which was brought into the SUPREME COURT OF THE UNITED STATES
by the virtue of an appeal taken by Charles W. Nordstrom (by his next
friend J. Henry Denning), whereon A. T. Van de Vanter, Sheriff
of King County, Washington, and the State of Washington
were made the parties appellees
agreeably to the act of Congress,
in such case made and provided, fully and at large appears.</p>

<p>And whereas, in the present term of October, in the year of our Lord
one thousand nine hundred the said cause came on to be heard
before the said SUPREME COURT, on the said transcript of record, and
o motions to dismiss or affirm which were argued bu counsel;
</p>

<p>On consideration whereof, It is now here ordered, adjudged,
and decreed by this Court that the order, of the 
said Circuit Court in this cause be, and the same is hereby, affirmed,
with costs; And that the said A. T. Van de Vanter,
Sheriff, and The State of Washington recover
against the said Charles W. Nordstrom,
(by his next friend J. Henry Denning), Eighty
four dollars and fifty cents for their
costs herein expended and have exceution
therefor. May 13, 1901.</p>

<p>You, therefore, are hereby commanded that such execution and
proceedings be had in said cause,
as according to right and justice, and the laws
of the United States, ought to be had, the said appeal
notwithstanding.</p>

<p>Witness the Honorable Melville W. Fuller, Chief of Justice of the
United States, the 31st day of May, in the year
of our Lord one thousand nine hundred and one
COSTS of Van de Vanter, Sheriff, et al.</p>

<p>Clerkj $35.00
Printing Record $29.50
Attorney $20.00
$84.50</p>

<p>James H. Mckenny</p>

<p>Clerk of the Supreme Court of the United States.</p>

<p>#784</p>

<p>GoB 7-3</p>

<p>SUPREME COURT OF THE UNITED STATES</p>

<p>No. 388, October Term, 1900</p>

<p>Charles W. Nordstrom (by
his next friend J. Henry Denning),</p>

<p>vs.</p>

<p>A. T. Van de Vanter,
Sheriff re., et al.</p>

<p>MANDATE</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON</p>

<p>JUN 10 1901</p>

<p>A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk</p>

<p>HM Matthew Dep.</p>

<p>SUPREME COURT OF THE UNITED STATES OCTOBER TERM 1900</p>

<p>Costs of A.T. Van de Vanter, Sheriff re., et al.,</p>

<p>in No. 388,</p>

<p>1900 October Form appearance, .25,
filing precipie and receipt, .50; filing papers, $2.25; filing motion,
.25; filing briefs, $5.00; submission, .20;
judgment, $1.00; filing
same, .25; recording, .40; mandate, $5.00; preparing record for printer, etc.,
$19.50; cost of printing record, $29.50; attorney's docket fee,
$20.00; costs and copy, .40 
</p>

<p>$84.50</p>

<p>$84.50</p>

<p>Fee Book , paage 17.873</p>

<p>Fees: James H. McKenney</p>

<p>Clerk Supreme Court U. S. </p>

<p> CERTIFICATE</p>

<p>United States of America }</p>

<p>ss.</p>

<p>Western District of Washington }</p>

<p>I, JAMES C. DRAKE, Clerk of the Circuit Court of the United States, for the Western
District of Washington, do hereby certify that the foregoing attached papers constitute the
JUDGMENT ROLL in the foregoing entitled cause, No. 784
wherein In re: Application of
Charles W. Nordstrom for
Writ of Habeas Corpus Plaintiff
and 
Defendant</p>

<p> In Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto set my hand and
offixed the Seal of said Circuit Court, this the 
30 day of DEC A. D. 1911</p>

<p>JAMES C. DRAKE</p>

<p>Clerk.</p>

<p>By B Owigher</p>

<p>Deputy Clerk.</p>

<fw type="footer"> &amp;</fw>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>