<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0466.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In The U.S. Circuit Court, 
District of Wash. Northern
Division.</p>

<p>In Re Application of Henry 
Craemer for Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Notice of Appeal.</p>

<p>FILED June 21 1897
IN THE 
U.S. Circuit Court.</p>
<ab>A. Reeves Ayres CLERK
By A. N. Moore DEPUTY</ab>

<p>Pratt &amp; Riddle,
Attys for Petitioner.
309-310-311 Bailey Bldg.</p>

<p>In The Circuit Court of the United States, District of Washington
Northern Division.</p>

<p>In The Matter of the Application of 
Henry Craemer for Writ of Habeas
Corpus and Relief Thereon.
NOTICE.</p>

<p>To Honorable W. H. Moyer, Sheriff of King County, State of 
Washington:</p>
<p>You will take notice hereby that Henry Craemer, now in your
custody duly petitioned the United States Circuit Court for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus, seeking relief thereupon and</p>
<p>Whereas, the said Writ and relief was denied, and</p>
<p>Whereas, said petitioner duly moved for the right of appeal
and for the transfer of his whole cause to the Supreme Court of 
the United States, and</p>
<p>Whereas, the said cause came only for argument as to the grant-
ing of the said appeal and the transfer fo the whole cause to the
appellate court, and was heard upon the 14th day of June,
1897, by the Hon. C. H. Hanford, Circuit Judge, and</p>
<p>Whereas, after hearing said application, an order of appeal 
was duly granted, and the said cause was so ordered transferred to 
the Supreme Court of the United States, a full copy of the afore-
said proceedings and the order allowing the said appeal, being
duly certified, is hereunto annexed for your information and 
advice, and</p>
<p>Whereas, under the Revised Statutes of the United States, being 
the laws of the United States, particularly section 766 of the said
Revised Statutes reads as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Sec. 766. "Pending the proceedings", etc. (Section copied in
<fw>(1)</fw>
full), and,</p>

<p>Whereas, the Supreme Court of the United States, in Re Jugiro
140 U.S. 295, construing the said section, defined the same to mean 
"in cases" etc., (Copied verbatim from Re M'Kane 61 Fed. 205 a 206)
which decision is more fully referred to in the case of In Re
M'Kane 61 Fed. 205, where it was held to mean that until final
decision in the Supreme Court of the United States no disturbance
of the condidtion of the prisoner as he was at the time of the
denying of the Writ can in anywise be had.</p>

<p>Therefore, you are hereby notified that you are to hold pos-
session or custody of the said petitioner, Henry Craemer, now in
your keeping at the city of Seattle, county of King, State of
Washington, in such manner as to your discretion shall seem meet
and proper, in no wise assuming for any cause to execute any sen-
tence of death whatsoever upon the said petitioner Henry Craemer,
and you will be duly notified of any further proceedings in the 
premises.</p>
<p>You will govern yourself accordingly</p>
<p>Respectfully.</p>
<ab>Pratt &amp; Riddle
Attorneys for Petitioner.</ab>

<p>United States of America
District of Washington
County of King  ) SS</p>

<p>Copy of the within Notice received, and service of the same 
is hereby acknowledged this 21 day of June, 1897.</p>

<ab>W. H. Moyer Sheriff of King County, state of
Washington.
James H. McElroy Prosecuting Attorney for King 
County State of Washington.</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>