<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0272.010.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Columbia George v. Charles B. Hopkins. Reply</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Czapla, Ethan P" xml:id="epc">Ethan Czapla</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0272.010</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Columbia George v. Charles B. Hopkins. Reply</title>
<date when="1906-03-28">March 28, 1906</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno>1390ColumbiaGeorgeIndian</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1906-03">March 1906</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>McCaffeery, James J.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>McNeils Island, Washington</term>
<term>Oregon State Penitentiary, Oregon</term>
<term>Salem, Oregon</term>
<term>King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>George, Columbia</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Hopkins, Charles B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Slater, R. J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Frye, Jesse A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#epc">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Service of the within Reply by delivery of a copy to the undersigned is hereby acknowledged this 26 day of March 1906</p>

<p>Jesse A. Frye
       Attorney for Respondent</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 1390 Original</p>

<p>In the Circuit Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington Northern Division</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of Columbia George for a writ of Habeas Corpus. Reply</p>

<p>Filed in the U.S. Circuit Court, Western Dist. of Washington. MAR 28 1906. A. Reeves Ayres, Clerk. HM Matthew, Dep.</p>

<p>Service of papers in this case may be made upon
       R.J. Slater
       Pendleton, Oregon</p>

<pb/>

<p>In the United States Circuit Court For The Western District of Washington Northern Division</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of Columbia George for a writ of Habeas Corpus. No. 1390</p>

<p>Reply to answer and return of the United States Government.</p>

<p>For reply to the answer and return of the United States Government filed herein, comes the above named
       applicant and denies each and every allegation in said answer and return contained, except as hereafter
       admitted or qualified.</p>

<p>Admits paragraphs one and two, excepting the allegation therein contained that the said Columbia George
       and Toy Toy were at the time said murder was committed tribal Indians, and admits that the said Columbia
       George and Toy Toy wer on the 21st day of October 1901, at Portland, Oregon, in the Circiut Court of the 
       United States for the District of Oregon, indicted, and said indictment was returned in said court as setforth on
       page three in lines one to sixteen inclusive of said answer and return, and admit that a trial was had of Columbia
       George and Toy Toy in said court, and that said Columbia George and Toy Toy were convicted of murder without
       capital punishment and sentenced to imprisonment at hard labor for life in the Oregon penitentiary at Salem Oregon,
       upon the commitment issued by the Judge of the United States Circuit Court for the District of Oregon, which said
       commitment was issued under a judgment in said cause rendered by said Circuit Court of the United States for the
       District of Oregon on the 3rd day of September 1901, and thereafter by an order of the Attorney General of the United
       States, the said petitioner Columbia George was transferred to the custody</p>

<pb/>

<p>of C.B. Hopkins, United States Marshal for the Western District of Washington, and that said Columbia George is now in
       the custody of said United States Marshal in the United States Penitentiary at McNeils Island, Washington, and that said
       petitioner is being held in said penitentiary pursant to the commitment issued by the United States Circuit Court of the District
       of Oregon, and pursuant to the order of the Attorney General of the United States, but denies that the custody of said Columbia
       George by the said United States Marshal for the Western District of Washington is legal, and denies that the Attorney General
       of the United States had power and authority to transfer said petitioner form the Oregon State Penitentiary at Salem Oregon, to
       the custody of the United States Marshal for the Western District of Washington. Admits that the term of sentence of the said
       Columbia George has not expired according to law or according to the commitment issued in the premises.</p>

<p>Admits that C.B. Hopkins, is now and for a long time piror hereto, has been the duly and qualified appointed United States Marshal
       for the Western District of Washington, and that the petitioner Columbia Gerge is in his custody as United States Marshal. 
       Admits that said petitioner is now being held in the United States Penitentiary on McNeils Island, State of Washington, and admits
       that at the time of the return, the said Columbia George and the said Toy Toy were full blooded Indians and the person murdered by
       them was a full blooded Indian, but denies that the crime was committed by them upon the Umatilla Reservation in the State of Oregon,
       except as setforth and as alleged in the petition to-wit, that said crime was comitted upon what is known as the Umatilla Reduced Reservation
       and upon land allotted to another Indian.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Denies that the said Columbia George was at the time of the return of said indictment or at the time of the trial and commitment or is now a tribal
       Indian belonging to the Cayuse Band of Indians, or that at the time of the commission fo said crime or during said trial and until sentenced, he was
       residing upon said Umatilla Indian Reservation in the State of Oregon, except as setforth in the petition for the writ of habeas corpus.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE: The petitioner prays that this Honorable Court for an abolute writ of habeas corpus in this matter, and that he be discharged from further
       custody of the said United States Marshal, for the reasons setforth and alleged in his petition and in this reply.</p>

<p>R.J. Slader
       Attorney for Petitioner</p>

<p>{State of Washington
       County of King} ss</p>

<p>I, R. J. Slater, being first duly sworn, depose and says: That I'm the attorney for the petitioner above named, and that I am persoanally acquainted with the
       facts setforth in the above reply and with all the matters connected therewith, and of my own personal knowledge know the same to beture. That I make this
       affidavit for the reason that the petitioner is now confined in the Penitentiary, is an Indian, and is not within this court.</p>

<p>R.J. Slater</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 26th day of March 1906.</p>

<p>James J. McCaffery
       Notary Public in and for the State of Washington Residing at Seattle</p>




</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>