<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0366.015">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Deposition of Cassius M. Clay Robinson</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0366.015</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington. Deposition of Cassius M. Clay Robinson</title>
<date when="1921-07-25">July 25, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-07">July 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Robinson, Charles Burdette</term>
<term>MacEchen, Alexander Joseph Gordon</term>
<term>Ficklin, Claude</term>
<term>Robinson, Cassius M. Clay</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Saskatchewan, Canada</term>
<term>Moose Jaw, Saskatchewan</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Decker, Fletcher</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, Adam</persName>
<persName>Sullivan</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-07" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>-1-</p>

<p>Dominion of Canada</p>
<p>Province of Saskatchewan</p>

<p>THE KING vs. FLETCHER DECKER.</p>

<p>THE DEPOSITION OF CASSIUS M. CLAY ROBINSON, taken this 25th day of July A.D. 1921 before the undersigned Alexander Joseph Gordon MacEchen, a Jusitce of the Peace in and for the Province of Saskatchewan, in the Dominion of Canada, in the matter of Fletcher Decker who is charged upon oath for that he on or about the 15th day of November in the year of our Lord One Thousand nine hundred and fifteen near Wiwa Hill Post Office in the Province of Saskatchewan aforesaid did steal about 300 bushels of flax the property of Claude Ficklin and was thereby guilty of theft.</p>

<p>NOW the said CASSIUS M. CLAY ROBINSON on his oath saith as follows:</p>

<p>I am a farmer living on the North-West quarter of Section Twenty-seven (27), Township Thirteen (13), Range Five (5), West of the Third Meridian in the Province of Saskatchewan in the Dominion of Canada. I have been living on the said land since 1917. I came to this country in the year 1912, and from 1912 to 1917 I lived on the North-West quarter of Section Ten (10) Township Fourteen (14), Range Five (5), West of the Third Meridian in the said Province. Both these quarters mentioned are near Wiwa Hill Post Office</p>

<pb/>

<p>-2-</p>

<p>in the said Province. I was on the North-East Quarter of Section Ten (10) already mentioned in the year 1915. I have known Fletcher Decker eighteen years. He came from Coeur D'Alene City in the State of Idaho, one of the United States of America. He came to Canada in the spring of 1912. From the year 1912 to 1915 Fletcher Decker lived within three miles of me in Saskatchewan aforesaid. Fletcher Decker is not living in my vicinity now, and I understand that he is at present in the United States of America. I had business dealings with Fletcher Decker in the fall of 1915. I heard about some flax being stolen from Claude Ficklin in November 1915. I have a brother named Charles Burdette Robinson. He was also a farmer in my vicinity in the year 1915, and he is still a farmer in that neighborhood. My said brother knew of my business dealings with Fletcher Decker. In the month of December 1915 my brother heard of the loss of Ficklin's flax already referred to, and heard that the theft had been traced to Fletcher Decker, and knowing of my business dealings with Fletcher Decker he came to me and told me what he had heard about the flax. the next morning after I had this conversation with my said brother Fletcher Decker came to my place to get a team of horses which i was to give him in pursuance of the business deal we had had together. My said brother Charles was at my place when Fletcher Decker came to my place in</p>

<pb/>

<p>-3-</p>

<p>December 1915. When Fletcher Decker came that morning I said to him "How much flax did you take "from Ficklin?" Decker said "I did not take any "Flax." I said, "Come on and 'fess up, I ain't "going to squeal on you or make any trouble, but "how much did you take?" He said, "Somewhere "between four and five hundred bushels. I didn't "keep track of it." I said, "The police is coming "out after you today, I think, and what are you "going to do about my horses?" - I was anxious that I should not lose on my deal with him if Decker went to jail. He agreed to leave the horses in charge of my brother Charles in case they arrested him. He was arrested after this, and skipped his bail. At the time of the conversation already referred to Decker still owed me on our deal $550.00.</p>

<p>(Signed) Cassius M. Clay Robinson</p>

<p>I, ALEXANDEER JOSEPH GORDON MacECHEN, one of His Majesty's Justice of the Peace in and for the Province of Saskatchewan in the Dominion of Canada, hereby certify that the foregoing deposition was taken on oath before me at the City of Moose Jaw, Province of Saskatchewan aforesaid, and was signed by the deponent in my presence, and I declare that the offence with which FLETCHER DECKER is charged is the crime of theft as defined by the Criminal Code of Canada.</p>

<p>(Signed) A. J. G. MacEchen (seal)</p>
<p>A Justice of the Peace in and for the Province of Saskatchewan.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>