<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0215.035">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chung Him and Seid Yam v. Henry M. White. Record of Hearing</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0215.035</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Chung Him and Seid Yam v. Henry M. White. Record of Hearing</title>
<date when="1920-06-30">June 30, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-06">June 1920</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Ketchikan, Alaska</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Him, Chung</persName>
<persName>Yam, Seid</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Corrigan, John L.</persName>
<persName>Winston, Will H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>U.S. Department of Labor</p>
<p>Immigration Service</p>

<p>Office of Inspector in Charge</p>
<p>Ketchikan, Alaska</p>

<p>No. 528/141.</p>

<p>June 30,1920.</p>

<p>Commissioner-General of Immigration,</p>
<p>Washington, D.C.</p>

<p>Adverting to Bureau No. 54821/148, I have the honor to transmit herewith record of hearing accorded SEID YIM (or SEID YAM), an alien Chinese found employed as a servant in a house of prostitution in this city, and whose arrest was ordered by the Assistant Secretary on the 3rd instant.</p>

<p>There is also transmitted herewith the brief of Will H. Winston, attorney for this and other aliens, the records in whose cases are also going forward today.</p>

<p>Attention is respectfully directed to the summary and recommendation appearing on page 2 of the record.</p>

<p>The alien is now at liberty under a $1,000 bond.</p>

<p><unclear>W G Strench</unclear></p>
<p>Inspector in Charge.</p>

<pb/>

<p>U.S. Department of Labor</p>
<p>Immigration Service</p>

<p>Ketchikan, Alaska, June 21, 1920.</p>

<p>In the matter of the arrest of SEID YIM (or SEID YAM)</p>

<p>Departmental warrant #54821/148</p>
<p>dated June 3, 1920.</p>

<p>William G. Strench, Inspector in Charge</p>
<p>Examiner and Reporter.</p>

<p>Hearing held at Federal Jail, Ketchikan, Alaska.</p>

<p>Will H. Winston, Attorney for alien, present.</p>
<p>H.A. Lee, Interpreter in Chinese.</p>

<p>The alien is informed that he has been taken into custody as directed in the above-described warrant, charging him with being in the United States in violation of law in that he has been found employed by, in or in connection with a house of prostitution, and that the purpose of this hearing is to afford him an opportunity to show cause, if any there be, why he should not be deported to the country of which he is a citizen. He was also given an opportunity to inspect the warrant as was also his attorney.</p>

<p>Copy of Departmental warrant is attached to this record, marked "Exhibit A".</p>

<p>Interpreter and alien duly sworn:</p>

<p>Q Inspector Strench to alien: Is Mr. Winston your attorney</p>

<p>A Yes.</p>

<p>Q What is your name? A Seid Yim.</p>

<p>Q Have you ever been known by any other name or names? A That is the only name I have been known by.</p>

<p>Q Have you a married name? A That is the name I was given when I was born.</p>

<p>Q Where were you born? A Province Canton, Sun Woi District, Chong Sah village.</p>

<p>Q Did your father ever live in the United States? A No.</p>

<p>Q You are now a citizen of China? A Yes.</p>

<p>Q How old are you? A I arrived in the U.S. when I was 16 years old and it was in the 5th year of the reign of Quong Sui. I am about 59 years old.</p>

<p>Q Where did you land when you came to the U.S.? A Portland, Ore.</p>

<p>Q How many trips have you made to China since then? A I went to Frisco in the 11th year of Quong Sui and took the SS "Pekin" for China and returned in the 13th year.</p>

<p>Q Have you made a trip to China since then? A Only that one trip; it must have been 30 years ago.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Q How long had you been working in this house of prostitution? A Altogether about 5 weeks and one day.</p>

<p>Q Why did you go to work in that sort ofa place? A The fat fellow down there told me that he was working at the place next to it and he told me to go and get that job.</p>

<p>Q Are you not aware of the fact that there is a law in the Territory of Alaska which provides that any male person who shall act as a servant or employee in any house of prostitution shall be deemed guilty of a felony and may be punished by a term of imprisonment of from two to five years in the penitentiary? A I did not knowit.</p>

<p>Q Have you any relatives in the United States? A I have some cousins in Portland; not exactly cousins but we come from the same village.</p>

<p>Q What is the name of your nearest relative in China? A Seid Kwai, who lives in the samevillage where I was born.</p>

<p>Q Have you ever been arrested before? A No.</p>

<p>Q Where is your certificate of residence? A It is now in the possession of the old man, Seid Rack, but I can remember the number of it; Application No. 2370; certificate number 4587.</p>

<p>Q Do you care to offer any reason why you should not be deported to China? A <gap></gap></p>

<p>Mr. Winston:</p>

<p>Q How long have you lived in Ketchikan? A About 5 years including this year.</p>

<p>Q During all that time that you have been here, have Chinese boys been working in the restricted district? A Yes.</p>

<p>Q Did you ever hear that it was against the law for Chinese to work in those places? A No.</p>

<p>Q Don't the Chinese and Japanese work over there openly, and the officers know they work there, and they trade with the business men up-town and represent the girls up-town- everybody knows that they are working there? A They know that we have been working there.</p>

<p>Q You have made no attempt to work over there on the sly, or anything like that? A No.</p>

<p>Q Have you ever known of a Chinese or Japanese boy or anybody else ever having been arrested over there? A No.</p>

<p>Summary and Recommendation.</p>

<p>Seid Yim is a Chinese subject, about 59 years of age, who according to his statements, has been in the United States over 40 years. He claims to have made one trip to China some 30 years ago.</p>

<p>He admits having been found employed as cook in a house of prostitution in this city, and it is respectfully recommended that an order of deportation to China be issued in this case.</p>

<p>W. G. Strench</p>
<p>Examining Inspector and Reporter</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>