<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Harry Smith v. United States. Brief.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Byrd, Samantha." xml:id="slb">Samantha Byrd</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0493.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Harry Smith v. United States. Brief.</title>
<date when="1916">1916</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1916">1916</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Hughes</term>
<term>Field</term>
<term>Lurton</term>
<term>Day</term>
<term>Permstick, Leonard</term>
<term>Tweed, William</term>
<term>Liscomb, Joseph</term>
<term>Davis</term>
<term>Ricky</term>
<term>Webb</term>
<term>Robers</term>
<term>Wiltberger</term>
<term>Stevens, Charles</term>
<term>McClaughry, Robert</term>
<term>Lange, Edward</term>
<term>Miller, Samuel F.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Smith, Harry</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, J.G.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Sullivan, J. J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Martin, Winter S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington North Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#slb">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT, IN AND FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, Plaintiff, vs. Harry Smith, Defendant. No. <del>3375</del>3376 BRIEF.</p>

<p>At your Honor's suggestion, I herewith present a few salient reasons why the contention, as presented by the petitioners, should be upheld, and why they should be discharged from imprisonment.</p>

<p>In a conversation with Mr. Martin, the Assistant United States Attorney, who prepared the Brief in this matter, it is conceded by him, and I herewith state it, that if the indictment upon which these men were tried and sentenced was void, your Honor has the right and it is your duty, under the law to discharge the prisoners. If the indictments are not void, <del><unclear></unclear></del><add>but</add> voidable, the defendants should avail themselves, by means of appeal or writ of error, or motion to quash, arrest of judgment, etc,. and writ of habeas corpus will not lie.</p>

<p>Counsel for the Government, however, contends that this indictment is voidable, and not void, and that it does state a cause of action, and that, therefore, my clients should have availed themselves of one of the foregoing remedies, other than the writ of habeas corpus, and practically states that if his position be well founded, my clients have, by reason of the fact that their counsel did not so act, no recourse, and must serve out their sentence.</p>

<p>I challenge the contention of counsel. It is not founded on the record, but is only the imaginative ingenuity of the District Attorney, upon an assumption of an implied charge in the indictment which does not exist. He claims that because the indictment charged</p>

<pb/>

<p><del><unclear></unclear></del> a volation of the Harrison Act, that that charge is an offense. Let us see. It is true the indictment charges a violation of the Harrison Act, but what violation of the Harrison Act, to-wit: having in possession certain derivative of morphine. etc., without having so registered. I contend that the Supreme Court in the Gin Fung Moy case, recently decided, through Mr. Justice Hughes, specifically held that this was not an offense. In other words, counsel cannot say because they charge a violation of an act, that that charges an offense. It is the facts in relation to the violation of the act, that make the offense, and the Supreme Court, having held that those facts, to-wit:"having in possession", which are no charged in the indictment, as being a violation of the Harrison Act, is not, indeed a violation of the Harrison Act, and is not an offense. Therefore, the indictment, stripped of the facts of having these drugs in possession, leaves nothing but a mere allegation of the violation of the act, which means nothing; inasmuch, as the facts in relation to said act, which were so charged by reason of the Supreme Court decision, viciates and makes void the whole indictment, and being void, makes their sentence under said indictment and committment illegal.</p>

<p>As was stated by Mr. Justice Field, in one of the decisions which your Honor has, and was aptly stated by this court in my argument the other day, the Government might just as well have charged these people with having in possession some innocent thing, or as your Honor said, a lead pencil. Your Honor has the cases before him which I presented in argument, after a most diligent search, and I am adding herewith a few more.</p>

<p>My clients have taken a Forma Pauperis. Their lawyers who had represented them, and who had saved no safeguard for them having taken all their money, but being interested in the point, and feeling the justice of their cause, I have aimed, fairly and impartially, to lay my cards upon the table for the District Attorney, in order that</p>

<pb/>

<p>justice might prevail; and I trust your Honor will understand that I am not trying to burden him with law for the purpose of allowing guilty ment to escape punishment, but am only aiming to present reasons why men who, in my estimation, are guilty of no offense, should be released.</p>

<p>It is conceded by the Government that if the judgment is void, your Honor has a right to discharge it. I will present further authorities on that point. I quote from the Encyclopedia of the Laws of England, Vol. 6, p. 472, on this point, which should have much bearing with this court for the reason that it is from the English law that the habeas corpus originated. It there states: "Purposes for which Writ of Habeas Corpus is Granted: Under the writ of habeas corpus, the court may examine into the legality of any commitment for a criminal or supposed criminal matter. No unlawful detention of an individual or deprivation of the liberty of an individual, whether the alleged cause be civil or criminal, or if there is no ground at all alleged for the detention may be inquired into by means of the issue of a writ of habeas corpus." The jurisdiction of a court on habeas corpus in such cases has been thus expressed: "If it appears clearly that the fact for which the party is committed is no rime, or that it is a crime, but that he is committed for it by a person that has no jurisdiction, the court discharges." Citing, Wilmot's Opinions, P. 106; Bacon, Abr., tit. Habeas Corpus, and the Bushel's case, 1670, Vaugh. 136. which last mention case is cited and approved in several Supreme Court cases which your Honor has before him.</p>

<p>As to your Honor's power to set aside or vacate a judgment which is void, I quote the following: "The court may at any time vacate or set aside a judgment which is void." Cyc., p. 825. "It has frequently been held that a judgment which is absolutely void may be vacated at any time, and that the right to have such judgment set aside is not lost by delay, regardless of whether or not the time for making the application is limited by statute." Cyc., p/ 842.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Quoting from Thomas vs. American Freehold Land Co., etc., 47 Fed., p. 556: "The defendant insists that the term having ended, we have no control over the judgment. In numerous cases cited by the defendant, to-wit: Bank vs. Moss, 6 Howard, 31; Sibbald vs. United States, 12 Pet., 492; United states vs. Bank, 6 Pet., p. 8, wherein it is held that after a Circuit Court has rendered judgment, it cannot set aside one of its own judgments upon motion, even for want of jurisdiction over the cause, were all decided upon cases where the court itself did not exceed its jurisdiction. It is true, however that where the court has jurisdiction of the parties and subject matter, if it makes a judgment or decree which is not within the power granted to it by the law of its organization, its decree of judgment is void."</p>

<p>Mr Justice Field in Windsor vs. McFay, 93 U.S., 282, said: "Courts must adjudicate in all things and cannot transcend the power confeerred by law."</p>

<p>"Where a court transcends the minutes prescribed for it by law, and assumes to act where it has no jurisdiction, its adjudications will be utterly void." Cyc., p. 358 R.D.</p>

<p>"No court of the United States can revise or amend its own final judgment or decrees for errors of fact or of law, The present motion, however, is not directed to the correction of any error of law or fact on the part of the court rendering the judgment, but counsel has intimated that he can show that the judgment is void. The court has jurisdition over this question." U.S. vs. Wallace, 46 Fed., 570.</p>

<p>"No judgment of a court is due process, if rendered without urisdiction in the court." Scott vs. McNeil, 38 Law Edition, 896.</p>

<p>"Sentence not within the jurisdiction of the court to impose is not merely unlawful, but is wholly void."Emery <unclear>VK.</unclear> U.S. Supreme Court Reps., p. 1093.</p>

<p>The unbroken voice of authority holds that a sentence of imprisonment, without jurisdiction, is void. The question reduced to its logical sequence, this is: "What is jurisdiction?" Jurisdiction means jurisdiction over the nature of the cause of action and the relief nought. Cyc. Supreme Court Reps., p. 709. "In order to give abiding effect to a judgment, it is essential that the court have jurisdiction of the person and of the subject matter. The want of jurisdiction is a matter that may be set up at any time." Emery Supreme Court Reps., p. 740 - (Jurisdiction)</p>

<pb/>

<p>"If the court has no general jurisdiction, or exceeds its jurisdiction, custody under its judgment is void, and will be released by habeas corpus."</p>

<p>Want of jurisdiction to render a particular judgment, party is entitle to habeas corpus, not merely where the court is without jurisdiction of the cause, but where it has no constitutional authority to render the particular judgment, a sentence without indictment is void, and a prisoner will be released on habeas corpus." Cyc. Supreme Court Reps., p. 650. (Habeas Corpus)</p>

<p>An amendment of the United States Consitution provides that no person may be held to answer for an infamous charge, save by an indictment by a grand jury. An indictment by a grand jury is an accusation setting forth the facts of the offense charged. If the accusation does not charge a crime against the Government. The defendant had not been indicted by a grand jury in this action. The defendant is not charged with any crime against the Government, and therefore, he has never been indicted by a grand jury.</p>

<p>Now, as to the fact that the record shows that no offense was ommitted, and that your Honor should discharge, read what our own Circuit Court of Appeals says in the case of Mackay v. Miller, 126 Fed., p. 161: "If it be true that the acts committed by the appellants which are set forth in the indictment in this case, are not within th intendment of Section 5447 of the Revised Statutes (U.S. Comp. St., 1901, page 3678) they do not constitute an offense against that statute, or against any other statute of the United States. Such being the case, it appears affirmatively from the return that the appellants are held in custody under a judgment which upon its face is void." I also call your attention to Ex parte Coy, 127 U.S., 731; 32 Law Ed., 247, holding: "The writ of habeas corpus, in case of a person held a prisoner by sentnece of court, can only release the prisoner when it is shown that the court HAD NO JURISIDICTION TO TRY AND PUNISH HIM FOR THE OFFENSE. The inquiry in such case is not whether there is in the indictment such specific allegation of the details of the charge as would make it good on demurrer, but whether the indictment described a class of offenses of which the court has jurisdiction, and alleges the defendant to be guilty. If the record of the case in which Judgment of imprisonment is pronounced CONTAINS NO CHARGE OF SUCH OFFENSE, HE SHOULD BE DISCHARGED."</p>

<pb/>

<p>Also Ex parte Bain, 121 U.S., 1; 30 Law Ed., 849, in which it is said: "There was nothing before the court on which it could hear evidence or pronounce sentence. The case comes within the principles laid down by this court in Ex parte Lange, 18 Wall, 163; Ex parte Parks, 93 U.S., 18; Ex parte Wilson, 114 U.S., 417, and other cases." I also call your attention to the following cases: Henry v. Henkel, 235 U.S., 219; Glascow v Moyer, 225 U.S., 423; 56 Law Ed., 1148; In re Lange, 18 Wall., 163; New York v. Eno, 155 U.S., 89. </p>

<p>In the case of De Bara vs. U.S., Circuit Court of Appeals, 6th Circuit, before Taft, Lurton and Day, Circuit Judges, Mr. Justice Day, in rendering his opinion, among other things, states as follows: on page 947 of 99 Fed. Rep.: "Ex oarte Vurgubuam 100 U.S., 339-343; Ex parte Lange, 18 Wall, 163; U.S. vs. Pridgeon, 153 U.S., 48, 38 Law Ed., 631. Under a writ of habeas corpus, the inquiry is addressed, not to errors, but to the question of whether the proceedings and the judgment rendered therein are for any reason nullities. The court of justice, or judge, shall proceed in a summary way to determine the facts of the case (in habeas corpus) by weighing the testimony and arguments, and thereupon to dispose of the party as law and justice require under a writ of habeas corpus. The inquriry, therefore, is: "Does the judgment exceed the authority of the court, and is the prisoner serving under a sentence beyond the power of the court to impose?"</p>

<p>I respecfully contend that that allegation and the reasoning therein stated applies to this case, the Supreme Court having held that possession of these drugs does not consitute an offense, and applies only to dealers, etc. Your Honor, in imposing a sentence upon an indictment with allegations of 'having in possession,' exceeded his authority. In other words, facts so alleged and proven were not an offense, as the Supreme Court has decided, and your Honor, therefore, sentenced these men to imprisonment for something which was not an offense against the laws of the United States.</p>

<pb/>

<p>If your Honor will examine the indictment in the two cases wherein your Honor granted the arrest of judgment and dishcarged the prisoners, you will see that it is the same indentical charge of 'having in possession'. It is true that your Honor granted an arrest of judgment in that case, and my clients might have done the same if their counsel had been apprised of what the intent of the law was, or had safeguarded the rights of my clients. But why did your Honor grant that arrest of judgment? Why, because as their grounds were in the said motion for arrest of judgment, that the facts alleged in the indictment did not consitute an offense. It was not that the indictment was defective or voidable, or that they failed to do this, or do that, but that the indictment did not charge an offense, and therefore, your Honor, in deciding in behalf of the defendants a few days ago, must have held, in granting said motion, that the indictment did not charge an offense, and if the indictment did not charge an offense, then it was void, and so the same line of reasoning here. The same kind of an indictment, the same lines of reasoning, the same effect, as presented by a writ of habeas corpus, as would have been presented by arrest of judgment, to-wit: that the indictment does not charge an offense, and is, therefore, void.</p>

<p>In re Permstick, 3 Wash., 672. This was a case wherein Permstick brought a complaint against a man, and the jury found the man not guilty, and believing that the complaining witness, Permstick, was actuated by malice, in bringing action, in their verdict of not guilty, against the defendant, also brought in the said further verdict, that Perstick in so acting and bringing the complaint, was malicious, and that it was without probable cause, and the court thereupon entered a verdict that Perstick pay the costs of the trial, and stand committed to jail until payment. Upon appeal so the Supreme Court, the entire court concurred in the opinion rendered by Mr. Justice Stiles, holding that the jury had not authority to so act,</p>

<pb/>

<p>nor the court. The court in rendering the decision, among other things, stated that the fact that a party has a right of apeal from a dugment against him does not estop him from maintaining an application for a wwrit of habeas corpus, where the court which rendered the judgment under which he was held had no jurisdiction over the subject matter. And cites approvingly, the case of People ex rel Tweed vs. Liscomb, 60 N.Y., 559, which clearly, and at length, discusses both the question of the right to habeas corpus, in addition to that of appeal, and that of the competency of the courts in such cases. Your Honor has that case before him, as I argued extensively from it the other day. It probably was one of the most important cases ever tried in the State of New York, and the opinion of the learned court in that state clarifies the situation, as presented here, and make nil of the argument of the learned District Attorney in my humble opinion.</p>

<p>In re Ex parte Davis, Supreme Court, Nev., 110 Pac. Rep., 1132. In this case, Davis was charged and convicted in the Justice Court for a misdemeanor, to-wit: carrying a concealed weapon. Upon appeal to the District Court, a trial was had de novo, and a judgment of conviction entered against him and a fine of $100.00,and in default of said fine, he to be committed to jail. He sued out a writ of habeas corpus on the grounds that he came within the exempt class, and that the court had no jurisdiction over the person or the subject matter, and no authority to render the punishment. The opinion per curiam, among other things, states as follows: "A number of contentions have been made by counsel for petitioner, upon hearing only one of which will be necessary to consider. At the outset, it is proper to note that the Writ of habeas corpus cannot be used to perform the functions of appeal or writ of error; that it can only go to a question of the jurisdiction of the court to enter the particular judgment, and not as to whether the court erred in the exercise of such jurisdiction. It is, in effect, contended by counsel for the state that, conceding that the court found as a fact that the petitioner was in the class of persons exempted from the</p>

<pb/>

<p>penal provisions of the act, nevertheless the court had jurisdiction of the person of petitioner and the subjectmatter embraced within the criminal complaint, and hence had jurisdiction to impose the particular judgment entered. If we concede this contention to be correct, it is the end of this proceeding. If this contention is the law, then upon a trail in the district court of a person charged with a violation of this act the court may, for example, find as a fact that he was the sheriff of the county, that he was carrying the concealed weapon in the discharge of his duty as such sheriff, and may, nevertheless, enter a judgment that he is guilty, and upon such judgment impose sentence of imprisonment; such judgment and sentence being only error of law, and not an excess of jurisdiction, which this court could redress. Again, suppose that the case had been tried by jury and a verdict of not guilty returned, and the court, notwithstanding, imposed judgment and sentence of imprisonment; can it be said that this would be simply error within jurisdiction? These examples are extreme cases, and probably would not be found in the concrete; but they are examples wherein the court would have jurisdiction of both the subject matter and the person, and, if the rule is as contended of cases of excess of jurisdiction, and hence beyond relief by habeas corpus.</p>

<p>The modern doctrine of jurisdiction, the excess of which habeas corpus may relieve against, goes not only to jurisdiction over the person and the subject-matter, but to the power or jurisdiction to render the particular judgment. 21 Cyc. and numerous cases cited in not 72, p. 297. With this modern doctrine, which is more in accord with reason and justice, this court is already in accord. Ex parte Webb, 24 Nev., 238, 51 Pac., 1027; Ex parte Dela 25 Nev., 346, 60 Pac. 217, 83 Amer. St. Rep. 603; Ex parte Rickey, 31 Nev., 82, 100 Pac. 134; Ex parte Roberts, 9 Nev. 44, 16 Am. Rep. 1. In Ex parte Webb, this court said: 'There are three essential elements necesary to render conviction valid. These are that the court must have jurisdiction over the subject matter, the person of the defendant, and authority to render the partiular judgment. If either of these elements is lacking, the judgment is fatally defective, and the prisoner held under such judgment may be released on habeas corpus. Brown on Jurisdiction, 110, and cases cited; Courts on Jurisdiction, 641, and citations. In Ex part Rickey, we quoted with approal from Re Corryell, 22 Val. 178, also quoted in Ex parte Kearney, 55 Cal. 229, the following: The court derives its jurisdiction from the law, and its jurisdiction extends to such matters as the law declares criminal, and none other; and, when it undertakes to imprison for an offense to which no criminaity is attached, it acts beyond its jurisdiction.'</p>

<p>No better illustration of the wisdom and justice of this view of the law could be found than in cases like that under consideration, where a statute makes the doing of a certain act a penal offense, and then exempts a certain class of persons from its provisions. As against the exempted class the law has no force or effect,</p>

<pb/>

<p>and the court is without power to impose punishment upon that exempted class for the doing of an act punishable as to others not within the exemption. Where however, upon the trial the evidence without conflict shows that the defendant is exempted from the penal provisions of the act, the court is without power to render a judgment of conviction, and a judgment of conviction in such a case would be in excess of the court's power, and void. The court quotes approvingly from Bishop on Stat. Crimes; Beccaria on Crimes; The Schooner Enterprise, 1 Paine, 33 Fed. Cas. No 4499.</p>

<p>And in United States v. Wiltberger, 5 Wheat, 76, 5 L Ed. 37 (Opinion by Chief Justice Marshall), the court says: 'It has been said that, although penal laws are to be consrued strictly, the intention of the Legislature must govern in their construction.' The Petitioner is discharge."</p>

<p>Upon the same line of reasoning, the court discharged Ex parte Legune, Ex parte Allen and Ex parte Van Hoeston.</p>

<p>In applying the same line of reasoning to the case at bar, the Government's contention falls flat, for my flinets having come within the class which the Supreme Court says are not mentioned in the statutue, to-wit: only those having in possession, and not dealers, then they are exempt from punishment for failing to register, as was the defendant in the Nevada case, for having a weapon in his possession, when by statute, he was exempt from punishment. I do not see how any reasoning could be more plain than that herein stated.</p>

<p>I would like to have your Honor read the case of Stevens vs. McClaughry, 207 Fed., 18, before Sanborn and Carland, Circuit Judges and Willard, District Judge. The court, through Mr. Justice Sanborn said that in granting a wrt of habeas corpus to the petitioner, and discharging him where he had been imprisoned at Leavenworth for a number of years, by virtue of a judgment of the Federal Court, beyond its jurisdiction, and therefore void, the court goes into the different distinctions of cases of habeas corpus, and earnestly and diligently present logical reasoning for their decisions, and on page 28, state as follows:</p>

<pb/>

<p>"And here is the true distinction between the cases in which the writ of habeas corpus may and those in which it may not issue. If judgment or sentence challenged is without the jurisdiction of the court and void, the writ may issue. If it is erroneous, but within the jurisdiction of the court which rendered it, the writ may not issue." And quoting approvingly from several cases, especially Ex parte Lange, 18 Wall, using the words of Mr. Justice Miller; "That one who should be sentenced by a justice of the peace having jurisdiction to fine for a misdemeanor, or by a court of general jurisdiction on an indictment for a libel, to imprisonment and death, who through ignorance or neglect should fail to appeal or procure a writ of error within the prescribed time, would be barred of relief by the writ of habeas corpus." And showing the fallacy of such, states as follows: "It is a writ of right. The acts of Congress declare that the court to which the application for it is made 'shall forthwith award a writ of habeas corpus, unless it appears from the petition itself that the party is not entitled thereto', and 'shall proceed in a summary way to determine the facts of the case, and thereupon to dispose of the party as law and justice require.' Revised Statutes, #755, 761. The petitioner is being restrained of his liberty for five years by a judgment of a federal court which was beyond its jurisdiction and void; and should be relieved from that restraint by the proper Federal Court by means of the writ of habeas corpus, and that he is not barred from such relief, by the fact that he might have obtained it by a writ of error, but failed to do so until it was too late. The court below should have issued the writ and discharged the prisoner."</p>

<p>Applying the same line of reasoning in the fore-mentioned case and all the cases presented to your Honor, to the case at bar. Here are defendants <add><unclear>ahealy</unclear></add> imprisoned, one for four months and the other for two months, upon an indictment, the facts of which the Supreme Court of the United States and this Honorable Court have stated do not constitute an offense. And, therefore, to compel them to remain in jail another day is a suspension of the write of habeas corpus, in depriving them of a right for which the writ was instituted, to-wit: where imprisonment or detention is unlawful and illegal, and without authority of law.</p>

<p>I trust that your Honor will graciously indulge in my continued smatterings of attempts at reason, but due to the importance</p>

<pb/>

<p>of the question, not only to my clients, but to others who may be confined in penitentiaries throughout the country, I have presented this matter at much length. Knowing your Honor's earnest desire to do as law and justice require, I feel certain that upon reading the decisions comparing the indictments with the ones of the two cases where in your Honor decided in behalf of the defendants a few days ago, and again reading the decision of the Supreme Court in the Gin Fung Moy case, that your Honor will apply the same rule of reasoning, and grant the writ.</p>

<p>Respecfully submitted,</p>

<p>John J Sullivan Atty for Petitioner</p>

<pb/>

<p>ORIGINAL NO. 3376 IN THE SUPERIOR COURT STATE OF WASHINGTON KING COUNTY <add>U.S. DISTRICT COURT <unclear></unclear> WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION</add></p>

<p>UNITED SATES OF AMERICA, Plaintiff vs. HARRY SMITH, Defendant</p>

<p>BIRIEF.</p>

<p>Filed in the U.S. District Court, Western Dist. of Washington, Northern Division <del>AUG 15, 1916</del>July <unclear>13</unclear>- 1916 Frank L. Crosby, Clerk by </p>

<p>BEELER &amp; SULLIVAN Lawyers 310-11 White Building, Seattle, Wash. Main 907.</p>





</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>