<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE UNITED DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT 
OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE 
UNLAWFUL DETENTION OF 
SEVENTY-THREE HINDOO
ALIENS.</p>
<p>) ) ) )</p>
<p>2532</p>
<p>TO THE HONORABLE JEREMIAH NETERER, 
UNITED STATES DISTRICT JUDGE, 
SEATTLE, WASHINGTON;</p>
<p>SECTION 20.</p>
<p>It is an admitted fact that the aliens are held 
on warrants of deportation issues by authority of 
Section 20. It will be noted that Section 2 of the Act 
states that persons likely to become a public charge are 
subject to be excluded, but under the admission and 
authority of the Gonzales case, 192 U.S. 1, and the 
case of Suekichi, 199 Fed. 750, Section 2 is not to be 
applied to alien residents, but only alien immigrants.</p>
<p>These aliens are held under authority of the 
deportation warrants and these warrants give as the only 
ground for holding and deporting said aliens in that they</p>
<p>HERBERT W. MEYERS 
ATTORNEY 
430-3 PIONEER BUILDING 
SEATTLE</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>were likely to become public charges at the time of their 
entry, and those warrants have taken the place of the 
warrants of arrest (see heading at top of warrants) and
the authorities hold that these warrants must be 
substantially correct and must be taken at their face value, 
and if errors have been made of a substantial nature, 
that the alien should be released on habeas corpus.</p>
<p>The courts have gone to the extent of holding 
that where the place where the aliens was to be deported 
was not stated in the warrant, but that there was a 
mere statement in said warrant that the alien should 
be deported to the country from whence he came, that 
that was insufficient, and the alien should be released 
on habeas corpus.</p>
<p>Attention is called to the affidavit of the 
interpreter attached hereto, who was present when about 
half the number of aliens in this case were examined 
by the immigration board at Manila, and passed, and this 
interperter furnishes letters from government officials,
showing that he was the official interpreter. He testifies 
that these men were lawfully admitted at Manila 
and that they could not have received the certificates 
attached hereto, which it is an admitted fact in the 
record that all of the aliens possessed, unless they had 
first had a certificate signed by the immigration 
officials in Manila, which were presented to the aliens 
after a proper examination and an admission at a regular 
port of entry.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>In all the cases that have come before the 
courts, it has been shown that the alien ran across the
border at a place other than a regular port of entry or 
that the alien testified falsely to be admitted, or 
that in some surreptitious or clandestine manner the 
alien unlawfully entered. In this case there is not 
a word or a line of the testimony to show any unlawful 
entry, but there is a testimony to show that they went 
to Manila in a boat operated by one of the regular steamship
lines, and the court will take judicial notice
of the fact that these big ocean liners do not land 
their passengers at some hidden shore, but that they 
are met before landing at the port of Manila by the
government officers and not a man is permitted to land
until after he is inspected and examined by the immigration 
and custom officers. They testified they were 
examined regularly and passed, and described, apparently
to the satisfaction of the government agents at Seattle, 
as they did not question the fact of the examination, 
that they had received an examination similar 
to the one received in Seattle, and had been passed
as entitled to enter, from six months to three years ago 
at the port of Manila.</p>
<p>It will be noted by referring to Section 12 
that the master or commanding officer of a steamer is 
required to make a report and to pay $4.00 head tax for
every man on board who comes within the requirements, and 
about midway of that paragraph it is stated that no 
master of any vessel shall be granted clearance papers</p>
<p>HERBERT W. MEYERS 
ATTORNEY 
430-2 PIONEER BUILDING 
SEATTLE</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>for his vessel until he has deposited such list or lists 
with the collecter of customs, and further that the 
collecter of customs with whom such list has been 
deposited, in accordance with the provisions of 
this section, shall promptly notify the commissioner 
general of immigration. This is for the purpose of 
having alines who are about to land, examined properly
by the proper board of immigration officers. After 
they were examined, as appears in the affidavit attached 
hereto, of the interperter, they are given the certificate 
marked "A", which it will be noted is signed 
by the immigration officals who conducted the examination, 
and that this certificate of identification, 
which shows proper admission and examination is then 
surrendered for the certificate marked "B", which it is 
an admitted fact, were held and surrendered to the 
government in every case, and special attention is 
called to the same interpreter's affidavit, in which he
tells of having lost his original certificate which showed 
his having been admitted, and having to get a duplicate, 
in order to get the certificate which was held and surrendered 
to the government by each one of the aliens
in this hearing. The government not only has failed 
to show an unlawful entry, but lawful entry, so far as 
it was in the power of the aliens to show, has been 
shown. It is preposterous to suppose that if the alien 
would send a cable to the immigration officer at Manila 
that he would look at his said records and tell said 
alien that his name was on the manifest showing him to</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>have lawfully arrived at Manila on a certain date, but 
the government, owning and controlling the records, 
could have gotten that information without any 
difficulty. The records are in the possession of the government, 
and it would tke this Honorable Court, or some 
other court, in order to secure this information from 
the government from their official records.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>It seems conclusive that by reference to Section 
36, page 17 of the immigration pamphlet, where it provides 
"that all aliens who shall enter the United States except 
at the seaports thereof, or at such place or places 
as the Secretary of Labor may from tiem to time designate, 
shall be adjudged to have entered the country unlawfully
and shall be deported as provided by Sections 
20 and 21 of this Act," especially inasmuch as the same 
section provides that the provision shall not effect the 
power of the commissioner general to regulate the entry 
and inspection of aliens along the borders of Canada 
and Mexico. After setting out in this section what the 
government deems to be an unlawful entry, and the aliens 
having all testifed and show evidence of an admission 
at Manila, and an examination, and as there is a total 
lack of evidence showing any kind of an unlawful entry, 
and further, inasmuch as the government did not demand 
a head tax from these aliens on entering Seattle, and 
as paragraph "E" of subdivision 3, page 22 of the pamphlet
states that a head tax is not demanded from aliens 
who have been lawfully admitted to the United States who</p>
<p>HERBERT W. MEYERS 
ATTORNEY 
430-3 PIONEER BUILDING 
SEATTLE</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>later shall go entransit from one part of the United 
States to another, it seems doubtful to us if the court 
can find that the government has complied with section 
20 of the law, and especially do these aliens not come 
within the provision of Section 2, as subdivision 4 of 
rule 14, page 33 of the pamphlet states that a failure 
to present a certificate shall be deemed presumptive 
evidence that an examination has not occured unless 
he shows that his presence in the country is lawful or 
that the limitation of the statute has expired, and 
certainly this provision is complied with when the alien 
has testified under oath that he was lawfully admitted 
and passed at Manila and resided there after such lawful 
admission for from six months to several years, in view 
of the faact that he was duly sworn and could be convicted 
of perjury for falsely swearing, and in view of the further
fact that the courts have held that alien residents 
have the same protection and have the same status as 
citizens in these matters, and it will not be denied that
the oath of a citizen or an alien resident, as the courts 
have unanimously decided these men to be, who has testifed 
definitely and positively of the lawful examination 
and admission, that that when connected with the fact
of the furnishing of a certificate only granted after 
the surrender of a certificate signed by the immigration 
official, showing a proper examination, and when connected 
with the further fact that the interpreter who has 
testified herein, who is a resident of the city of 
Seattle, testifies that he was present when more than half</p>
<pb></pb>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>