<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN
DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the matter of the Petition
of K. Gregory, M. 
Aloshin, I Riaboff, P.
Neanlin I Emelin, L. Orloff
G. Yakimoff, and P. Yakimoff,
aliens, for a WRIT OF HABEAS
CORPUS</p>
<p>No. 2646 
BRIEF</p>
<p>The matter for consideration in this case seems to me to be res adjudicata until the case of In
Re Unlawful Dentention of Mullah Singh and Seventy-two other Hindu Aliens, Case No. 2532, has been
reversed by the Supreme Court. In that case the court says:
"The Jurisdiction of the court is limited to ascertaining whether the petitioners were denied a
hearing."</p>
<p>And the Court cites to sustain the proposition on the following:
Ekin v. united States, 142 U.S. 650;
Yamataya v. Fisher, 189 U.S. 66;
United States v. Ju Toy, 198 U.S. 253;
Lee Moon Sing v. United States, 158 U.S. 538;
Chin Yow v. United States, 208 U.S. 8.</p>
<p>The Court further says:
"A hearing having been accorded, the court is precluded from a repexamination of the issue
presented, merely because it is contented that the conclusion of the immigration officers, based
upon the testimony presented was wrong."</p>
<p>The Court's decision is borne out by the resoning and the exact language of our Supreme Court
cases. Thus, in  Chin Yow v. United States, 52 L.Ed. 369, the Court says:
<pb/>
"But unless and until it is proved to the satisfaction of the judge that a hearing properly so
called was denied, the merits of the case are not open, and, we may add the denial of a hearing
cannot be established by proving that the decision was wrong."</p>
<p>And in the case of De Bruler v. Gallo, 184 Fed. 566, at page 569, that court follows the
reasoning of this court, saying at 569,
"The contention being that the only question then properly before the court was whether or not the
appellee had been given a fair hearing by the officers of the Department of Commerce and Labor upon
the order to show cause why she should not be deported to the country from which she came. The
position of the government in this respect must be sustained."</p>
<p>It is the contention of the Government in this case that if these Russions were given any hearing
at all, it makes no difference whether the immigration authorities erred in either an interpretation
of the law or in the finding of their facts, the courts have no authority whatsoever to interfere in
the premises. In short, it is our contention that the administration of this law is placed
exclusively in the hands of the immigration authorities and that the courts have no more authority
to interfere with their actions, whether their error be in law or fact, than they would to interfere
with the action of a consul or ambassador. the introduction of foreigners into our country is a
matter which concerns international relations alone. There is no guarantee of the Consitution of the
United States to which an alien who has never been admitted to America is entitled, and it would be
as disasterous for the court to interfere with the administration of the immigration law as ti would
in the case of the dealings with foreign countries, because this is a matter which concerns 
<pb/>
our dealings with a foreign nation. In this particular case it is shown that the fact that the alien was
excluded from Canada was given consideration on account of the fact that from a courtesy existing
between the two countries it has been customary for Canadians to exclude any one not allowed to
enter the United States, and vice versa.</p>
<p>We are borne out in this case by that of Ekiu v. United States, 35 L. Ed. 1146, 1150, 139-142
U.S.Sup.Ct. Rep. 1146, where the Act of 1891 was under consideration. Section 1 of that Act was in
substance the same as ours; it provided that all idiots, insane persons, paupers or persons likely
to become a public charge, etc., should be excluded. Under Section 1 a woman was being detained on
the grounds that she was liable to become a public charge and was therefore prohibited from landing,
and she went to the courtsand had a writ of habeas corpus issued, and in considering whether she was
entitled to it, the court, at page 1150, says:
"Section 7 of the Act of 1891 establishes the office of superintendent of immigration, and enacts
that he '"shall be an officer in the Treasury Department, under the control and supervision of the
Secretary of the Treasury."' By Sec. 8 '"the proper inspection officers"' are required to go on
board any vessel brining alien immigrants and to inspect and examin them, and may for this purpose
remove and detain them on shore, without such removal being considered a landing; and '"shall have
power to administer oaths, and to take and consider testimony touching the right of any such aliens
to enter the United States, all of which shall be entered of record;"' '"all decisions made by the
inspection officers or their assistants touching the right of any alien to land, when adverse to
such right, shall be final unless appeal be taken to the superintendent of immigration, whose action
shall be subject to review by the Secretary of the Treasury."'</p>
<p>And again the Court says:
<pb/>
"The decision of the inspector of immigration being in conformity with the Act of 1891, there can be
no doubt that it was final and conclusive against the petitioner's right to land in the United
States. The words of section 8 are clear to that effect, and were manifestly intended to prevent the
question of an alien immigrant's right to land, when once decidedadversely by an inspector, acting
within the jurisdiction conferred upon him, from being impeached or reviewed, in the courts or
otherwise, save only  by appeal to the inspector's official superiors, and in accordance with the
provisions of the Act. Section 13, by which the circuit and district courts of the United States are
'"invested with full and concurrent jurisdiction of all causes, civil and criminal, arising under
any of the provisions of this Act,"' evidently refers to causes of judicial cognizance, already
provided for, whether civil actions in the nature of debt for penalties under sections 3 and 4, or
indictments for misdemeanors under sections 6, 8 and 10. Its intention was to vest concurrent
jurisdiction of such cases in the circuit and district courts; and it is impossible to construe it
as giving the courts jurisdiction to determine matters which the Act has expressly committed to the
final determination of executive officers."</p>
<p>Passing on this case by these tests, we must ask whether the petitioners were denied a hearing.
If an inspector's decision was final under the Act of 1891, how much more should we construe the Act
of the Special Inquiry Board, final under Section 25 of our Act.</p>
<p>Section 25, after giving the personnel of the Board says:
"Such boards shall have authority to determine whether an alien who has been duly held shall be
allowed to land or shall be deported. All hearings before boards shall be separate and apart from
the public, but the said boards shall keep a complete permanent record of their proceedings and of
all such testimony as may be produced before them."</p>
<p>Then the Act says:
"Provided, That in every case where an alien is excluded from admission into the United States,
under any law or treaty now existing or hereafter made, the decision of the appropriate immigration
officers, if adverse to the admission of such alien
<pb/>
s, shall be final, unless reversed on appeal tothe Secretary of Commerce and Labor."</p>
<p>So under Section 25 the decision of the Board is final, just as under the Act of 1891 referrred
to by the Supreme Court in the Ekiu case the decision of the Inspection Officer was final. If the
arbitrary action of a single officer should be final and upheld by the Supreme Court, why should not
the action of a Board of three men, whose decisions are more apt to be judicial in character, be
final?</p>
<p>It seems to me that the above case is decisive of this question and the courts should have all
taken the above reasoning under the Ekiu case. But supposing you would say that there must be some
testimony taken under the Act, what would be the law in this case? Would there be any testimony? We
must reply in the affirmative,- there was testimony. These men were in person before the Board.</p>
<p>In the case of United States v. Rodgers, 191 Fed. 970, it was held that where an alien immigrant
was before the Board of Inspectors, so that they had an opportunity to inspect and examine him in
person, and he was given a fair hearing and full opportunity to present evidence, an order denying
him admission on the ground that he is likely to become a public charge cannot be reviewed by the
courts in habeas corpus proceedings as not supported by evidence. See also United States v.
Williams, 190 Fed.  897.</p>
<p>The Court in the Rodgers case, page 973, quotes with approval the following language used in the
Williams case:
"Ever since the decision of the Supreme Court 
<pb/>
in Nishimura Ekiu v. United States, 142 U.S. 651 (12
Sup.Ct.336, 35 L. Ed. 1146), it has, so far as I know, Been held in this circuit that if the board
of inspectors had the alien beofre them so that they might themselves inspect and examing him, there
was sufficient before them to warrant his exclusion on the ground that he was liable to become a
public charge, if, in their discretion, they reached such a conclusion. Nothing which has been
presented on this argument persuades me to reverse this holding."</p>
<p>In an earlier case, namely, United States v. Williams, 186 Fed. 354,356, the Court followed the
same rule. Thus it says;
"But the immigration acts confer exclusive power upon the immigration officials to determin such
questions, and the courts, so long as the procedure prescribed by the immigration acts and the rules
established for their administration is sibstantially followed, have under the decisions of the
United States Supreme Court no jurisdiction to interfere."</p>
<p>This latter was a very hard case, but the Court had to leave it to the immigration authorities.</p>
<p>You will note that the law says in every case where an alien is excluded from admission under any
law or treaty now existing, or hereafter made, the decision should be final.</p>
<p>Suppose this was a case in which the immigration authorities were excluding these aliens under a
treaty: would the courts have any right to interfere as soon as they had adopted the form or
procedure required by the Act? We believe not. They would have no more right to do so than they
would to interfere with the action of a consul or ambassador. The question of admission and
exclusion of foreigners into America rests entirely with Congress. The The execution of these laws
can be left to anybody of men Congress may desire to designate. In this particular in-</p>
<pb/>
<p>they had a hearing according to law; they kept a record according to law; they came to a decision
according to law and this decision was affirmed by the Secreatary of Labor in accordance with the
law; they held that the Russians were likely to become a public charge, according to law. It makes
no difference what was the reason for their coming to this wrong conclusion - if it were wrong -
this is a question of international law and the courts have no right to interfere. This is a
stronger case than the seventy-three Hindus, because they had already landed in our country and had
thus come withing the jurisdiction of the court.</p>
<p>The question as to whether a person is liable to become a public charge is one involving many
facts. It is impossible for the court under the Act to say what matters are to be considered by the
immigration on authorities in determining this question, it may be the health of the immigrant, it
may be the condition of the country, the mentality of the immigrant. In passing on the question such
a broad range of reasons would enter into it that it is impossible for the Court, under the Act, to
prescribe its limits. Congress left all these matters for the immigration authorities because it
assumed that such authorities would be more familiar than courts with local conditionsand wit the
knids of men who would be likely to become public charges.</p>
<p>We are forced to the conclusion that the question as to whether a person is liable to become a
public charge is bound to be one exclusively of fact, and if this final fact is decided adversely to
an immigrant the reasons of their arising at their conclusion is a matter that the court has no
right to interfere with.</p>
<pb/>
<p>If the court should reverse the action in this case, it puts itself in the position of
interpreting and enforcing the immigration laws in spite of the face that Congress left this
exclusively to the immigration authorities.</p>
<p>Respectfully submitted,</p>
<p>Clay Allen
United States Attorney.</p>
<p>P Fishourne
Assistant United Sates Attorney</p>

<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>