<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.269.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title> In Re: Ex Parte - Turner Jackson Petitioner For A Writ of Habeas Corpus </title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Banse, AD" xml:id="ab">AD Banse</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.269.001</idno>
<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">  In Re: Ex Parte - Turner Jackson Petitioner For A Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="2022-06-07"></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington </repository>
<collection> RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle </collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName> Turner Jackson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName> C.B. Hopkins</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>C.H. Hanford</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> 
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>  

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs ="hc.case.wa.269.001"/>

<!-- <p>Reproduced at the National Archives at Seattle </p>-->

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT,  FOR THE NINTH JUIDICIAL CIRCUIT, WESTERN  DISTRICT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE, THE ABOVE ENTITLED COURT, AND CORNELIUS H. HANFORD, Judge of the same: -</p>

<p>I.-</p>

<p> Comes now your petitioner, Turner Jackson, a citizen of the United States and of the State of  Washington, and respectfully shows to your Honorable Court that he is unlawfully held in custody by C.B. Hopkins, United States Marshal for the District of Washington, in the United States penitentiary at McNeil's Island, in said State of Washington and within this District.-</p>

<p>II-</p>
<p> That your petitoner was sentenced upon the 6th day of  January, 1899, and arrived at said penitentiary and was a then incarcerated on the 13th day of Janurary, 1899. That the sentence of the court before whom your petitioner was tried was that he should be confined in said penitentiary for the period of ten (10) years, and your petitioner has been incarcerated under said sentence ever since his incarceration in said penitentiary he has been a good prisoner, and for the record of his conduct shoes that he has faithfully observed all of the rules and has not been subjected to punishment, and that he is entitled to a deduction from the term of his sentence to be estimated under the laws of the United States of America as commencing on the first day of his arrival at the penitentiary, which deduction, under the law of the United States of America, amounts to ten (10) days for each month of his sentence.  </p>

<p> III</p>

<p>  That your petitioner has not been sentenced under more than one sentence, but is incarcerated in said penitentiary under one sentence alone.</p>

<p> IIII</p>

<p> That under and by virtue of said sentence, and the condition and terms thereof, and the laws of the United States of America, your petitioner is entitled to a discharge from said penitentiary, and was so entitled to a discharge therefrom upon the 8th day of Septmenber, A.D.1905, but that said United States Marshal refuses to discharge your petitioner from said penitentiary, although his time for which he was sentenced, after deducting "good time", as provided by the laws of the United States of America, has fully expired. </p>

<p> V</p>

<p> That your petitioner is a man of well established reputation, and was so at the time of his sentence. That he is in all respects entitled to the benefits of every law the United States providing for the incarceration and discharge of prisoners sentenced from any quarter of the United States to any jail or penitentiary therein.  

Wherefore, your petitioner prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus may issue out of and under the seal of this Honorable Court, directed to C.B. Hopkins, United States Marshal for this District, commanding him to have the body of your petitioner, together with the return of the date and cause of his detention, before this Honorable Court on a day to be designated therein, and that on such return and hearing had thereon, your petitioner may be discharged from said custody and imprisonment. And your petitioner will ever pray.    </p>

<p>  Truner Jackson by R.S. Jones his Atty.</p>

<p> United States of America, Ninth Judicial District, State of Washington, County of King,  ss.</p>

<p> Richard Saxe Jones, being first duly sworn, on oath deposes and says: That he is attorney for the petitioner above named: has read the foregoing petition, knows the contents thereof, and the facts therein stated are true. That he makes this affidavit upon behalf of the petitioner because the petitioner is now incarcerated in the penitentirary at McNeill's Island and cannot personally make this affidavit.</p>

<p> R.S. Jones</p>
<p> Subscribed and sworn to before me this 2d of September, A.D. 1905. </p>
<p> Jas. A. Snoddy </p>
<p> Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>