<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0221.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chin Quock Wah vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0221.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Chin Quock Wah vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-05">May 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Allen, Clay</term>    
<term>Beeler, Adam</term>
<term>Ching, Wing Hin</term>
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Densmore, J. B.</term>
<term>Fishburne, George P.</term>
<term>Lakin, Edward M.</term>
<term>McGerrick</term>
<term>Neterer, Jeremiah</term>
<term>Sullivan, John J.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>China</term>
<term>Boston, Massachusetts</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Chin Quock Wah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Adam Beeler</persName>
<persName>Sullivan, John J.</persName>    
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Clay Allen</persName>
<persName>George P. Fishburne</persName>    
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-03" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION 
OF CHIN QUOCK WAH FOR A WRIT 
OF HABEAS CORPUS ) 
No. 2971.
Filed May 10, 1915.</p>

<p>Beeler &amp; Sullivan For Applicant.
Clay Allen, U. S. District Attorney) For Government.
George P. Fishburne, Asst. " )</p>
<p>NETERER, District Judge:</p>
<p>It is alleged in the amended petition that the petitioner
is restrained of his liberty by the United States Commissioner 
of Immigration, in that he is ordred deported, contrary to law, 
and states that on the 14th of September, 1914, he arrived at 
the port of Seattle, made application for admittance, and that
he was given a hearing by the Immigration officials and testimony
was taken from time to time, and on the 25th of November,
1914, an order was issued by the Commissioner of Immigration, 
finding that he was not entitled to remain in the United States, 
and his deportation was ordered; that on the same day an appeal was
taken to the Secretary of Labor; that the appeal was determined 
by one J. B. Densmore, Solicitor of the Department, as Acting
Assistant; that at said time the Secretary of Labor and his 
Assistant were at their respective offices, and the action
of Densmore was not authorized by law, and that the petitioner, by 
reason thereof, did not have a hearing upon his appeal, and that
he has been denied due process of law; that he is the minor son 
of Ching Wing Hin, a native born Chinaman of the United States; 
and prays that he be discharged and allowed to join his father, 
who is a merchant in Boston, Mass. It is further alleged that
the petitioner was denied the right to have counsel appear before 
the Secretary of Labor and present oral argument in support of
his appeal.</p>
<p>Return is made in which it is admitted that the petitioner 
arrived in the United States and applied for admission, and that
he was denied admission and ordered to be deported; admits that
<fw>--1--</fw>
<pb/>
appeal was made to the Secretary of Labor; denies that said 
appeal was not heard by the Assistant Secretary; denies that
applicant is the minor son of a domiciled Chinaman; denies that
he is the son of Ching Wing Hin; denies that Ching Wing Hin is 
a native born Chinaman of the United States, or entitled to 
remain in the United States.</p>
<p>The contention of the petitioner that his appeal was 
improperly disposed of is not well founded. The record 
discloses that the appeal was heard and disposed of by the Assistant
Secretary of Labor. The contention that he was deprived of 
a fair hearing and not accorded due process of law, is, I think, 
equally unfounded. There is no provision of law to my knowledge
which accords to an immigrant the right of counsel before the
Commissioner of Labor. This matter was before this court in 
re application of Chin Hing, opinion filed May 10, 1915, in which 
the language of Judge Lacombe, used in U. S. v. Williams, 190
Fed. 898, was quoted, as follows:</p>
<p>"There is nothing in the statute which calls for 
the presence of counsel at the examination of aliens 
preliminary to admission; nothing to indicate that it 
was the intent of Congress that these investigations 
in hundreds of thousands of cases touching the 
qualifications of an alien seeking to enter were to be 
conducted as trials in court, with counsel present to 
represent the alien, witnesses called to testify, and 
elaborate examination and cross-examination of them".</p>
<p>It is strenuously contended that the fact of Chin Wing 
Hin's birth in the United States was definitely disposed of
and became a legal status established by a certificate issued
by one McGettrick, United States Commissioner, granting the
right to enter the United States as an American citizen. 
Referring to the McGettrick certificate, this court in Ex Parte Mac
Fock, 207 Fed. 696, at page 698, said:</p>
<p>"The first question to be disposed of is: Is the
certificate which was presented a judgment in 
contemplation of the exclusion act? I think a reading of 
the document is sufficient to conclusively show that 
it is not. On its face it shows that it is not a 
judgment. It does not purport to be a certified copy 
of any judgment or record of judgment. It is not a
document which could be considered as evidence by any 
court or tribunal. It is merely a statement that a 
certain act had been done. It does not purport to, 
<fw>--2--</fw>
<pb/>
nor does it in fact fill the requirements of any rule 
of evidence, state law, or act of Congress with 
relation to authentication of records of the United States.</p>
    <p>'A written statement by a United States 
    Commissioner that a Chinese person of a certain name 
    was brought before him and was adjudged to have
    the right to remain in the United States by reason
    of being a citizen is not evidence of a judgment.</p>
    <p>Ah How v. United States, 193 U. S. 63; United States
    v. Lew Poy Dew (D. C.) 119 Fed. 786".</p>
<p>I have examined the testimony with relation to the 
vocation of Chin Wing Hin and likewise that pertaining to the 
relationship of the applicant to Chin Wing Hin, and upon the 
evidence presented, I cannot say that the conclusion is 
erroneous and that the applicant was not accorded a fair hearing. </p>
<p>The writ is discharged and the petitioner remanded to 
the custody of the Department of Immigration. If the petitioner 
appeals from this order within ten days, he may be released on 
filing recognizance in the sum of $2000.00, conditioned as 
provided by law, pending the appeal.</p>

<ab>Jeremiah Neterer
JUDGE.</ab>

<fw>--3--</fw>
<pb/>

<p>No. 2971.</p>

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT 
OF THE UNITED STATES
FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
<add>Northern Division.</add></p>

<gap/>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. District Court, 
Western Dist. of Washington,
NORTHERN DIVISION
MAY111915</p>
<ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk,
By EML Deputy
2x</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>