<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0268.009">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ernest Hutchinson v. City of Seattle. Answer and Return.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Tecca, Lauryn." xml:id="lnt">Laura K. Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022-06</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0268.009</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ernest Hutchinson v. City of Seattle. Answer and Return.</title>
<date when="1904-04-23">April 23, 1904</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1904-04-23">April 23, 1904</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Thos. R. Delaney</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hutchinson, Ernest</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>City of Seattle</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#lnt">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT OF THE NINTH CIRCUIT
IN AND FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE PETITION 
Of
ERNEST HUTCHINSON, for a Writ
of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>ANSWER and RETURN.</p>

<p>Comes now Thos. R. Delaney, as Chief of Police of the City of
Seattle, King County, Washington, and in compliance with the order from
this HOnorable Court, and in answer to petition herein, makes his return
herein and says: That he is the Chief of Police of the City of Seattle,
King County, Washington, and the one to whom the order and writ in this
cause was directed, and on whom served, and the one having in charge 
and custody, at said time, the said Ernest Hutchinson, and that said 
Ernest Hutchinson was in his custody at said time by reason of a complaint
having been made and sworn to before R.R. George, one of the
Justices of the Peace and police judge in and for the said City of
Seattle, and filed with said Police Judge, charging the said Ernest
Hutchinson with the violation of Section 7 of Ordinance No. 6036 of the
said City of Seattle, and a warrant based upon said complainst and issued
from said Court, and by reason of the authority of said complaint 
and warrant, a certified copy of said complaint and warrant, and also
of Section 7 of Ordinance No. 6036, are hereto attached, referred to
and made a part of this answer and return.  </p>

<p>Said respondent further says that the said Ernest Hutchinson 
is now and will remain at liberty on his own personal recognizance, and</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>only voluntarily surrendered himself into the custody of said respondent
as Chief of Police for the purpose of securing a writ of
Habeas Corpus in order to test the validity of Section 7 of said Ordinance 
No. 6036 of said city.</p>

<p>T.R. Delaney
Chief of Police of The City of Seattle.</p>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON,
COUNTY OF KING.
ss.</p>

<p>Thos. R. Delaney, being first duly sworn, says: That he
is the Chief of Police of The City of Seattle, King County, Washington,
and the person upon whom was served the Writ of Habeas Corpus in this
cause, and the one having in charge the said Ernest Hutchinson at the 
time of the service of said Writ, and that he has read the answer and
return herein, knows the contents thereof, and believes the same to be 
true.</p>

<p>T.R. Delaney</p>

<p>Subsribed and sworn to before me this 23 day of April 1904.</p>

<p><unclear>Ellis T. Brules</unclear>
Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at
Seattle.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>ORDINANCE NO.6036</p>

<p>AN ORDINANCE to license and regulate certain trades and occupations in
The City of Seattle, providing penalties for the violation thereof
and repealing all ordinances inconsistent therewith.</p>

<p>Be it ordained by the City of Seattle as follows:</p>

<p>Sec. 7. Subdivision 1. It shall be unlawful for any one to sell, 
offer or attempt to sell goods and merchandise by selling trading
stamps, checks, tickets or other thing of whatever name to merchants,
the same by such merchants being delivered to customers upon the purchase
of goods and merchandise, and then exchanged by such customers
with the person selling such trading stamps, checks, tickets or other
thing of whatever name for his goods and merchandise, without first
paying into the city treasury the sum of six hundred dollars, and upon
receipt showing such payment, procuring a, license, issued by the City
comptroller authorizing the same. Such license shall be issued for 
the period of twelve months.</p>

<p>Subdivision 2. Any merchant who deals in or uses any trading
stamps, checks or tickets mentioned in subdivision one of this section
must also first pay into the city treasury the sum of one hundred dollars, 
and upon receipt showing such payment, procure a license, issued
by the City Comptroller, authorizing the same. Such license shall be
issued for the period of twelve months.</p>

<p>Subdivision 3. Any person found guilty of any violation of this
section shall be fined in any sum not exceeding one hundred dollars
or sentenced to the City jail not to exceed thirty days, or be both fined
and imprisoned.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Sec. 23 This Ordinance shall take effect and be in force from
and after its passage and approval, if approved by the Mayor; otherwise
it shall take effect at the time it shall become a law under the
provisions of the City Charter.</p>

<p>Passed the City Council the 11th day of June 1900
and signed by me in open session in authetication of its passage.</p>

<p>W.V. Rinehart
President of the City Council.</p>

<p>Approved by me this 14th day of June 1900
T.J Humes
Mayor.</p>

<p>Filed by me this 14th day of June 1904
Attest: Frank H. Paul
City Comptroller and ex-officio City Clerk.</p>

<p>By G.K. Coryell
Deputy Clerk.</p>

<figure><p>Seal</p></figure>

<p>Published June 15th 1900</p>

<p>Frank H. Paul
City Comptroller and ex-officio City Clerk.</p>

<p>By G.K. Coryell
Deputy Clerk.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON
County of King,
City of Seattle.
ss.</p>

<p>I, John Riplinger, City Comptroller and ex-officio
City Clerk of the City of Seattle, do hereby certify that the within
and foregoing is a true and correct copy of The Title; Enacting Clause;
Section 7; Section 23; Clause showing date of passage, approval, 
filing and publication of Ordinance No. 6036,
as the same appears on file in my office.</p>

<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF I have hereunto set my hand and affixed the
seal of the City of Seattle this 23rd day of April
A.D. 1904</p>

<p>John Riplinger
City Comptroller and ex-officio
City Clerk of the City of Seattle
By <unclear>Eustace</unclear> Deputy </p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Exhibit B
THE CITY OF SEATTLE
IN THE JUSTICE COURT IN AND FOR SEATTLE PRECINCT
KING COUNTY, WASHINGTON.
Before R.R. George, Police Judge.</p>

<p>THE CITY OF SEATTLE
vs.
Ernest Hutchinson
No. 3817
CRIMINAL COMPLAINT</p>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON, COUNTY OF KING, THE CITY OF SEATTLE, SS.</p>

<p>E.C. PHAIR, being first duly sworn says: That on the 14th
day of January, 1904, at the City of Seattle, in said King County,
Washington, the said Ernest Hutchinson did commit a misdemeanor by
offering and attempting to sell merchandise by selling trading stamps 
as follows, to-wit: Then and there being the said defendant in said
city did wilfully and unlawfully attempt to sell general merchandise
and goods by selling trading stamps to the said E.C. Phair, a merchant
in said city, doing business at No. 1420 E. Madison St., the said
stamps to be delivered by said E.C. Phair to his customers upon such 
customers making a purchase from said E.C. Phair, and such trading
stamps then exchanged by such customer with the said defendant for his 
goods and merchandise, said stamps bearing the following written words:
"National Trading Stamp Co." "New York", Buyer's Stamp" and the same
was done by said defendant wihtout any license from said City of Seattle
so to do, all of which is contrary to Ordinance No. 6036, Section
7, Subdivision <unclear>law</unclear> 3, of the City of Seattle, entitles "An Ordinance
to license and regulate certain trades and occupations in the City of 
Seattle, providing penalties for the violation thereof and repealing
all Ordinances inconsistent therewith." Approved June 14th, 1900, and
against the public good, peace and good order of the City of Seattle.</p>

<p>E.C. Phair.
Name.</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me, this 1st day of February, 1904.
R.R. GEORGE.
Police Judge.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>WARRANT OF ARREST.</p>

<p>THE CITY OF SEATTLE,
PLAINTIFF
vs.
Ernest Hutchinson,
Defendant</p>

<p>Warrant. Exhibit C.</p>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON,
COUNTY OF KING,
THE CITY OF SEATTLE.
SS.</p>

 <p>IN Justice Court, R.R. George, Police Judge.
to the CHIEF OF POLICE OF SAID CITY, OR SHERIFF
OR CONSTABLE OF SAID COUNTY, GREETING:</p>

<p>WHEREAS, E.C. Phair, had this day complained in writing, under
oath, to the undersigned, one of the Justices of the peace and Police
Judge in and for said Seattle Precinct, King County, that on the 14th 
day of January, 1904, Ernest Hutchinson, in said City; County and State,
did commit the offence of unlawfully attempting to sell goods and merchandise
by selling trading stamps in said city.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, in the name if the State of Washington, you are
commanded forthwith to apprehend the said Defendant and bring him before
me to be dealt with according to law.</p>

<p>Given under jmy hand this 1st day of February, 1904.
R.R. George, 
Police Judge.</p>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON,
COUNTY OF KING,
THE CITY OF SEATTLE.
SS.</p>

<p>I hereby certify, That I have arrested the within named Ernest Hutchinson and have him now in court.
John Sullivan, Chief of Police.
By</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>State of Wahington,
County of King.
ss.</p>

<p>I, R.R. George Judge <del>Clerk</del> of the <del>Municipal</del> Police
Court of the City of Seattle, King County, Washington, do hereby certify that the foregoing and annexed <unclear></unclear> complaint and warrant marked Exhibit 'B."C" <del>transcript
contains, and is</del> true and correct <unclear></unclear> the complaint and arrest on file in this 
said case of 
The City of Seattle Plaintiff
vs.
Ernest Hutchinson Defendant
and that the annexed and attached papers are all the process and other papers relating to the action and filed with me, 
and all of which are correct.</p>

<p>Dated at Seattle, Washington, 23rd day of April 1904
R.R. George
Judge <del>Clerk</del> of the <del>Municipal</del> Police Court of the City of Seattle.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>No. 1183</p>

<p>In the United States
Circuit Court
FOR THE DISTRICT OF Washington
Northern Division</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of Ernst 
Hutchinson for a 
Writ of Habeas
Corpus</p>

<p>Filed in the
U.S. Circuit Court 
Dist. of Washington
Apr 23 1904</p>

<p>A. Reeves Ayres
<unclear></unclear>
Mitchell William
Ellis DeBruler
H.A. Wilson
Attorney for Thos. R Delaney
as Chief of Police</p>

<pb></pb>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>