<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0210.010">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Hisayo Kuwahara v. Henry M. White. Decision</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0210.010</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Hisayo Kuwahara v. Henry M. White. Decision</title>
<date when="1920-02-04">February 4, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-02">February 1920</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Kuwahara, Sakutaro</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Kuwahara, Hisayo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Kiefer, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Moore, Ben L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-01" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Feb 4 1920</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>

<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<pb/>

<p>Decision:</p>

<p>No. 5004.</p>

<p>Filed Feb. 4, 1920.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of Sakutaro Kuwahara for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Robt. C. Saunders, U.S. Atty.,</p>
<p>for Commr. of Immigration.</p>

<p>James Kiefer, Atty.,</p>
<p>for Petitioner.</p>

<p>NETERER, District Judge,</p>

<p>The petitioner is a Japanese seeking to enter the United States. She is excluded by the Commissioner at Seattle, and detained for deportation, and has sued out a writ of habeas corpus. By the return, it appears that on September 27, 1919, she arrived at the Port of Seattle on board the S.S. "AFRICA MARU"; that on the 3d of October, a Board of Special Inquiry was appointed, and after hearing duly had, she was excluded. The matter was reopened, and a further hearing had on October 17th. Appeal was taken to the Secretary of Labor, who affirmed the finding of the Special Board of Inquiry. A copy of the testimony, findings, and affirmance, are made a part of the return. The petitioner asserts she was not given a fair hearing. The testimony shows, and the board finds, that petitioner and her husband were married in Japan, before he came to the United States. The status of the petitioner must, therefore, be determined by the legal status of her husband. If he is qualified to remain, then the wife may be admitted.</p>

<p>The record shows that the husband has a total deposit in the banks, Liberty Bonds, and Savings Stamps, $1,535.10. The first deposit appears to be dated August 16, 1917, in the sum of $200.00. There was also exhibited an accident insurance policy of the American Casualty Company, dated April 1, 1915, insuring the husband, showing payments to date. The husband, during the year 1918, paid $32.11 income tax. The testimony further shows that the husband was employed by the Eatonville Lumber Company for "about five years" the last nameddate, "about $150 per month." The Board of Inquiry, on the rehearing, after discussing the testimony, says:</p>

<p>"It is the unanimous belief of the Board of Special Inquiry that the alien Sakutaro Kuwahara, the husband of the applicant, entered the United States surreptitiously at some date subsequent to November, 1914, that at the time of entry he was of the excluded classes; and, as he has not established to the satisfaction of the Board that he has been within the United States for a period of five years or more, the Board votes unanimously to deny admission to the applicant and votes to exclude her on the ground that she is a person likely to become a public charge * *."</p>

<p>There is no testimony in either hearing that the husband was of the excluded class. The newspaper article is not evidence.</p>

<pb/>

<p>If he was of the excluded class, his residence in the United States for five years would ripen into a license to remain. If he was not of the excluded class, then his surreptitious entry into the United states would ripen into permission to remain, three years after entry. Sec. 4289 1/4 JJ Compiled Statutes 1918; Act. Feb. 5, 1917; 39 Stat. at Large, 889.</p>

<p>A Board of Special Inquiry has no more right to draw inferences from facts that do not necessarily and legitimately authorize such inferences, or to indulge in unwarranted presumptions, than it has to find any other fact without evidence, and if a board indulges in unwarranted presumptions, or finds a fact not predicted upon evidence, a fair trial is not given. At the time of the arrival of the petitioner, the husband was, under the law, by reason of limitation, qualified to remain; first, because it has not been shown that he was within the excluded class, and admitted by the Board to have been here more than three years; second, the competent testimony presented upon both hearings, I think, shows that the husband was within the United States for five years. There is no testimony to the contrary, and the interferences drawn are not warranted. The testimony, I think, is conclusive that the husband was employed by Ohashi - Washington Garden at Fife, for approximately one year prior to his engagement with the Eatonville Lumbar Co., where he worked for "about five years" immediately preceding September 25, 1919. That he is frugal and able to provide for his wife is established by the testimony, and nothing to the contrary appears.</p>

<p>The writ is granted.</p>

<p>Jeremiah Neterer</p>
<p>Judge.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>