<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-09" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION 
OF BEN WA, FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS 
CORPUS FOR TUNG KEE</p>
<p>No. 2202 
PETITION.</p>
<p>Comes now Ben Wa and petitions the above entitled court 
and shows as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>That heretofore and on or about the thirteenth day of 
April, 1912, Tung Kee arrived at a port of the United States, on 
board the steam ship "Talthybius", and applied to the inspector 
of the United States in charge for entry, and the said Tung Kee 
alleged and proved before the said inspector that he was a citizen 
of the United States, having been born in the City of Portland in 
the State of Oregon, of Chinese parentage.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>That the local inspector in charge of the hearing denied
the application of the said Tung Kee, and an appeal was prosecuted
to the secretary of Commerce and Labor, who hertofore affirmed 
the decision of the local office, and an order has been made by 
the secretary of Commerce and Labor to deport the said Tung Kee 
to China, and said order of deportation is about to be carried 
out by Ellis De Bruler, Commissioner of Immigration stationed in 
the City of Seattle, County of King and State of Washington, although 
the said Tung Kee is a citizen of the United States and 
entitled to remain in the United States, and said order will be 
enforced unless the same is stayed by order of this court.</p>
<p>TUCKER &amp; HYLAND</p>
<p>LAWYERS</p>
<p>SEATTLE, WASH.</p>
<pb/>
<p>III.</p>
<p>That the record of the hearing before the inspector of
the United States at the time of the application of the said Tung 
Kee for admission, shows upon its face a clear record and the clear 
right of the said Tung Kee to be admitted and to remain in the 
United States.</p>
<p>IV.</p>
<p>That the only witnesses who testified therein testified
clearly and unequivocally that the said Tung Kee was bron in the 
said City of Portland, Oregon, and gave facts and data in reference 
thereto which would convince the mind of any person of the absolute
right the said Tung Kee had to remain in the United States.</p>
<p>V.</p>
<p>That the evidence for the said Tung Kee at such hearing
was of such an undisputable character that the rejection of his 
said application amounts to and is a denial of a fair hearing and 
consideration of his case, to which he is entitled under the constiution
of the United States, and by reason of said decision of 
the inspector, together with the affirmance thereof by the secretary 
of Commerce and Labor, on account of said clear and convincing 
proof, is a denial of justice to the said Tung Kee, and the
said Tung Kee has been deprived of his liberty without due process 
of law in contravention of the constitution of the United States.</p>
<p>VI.</p>
<p>That your petitioner hereby refers to the testimony and 
proof introduced at the hearing before the inspector, by reason of 
which hearing an order of deportation was entered against the said 
Tung Kee, and makes said proof and testimony a part of the petition 
herein as fully as if copied at length in this petition.</p>
<p>TUCKER &amp; HYLAND</p>
<p>LAWYERS</p>
<p>SEATTLE, WASH.</p>
<pb/>
<p>WHEREFORE your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas 
corpus be issued, directed to Ellis De Bruler, Commissioner of 
Immigration, Seattle, Wash., directing him to produce the body 
of the said Tung Kee before this court, and upon hearing, that 
he be released and given permission to remain in the United States, 
and that an order be issued herein, directed to the said Ellis De 
Bruler, directing him cause why such a writ of habeas corpus 
should not be granted, and that a further order be granted herein, 
directed to the said Ellis De Bruler, to withhold the order of deportation 
against the said Tung Kee until the final adjudication 
herein.</p>
<p>Tucker Hyland</p>
<p>ATTORNEYS FOR PETITIONER.</p>
<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON }Ss.</p>
<p>BEN WA, being first duly sworn, on the oath desposes and says: 
That he is the petitioner in the above matter, that he 
has read the foregoing, knows the contents thereof, and the statements
made are true, as he verily believes.</p>
<p>Ben Wa</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me as July 9, 1912</p>
<p><unclear> L. Seyland</unclear></p> 
<p>Notary Public in and for the 
State of Washington, 
residing at Seattle</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>