<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0365.014">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John Matthews v. Henry M. White. Testimony</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0365.015</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">John Matthews v. Henry M. White. Testimony</title>
<date when="1921-08">August 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-08">August 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fisher, Thomas M.</term>
<term>Matthews, Mike</term>
<term>Huestis, Edward</term>
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Matthews, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>U.S. DEPARTMENT OF LABOR
IMMIGRATION SERVICE</p>

<p>REPORT OF HEARING
IN THE CASE OF
JOHN MATTHEWS</p>

<p>Under Department Warrant No. 54904/149, Dated November 15, 1920</p>

<p>Hearing conducted by Thos. M. Fisher, Immigrant Inspector,
At McNeil Island Penitentiary, Wash. on January 11, 1921
Minutes taken and transcribed by C.V. Cattrell, Junior Clerk.</p>

<p>Said John Matthews
being able to speak and understand the English language satisfactory, an interpreter;
- -, contempt in - - was not employed
______</p>

<p>Said John Matthews
was then informed that the purpose of said hearing was to afford him an opportunity to show
cause why he should be be deported to the country whence he came, said warrant of arrest being
read, and each and every allegation therein contained carefully explained to him, said person
was then offered an opportunity to inspect the warrant of the arrest and the evidence upon which it was
issued, which privilege was not accepted; and alien being first duly sworn -
the following evidence was then and there presented:</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>#37012/600
John Matthews</p>

<p>Q   At the hearing to be accorded you under this warrant of arrest you
    have the right to be represented by counsel. Is is your desire to
    be represented?     A. No.
Q   What is your name?      A. Jack Matthews
Q   How old are you?        A.I am twenty-eight now.
Q   Where were you from?    A. I was born in the Ukrainian, under the
flag of Austria.
Q   When did you leave Australia?   A. I left Austria in 1906 or 1907.
Q   Where did you go?               A. I came to New York.
Q   Do you know what boat you came on?      A. I landed at St. John or
Halifaz; St. John I think.
Q   Where did you get on the boat?  A. I got on the boat at Antwerp,
Belgium.
Q   Do you know the name of the boat? Montezuma
Q   Do you know the date you arrived at Halifaz or St. John? A. No, sir.
Q   Do you know about what time?    A. It was in the spring of the year,
in April
Q   It was in 1906 or 1907? A. Yes
Q   Where were you going?   A. I was going to New York; I stayed there
for a short time while then  I went back to Montreal. I was in Ottawa
because I had a friend there I wanted to stay there.
Q   Who was your friend in Ottowa? A. He has gone back home before
the war.
Q   Were you coming to him?     A. When I found his address is there
I wanted to find him.
Q   How long were you in Ottowa? A. Not very long; then I went to
Cobolt (phonetic spelling) in Ontario, the big mining place.
Q   How long there?     A. I was there for about 9 years, at Cobalt,
Porcupine, and Golcondo in the mines.
Q   You were working in the mines?  A. Yes sir.
Q   What were you doing in the mines?   A. I was a machinist.
Q   You are a machinist are you?    A. Yes, sir.
Q   After that where did you go?    A. After that, I was there
for quite a while then I went to Sault Ste Marie; I was working in the
machine shop for the McPine people - - that is a big iron mine.
Q   Then after you left there where did you go? A. After I left there
I went down to British Columbia, Vancouver, between Vancouvr and
Prince Rupert, Canada, prospecting.
Q   Then where?     A. I stayed there for a while then I came to the
United States in 1919.
Q   What month?    A.  Between September, or about September.
Q   How did you come to Seattle?    A. By boat.
Q   From Vancouver?     A. From Prince Rupert
Q   Did the boat touch at Vancouver or Victoria? A. Yes.
Q   Were you examined by Immigrant Inspector and pay head tax? A. Yes
I have my receipt here- -they have it here in the office.
Q   How long did you stay in Seattle? A. I went to Alaska, to the Kennicott
Mine, Alaska.
Q   How long did you work there for them?   A. I worked there two
months before I was arrested.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Q   You were charged with sending obscene matter through the mail?
A. Yes
Q   You entered a plea of guilty? A. Yes
Q   That was in Valdez?           A. Yes. My sentence was one year.
Q   It was one year and one day, wasn't it? A. I am not sure, yes.
Q   That was May 4, 1920, you were sentenced? A. Yes.
Q   Now you had been arrested on another charge? Weren't you
arrested, something about a watch? A. Yes
Q   You pleaded not guilty to that? A. I pleaded not guilty and
they didn't find me guilty.
Q   They acquitted you? A. Yes
Q   It was charged you took that watch? A. The charge against me
was they found a watch in my possession on which had been lost from
the United States post office, which I bought in Seattle before
I took the boat. When I went to work I carried that watch with
me.
Q   You were acquitted of the charge? A. Yes, I was not guilty.
Q   Have you ever taken the steps to become a citizen of the United
States? A. No, no papers.
Q   Have any relations living in the United States or in
Canada? A. Yes, I have a brother in Canada.
Q   What is his name? A. Mike Matthews.
Q   Where does he live? A. Alberta
Q   What place? A. I write every time to Winnipeg, Ukrainian
Labor Temple
Q   What town? A. In Winnipeg
Q   Did you ever become a citizen of Canada? A. No, sir, I did not.
Q   Have you any property in Canada or in the United States?
A. I have property in Canada, not in the United States.
Q   Where in Canada? A. In the "West Shining Tree", that is a
mining claim in Ontario.
Q   Have you a title to it? A. Not here, no.
Q   Have you relatives in the old country? A. One sister in the
old county.
Q   Do you know here address? A. I haven't heard since the war started.
Q   Now then, is there anything else you want to say to show why you
should not be deported from this country? A. I got nothing to
say.    My record in Canada, which is as clear as could be must
speak for me.
Q   Who knows about your residence in Canada? A. You could write to
Cobolt and find my name.
Q   Who knows you? A. The people who know me there, write to the
Beaver Mine.
Q   They know you under this name of Matthews? A. Yes. Write the
O'Brien people, Golcondo.
Q   What is the address of your parents in the mine? A. I never
heard since I have been arrested. One is an engineer and the
other is a miner and they work different places; also I never
wrote from here to let them know where I am now; I only wrote
to my brother from here.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>37012/600</p>

<p>The alien produced a Canadian registration card issued to
one Yan (his X mark) Matveyaff, #41.111.423 at Suolburg, Ontario,
June 22, 1918;</p>

<p>Head tax receipt, #14188 Form 569a dated Victoria, B.C. August
31, 1919, signed Edward Huestis;</p>

<p>also a School Tax Receipt, #13556, dated October 30, 1919, showing
receipt from J. Matthews of five dollars for school. 24, signed by
C.W. Lloyd, school tax collector for town or school district of
Blackburn </p>

<p>Attest:
C.V. Cattrell,
Stenographer</p>

<pb></pb>
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>