<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-09" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE WESTERN
DISTRICT OF THE WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>Nick Mordevich, 
Plaintiff, 
vs.  
Joseph Jacoby, 
as Marshall of the above named District, 
Defendant. }</p>
<p>PETITION FOR A WRIT 
OF 
HABEAS CORPUS. 2139</p>
<p>The plaintiff and petitioner above named 
shows to the Court that he is unlawfully restrained of his 
liberty by the above named defendant in this</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>The petitioner and complainant is a citizen of the 
United States conducting the business of seine fisherman plying 
his vocation upon the waters of Puget Sound within the State of 
Washington, and has been so engaged for many years last past. He 
has a license and during all the time hereinafter shown had a 
license from the State Fish Commissioner of the State of Washington
authorizing him to take fish during the year of 1912 in the waters 
of Puget Sound, said State.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>That between the first day of April and the 16th day of 
April, 1912, he with others similarly situated, was taking fish 
from the waters of said Sound at a point along the northerly
beach of Hales' Passage, a stretch of water seperating Lummi
Island from the main land in Whatcom County, said District. That the Lumni Indian Reservation borders Hales' passage on the northeast 
side and the fore shore of such reservation is washed by the ebb 
and flow of the tide and the beach exposed at low tide varies in width from a few feet to as much as eight hundred feet.</p>
<pb/>
<p>On or about the 16th day of April, 1912, petitioner was plying 
his vocation at fisherman, casting his seine and taking herring 
along the waters aforesaid and in order to operate his 
said seine he approached the shore to shallow water and one end 
of the seine was held by another person between the line of 
high tide and low tide while plaintiff himself extended said seine 
and cast it into deep water, bringing it in a semi-circle to connect
both ends on the beach when said seine would be drawn and tied 
and the catch of fish taken to a receiving vessel anchored in deep 
water and there disposed of for shipment to market. </p>
<p>III.</p>
<p>That while so fishing the said defendant took possession
of the complaint under a warrant charging him with unlawfully 
fishing upon the said Indian Reservation, took him before the 
Honorable A. L. Black, Jr. United States Commissioner sitting in 
Bellingham, Who pretended to hold a hearing, preliminary, for the 
purpose of inquiring whether the plaintiff had violated any law
and charging the plaintiff with having returned to the said 
reservation after having been removed by the Indian Agent. That 
evidence was adduced before said Commissioner the material and 
substantial part of which evidence was to the effect that while 
this petitioner had been engaged in fishing in the manner aforesaid
ant at a time when he was below the line of high tide at 
the place aforesaid, the Indian Agent or sub-agent had said to 
your petitioner that he was on the Indian Reservation and must 
cease fishing there and go away, and there was no other or additonal 
evidence or testimony material to the charge made against 
the petitioner or under the affidavit charging the offense or the 
warrant upon which your petitioner was apprehended. That by 
treaty between the Indian Tribes and the United States made the 
2nd day of January, 1855, at Point Elliot, Washington Territory and 
proclaimed April 11, 1859, the Island called Chohohosen was 
reserved by the Indians for their exclusive use, said Island 
being defined and brodered as situated in the Lummi Reservation 
at the point of seperation of the mouths emptying respectively
<pb/>
onto Bellingham Bay and the gulf of Georgia.</p>
<p>IV</p>
<p>By Executive Order No.1301 issued November 22 1873, the boundaries of 
Lummi Indian Reservation were prescribed as beginning an the mouth
of the Nooksack River, thence up the river to the ahe line between sectio
7 &amp; 8 township 38 north range 2 East, thence west along said line 
to low water mark on the shore of the gulf of Georgia, thence southerly
and easterly along the said shore with the meanders thereof, acros 
the western mouth of Lummi river and around Point Francis, thence nor 
easterly to the place of beginning.</p>
<p>V.</p>
<p>Your petitioner and complainant shows that upon the organization
of the State of Washington and the adoption of the constitution
of the State of Washington by said State, the said State be 
came the owner of all the shore lands lying between the line of ordinary
high tide and ordinary low tide within the boundry of said 
State by virtue of its sovereignty and the United States had never
patented any of the lands along the said Indian Reservation.</p>
<p>VI.</p>
<p>Your petitioner and complainant shows that at no time did 
he reside upon or intend to reside upon any shores of the said Indian
Reservation and had never been upon said Reservation at any point 
nor above the line of high tide. He had never been removed from 
said Reservation and never returned to said Reservation with any intention
or purpose whatever, except as aforesaid in the exercise of 
his rights as a fisherman under the license of the State of Washington.</p>
<p>VII.</p>
<p>That notwithstanding his rights as aforesaid the said 
United States Commissioner and the said United States Marshall 
have caused your petitioner's arrest, incarceration in jail and 
now restrains his liberty upon the pretended charge that he 
had been removed from the said Indian Reservation and had unlawfully 
returned thereto. That no probable cause exists for holding 
this petitioner to answer for the crime of having returnd to the 
said Reservation after having been removed therefrom nor for unlawfully
being upon the said Reservation in the taking of fish</p>
<pb></pb> 
<p>from the waters of Puget Sound in the manner and the time and place 
as aforesaid and all these things your petitioner is ready to 
verify.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE your petitioner asks that the Court grant 
to him the Writ of Habeas Corpus, that the illegality of his 
restriant be inquired into and upon the final hearing, he be 
discharged.</p>
<p>S.M. Bruce</p>
<p>State of Washington, 
County of Whatcom. } ss.
Attorneys of Petitioner</p> 
<p>Nick Mordevich
being first duly sworn on oath deposes and says: That he is the petitioner 
named above, that he has read the foregoing complaint, 
knows the contents thereof and the statements therein set forth 
are true.</p>
<p>Nick Mordevich</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 20th day of April</p>
<p><unclear>C.E. Williams</unclear>
NOTARY PUBLIC residing at 
Bellingham, Washington.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>