<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0180.012.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Brief.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0180.012</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Brief.</title>
<date when="1913-12-12">December 12, 1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2628AlbertYoung&amp;KamasaburoSugiura</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-12">December 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Brace, H. G.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>White, Henry M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Denamore, J. D.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>DeBruler, Ellis</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Saito, Hana</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Ito, K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Uneda, K.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Washio, Shotaro</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>San Fransico, California</term>
</keywords>


</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Young, Albert H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sugiuro, Kamasaburo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Myers, H. A. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>McClellan, R. W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Johnstone, Walter L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, G. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States, for the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division</p>
<p>In the matter of the Petition of
Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo
Sugiura, alias B.K. Sugiura,
aliens, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus | No. 2628
Petition for a Writ
of Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>To the Honorable Judge of the above entitled Court:
The petitioners above named, as and for a petition for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus, respectfully represent and allege:</p>
<p>I. 
That your petitioner, Albert H. Young, is of the age of
twenty-six years, and has resided in the United States for more than
five years last past, and is now and has been a resident of Seattle,
King County, Washington, during said time; that he is an interpreter
by profession, and a student of law.</p>
<p>That your petitioner, Kamasaburo Sugiura, alias B.K. Sugiura,
is of the age of thirty-three yearsl, and has resided in the
United States for more than nine years last past; that he is married,
has a wife and one child, and they are now residing in the City of
Seattle, King County, Washington; that he is now, and for the last
six years, has been engaged as a traveling salesman for H.G. Brace
&amp; Co., of Seattle, Washington, and is also, by profession, an interpreter.</p>
<p>II.
That your petitioners and each of them are unlawfully imprisioned, detained, confined, and restrained of their liberty, by
Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration, having chargee of the
United States Detention Station at Seattle, in the State of Washington,
under an alleged, pretended, and illegal warrant for arrest of
<fw>1</fw>
<pb/>
said aliens, issued and signed by one J.B. Denamore, Acting Secretary
of Labor of the Government of the United States, on the 21st day of
August, 1913, and an alleged, pretended, and illegal Warrant for
Deportation of said Aliens, issued and signed by said J.B. Denamore,
Acting Secretary of Labor of the Government of the United States, on
the 29th day of November, 1913, which said Warrant for Arrest is in
words and figures as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>"Warrant - Arrest of Alien
United States of America
U.S. Department of Labor
Washington</p>
<p>No. 53510/248</p>
<p>To Ellis DeBruler, Commissioner of Immigration, Seattle, Washington,
Or to any Immigrant Inspector in the service of the United 
States.</p>
<p>Whereas, from evidence submitted to me, it appears that the aliens
Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiura, alias B.K. Sugiura, who
landed at an unknown port, have been found in the United States in
violation of the Act of Congress approved Feburary 20, 1907, amended
by the Act approved March 26, 1910, for the following among other
reasons:</p>
<p>That the said aliens are unlawfully within the United States in 
that they have been found assisting, protecting, or promising to protecct
from arrest, a prostitute or prostitutes.
I, J.B. Denamore, Acting Secretary of Labor, by virtue of the
power and authority vested in me by the laws of the United States, do
hereby command you to take into custody the said aliens and grant
them a hearing to enable them to show cause why they should not be
deported in conformity with law.</p>
<p>The expenses of detention hereunder, if necessary, are authorized,
payable from the appropriation "Expenses of Regulation Immigration,
1914". Pending further proceedings the aliens may be released from
custody upon furnishing satisfactory bond in the sum of $1000.00 each</p>
<p>For so doing, this shall be your sufficient warrant.</p>
<p>Witness my hand this 21st day of August, 1913.</p>
<p>(signed) J.B. Denamore
Acting Secretary of Labor"
CEB</p>
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
<p>That said Warrant for Deportation is in words and figures
as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>"Warrant - Deportation of Alien
United States of America
Department of Commerce and Labor
Washington</p>
<p>No. 53510/248 A</p>
<p>To Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration, Seattle, Wash.</p>
<p>Whereas, from proofs submitted to me, after due hearing before
Immigrant Inspector B.A. Hunter, held at Seattle, Wash., I have
become satisfied that the alien Albert H. Young, and Kamasaburo Sugiura, 
alias B.K. Sugiura, who landed at some unknown port, have been 
found in the United States in violation of the Act of Congress approved 
Feburary 20, 1907, amended by the Act approved March 25, 1910,
to-wit:</p>
<p>That the said Aliens are unlawfully within the United States in
that they have been found assisting a prostitute and protecting, or
promising to protect from arrest, a prostitute, and may be deported
in acoordance therewith:</p>
<p>I, J.B. Denamore, Acting Secretary of Labor, by virtue of the
power and authority vested in me by the laws of the United States, do
hereby command you to return the said aliens to Japan, the country 
whence they came, at the expense of the appropriation "Expense of
Regulating Immigration, 1914". You are directed to purchase transportation
for the Aliens from Seattle, Wash. to their home in Japan,
at the lowested scheduled steerage rate available, payable from the
above named appropriation.</p>
<p>For so doing, this shall be your sufficient warrant.</p>
<p>Witness my hand and seal this 29th day of November, 1913.</p>
<p>J.B. Denamore
Acting Secretary of Labor"
(Seal)</p>
<p>III.
That under and by virtue of said Warrant of Arrest and
Warrant for Deportation, your petitioners were and now are under
arrest and detention by said Commissioner of Immigration, and ordered
deported from the United States to Japan all without due and legal
process, and in violation <add>of Acxt V of the amendments to the Constitution of U.S.</add> of their full legal rights, in this, that
by the terms of said Warrant of Arrest and Warrant of Deportation,
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
your petitioners were and are charged with being "unlawfully within
the United States, in that they have been found assisting, protecting
or promising to protect from arrest, a prostitute or prostitutes."</p>
<p>IV.
Your petitioners further allege that on the 17th day of 
October, 1913, a pretended hearing was had upon said warrant of
Arrest, at the Detention Station in Seattle, aforesaid, before the
Commissioner of Immigration there in charge, at which time the said
Commissioner of Immigration took the testimony of each of your petitioners,
and then toerafter filed, as part of the evidence in
said matter, the affidavits of one Hana Saito, one K. Ito, and one
K. Uneda, copies of which, marked Exhibits "A", "B", and "C", respectively,
and hereto attached and made a part hereof, and afterwards,
to-wit, on the 3rd day of November, 1913, said Commissioner further
took the affidavit of one Shotaro Washio, a copy of which is hereto
attached, marked Exhibit "D", and made a part hereof, and filed the
same as a part of the evidence in said matter. But your petitioners
allege that the affidavit of Hana Saito was taken in the City of
Tacoma, State of Washington, on the 16th day of October, 1913; that 
each of the affidavits of K. Ito and K. Uneda, were taken in the City
of San Francisco, State of California, prior to the issuance of said
Warrant of Arrest, and of the arrest and hearing thereon, to-wit, on
the 3rd day of June, 1913; that the said affidavit of Shotaro Washio
was taken in the Jail of King County, Washington, long after the said
hearing of said matter before the Commissioner of Immigration.</p>
<p>Your petitioners allege that neither they, nor their attorney,
were given any notice or opportunity to and did not appear at the
time and place of the taking of either of said affidavits of Hana
Saito, K. Ito, or K. Uneda, and had no opportunity to and did not
<fw>4</fw>
<pb/>
cross-exmine said witnesses in any manner touching the matters and
things purported to be testified to by them in said affidavits; and
that at no time were your petitiners ever confronted, face to face,
by said affiants, nor did said affiants, at any time, appear in person
before your petitioners and testify to any of the matters alleged in
said Warrant. Your petitioners further say that at the time of the
taxing of the affisavity of said Washio, he was then confined in the
County Jail of King County, Washington, under sentence of having
violated the white-slavery Act. Counsel for your petitioners was notified
and did appear at the time and place of taking said affidavit,
but your petitioners, being then confined in said Immigration Station,
were not notified and were not given an opportunity to, and did not
appear at the taking of said affidavit, nor of being confronted by
said affiant at the taking thereof.</p>
<p>V. 
Your petitioners allege that said Warrant of Arrest and
Warrant of deportation, together with said affidavits, are all the
proceedings had and held thereunder and taken by the said Government
of the United States, in said matter, except, that your petitioners
further state that they have been informed and believe the same to
betrue, and so allege the same, that the Department of Labor, at
Washington D.C., and the Secretary thereof, made and conducted an 
independent investigation concerning the charges set forth in said
Warrant; and received other evidence and communication, and information
in addition to that product at said pretended hearing; and that
said investigation, information and communication were made without
any notice to, or knowledge or a part of these petitioners, and without
any opportunity to be present in person to by counsel, or to take
part in any manner therein, and your petitioners allege that each of
<fw>5</fw>
<pb/>
of said Warrants, and all of said proceedings, are illegal, iregular,
insufficient, and void, and against the law, for the following reasons, 
to-wit:</p>
<p>(a) That said Warrant of Arrest is indefinite and uncertain,
and fails to charge any specific offense as having been committed by
your petitioners, and fails to charge or name the person or persons,
or any time, place, state, or location in which the alleged charge of
protecting such as prostitute or prostitutes from arrest, or whom, or
where, or when, and in what manner your petitioners protected said
prostitute or prostitutes from arrest, or promised to so protect, and
fails to definitely charge what arrest was then being, or about to be
made, and under what authority.</p>
<p>(b) Your petitioners allege that said Warrant for Deportation
is in the same manner indefinite and uncertain, and fails to allege
what specific offense your petitioners have been found guilty of committing
and upon which they have "been found in the United States in
violation of the Act of Congress approved Feburary 20, 1907, amended
by the Act approved March 26, 1910" and by which "the said Aliens are
unlawfully within the United States", in that said Warrant fails to 
definitely state what prostitute or prostitutes, what time, and at 
what place your petitioners were found guilty of protecting from arrest,
or whom, when, and where they promised to protect such prositute
or prostitutes, or what arrest was then being or about to be made.</p>
<p>(c) That neither of said Warrants or said affidavits charge any
particular offense against either of these petitioners, or definitely
refer to any particular act upon the part of your petitioners amounting
to the offense for which they are, in said proceedings, found
guilty and ordered arrested and deported. And your petitioners further
allege that under their own sworn statements aforesaid, they positively
<fw>7</fw>
<pb/>
denied having at any time protected or promised to protect, any
prostitute or prostitutes, or any arrest, at any of
the times referred to in any of said affidavits, being or about to be
arrested; and that at said hearing before said Commissioner, they
strongly attested their innocence or any such charge, and still now
protect their innocence thereof.</p>
<p>(d) That your petitioners have at no time, since their said
arrest, had a fair trial or hearing, or any trial or hearing according
to law.</p>
<p>VI.
Your petitioners allege, that pursuant <del>there</del>to, said warrant
of Arrest and said pretended hearing, and said Warrant of Deportation,
they were arrested by the Immigration Authorities at Seattle, and
were and now are detained by said Commissioner of Immigration at said
Station, and under and by virtue of said Warrant of Deportation, are
ordered to be deported from the United States to Japan, on or about 
the 16th dat of December, 1913, pending which order and deportation,
they are now being detained at said station. And that your petitioners
are all, as aforesaid, unduly, illegally, and wrongfully imprisioned
and detained at said Station, and deprived of their liberty, in violation
of their legal rights and of the rules governing such hearings
thereunder, for which reason the now bring this, their petition for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>Wherefore, your petitioners pray that a Writ of Habeas 
Corpus be, and the same may issue out of and under the Seal of this
Honorable Court, directed to the said Henry M. White, Commissioner of
Immigration, in and for the United States and the District aforesaid,
<fw>7</fw>
<pb/>
at the Immigration Station thereof, then and there commanding him,
the said Henry M. White, Commissioner as aforesaid, to forthwith
bring the bodies of said Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiura, alias
B.K. Sugiura, before this Honorable Court, at such time as the 
Court may direct, then and there to be dealt with according to law,
and to abide such Decree as this Honorable Court may make in the
premises.</p>
<ab>Albert H. Young
Kamasaburo Sugiura
Petitioners</ab>
<ab>R.N. McClelland
HAP Myers &amp;
Walter L. Johnstone
Attorneys for Petitioners</ab>
<pb/>
<p>Western District of Washington
County of King | ss</p>
<p>Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo
Sugiura, aliad B.K. Sugiura, being first duly, serverally sworn,
deposes and says, each for himself: that he is one of the petitioners
in the above and foregoing petition; that he has carefully read 
the same, knows the contents thereof, and the allegations therein
contained are true, except the statements therein averred on information
and belief, and as to these, affiants verily believe the same
to be true.</p>
<ab>Albert H. Young
Kamasburo Sugiuro</ab>
<p>Severally subscribed and sworn 
to before me this 12 day of 
December, A.D. 1913</p>
<figure/>
<ab>Walter AS <unclear>Tenptone</unclear>
Notary Public residing at 
Seattle, Washington</ab>
<pb/>
<p>No. 2628 2x</p>
<p>In the 
District Court
of the United States
For the Western District
of Washington
Northern Division</p>
<p>In the matter of the Petition
of Albert H. Young and
Kamasaburo Sugiura, alias B.
K. Sugiura, aliens, for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Petition for a Writ 
of Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Filed in the
U.S. District Court
Western
Dist. of Washington
Northern Divison
Dec 11 1913
Frank L. Crosby, Clerk
By EML Deputy</p>
<p>R.W. McClellan, H.A.P. 
Myers &amp; Walter L. Johnstone
Attorney for Petitioners
Empire and Leary Buildings
Seattle, Washington</p>
<p>J.L. MacDonald Company No. 183</p>
<pb/>
<p>Service of within Petition
and recipt of copy admitting this
<gap reason="blank"/> day of
December 1913</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>