<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0177.002.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">April 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Bajlo, Gek</term>
<term>Baljo, Jack</term>
<term>Bajlo, Tonka</term>
<term>Brockway, E. B.</term>
<term>Cushman, Edward E.</term>
<term>DeBruler, Ellis</term>
<term>Fisher, Thomas M.</term>
<term>Larkin, Ed M.</term>
<term>Riddle, C. F.</term>
<term>Runderwood</term>
<term>Wilson, W. B.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>United States District Court, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Tonka Bajlo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>C. F. Riddell</persName>
<persName>E. B. Brockway</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Edward E. Cushman</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
<del>SOUTHERN</del> <add>Northern</add> Division.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Tonka Bajlo for the Writ of 
Habeas Corpus. ) 2459
No. 1328.</p>

<p>RETURN TO ORDERS TO SHOW CAUSE
AND ANSWER TO PETITION.</p>

<p>To Honorable Edward E. Cushman, Judge of the Above entitled
Court: - </p>
<p>Comes now Ellis DeBruler, Commissioner of Immigration
at Seattle, Washington, and for return to the Order to Show 
Cause herein filed April 16, 1913, shows to the Court that
he has not at any time failed to safely keep the said Tonka
Bajlo since the date of her original arrest, and that no
order of this court has ever issued requiring him to safely
keep the said Tonka Bajlo a prisoner; and for return to the
Order to Show Cause issued herein on April 17, 1913, and for 
answer to the Petition filed herein, states as follows:</p>
<p>- I -
Said Ellis DeBruler denies that the said Tonka Bajlo
is confined in violation of the Constitution of the United
States; that she was compelled to testify against herself 
upon a criminal charge; also denies that she had no opportunity
to present evidence on her behalf, and denies that
she was ordered deported upon a criminal charge. He further
denies that she did not understand the nature of the proceeding
against her, and that she made any deman for counsel
<pb/>
until after the matter had been closed upon a fair, proper and regular hearing.</p>
<p>- II -
Said Ellis DeBruler further denies the charges against 
against said Tonka Bajlo are without foundation of law or
fact, and that any order for her deportation was made without
an opportunity for her to have proper legal hearing.</p>
<p>- III -
Said Ellis DeBruler alleges that the said Tonka Baljo
is detained by virtue of the final ruling of a competent 
tribunal, to-wit: The Secretary of Labor of the United 
States, and denies that she is restrained of her liberty by 
reason of any false charges against her. The said Ellis
DeBruler further alleges that he has no knowledge or information
sufficient to for a believe, and therefore denies that
the charges made against her by Jack Bajlo, her husband, 
were for the purpose of wreaking vengeance upon her, the said
Tonka Baljo.</p>
<p>And for a further and separate answer and return to 
said Order to Show Cause, and said Application for a Writ
of Habeas Corpus, said Ellis DeBruler, alleges that on or
about the 7th day of April, 1913, said Tonka Baljo was 
arrested by one Thomas M. Fisher, Inspector of Immigration,
stationed at Seattle, Washington, under authority of the
Department of Labor of the United States in violation of the 
Act of Congress approved February 20, 1907, and amended by
the Act of March 26, 1910, to-wit: That she was an alien
found practicing prostitution after her entry into the 
United States, and as such, liable to deportation in the
<pb/>
<fw>(2)</fw>
manner prescribed by law. That said authority for said
arrest adn detention of said applicant is found in the 
warrant duly and regularly issued on the 7th day of April, 
1913, by W. B. Wilson, Secretary of Labor, andopy of the 
said warrant being attached hereto and made a part of this 
return; nthat the original of said warrant was forwarded to 
said Ellis DeBruler by telegram on said April 7, 1913, copy
of said telegram being also hereto attached and made a part hereof.</p>
<p>That on April 7, 1913, said Tonka Bajlo and other witnesses
were duly and regularly examined by said Thomas M.
Fisher, who was then and there a duly qualified and acting
Inspector of Immigration, stationed at Seattle, Washington,
acting under the authority of the laws of the United States
and the rules and regulations of the Bureau of Immigration 
of the Department of Labor of the United States, and as such
Inspector had power to examine said Tonka Baljo
to remain in the United States; that the testimony so given 
at said examination was duly and regularly taken down in
shorthand and thereafter transcribed and forwarded on or
about the 9th day of April, 1913, to the Department of Labor
at Washington, D. C. That said record, together with the 
record of the examining Inspector, and the recommendation of
Ellis DeBruler, the Commissioner as aforesaid, were received
by the Department of Labor at Washington, D.C., and then and
there carefully considered by said officers, and on the 15th 
day of April, 1913, said Department and said Secretary of 
Labor decided adversely to said applicant, and became and
were satisfied that she was an alien subject to deportation
<pb/>
<fw>(3)</fw>
under the laws of the United States, and ordered her deportation
to the country from whence she came. That a copy of the
testimony so taken at the hearing aforesaid is attached hereto, 
made a part hereof, and that in addition, the copy of
the whole record of such proceeding is attached hereto and
made a part hereof. Special attention is called to the 
following portions of said record, found on the pages thereof 
indicated:</p>
<p>1. Affidavit of complaining witness, Gek Bajlo (pp
41, 42).</p>
<p>2. Request of Inspector Fisher for warrant (p 45).</p>
<p>3. Copies to cipher telegrams from Commissioner 
DeBruler to the Immigration Service, requesting
warrant for the arrest of alien (pp 44, 46).</p>
<p>4. Copy of written request by Commissioner DeBruler, 
requesting warrant for the arrest ofalien (p.40).</p>
<p>5. Telegram of Secretary Wilson authorizing arrest
and hearing of alien (p 36).</p>
<p>6. Written order from Secretary Wilson to the same
effect (p 38).</p>
<p>7. Medical certificate by surgeon Runderwood (p .37).</p>
<p>8. Transcript of proceedings had and evidence taken 
under authority of such warrant (pp 14-22 inc).</p>
<p>9. Finding of Inspector Thomas M.Fisher based on 
above matters (pp 22,23).</p>
<p>10. Letter of Commissioner DeBruler to the Commissioner 
General, enclosing full record of all prior proceedings 
and recommending deportation of alien.
(pp 12, 13).</p>
<p>11. Code telegraphic warrant from Secretary Wilson
<pb/>
<fw>(4)</fw>
finding alien to have been practicing prostitution 
and a person who at the time of her entry was 
liable to become a public charge, and ordering
her deportation; also translation of the same (p.5).</p>
<p>That the foregoing are the reasons why the said Tonka
Bajlo is detained by Ellis DeBruler, in custody, and why 
said Ellis DeBruler now detains her in custody pending the 
orders of the above entitled court in the premises; that by
reason of the premises, this Court has no jurisdiction to
review the acts of the Secretary of Labor of Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, said Ellis DeBruler having shown good reason
for his detention of the said Tonka Bajlo, prays the above 
entitled court that this action be dismissed, the Order to 
Show Cause quashed, and that the application and Petition for 
said Writ be denied, and that he be allowed to go hence and 
have his costs.</p>
<ab>C. A. Riddell
United States Attorney</ab>
<ab>E B Brockway 
Assistant United States Attorney</ab>
<p>THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION ) ss.</p>
<p>Ellis DeBruler, being first duly sworn on oath deposes
and says: That he is the party named in the foregoing
Answer; that he has read the same,knows the contents thereof,
and verily believes the same to be true.</p>
<ab>Ellis DeBruler</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 21st day of April, 1913.</p>
<ab>Ed M Larkin
Deputy Clerk, U.S. Dist. Court, Western Dist. of Washington</ab>
<pb/>
<fw>(5)</fw>
<p>No. 1328</p>
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT
OF THE UNITED STATES
FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application 
of Tonka Bajlo for 
a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>RETURN TO ORDERS TO SHOW
CAUSE AND ANSWER TO PETITION</p>    
<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington
APR 21 1913</p>
<p>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk.</p>
<p>By EML Deputy</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>