<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0459.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Moy Wah v. J. C. Drake. Deposition of Thomas Hawks</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0459.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1893-06-06">June 6, 1893</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1893-06">June 1893</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Hawks, Thomas</term>
<term>Richards, N. C.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Wah, Moy</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Drake, J.C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Snell, Marshall K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Brinker, Wm. H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Circuit Court of the United States for the District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Washington, Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-09" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, FOR THE DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, WESTERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application 
of Moye Wah, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>State of washington, )
County of Pierce
:ss.
<del>County of Pierce</del></p>

<p>Thomas Hawks being first duly sworn on his oath deposes and
says:-</p>

<p>That he is and has been for a number of years last past
a citizen and resident <del>of</del> and freeholder of the City of Portland,
Multnomah County, Oregon, and was for a number of years, deputy
sheriff and a member of the police force of said city, and has for
three years last past been deputy tax collector, engaged in the 
collection of taxes in said city; that he is the identical person
who signed as Capt. Thomas Hawks the statement in the foregoing
exhibit "A" attached to the certificate of <del>wah Ni</del> Moy Wah as ac-
knowledged on the 22nd day of January, A.D., 1892 before J.E.
Marks, Notary Public; that he is well and personally acquainted
with said Moy Wah, and has, at different times, collected taxes of
him and called at his place of business which is 168 Fifth Street
Portland; that the said Moy Way is a member of the firm of Gum
Wing Chung &amp; Co., at said number; and deponent further says that
owing to the fact that he was assigned, in the performance of his
duties both as policeman and tax collector, to the district oc-
cupied by the Chinese, he has, at different times been called up-
on to sign statements for Chinamen who were intending to go to
China and return to the United States; and deponent further says
that he is duly informed and verily believes that the said Moy 
Wah is a member of said firm of Gum <del>Chung</del> Wing Chung &amp; Co., de-
ponent having at various times seen said Moy Wah engaged in work-
ing about and employed in said place of business of said firm in
Portland, and deponent has examined the original of said certifi-</p>

<pb/>

<p>cates and knows the contents thereof andsays that each and every
statement therein contained is true to the best knowledge and be-
lief of deponent; and deponent further says that said Moy Wah did
depart and go to China at and about the time of his obtaining said
certificate and that he verily believes that he went there for the 
sole purpose of further aiding and assisting in the carrying on of
said business of said firm as aforesaid, as represented by said
Moy Wah in said certificate, and deponent verily believes that said
Moy Wah is a good, respectable and bona fide Chinese merchant of
the United States and has been for three or more years last past,
deponent stating upon oath that he has known him for at least that
long including the period of his said absence from the United
States, and deponent is duly informed and verily believes that at
this time he has an interest in and is one of the joint owners of
the business as carried on by said firm and is a good, honest,
upright and bona fide Chinese merchant as aforesaid.</p>

<p>Thomas Hawks</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 6th day of June, 1893</p>

<p>N.C. Richards</p>

<p>Notary Public in and for Pierce County
Residing at Tacoma, Washington.</p>

<pb/>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>