<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0215.012">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chung Him and Seid Yam v. Henry M. White. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0215.012</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Chung Him and Seid Yam v. Henry M. White. Petition</title>
<date when="1920-10-25">October 25, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-10">October 1920</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Stremch, William G.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Ketchikan, Alaska</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Him, Chung</persName>
<persName>Yam, Seid</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Corrigan, John L.</persName>
<persName>Winston, Will H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-03" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Original</p>

<p>No. 5630</p>

<p>In the <del>Superior</del>District Court of the <del>State</del> United States for the Western District of Washington</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Oct 25 1920</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<p>John L. Corrigan</p>

<p>Attorney for</p>

<p>920 Lbrary Building</p>
<p>Seattle, Wash.</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 5630</p>

<p>Petition</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Jung Ham and Seid Yam for a Writ of Habeas Corpus,</p>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE JEREMIAH NETERER, JUDGE OF THE ABOVE ENTITLED COURT:</p>

<p>Your petitioners, Jung Ham and Seid Yam respectfully petition and show to your Honor as follows:</p>

<p>I</p>

<p>That said petitioners and each of them are now and at all times for more than thirty (30) years last past, have been residents of the United States; that they are persons of Chinese descent and that they have in all respects complied with the laws of the United States governing the residence of Chinese persons within the United States and have been at all times, within the past thirty (30) years within the United States.</p>

<p>II</p>

<p>That Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration, is restraining petitioners and each of them of their liberty and that said restraint is not by virtue of any judgment or order of any court or tribunal or by virtue of any execution issued upon any judgment or order. That the cause or pretense of said confinement and restraint of your petitioners, according to the best knowledge and belief of the said petitioners is an order of arrest made by the Assistant Secretary of Labor, Louis F. Post, of Washington, D.C., and that such arrests were made by William G. Stremch, Immigration inspector, Ketchikan, Alaska, on or about the <gap></gap></p>

<pb/>

<p>day of June, 1920. That no copies of any warrant or other process of any kind was ever served upon your petitioners or either of them and that your petitioners are unable to attach hereto any copy of said warrant or process for that reason.</p>

<p>III</p>

<p>That your petitioners further allege that the cause for issuing said warrant is for the purpose of having your petitioners deported to China upon the ground that your petitioners and each of them have violated the terms and provisions of Section 19 of the Act of February 5th, 1917, in that your petitioners are charged (as they are informed) with having been employed in, or in connection with, a House of Prostitution. That in truth and in fact said charge is untrue and false. That your petitioners and each oth them are cooks by occupation and also for some years past, have been employed during this fishing season, in Fish Canneries in Alaska. That during a time when the fish canneries were not being operated in the year 1920, your petitioners and each of them sought employment elsewhere and your petitioner, Jung Ham was employed for a period of about two and one-half months and your petitioner, Seid Yam, was employed for a period of about five (5) weeks at a certain house in Ketchikan, Alaska; that each of said petitioners was employed in his occupation as a cook; that if said house was in fact a house of prostitution, that fact was not known to either of your petitioners herein. That neither of your petitioners came in contact with any immoral person and had no knowledge whatsoever that said place was a house of prostitution if such be the fact.</p>

<p>IV</p>

<p>That the only hearing or trial accorded to either of your petitioners was that each of your petitioners was questioned by an official connected with the Immigration Service at Ketchikan, Alaska,</p>

<pb/>

<p>that neither of your petitioners is able to read or write the English language and neither of your petitioners are able to understand or follow a conversation conducted in English. That both of your petitioners answered such inquiries as were addressed to them by said Immigration official to the best of their respective abilities and truthfully but said Immigration official did not inform your petitioners or either of them and your petitioners and each of them did not know that he was being charged with any offense or violation of the laws of the United States. That said Immigration official did not have any interpreter present to translate his unquiries and your petitioners and each of them were not represented by counsel and did not know or understand the purpose or object of the inquiries being made by said Immigration official. That said petitioners and each of them did not know or understand that they had the right to have witnesses called in their behalf and that no such witnesses were called. That said petitioners and each of them if given the opportunity, or if they had been advised that it was necessary or proper so to do, would have been able to conclusively establish their entire innocence of any wrong doing whatsoever and that they had no knowledge whatsoever that the place where they had been employed at Ketchikan was a house of prostitution (if such was the fact).</p>

<p>V</p>

<p>That petitioners therefore allege that they and each of them have been denied a fair hearing and that there was no evidence whatsoever to support the alleged charge against them or either of themand that the order or deportation hereinafter referred to is arbitrary and unsupported by fact or law.</p>

<p>VI</p>

<p>Your petitioners further allege that an order of deportation has been issued against each of them and unless this Court issues a Writ of Habeas Corpus said order of deportation will be</p>

<pb/>

<p>executed and your petitioners and each of them removed from the United States to China. That no copy of said order of deportation has ever been delivered to your petitioners or either of them and for that reason petitioners are unable to attach copies of said order hereto.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE your petitioners pray that an order of this court be issued requiring the said Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration, to appear at a time and place to be designated in said order and show cause why a Writ of Habeas Corpus should not be issued and further commanding the said Henry M. White not to suffer or permit your petitioners or either of them to be taken or removed from the city of Seattle upon any pretext whatsoever until the further order of this court. Your petitioners further pray for such other and further relief as may be meet and proper in the premises.</p>

<p>J L Corrigan</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioners.</p>

<p>State of Washington, County of King,</p>

<p>ss</p>

<p>Jung Ham and Seid Yam being duly sworn each for himself and not one for the other, on oath deposes and says: That he is the petitioner in the above named Petition; that he has read the foregoing Application for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, knows the contents thereof and believes the same to be true.</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 25th day of October, 1920.</p>

<p>(Signiture in Chinese)</p>

<p>Seid Yam</p>

<p>J L Corrigan</p>

<p>Notary Public in and for the state of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>