<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0184.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Harry Gong vs. United States. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0184.005</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">January 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Banks, W. W.</term>
<term>Bean, R. S.</term>
<term>Bonham, R. P.</term>
<term>Gong, Harry</term>
<term>Lakin, Ed M.</term>
<term>Sargeant, John H.</term>
<term>Vaudenrig, George S.</term>
<term>Yow, Yut</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
<term>China</term>
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
<term>Washington, D.C.</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Harry Gong</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>George S. Vaudenrig</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>R. S. Bean</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>United States District Court, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>(Copy)</p>

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR 
THE DISTRICT OF <del>OREGON</del> <add>Washington
Northern Division</add></p>
<p>2648</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of 
<del>YUT YOW</del> <add>Harry Gong</add>
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus <add>for Yut Yow</add> )
Petition for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>To the Hon. R. S. Bean, Judge of the Above entitled court.</p>
<p>The petition of <del>Yut Yow</del> <add>Harry Gong</add> respectfully represents and shows
unto your Honor as follows:</p>
    <p>I.</p>
<p>That the petitioner is <add>next friend of Yut Yow</add> a native born citizen of the United 
States of Chinese parentage and was born in the city and County of 
San Francisco, in the State of California in the year 1869, and is 
now of the age of 45 years and ever since said time has been and is 
now a citizen, resident and inhabitant of the United States and that 
the parents of  petitioner were at the time petitioner was born as 
aforesaid domociled residents of said City of San Francisco, State
of California.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>That <del>petitioner</del> <add>said</add> Yut Yow is imprisoned, detained, confined 
and restrained of her liberty by <del>R. P. Bonham, Acting Chinese Inspector </del> <add>John H. Sargeant, Assistant Commissioner</add>
in Charge of the Department of Commerce and Labor of the United States
at the city of <del>Portland, in the county of Multnomah, State of Oregon</del> <add>Seattle, Washington</add>
and within the jurisdiction of the above entitled court. That said
imprisonment and restraint is not by virtue of any process issued by 
a court of the United States or by a judge or commissioner thereof, in
a case where such court, judge, or commissioner have acquired exclusive 
jurisdiction under the laws of the United States, and that such imprisonment
and restraint is not by virtue of any judgement or decree of conpetent
tribunal of civil or criminal jurisdiction, nor by virtue of any 
execution issued under such judgement or decree. That the cause or
<fw>1.</fw>    
<pb/>
or pretense of such imprisonment and restraint according to the best 
knowledge and belief of your petitioner is as follows:</p>
<p>III.
That <del>petitioner</del> <add>said Yut Yow</add> is imprisoned under a pretended warrant 
alleged to have been issued by the Secretary of Commerce and Labor of 
the United States, which said pretended warrant commands the said R. P. 
Bonham or other officer of the United <add>States</add> Immigration Service at Portland,
Oregon, to deport said petitioner to the Empire of China. That said
imprisonment, detention, confinement and restraint is unlawful and 
illegal and the said pretended warrant of deportation and proceedings
thereunder and unlawful and illegal in this, to-wit: That your petitioner
was arrested and confined in jail at the City of Portland,
Multnomah County, State of Oregon, at the instance and request, and 
under the direction of the United States Chinese Inspector in Charge
at Portland, Oregon, on November 4, 1913, without a warrant or other 
authority having been granted by any court of said City, County or 
State, and without any authority of law therefor, and that at said
time said United States Chinese Inspector, a pretended statement,
which said pretended statement was afterwards reduced to typewriting, 
a copy of which is annexed hereto, marked "Exhibit A" and made a part
of this petition. That said pretended statement was not voluntarily
made by petitioner and was obtained from petitioner by duress and
petitioner was not informed at said time that any statement made by her
would or could be used against her in the proceedings which resulted
as herein stated in issuing the pretended warrant of deportation 
as aforesaid.</p>
<p>IV.
That said pretended statement contains among other things
the following:questions and answer:</p>
<p><add>admit</add> "Q. It is true that you have been a prostitute for some 
<fw>2.</fw>
<pb/>
years in this city?</p>
<p>A. Yes.</p>
<p>Q. For how many years?</p>
<p>A. 15 years."</p>
<p><add>Deny</add> and petitioner alleges that she did not make the above answers to the 
questions above set forth in the pretended statement. Petitioner alleges 
that she stated at said time that she had never been a prostitute in 
said City of Portland but that she had resided in said City for 15 years.</p>
<p>V.
Your petitioner further alleges that based upon said pretended 
statement the Chinese Inspector in Charge at Portland, Oregon, thereafter
and on or about November 6, 1913, applied for a warrant of arrest for 
your petitioner to the Secretary of Commerce and Labor of the United 
States and on said date, to-wit, November 6, 1913, based upon said
pretended statement that said Secretary of Commerce and Labor issued a 
pretended telegraphic warrant charging petitioner with being an alien 
and a prostitute at the time of her alleged entry into the United States
and that petitioner entered the United States for the purpose of prostitution,
or their immoral purpose, and that petitioner had been found 
practicing prostitution subsequent to her alleged entry into the United
States and that she was unlawfully within the United States in that
petitioner had been found employed by, in or in connection with a house 
of prostitution or resort habitually frequented by prostitutes, or 
where prostitutes gather, and that petitioner had been found an inmate 
of a house of prostitution.</p>
<p><add>Don't except that 
Deny that statement was a pretended statement</add></p>
<p>VI.
<add>Deny</add>That thereafter and on November 11, 1913, pursuant to said 
pretended telegraphic warrant the Chinese Inspector in Charge at
Portland, Oregon, proceeded to conduct an alleged hearing upon the
charges contained in said alleged warrant an dcertain pretended testimony
was on said date secured ex parte from petitioenr and two Police 
Officers of the City of Portland, Oregon, a copy of which said pretended
testimony is attached hereto, marked "Exhibit B" and made a
part of this petition.</p>
<fw>3.</fw>
<pb/>
<p>VII.
Your petitioner alleges that she had no opportunity to be 
present when the said pretended tesimony of said Police Officers
was taken and had no notice of the time and place of taking the same.</p>
<p>VIII.
That after the taking of said pretended testimony said 
United States Immigration Inspector in Charge at Portland, Oregon,
marked "Exhibit A" and "Exhibit B" respectively, to the Secretary of 
Commerce and Labor of the United States at Washington, D. C. together
with an unfavorable report to your petitioner and thereupon 
said pretended warrant or order of deportation was made by said
Secretary of Commerce and Labor and based solely upon said pretended
testimony adjudgin your petitioner guilty of said charge and ordering
her deported to China. Your petitioner alleges that she has been 
deprived of a full and fair hearing upon said charge and upon her 
right to be and remain the United States by reason of the taking 
of the pretended testimony and proceedings on November 4, 1913, at
the Police Station as hereinbefore set forth, and that the taking of 
said testimony by the Chinese Inspector in Charge at Portland, Oregon
and the consideration of said testimony by the Secretary of Commerce
and Labor of the United States was unjust, illegal and arbitrary and
constitutes an abuse of discretion and power vested in said Chinese 
Inspector in Charge and said Secretary of Commerce and Labor. The 
said consideration of such testimony deprived petitioner of a full
and fair hearing within the meaning of the Immigration Laws and Rules
and Regulations pretaining thereto, and your petitioner has thereby
been deprived of her liberty without due process of Law.</p>
<p>IX.
Your petitioner further alleges that she has also been deprived
of a full and fair hearing upon said charge and upon her right
to be and remain in the United States by reason of the refusal of 
the United States Chinese Inspector in Charge at Portland, Oregon, on
<fw>4.</fw>
<pb/>
November 11, 1913, to give petitioner a reasonable time from said 
date petitioner was examined in order to secure witnesses as to her 
nativity in the United States in the City of San Francisco, State of 
California.</p>
<p>X.
Your petitioner further alleges that said imprisonment, detention, 
confinement and restraint is also unlawful and illegal in 
this, that subsequent to peitioner's arrest as aforesaid and prior to
the date of said pretended warrant of deportation, and on to-wit,
November 21, 1913, she was lawfully married at the City of Portland, 
Multnomah County, State of Oregon, to a native born citizen of the
United States, and petitioner alleges that said Secretary of Commerce 
and Labor had due notice and knowledge of petitioner's marraige as 
aforesaid prior to the issuance of said alleged warrant of deportation, 
and petitioner alleges that by virtue of said marriage petitioner takes 
the status of her said husband and is a citizen of the United States.
And petitioner alleges that by reason fo said marriage said pretended
warrant of deportation is null and void. That said illegality of said 
imprisonment has not been adjudged upon a prior Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p><add>Denied on in petition &amp; belief</add></p>
<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner prays that a Writ of Habeas Corpus
issue directed to said R. P. Bonham, United States Acting Chinese
Inspector in Charge, commanding him to have the body of the said Yut
Yow before your Honor at a time and place therein to be specified, 
to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by your 
Honor concerning her, the said Yut Yow, together with the time and
cause of her detention, and the said Writ and that petitioner be admitted
to bail in a reasonable sum until further order of this court.</p>
<ab>Harry Gong
Petitioner.</ab>
<ab>George S Vaudenrig
Attorney for Petitioner.</ab>
<fw>5.</fw>
<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
DISTRICT OF <del>OREGON</del> <add>Washington</add>
<add>Northern Division</add> ) ss.</p>

<p>I, <del>Yut Yow</del> <add>Harry Gong</add>, being first and duly sworn depose and say:
That I am the petitioner named in the foregoing petition, that
I have read said petition and know the contents thereof and the same
are true as I verily believe.</p>

<ab>Harry Gong</ab>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 11th day of January, 1914.</p>
<ab>Ed M Lakin
<del>Notary Public for Oregon</del>
<add>Deputy Clerk, U.S. Dist. Court, Western Dist. of Washingt</add></ab>

<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
DISTRICT OF <del>OREGON</del> <add>Washington</add>
<add>Northern Division</add></p>

<p>I, <del>W. W. Banks</del> <add>G S Vaudenrig, do hereby certify that I am petitioner's 
attorney, that the above and foregoing petition is well founded in 
law.</add></p>

<ab>G S Vaudenrig
Attorney for Petitioner.</ab>
<figure> </figure>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>