<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0472.001"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0472.001</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">September 2, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date>29 July 1899</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Denning, J. Henry</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>grace</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName></placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.1183.002"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->

<head> House Bill No. 340
State of Washington, Ninth Regular Session
Read first time February 20, 1905; ordered printed, and referred to Committee on Judiciary. </head>
<p> Making it a misdemeanor to sell or exchanged property under the representation, advertisement
notice or inducement that an unidentified, unknown, unselected, or chance
prize, premium or premium gift, or that a stamp, trading-stamp, coupon or other like
device, entitling the holder to recieve such a prize, premium or premium gift, or that
the redemption of such a stamp, trading-stamp, coupon or other like device so given is
to be part of the transaction, or to sell or exchange any trading-stamp, stamp, coupon,
or other like device to aid such sale or exchange, as aforesaid, and providing a penalty
therefor. </p>
<p> Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Washington:
Section 1. Whoever sells or exchanges any property or offers or attempts so to do
upon a representation, advertisement, notice of inducement that anything unidentified
by or unselected by the purchaser at or before the time of the sale or exchange or upon a
representation, advertisement, notice or inducement that anything whose precise nature
is not known to the purchaser at the time of the sale or exchange as to be completely
identified beyond the necessity of any further or other selection or upon a representation
notice, advertisement, or inducement that any property whose selection will depend
upon chance or hazard in any manner whatsoever is or is to be delivered or recieved
or is in any way connected with or is a part of the transaction as a prize, premium or
premium-gift; or whoever sells or exchanges any property or offeres or attempts to do
upon a representation, advertisement, notice or inducement that a stamp, trading-
stamp, coupon or other device which entitiles te purchaser to demand or recieve either from
the vendor or from any other person, corporation, association, or company any property
whose selection will depend upon chance or hazard or in any manner whatsoever, is to
be delivered or recieved or is iin any way connected with or is a part of the transaction
as a price, premium or premium-gift; or whoever sells or exchanges any trading-stamp,
stamp, coupon or other like device device upon a contract to enable the person to sell or exchange
property, or attempt so to do, upon any representation, advertisement, notice or inducement
of any kind hereinbefore mentioned; or whoever delivers any goods, wares or merchandise
upon the representation of any such stamp, coupon or other like device so

<pb/>

given or caused to be given shall for each offense be guilty of a misdemeanor and be
punishable by a fine of not less than $20 or more than $500, or imprisonment in a county
jail for not less than ten days, nor more than six months, or by both: Provided, however,
That the provisions of this act shall not apply or extend in any manner to the redemption
of any such stamp, trading-stamp, coupon or other like device that may have been issued
as a premium prize or premium-gift prior to the time this act takes effect: And provided
further. That the provisions of this act shall not apply or extend to any sale or exchange
of articles in bulk, heap or mass, or a part or portion thereof; which sale or exchange
is not made, effected or induced by or upon any representation, advertisement,
notice or inducement of any kind hereinbefore specified. Provided further, that
this act shall not apply to any person giving a due bill on the
sale of merchandise and redeeming the same himself in merchandise
<add>Provided further, That this act shall not apply to agricultural
or church fairs conducted for scientifis or chartiable purposes. </add> </p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>