<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0190.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Joseph Hansen v. Henry M. White. Complaint</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0190.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Joseph Hansen v. Henry M. White. Complaint</title>
<date when="1918-11-14">November 14, 1918</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1918-11">November 1918</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Burford, S. J.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Denmark</term>
<term>Seattle, King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hansen, Joseph</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court For The Western District of Washington Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#lkw">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2019-10" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>No 4357</p>

<p>In the District Court of the United States For the Western District of Washington Northern Division</p>

<p>Complaint Joseph Hansen</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Filed in the United State District Court Western District of Washington Northern Division. Nov 14 1918</p>

<p>George F. Vanderveer. Ralph S. Pierce Attorney for Plaintiff 607 Central Building Seattle Wash.</p>

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0190.001"/>

<p>In the District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>4357 C-O-M-P-L-A-I-N-T.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of JOSEPH HANSEN, for a writ of habeas corpus,</p>


<p>The complainant, Joseph Hansen, appearing by George F. Vanderveer and Ralph S. Pierce, his attorneys, complains to the court an alleges and petitions as follows:</p>

<p>1.</p>

<p>That at all the times hereinafter mentioned, complainant was and still is a subject of the King of Denmark, lawfully domiciled in the United States of America; that he is not restrained of his liberty on any charge or conviction of crime, nor on any process issued on any final judgement of a court of competent jurisdiction, nor on any warrant, committment or other process issued on any indictment or information; nor on any order or warrant of committment, otherwise than as hereinafter specified.</p>

<p>2.</p>

<p>That on the 10th <add>8th</add> day of April, 1918, complainant was arrested by an Immigration Inspector of the United States, on a warrant of arrest issued by the Secretary of Labor of the United States, wherein complainant is charged with being an alien, and with having been found within the United States, advocating or teaching the unlawful destruction of property, and with having been a person likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry into the United States; and on the 5th day of July, 1918, pursuant to the mandate of said warrant, complainant was taken before S. J. Burford, and Immigration Inspector of the United States, at Seattle, Washington

<pb/>

and given a hearing, for the purpose of inquiring into the merits of said charge, and upon being asked by said S. J. Burford regarding his belief in violence; in sabotage; "I believe in respecting any piece of property since I expect to be part owner of it sooner or later", and claimant further stated that he had been in the United States since 1914.  That said questions and answers were reported by a stenographer employed by the United States Department of Labor, and subsequently transcribed, and introduced in evidence against complainant in substantiation of the charges contained in the warrant of arrest hereinabove referred to, together with many other questions and answers having no bearing upon and in no manner material to said charges; and that said transcript constitutes the only evidence ever introduced against complainant in substantiation of said charges.  That at no time was complainant questioned as to whether had ever advocated or taught the unlawful destruction of property, or anything else, or even whether he believed in such unlawful destruction, except as above indicated, nor was he questioned about his ability to work and support himself, or about the likelihood of his becoming a public charge at the time of his entry into the United States, or at any other time, except as above indicated; nor was any evidence of any character offered or received upon any of said questions, except as above indicated.</p>
<p>3.</p>
<p>That complainant is now, and ever since the 24th day of April, has been continuously restrained of his liberty in the United States Immigration Detention Station, at Seattle, King County, Washington, by Henry M. White, United States Commissioner of Labor, stationed at Seattle, under the pretended authority of the warrant of arrest issued by the Secretary of Labor, as hereinabove alleged, and not otherwise, and that said restraint is illegal for the following

<pb/>

 reasons, to-wit:</p>
<p>First:   That although approximately seven months have elapsed since the warrant upon which complainant is held in custody, was originally issued, and complainant arrested thereunder, and more than four months have elapsed since the hearing conducted in pursuance of the mandate in said warrant was fully concluded, and although complainant has at no time requested, consented to nor in any manner been responsible for any delay in conducting or concluding said hearing or in deciding the issues presented thereon;  and although nearly thirty days have elapsed since the record of the proceedings on said hearing was finally transmitted to the Secretary of Labor of the United Sates, for his decision and order, still said Secretary has rendered no decision and made no order in said matter and by reason thereof and of the manner in which said hearing was conducted and complainant compelled to testify thereat, against himself, complainant has been restrained of his liberty, without due process of law and deprived of his rights under the provisions of the Fourth Article of the Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</p>
<p>Second:  That on the hearing conducted to inquire into the charges upon which complainant is restrained of his liberty, above referred to, no evidence whatever was introduced, to sustain the charge that complainant had ever advocated or taught or been found advocating or teaching the unlawful destruction of property, or that he was at the time of his entry into the United States, or at any other time, likely to become a public charge, upon which the Secretary of Labor of the United States, could make an order directing that complainant be deported from the United States, or any other order, in any manner restraining complainant of his liberty, and that any warrant or order which said Secretary of Labor might make other than an order discharging complainant from custody, would be arbitrary and void.</p>

<pb/>

<p>4.</p>
<p>That complainant is informed and believes that there are only two copies of the testimony introduced on the hearing of the charges upon which he is restrained of his liberty, and that one of said copies is in the possession of the Secretary of Labor of the United States, at Washington, D.C., and the other in the possession of Henry M. White, Commissioner of Labor and the United States, at Seattle, Washington.  That complainant demanded a copy of said evidence, in order that he might attach the same to this petition, but his demand therefor was refused by said Henry M. White.  That complainant is a common laborer and as a result of his long confinement and the deprivation of his usual means of support, he is unable, by reason of his poverty, to pay for the preparation of such a copy, but deponent is informed by his attorney, and believes that if the said Henry M. White is required to produce the transcript of said evidence, now in his possession, and make the same a part of his return herein, or exhibit the same to the court, the verity of complainant's allegations in relation thereto will clearly appear therefrom.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, complainant prays an order directing the Clerk to issue out of and under the seal of this court, a writ directed to Henry M. White, Commissioner of Labor for the United States, stationed at Seattle, Washington, requiring him to produce the body of complainant in the above entitled court, before the Hon. Jeremiah Neterer, a judge thereof, on the<gap></gap>day of November, 1918, at <gap></gap> o'clock in the <gap></gap> noon, and that he then and there show cause, if any he has, why the complainant should be further restrained of his liberty, and further directing that said Henry M. White also then and there produce, properly authenticated under his seal, copy of the testimony taken at the hearing held pursuant to the mandate of the warrant of arrest issued by the Secretary of Labor, pursuant to which complainant, said Joseph Hansen, that complainant may secure full relief without unnecessary costs, which he can ill afford to pay;  and complainant further prays that Ralph S. Pierce, on of his attorneys, be authorized to serve said writ.</p>

<p>George F. Vanderveer, and Ralph S. Pierce</p>


<p>Joseph Hansen says that he is the complainant in the above entitled cause;  that he has read the foregoing complaint, knows the contents thereof and does solemnly, sincerely and truly declare and affirm that the same is true to his knowledge.</p>

<p>Joseph Hansen</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>