<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-09" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In The Circuit Court of the United States For the State of Washington</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of Charles W. Nordstrom for Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>State of Washington</p>
<p>County of King.</p>

<p>Personally appeared before the undersigned, James Hamilton Lewis, who being duly sworn upon oath deposes
       and says that he is the attorney for Charles W. Nordstrom, and that while the United State Circuit Court was duly
       in session at is regular June term, and particularly July 25th, affiant duly presented to the Honorable C. H. Hanford
       sitting as Judge of the Circuit Court, and while the said Court was duly in session the petition of petitioner praying
       for a writ of habeas corpus upon the ground that he was being restrained of his liberty in violation of the constitution
       of the United States, and did in said petition and in the prayer of said petition move the court and also orally move the
       court for an order  for writ of habeas corpus in behalf of the petitioner and against the said Sheriff of the County to show
       cause at an appropriate time preceding August 23rd addressed to the said Sheriff to show cause why the said writ should
       not issue, and the Honorable Judge of the said Court took the said petition and the said motion under consieration and on
       July 26th, did address to this affiant as counsel for the said Nordstrom that certain communication on the date of July 26th
       declining to issue the writ or any order in the cause</p>

<pb/>

<p>and for the reason that in the opinion of the Honorable Court the petition was without merit and for the other reasons stated
       in the communication in writing, declined to further have to do in any wise whatsoever with the said cause. That thereafter,
       towit: on August 7th the said Honorable Court was petitioned and requested by this affiant for the privilege of filing the petition
       for habeas corpus in the Clerk's Office of the Federal Court, and also to file a letter or communication from the said Judge 
       denying to said petitioner and declining to issue any order thereon. That the Honorabl Judge after said request and petition to
       file said papers consented that the same be done, giving his consent to the filing of both the petition and the said communication
       or letter, or writing declining to issue any writ or to give any further or other order or action in the premises. That affiant stated to the
       Honorable Judge that he desired to file the said letter that he may be as within the Whitten case, take such advantage of the same as
       he might in view of the gravity of the case, being one in which a human being was sentenced to death. That affiant asked the Honorable
       Court he might say to the Clerk that it was with consent of the Court and the Honorable Judge consented that affiant inform the Clerk that 
       such was his consent. That affiant so informed the Clerk, Honorable R. M. Hopkins and his Deputy. That affiant believes that R. M. Hopkins
       ascertaining that the Honorable Judge consented to the filing of said letter for the reason that the Honrable Judge desired to give to the 
       petitioner any benefits that he might derive from the same, and that the said Clerk of the said Court did thereafter when being so informed
       or advised in the premises towit, August 8th duly filed the said letter in said Court along with the said petition. That the Honrable Judge made
       no writen order in the premises, giving to affiant only his verbal statement and verbal assent as therein stated. That on Friday, August 9th,
       the Post-Intelligencer</p>

<pb/>

<p>a leading daily paper of the City of Seattle published what purported to be a statement of the Honorable Judge respecting the filing of said
       letter and said petition, in which the Honrable Judge is represented to have said concernign said letter and the consent to filing of the same
       of the following:</p>

<p>That affiant states upon oath that the statement of the Honorable Judge concerning the same is correct and is a just and proper statement on the
       part of the Court as to what transpired concerning the statement on the part of the Court as to what transpired concerning the filing of said papers;
       and that the statement of the Honorable Judge so quoted is correct and true, and affiant files this affiant herewith in order that no misunderstanding
       at a later time in the cuase or through any of its stages could in anywise arise either through any dispute as to what the Honorable Judge really did
       or as to what this affiant did. That the statement herin included in said paper is all upon the subject that ever transpired between the Honorable Court
       and affiant, and is herein made a part of this affidavit for the purpose of preventing any assumption of any person whomsover or intimation from any source
       whatsoever that anything else was done in any other manner than is herein stated.</p>

<p>James Hamilton Lewis</p>

<p>Subscribed and worn to before me this 12th day of August, 1901.</p>

<p><unclear>Ron Hickins</unclear></p>
<p>Clerk of the U.S. District Court, District of Washington</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>