<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title></title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Yu, Jingming" xml:id="jy">Jingming Yu</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington</title>
<date when="2022-06-20">June 20, 2022</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-08">August 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
                  
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#jy">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0000.000"/>

<p>In the Matter of the Extradition of FLETCHER DECKER.</p>
<p>__________</p>

<p>TRANSCRIPT OF PROCEEDINGS Before Robert W. McClelland, U. S. Commissioner, at Room No. 316 Marion Building, Seattle, Washington, August 24th and 25th, 1921.</p>

<p>_____</p>

<p>APPEARANCES: Miss CHARLOTTE KOLMITZ, Asst. U. S. Attorney, and IVAN L. HYLAND, Esq., (Of Messrs. Tucker &amp; Hyland) For the Petitioner; ADAM BEELER, Esq., (of Messrs. Beeler &amp; Sullivan) appearing for Defendant.</p>

<p>----------</p>


<p>G. H. L. MURRAY,    Being first duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>DIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>By Miss KOLMITZ:</p>

<p>Q    What is your name?</p>
<p>A    George H. L. Murray</p>
<p>Q    Your residence?</p>
<p>A    Seattle.</p>
<p>Q    What is your business or occupation?</p>
<p>A    British <add>Vice</add> Consul at Seattle.</p>
<p>Q    On whose behalf, and under whose authority do you appear here?</p>
<p>A    The Government, at Saskatchewan, Canada.</p>
<p>Q    Where is the Province of Saskatchewan?</p>
<p>A    In Canada.</p>
<p>    Miss. KOLMITZ: That is all. Any questions, Mr. Beeler:</p>
<p>    Mr. BELLER: No.</p>

<p>G. H. L. Murray<!--signed--></p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 26th day of August, 1921.</p>

<p><unclear>A. M. Clellarrd</unclear></p>
<p>U. S. Commissioner</p>

<p>Seal<!--written and circled--></p>


<p>CLAUDE H. FICKLIN,  Being first duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>DIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>By Miss KOLMITZ:</p>

<p>Q    What is your name?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Now at this time, if it please the Court, I desire to object to this proceeding, and object to the introduction of any further testimony herein on these grounds; First, that the warrant of arrest issued by the United States Commissioner fails to show upon its face that the Commissioner was authorized to issue, as required in a proceeding of this kind, any extradition, expressly under the treaty of 1842 between Great Britain adn teh United States, and I have a case directly in point on that objection, and that therefore the warrant of arrest is illegal and void. And, second, object to the introduction of any testimony in this proceeding on the ground that the information and complaint made by F. W. Chard, and which is the basis for this whole proceeding, does not allege facts sufficient to constitute the crime of theft or stealing, as defined by the laws of Canada, and I have the Statute of Canada here to establish that fact. There are a few other objections which I have, but which I do not think should be raised at this time, but which I will raise at the proper time, but I do raise those two at this time.</p>
<p>    (Argument.)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The only question that struck me at the time the warrant was issued, was on the affidavit of Thomas Waters, Deputy Marshal. The question came to my mind; I hadnt much time to look it up, as to whether the affidavit should not have been made by some representative of the British Government of Canada. However, the original complaint was afterwards amended, and that complaint was sworn to by George H. L. Murray, a representative of the British Government; I dont know that it would be necessary to issue a new warrant, an alias warrant, to conform to the ammended complain. I rather take it that the process follows all the pleadings in the case, the original and amended; what do you have to say about that, Mr. Hyland:</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: It seems to me that we have to prove, as a matter of fact in this proceeding, that the extradition is sought by a foreign country, and the original complaint does not show that, as a matter of fact, but the amended complaint does; and I doubt very much whether it is necessary for the complaint to show that, if the proof is shown at the time of th ehearing, that the complaint is sought by a foreign government, and that is the reason for Mr. Murray's testimony here, to supplement and show why the proceeding is brought; it does tno seem to me it makes any difference, whethe rin the original complaint or not, as long as showing is made upon the hearing it was done at teh request of the foreign government.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I dont exactly catch your argument in regard to the insufficiency of the warrant; do you contend that the warrant should show on its face, or allege onits fact the authority of the Commissioner for issuing the warrant?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Exactly so, and this decision is absolutely in point. (Reads decision)</p>
<p>    (Argument)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The question arises, have I a right to amend this, or issue an alias warrant; I don't see the logic of it, but if it is necessary I am willing to do it; I can certify that I am authorized to, but that is a very funny sort of proceeding.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: This is a summary proceeding; it seems to me you would have a right to amend that any way you like; of course, I think that the hearing ought to go ahead just the same.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I have the right, or the Government has the right, or the Government of Canada has the right to amend its complaint; I dont know any reason why the process cannot be amended, or an alias warrant issued and served on the amended complaint; this original warrant was issued on the first complaint. I declare I dont see the logic of those decisions at all. I can put a self serving declaration in here that I am duly authorized to act; that does not establish the fact at all.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: You can say on your warrant you are authorized to do this.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Yes; the very fact I have done it is tantamount to that sort of a statement. I believe I will think about it until after lunch; look up my appointment; I dont want to get anybody into trouble.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I have another point I want to present when we convene, before we proceed with the introduction of evidence.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: It dont have reference to jurisdiction?</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: You content there is no complaint under the laws of Canada?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: That is one of my contentions, yes.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: It seems to me that ought to be a matter of proof; it is established by the complaint and affidavit; whether that is sufficient or not. We will adjourn until 2 o'clock.</p>
<p>    (At this time an adjournment was taken until 2 p. m.)</p>

<p>--------</p>


<p>AFTERNOON SESSION, 2 p. m.</p>
<p>Hearing resumed:</p>

<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I thought I was right, Mr. Beeler; I dont think it is necessary for me to certify that fact, but I have certified it on the bottom of the warrant.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Then shall we read the authorization into the record, so that it will be complete, as well as on the warrant; this transcript of the record will go up, and it may as well be in there.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The warrant goes up with the transcript.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: The authorization of the Commissioner will go up as part of the record. We will read that into the record when the time comes.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Does the record show in what capacity you are appearing for the government?</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: The British Vice Consul.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: For the purpose of the record, I want to object to the changing or amending of the warrant at this time.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Very well.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>