<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0493.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Harry Smith v. United States. Judgment.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Byrd, Samantha." xml:id="slb">Samantha Byrd</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0493.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Harry Smith v. United States. Judgment.</title>
<date when="1916-07-17">July 17, 1916</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1916-07-17">July 17, 1916</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Pitney</term>
<term>Bradley</term>
<term>Lamar</term>
<term>Gilbert</term>
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Smith, Harry</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Slomen, Barney</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, J.G.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Sullivan, J. J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Martin, Winter S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#slb">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
           
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION OF HARRY SMITH FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS No. 3376 </p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION OF BARNEY SLOMEN FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS No. 3375. Filed July 17, 1916.</p>

<p>ON PETITIONS FOR WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS. WRITS GRANTED.</p>

<p>Clay Allen, U.S. District Attorney Winter S. Martin, Assistant U.S. District Attorney For Government.</p>

<p>Beeler &amp; Sullivan, For Defendants.</p>

<p>Netkerer, District Judge:</p>

<p>The defendants were each seperately indicated under Section 8 of the Act of December 17, 1914, Chapter 1, 38 St. at L. 785, 789. The defendant Smith was tried before a jury and convicted March 29, 1916, and on the 31st of March following was sentenced before a jury and convicted on the 23rd of May, 1916, and sentenced to serve five months on the fifth day of June.</p>

<p>On the 5th day of June, 1916, the Supreme Court, Mr. Justice Hughes and Mr. Justice Pitney dissenting, in U.S. v. Jin Fuey Moy held tat persons named in section 0 of the act must be taken to refer only to the class of persons who are required to register by section 1, and that it is not an offense for a person to have these articles in his possession with no intention of vending.</p>

<pb/>

<p>The petitioners contend that the acts charged in the indictment not being in violation of law, the court had no jurisdiction to pronounce judgment, and that the judgment is void, and habeas corpus is the proper remedy.</p>

<p>Mr. Justice Lamar, in Henry v. Henkle, 235 U.S. 219, on page 228, said: "In view, however, of the nature of the writ and of the character of the detention under a warrant, no hard and fast rule has been announced as to how far the court will go in passing upon questions raised in habeas corpus proceedings."</p>

<p>Mr. Justice Bradley, in Ex Parte <unclear>Slebold</unclear>, 100 U.S. 371, at page 376, said: "An unconstitutional law is void and is as no law. An offence created by it is not a crime. A conviction under it is not merely erroneous, but is illegal and void, and cannot be a legal cause of imprisonment. It is true, if no writ of error lies, the judgment may be final, in the sense that there may be no means of reversing it. But personal liberty is of so great moment in the eye of the law that the judgment of an inferior court affecting it is not deemed so conclusive but that, as we have seen, the question of the court's authority to to try and imprison the party may be reviewed on habeas corpus by a superior court or judge having authority to award the writ. We are satisfied that the present is one of the cases in which this court is authorized to take such jurisdiction. We think so, because, if the laws are unconsitutional and void, the Circuit Court acquired no jurisdiction of the causes. Its authority to indict and try the petitioners arose solely upon these laws."</p>

<p>The Circuit Court of Appeals of this Circuit, in Mackey v. Miller, 126 Fed. 160, through Circuit Judge Gilbert, on page 163, said: "Question is made of the power of this court upon habeas corpus to discharge the appellants upon the facts set forth in the record, and it is said that the writ of habeas corpus cannot be used to perform the function of a writ of error. But the doctrine is well established that upon a writ of habeas corpus if it appear that the court that rendered the judgment had not jurisdiction to render it, either because the proceedings under which they were taken were unconstitutional or for any other reason the judgment is void and may be question collaterally, and the person who is imprisoned the reunder may be discharged from custody on habeas corpus. Ex Parte nielsen, 131 U.S. 271; Ex Parte Lange, 18 Wall. 163; Ex Parte Siebold, 100 U.S. 371. If it be true that the acts committed by the appellants which are set forth in the indictment in thiscase are not within the intendment of Section 5447 Rev. Stat. they do not constitute an offense against the statute or against any </p>

<pb/>

<p>other statute of the United States. Such being the case, it appears affirmatively from the return that the appelants are held in custody under a judgment which upon its face is void."</p>

<p>No statute being violated, U.S. v. Jin Fuey Moy, supra, the judgment rendered has no charge upon which to be predicated, and is void. The judgment of conviction as to Slomen, being rendered during the term, is within the control of the court, Bronson v. Schulten, 104 U.S. 410; Phillips v. Negley, 117 U.S. 665, and as to the relief demanded, it is not very material whether it is rendered in this proceeding or on motion in the original case, he should be discharged. In view of the language of Mr. Justice Bradley, In Re Siebold, supra, and of the Circuit Court of Appeals, in Mackey v. Miller, supra, I believe the same order should be made as to Smith, who presents this petition in forma pauperis. He could not present the matter to the Circuity Court of Appeals, and every reasonable doubt as to the court's rights to release him on his petition will continue his wrongful detention, and justice will be best served by restoring his liberty.</p>

<p>Jeremiah Neterer Judge.</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 3375 + 3376</p>

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON Northern Division.</p>

<p>Filed in the U.S. District Court, Western Dist. of Washington, Northern Division JUL 17 1916 FRANK L.C CROSBY, Clerk, Crosby <unclear></unclear></p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>