<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0271.009">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Joseph Walton v. L. C. Smith. Opinion</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Czapla, Ethan P" xml:id="epc">Ethan Czapla</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0271.009</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Joseph Walton v. L. C. Smith. Opinion</title>
<date when="1906-07-09">July 9, 1906</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuits Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno>1376JosephWalton</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1906-07">July 1906</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>McKay, K.</term>
<term>Bergfeldt, Alfred</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Walton, Joseph</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Smith, L. C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Cutte and Dorety</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Mackintosh, Kenneth</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court</orgName>
<placeName>Ninth Judicial Circuit. Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#epc">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>No. 1376</p>

<p>In the Circuit Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</p>

<p>In re Joseph Walton, Petitioner for Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Opinion</p>

<p>Filed in the U.S. Circuit Court, Western Dist. of Washington</p>
<p>FEB 9 1906, A. Reeves Ayres, Clerk.</p>

<p>P. W. N. Hapkins. Dep.</p>

<pb/>

<p>United States Circuit Court Western District of Washington Northern Division</p>

<p>In re Joseph Walton, Petitioner for Writ of Habeas Corpus. No. 1376 Filed July 9th, 1906.</p>

<p>The petitioner being in custody under a warrant for his arrest for violating a statute, claimed a 
       right to be discharged by a federal court, on the ground that, the statute is void, because, it 
       contravenes the fourteenth amendment of the national constitution. Petitioner remanded.</p>

<p>Cutts and Dorety, For Petitioner.</p>
<p>Kenneth McIntosh. Prosecuting Attorney, For respondent.</p>

<p>Hanford, District Judge:

        The object of this proceeding is to obtain a federal court decision condeming, as unconstitutional, a statute
        of this state, approved March 3, 1903, entitled, "An act to prohibit the carrying on the business of barbering
       on Sunday, and provding a penalty for the violation thereof." The first action, only, is material, and it reads as follows:</p>

<p>"Section 1. That it shall be unlawful for any person, persons or corporation to carry on the business of barbering on Sunday."</p>

<p>Laws of Washington, 1903. . 68</p>

<p>The petitioner has been scoused by an affidavit sworn to by one K. McKay before a Justice of the Peace, of the crime of
       "barbering on Sunday" committed as follows:</p>

<p>"Then and there being the said Joseph Walton, in the County of King, state of Washington, on the 31st day of December
       A.D. 1905, the said day being the first day of the week, commonly</p>

<pb/>

<p>known as Sunday, did then and there willfully and unlawfully carry on the business if barbering, contrary to the form of the statute
       in such case made and provided, and against the peace and dignity if the state of Washington."</p>

<p>Upon the accusation made in that form, the Justice of the Peace issued a warrant, pursuant to which the petitioner was taken
       into custody by the Sheriff of King County, and held at the time of suing out a writ of habeas corpus, in this court. The petitioner
       alleges in his petition, and it is not controverted by the return, that barbering is his regular business, and that the act constituting
       the supposed crime of barbering on Sunday was commited by shaving a customer in his, the customer's room, in a hotel. In the
       argument made in his behalf, however, it is admitted that: "On Sunday, December 31st, 1905, petitioner did go to the rooms of guests
       for compensation. It is admitted that he thereby "carried on the business of barbering on Sunday," contrary to the provisions of an act
       of the legislature of the state of Washington." The argument made in the petitioner's behalf affirm two propositions, vis.</p>

<p>a. The act is unconstitutional in so far as it interferes with labor, apart from the opening of shops, in that it forbids one form of labor
       on Sunday, and permits, by not forbidding, all others.</p>

<p>b. Even though restricted, by interpretation, so as to only prohibit the opening if shops for business on Sunday, it would be unconstitutional, 
       in that it discriminates unfairly against a particular business, which is not specially harmful, by reasin of any tendency to disturb the quiet
       of Sunday, or to injure public health or morals.</p>

<pb/>

<p>By a Per Curiam decision, in the case of the State of Washington v. Alfred Bergfeldt, the Supreme Court of this state has decided, in general
       terms, that the statute in question is not unconstitutional. It appears, however, in the report of that decision, that the Supreme Court was not
       required in that case to express an opinon as ti the criminality of labor by a professional barber on Sunday in the homes of customers or in
       the rooms of guests in a hotel.</p>

<p>The statute may, by judicial construction, be so limited in its scope as ti only prohibit the carrying on of the barbering business in an open
       shop or local place of business in Sundays, and thus construed it can only be regarded as a Sunday observance law, consonant with
       a general law of the state requiring all places of business to be closed on Sundays, and the objection to it on the ground that it invidiously
       discriminates against barbers by restricting their right to earn money by labor on days when others may lawfully do so, merely because they
       are barbers, will be eliminated, and its constitutionality can be sustaind in the authority if the decision of the Supreme Court of the United
       States in the case of Petit v. Minnesitam 177 U.S. 164. The restricted construction suggested is justified by the following rules:</p>

<p>"In arriving at the intent of the legislature in enacting a statute, not only must the whole statute and every part of it be considered, but where
       there are several statutes in pori materia they are all, whether referred to or not, to be taken together and one part compared with another in the
       construction if any material provision."</p>

<p>26. Amer. and Eng. Encyc. Law. (2d Ed.) 620</p>

<p>"There is a presumption in favor of the constitutionality of a statute and in accordance therewith, when a statute is suseptible of two constructions,
       one of which supports the act and gives it effect and the other renders it unconstitutional and void, the former will be adopted, even though the latter may
       be the more natural interpretation of the language used."</p>

<pb/>

<p>"A restricted construction of a statute should be adopted where one more broad would bring the statute in conflict with the constitution."</p>

<p>The law has been upheld by a decision of the Supreme Court of the state, and as the objections to it founded upon the Fourteenth Amendment
       to the national Constitution may be avoided by a reasonable construction of its provisions, this court must decide that it is not unconstitutional, and
       also decline to pass upon the question whether, the petitioner is guilty or not guilty under the law thus construed, If, on his trial, the proof fails to
       establish the facts necessary to constitute a violation of the provisions if this statute, which are not in conflict with the constitution of the state, nor
       of the United States, he should be acquitted by the court which has jurisdiction to try him upon a plea of not guilty. If erroneaously convicted
       under the law broadly construed, he can obtain adequate relief from the consequences, by a writ of error from the highest court of the country, and to 
       that tribunal he should resort.</p>

<p>It is the decision of the court that the petitioner should be remanded, and left to defend his rights in the courts of the state and in the Supreme Court
       of the United States, which he can reach, if necessary.</p>

<p>It is conceded that this decision evades proposition in the petitioner's argument, but in taking this course the court is not shirking a duty. The federal
       courts are required to exercise discretion in granting of refusing writs of habeas corpus, petitioned for by defendents prosecuted under the criminal
       laws of the states, and prudence in the exercise of their power is necessary to avoid the intolerable confusion which would neccessarily result from
       their assumption of supervisory control of criminal prosecuations in state tribunals; and for this reason petitioners for write of habeas corpus are usually</p>

<pb/>

<p>remitted to the remedies afforded by the power of appellate tribunals to correct errors in the judgements of courts exercising primary jurisdiction.</p>

<p>It is only when individuals are prosecuted oppresively, under statutes which are clearly repugnant to the national constitution, that the federal courts
       within a state may with propriety interfere, unless, by reason of extraordinary conditions, it i necessary to do so, to prevent rank injustice. They should
       not obstruct judicial proceedings in state courts for the mere purpose of inquiring whether indictments are good or bad, whether the proceedings are
       regular or irregular, or whether defendants are guilty or not guilty.</p>

<p>In re Davenport, 102 Fed. Rep. 540
       Brown v. Urquehart, 139 Fed. Rep. 846.</p>

<p>Inasmuch as this case differs in its facts from all other cases which have been adjudicated, it is expedient for those interested, as the petitioner is,
       to make it a test case, and proceed with it, in the most direct way to the court of final resort. Having deliberately chosen to not submit to the law,
       which is valid to some extent, the petitioner should not complain of unreasonable oppresion, because he is required to pursue the usual course of
       litigation. Petitioner remanded.</p>

<p>C.H. Hanford, Judge</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>