<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0222.011">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Francis Stephen Medcraf vs. Frank T. Hodge. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0222.011</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Francis Stephen Medcraf vs. Frank T. Hodge. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-09">September 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>










</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Francis Stephen Medcraf</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Frank T. Hodge</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>George D. Emery</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Frank P. Helsell</persName>
<persName>Alfred H. Lundin</persName>    
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-04" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN RE APPLICATION OF 
FRANCIS STEPHEN MEDCRAF 
FOR WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS )
No. 3038.
Filed September 23, 1915.</p>
<p>George D. Emery, For Petitioner.</p>
<p>Alfred H. Lundin, Prosecuting Atty. 
Frank P. Helsell Asst. " " ) For State.</p>
<p>NETERER, District Judge:</p>
<p>The petitioner alleges that he is unlawfully detained
and restrained of his liberty by the Sheriff of King County,
Washington, upon a judgment of conviction for violation of the 
provisions of Sections 8412-8425 Remington &amp; Ballinger's Codes
and Statutes of Washington, he was being charged with practicing
dentistry for a fee in the State of Washington, without having
first filed for record and recorded in the office of the Auditor
of the County wherein he then and there practiced, to-wit,
King County, a certificate from the Board of Dental Examiners 
of the State of Washington, authorizing him to so practice as 
provided by law. He alleges that at the age of thirteen he 
was regularly apprenticed to a practicing dentist in London,
England, and served his apprenticeship the full term of five
years; that he "worked as dental assistant" to a surgeon 
dentist at Athens, Greece, for the term of two years, and as 
dental mechanic in the regular study and practice of that profession; 
that he returned to London "for further study and prosecuted
such study in dental surgery for six months" under William
Lombardi, under whom he served his apprenticeship; that in 1896
he was engaged in the office of Dr. Waldo Royce, dentist at 
Tunbridge Wells, England, a graduate of Harvard University, for 
eight months, as general dental assistant; that thereafter he 
was employed by Mr. James Shillcock, at Cannes, France, for five
months; and afterward entered the office of William Lombardi,
<fw>--1--</fw>
<pb/>
at London, and studied and practiced dental surfery for five 
months, and then, at Nice, France, acted as general assistant
and continued in that practice for the term of six months;
and in 1898 served for four months as dental mechanic at Mile 
End Road, London, and then returned to Nice, France, where he 
was employed for seven months in the practice of general 
dental work; and, in 1899, acted as general dental mechanic for 
four months in the office of Isador Clifford, in London, who 
treated "the then Prince of Wales, who is now the King of 
England"; did further assistant dental work in 1900, at Nice,
France, and in 1901 returned to London and opened an office
where he continued the practice of dentistry for two years; and
then, on account of ill health, removed to Alberta, Canada,
where he practiced dentistry for five years, and in February,
1908, removed to Seattle, Washington, "where he has continued
the practice of dentistry undisturbed until the issu<del>e</del> <add>ance</add> of the
warrant of arrest herein complained of." That before beginning
the practice of dentistry in Seattle, Wash. for license 
to practice, <add>he</add> "tendered the legal fee and offered himself for
examination pursuant to law, and in all things complied with 
the requirement of the statutes in such cases made and provided,
save only that he did not present any diploma from any
college of dentistry whatever for the reason that he did not 
possess one and does not now possess any, having obtained his 
profession, learning and skill at the places, by the practice
and study, and in the manner hereinbefore set forth." That the 
State Board of Dental Examiners refused to receive the application
of petitioner, and refused to grant him any licesne; and 
further states that he is qualified to practice dentistry and 
is willing to pay the fees, and sets forth in the petition the
</p>































</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>