<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0372.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Vincenzo Ubaldino v. T.W.Lynch. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0372.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Vincenzo Ubaldino v. T.W.Lynch. Petition</title>
<date when="1921-12-09">December 9, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-12">December 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Ubaldino, Vincenzo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Lynch, T.W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Dore, John F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Frater, John A.</persName>
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-08" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>No. 6440</p>
<p>Petition</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of VINCENZO UBALDINO for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>To the Honorable Jeremiah Neterer, Judge of the above entitled Court:</p>

<p>Your petitioner, Vincenzo Ubaldino, respectfully petitions and shows to your Honor as follows:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That your petitioner is now and at all times for more than ten years last past has been a resident of <add>and domiciled in</add> the Dominion of Canada, and that for the past four years he has been a resident of the City of Vancouver, British Columbia.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>That Luther Weedin, Commissioner of Immigration, is restraining your petitioner of his liberty, and that said restraint is not by virtue of any judgment or order of any court or tribunal, or by virtue of any execution issued upon any judgment or order; that the cause or pretense of said confinement or restraint of your petitioner, according to the best knowledge and belief of said petitioner, is an order of arrest made by the Acting Secretary of Labor, Theodore G. Risley; that said arrest was made by Thomas M. Fisher, Immigra-tion Inspector at Seattle, Washington, on or about the 14th day of April, 1921; that no copies of any warrant or process of any kind was ever served upon your petitioner, and that your petitioner is unable to attach hereto any copy of warrant or process for that reason.</p>

<p>III></p>

<p>That your petitioner further alleges that the cause for issuing such warrant is for the purpose of having your petitioner deported to Italy upon the ground that your petitioner violated the terms and provisions of the Act of February 5, 1917, in that your petitioner is charged, as he is informed, with having knowingly, willfully and unlawfully attempted to return to and enter the United States from foreign territory contiguous to the United States, to-wit the Dominion of Canada, on the 19th day of February, 1921, your petitioner having been arrested and deported from the United States of America to the Dominion of Canada upon a warrant of arrest issued by Louis F. Post, Assistant Secretary of Labor, on the 18th day of October, 1917, upon the ground that your petitioner had procured or attempted to procure or import a woman for immoral purposes, in violation of the Act of Congress approved February 20, 1907, and amended by the Act approved March 26, 1910.</p>

<p>IV.</p>

<p>That during the May Term, 1921, of the United States District Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division, and indictment was returned against your petitioner in violation of Section 4 of the Act of February 5, 1917, and that on June 20, 1921, your petitioner was <add>foudn guilty and</add> sentenced to serve five months in the King County, Washington, jail for said violation, as more fully appears from the records and files of this court in that certain cause numbered <gap></gap>, entitled United States of America, Plaintiff, vs. Vincenzo Ubaldino, alias Vincenzo Ubaldini, Defendant.</p>

<p>V.</p>

<p>That since the expiration of his sentence in the King County jail your petitioner has been restrained of his liberty by the United States Commissioner of Immigration, and your petitioner is informed that said Commissioner of Immigration is restraining him in order to</p>

<pb/>

<p>deport him to Italy.</p>

<p>VI.</p>

<p>That under the Act of Congress of February 5, 1917, your petitioner alleges that the order of deportation hereinafter referred to is arbitrary and unsupported by fact or law.</p>
<p>VII.</p>

<p>Your petitioner further alleges that an order of deportation has been issued against him and, unless this court issues a writ of habeas corpus, said order of deportation will be executed and your petitioner removed from the United States to Italy; that no copy of said order of deportation has ever been delivered to your petitioner, and for that reason your petitioner is unable to attach a copy of said order hereto.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner prays that an order of this court be issued, requiring the said Luther Weedin, Commissioner of Immigration, to appear at a time and place to be designated in said order, and show cause why a writ of habeas corpus should not be issued, and further commanding the said Luther Weedin not to suffer or permit your petitioner to be taken or removed from the City of Seattle upon any pretext whatsoever until the further order of this court.</p>

<p>And your petitioner further prays for such other and further relief as may be meet and proper in the premises.</p>

<p>John F. Dore</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner</p>

<pb/>

<p>United States of America, State of Washington, County of King.</p>

<p>ss.</p>

<p>VINCENZO UBALDINO, being first duly sworn, on oath deposes and says: That he is the petitioner in the above and foregoing petition; that he has <add><unclear>heard</unclear></add> read said application for writ of habeas corpus, knows the contents thereof, and believes the same to be true.</p>

<p>Vincenzo Ubaldino</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me, this 9th day of December, 1921.</p>

<p>FC Reagan</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Dec 10 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>