<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0372.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Vincenzo Ubaldino v. T.W. Lynch. Decision</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0372.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Vincenzo Ubaldino v. T.W. Lynch. Decision</title>
<date when="1921-12-30">December 30, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-12">December 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Canada</term>
<term>Carmina, Italy</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Ubaldino, Vincenzo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Lynch, T.W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Dore, John F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Frater, John A.</persName>
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-08" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the United States District Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>No. 6440.</p>

<p>Decision.</p>

<p>Filed Dec. 30, 1921.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Vincenzo Ubaldino, or Ubaldinno, alias Jose Lombardo. For a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>John F. Dore, Attorney for Petitioner.</p>

<p>Thomas P. Revelle, U.S. Atty, and John A. Frater Asst. U.S. Atty, Attorneys for United States.</p>

<p>NETERER, District Judge, - - - - </p>

<p>The alien is ordered deported to Italy. It is conceded that the petitioner is wrongfully in this country. It is contended that there is no warrant of law in the record authorizing the deportation to Italy. The only testimony in the record with relation to the petitioner's nativity is: "Q. What is your father's name? A. Ubaldino. Q. Where does he live? A. Italy. Q. Whereabouts in Italy? A. Carmina." Examined by his counsel. "Q. You have been living in Canada all of the time? A. Yes. Q. The only countries you have been living in is Canada and the United States. A. That is all."</p>

<p>There is no presumption that Italy is the country from whence the petitioner came, because his father lives there. The record is conclusive that the petitioner was heretofore deported to Canada from the United States; that he came to the United States from Canada from the United States; that he came to the United States from Canada, and lived in Canada for sometime. The Immigration Act Provides that the alien "shall be taken into custody and returned to the country from whence he came." Hence under the testimony the only country to which the petitioner can be deported is Canada.</p>

<p>The practice of the Circuit Court of Appeals of the Second Circuit is to modify the order of Deportation by directing the alien to be returned to the proper country. United States vs. Sisson, 232 Fed. 559.</p>

<pb/>

<p>The order here will be that the warrant of deportation be amended so as to deport the petitioner to Canada instead of to Italy, and unless notice of appeal is given within ten days <del><unclear></unclear> this decision</del> the order of deportation may be considered amended and the petitioner deported to Canada.</p>

<p>Neterer</p>
<p>Judge.</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Dec 30 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>