<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0235.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Leroy Smith v. O.P. Halligan. Sentence and Judgment.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Byrd, Samantha." xml:id="slb">Samantha Byrd</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0235.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Leroy Smith v. O.P. Halligan. Sentence and Judgment.</title>
<date when="1916-05-15">May 15, 1916</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1916-05">May 1916</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Sawtelle, William H. </term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>United States District Court For the District of Arizona</term>
<term>State Penitentiary of the State of New Mexico at Santa Fe</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Smith, Leroy</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Halligan, O.P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Sullivan, John J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Beeler, Adam</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Cushman, Edward E.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States</orgName>
<placeName>District of Arizona</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#slb">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE DISTRICT OF ARIZONA</p>

<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, vs. Leroy Smith Defendant. } May Term, A.D., 1916. May 15th A.D., 1916. PRESENT: Honorable Wm. H. Sawtelle, Judge. <add>267 Tucson</add> No. C Convicted of the crime of violation of the Act of December 17, 1914.</p>

<p>The defendant being present in open Court in person, and <del>by his counsel</del></p>

<p>The United States Attorney for Arizona present on the part of the United States. And this being the time heretofore fixed for passing Judgment on the defendant in this case, the defendant, Leroy Smith was duly informed by the Court of the nature of the Indictment found against him for the crime of violation of the act of December 17, 1914, committed on the 7th day of April, A.D., 1916; of his arraignment and plea of Guiltyas Charged in the Indictment on the 8th day of May, A.D. 1916.</p>

<p>The defendant was then asked if he had any legal cause to show why Judgment should not be pronounced against him; and no sufficient cause being shown or appearing to the Court, thereupon the Court renders its Judgment: That, whereas you LeRoy Smith having been duly convicted in this Court of the crime of violation of the act of December 17th, 1914, it is found by the Court that you are so guilty of said crime.</p>

<p>IT IS THEREFORE ORDERED, ADJUDGED AND DECREED,  and the judgment and sentence of the Court is, that you Leroy Smith be punished by imprisonment in the State Penitentiary of the State of New Mexico at Santa Fe, New Mexico, for a term of One Year and One Day to dat from May 15th, 1916, and, <del>and time you pay a fee of Hundred Dollars ($____) and in default of the payment of said fee</del> that you stand committed.</p>

<p>The defendant was then remanded to the custody of the United States Marshal for said District, to be by him delivered into the custody of the proper officer of said State Penitentiary of the State of New Mexico, at Santa Fe, Ne Mexico.</p>

<p>AND IT IS FURTHER ORDERED, that a certified copy of this judgment shall be sufficient Warrant for the said Marshal to take, keep and safely deliver the said Leroy Smith into the custody of the proper officers of said State Penitentiary of the State of New Mexico at Santa Fe, New Mexico, and a sufficient Warrant for the officers of said State Penitentiary of the State of New Mexico at Santa Fe, New Mexico. to keep and imprison the said Leroy Smith.</p>

<p>WILLIAM H. SAWTELLE, Judge.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>