<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0147.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Gladys Fredrika Fuson v. Territory of Washington. Memorandum Decision</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Hidalgo, Emily" xml:id="eh ">Emily Hidalgo</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0147.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Gladys Fredrika Fuson v. Territory of Washington. Memorandum Decision</title>
<date when="1916">November 2, 1916</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1916-11"></date>November 1916</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Fuson, Gladys Fredrika</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wilson, P.H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Alfred H. Lundin,</persName>
<persName>Frank P. Helsell</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Dykeman, King</persName>
<persName>Cushman, Joseph</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#eh">transcribed and encoded</change>
<change when="2022-02" who="#sjs">reviewed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0147.002"/>

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES,
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION 
OF MRS. GLADYS FREDRIKA FUSON,
FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.} 
NO.3451.
MEMORANDUM DECISION
FILED, Nov. 2, 1916</p>

<p>P.H Wilson, For Petitioner</p>

<p>Alfred H. Lundin, 
Frank P. Helsell,    For Respondent</p>

<p>CUSHMAN, Distorict Judge.</p>

<p> Petitioner, a minor, by her next friend, sues to be 
discharged by writ of habeas corpus, averring that, on October 
20, 1916, she was a resident of Jefferson County, Washington;
that on that date she was arrested withough warrant or information 
and removed to King County, Washington, where she is imprisoned
withought sentence of any competent court; that such imprisonment 
is contrary to the Constitution of the United States; that she is 
a married woman; that her husband has sued her for divorce and
that she belives she is being held to prevent her making her defense
in such suit</p>

<p>By the return it is shown that on October 24, 1916, a 
petition was filed in the Sueprior Court of the State of Washington
for King County, upon a sworn complaint averring that the petitioner 
in the present proceeding was a delinquent child in need
of the care and protection of the court.The return further shows
that, on October 25, 1916, after hearing the evidence upon such

<pb/>

petition, the court found the petitoner in the present cause to 
be a delinquet child, living under conditions jeopardizing her
moral welfare;that her father was dead and the whereabout of 
her mother unknown and ordering that she be, and remain a ward of 
the court in the custody of the county detention home, subject 
to the order of the court. The petition was filed in this court 
October 26, 1916- after the making of the above order.</p>

<p> The validity of the law under which the proceeding in 
question was held is not attacked. It is Chapter 160, Laws of 
1913 (3 Rem. &amp; Bal. Code, Decs.1987-1 to 1987-18). This law 
upheld and a married girl under eighteen held to be subject to 
its provisions, in spite of her marrige, in In re Lundy (82 Wsh,.
148).</p>

<p>Upon the hearing matter mainly complained of was
petitioner's arrest in Jefferson County on the oral order of a 
Judge of the State court of King County and her removal to the 
latter county,</p>

<p>The petitioner having theretofore been in custody as 
a ward of the King County court, discharged from such custody and
the supervision of the court upon her marriage---she still being 
under eighteen---it is not altogether certain, after her return to 
the jurisdiction of the court---even if such return was, as claimed, 
involuntary on her part, which latter fact is denied--- that that,
alone, would deprive the court of jurisdiction to make the order.</p>

<p>The court's process is not confined by county lines and 
if, after her discharge in full, petitioner again became a delinquent 
before going from King to Jefferson County, the want of the 
court's jurisdiction would be so gravely in doubt as to require the 
denial of the writ in any event.</p>

<p> The petition upon which the order of detention was
made avers that the delinquent is a resident of King County. As</p>

<p>-2-</p>

<pb/>

<p>stated above, petitioner avers that, at the time of her arrest
she was a resident of Jefferson County, but that would present a 
question of fact for the State court to determine in passing on
its own jurisdiction.</p>

<p>A writ of habeas corpus is not designed to discharge the 
same functions as a writ of prohibition.</p>

<p>The petition upon which the order of detention was made
further avers that, after petitioner deserted her husband, she had,
in both King and Jefferson Counties, consorted illicity with objectionable 
companions.</p>

<p> Upon the hearing in this court, it was conceded that 
the order of detention made, and under which petitioner is now
held, was of a temporary character--- petitioner having asked for 
a change of Judge to try the question of her alleged delinquency,
which petition for a change of Judge has not yet been acted upon.</p>

<p>Under the foregoing state of the record and conceded facts,
the writ must be denied, as in the orderly administration of justice
and in the exercise of the discretion vested in this court in 
protecting all persons in their rights under the Constitution of 
the United States, the better practice requires that a petitioner
be required to first exhaust all his, or her remedies---at least 
in cases such as the present---by appeal or writ of error in the 
ordinary course.</p>

<p>Bailey on Habeas Corpus,
Secs. 22 &amp; 23;</p>

<p>Ex parte Royakk, 117 
U.S., 241;</p>

<p>In re Lincoln, 202 
U.S., 178.</p>

<p>In In re Fredrick (149 U.S., 70), it was said:-</p>

<p>"But whether this practice in the States of Washington 
is warranted; under a correct constitution of said sec. 
1429 (2 Hill's Ann. Stats. &amp; Code of Wash.) of the code, 
or whether, if it is, that section violates the Fourteenth 
Amendments to the Federal Constitution, in that it operates</p>

<p>-3-</p>

<pb/>

<p>to deprive a defendant whose case is govern by it of 
his liberty withought due process of law, we do not feel
called upon to determine in this case, because we are
of opinion that, for other reasons, the writ of habeas
corpus was properly refused.</p>

<p>"While the writ of habeas corpus is one of the remedies 
for the enforcement of the right to personal freedom, it 
will not issue, as a matter of course, and it should be 
cautiously used by the federal courts in refrence to state
prisoners.******</p>

<p>"We adhere to the views expressed in that case (In re 
Wood 140 U.S., 218, 290). It is certainly the better 
practice, in cases of this kind, to put the prisoner to 
his remedy by writ of error from this court, under section 
709 of Revised Statures, than to award him a 
writ of habeas corpus. For under proceeding by writ 
of error, the validity of the judgment against him can 
be called in question, and the deferal court left in a 
position to correct the wrong, if any, done the petitioner, 
and at the same time leave the state authorities in 
a position to deal with him thereafter, within the limits 
of proper authority, instead of discharging him by habeas 
corpus proceedings, and therby depriving the State of 
the opportunity of asserting further jurisdiction over
his person in respect to the crime whith which he is charged.
(at pp. 75,77, &amp; 78)</p>

<p>The rule is discharged and petitioner remanded to the 
custody of the county detention home of King County, subject to 
the order by which she was therein held at the time the first 
order herein was made.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>