<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0148.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Marie Le Fevre, Yvonne Le Fevre, &amp; Georgette Normand v. M. Angelique. Allegations</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Hidalgo, Emily" xml:id="eh">Emily Hidalgo</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0148.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Marie Le Fevre, Yvonne Le Fevre, &amp; Georgette Normand v. M. Angelique. Allegations</title>
<date when="1903">Febuary 16, 1903</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Lavin, James P.</term>
<term>Cushman, Edward E.</term>
<term>Hopkins, R. M.</term>
<term>Ayres, A. Reeves</term> 
<term>Frye, Jesse A.</term>
<term>Gay, Wilson R.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Republic of France</term>
<term>Victoria, British Columbia</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>LeFevre, Marie</persName>
<persName>LeFevre, Yvonne,</persName>
<persName>Normand, Georgette</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>M. Angelique</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Gill, H. C.</persName>
<persName>Hoyt</persName>
<persName>Frye, Herman S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Cushman, Edward E. </persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, Cornelius H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>District of Washington, Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#eh">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0148.006"/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition
of James P. Lavin, Immigrant Inspector 
and Sister M. Angelique,
Sister Superior of the House of 
thex Good Shepard, for a Writ 
of Certiorari}
No. 1078</p>

<p>Comes now James P. Lavin and Sister M. Angelique, petitioners above
named, by Edward E. Cushman, Assistant United States Attorney, and for
an answer and return to the writ and petition for habeas corpus of 
Yvonne Le Fevre, Marie Le Fevre and Georgette Normand,shows the Court:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That they admit the allegations contained in paragraphs one and two
and deny the allegations of paragraphs three, save as herinafter explained
and qualified</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>They deny the allegations of paragraph four.
For a further return and answer to said petition and writ your
petitioners shows: That prior to the filing of the application for a 
writ of habeas corpus herein you petitioner, James P. Lavin, was and 
still in a revenue officer of the Tresury Department, to-wit, Immigrant
Inspector for the collection district of Puget Sound; that each said
applicants for writ of habeas corpus, to-wit, Yvonne Le Fevre, Marie
Le Fevre and Georgette Normand, is a native citizen of the Republic of 
France: that your petitioner, James P.Lavin, heretofore, in the discharge 
of his duties as such officer, on the 9th day of February, 1903,
temporarily removed said applicats from the steamship Rosalie upon its
arrival in Seattle from the foreign port of Victoria, British Columbia,
from which port it has brought said applicats: that said removal was
for the purpose of determining and investigating whether they were immigrants

<pb/>

and properly entitled to enter the United States, and not for
the purpose of landing them in the United States in any sense; that
thereafter a board of special inquiry was convened of the Treasury officials
and revenue officers, according to law and the regulations of the 
Treasury Department, to determine the eligibility of the above named
applicats to land and enter the United States: that upon such investigation
it was found and determined that said immigrants had within one
year prior thereto been imported into the United States at the port of 
New York from France for the purpose of prostitution: that it was further
found and determined that each one of them was <add>a pauper and</add> liable to become a
public charge: that it was further found that immediatly prior to their 
having been taken from said vessel from such purpose by your petiioner,
James P. Lavin, they had left the United States and gone to Victoria,
British Columbia, from which place they were returning to the United
States when so taken and removed; that upon this state of facts it was
found and determined that they were not lawfully entitled to be in or 
enter the United States and that they should be deported and returned to 
the county to which they belonged and from whence they came: that the
question of whether they be deported to British Columbia of France was 
and still is held under advisement and is in process of determination
by the proper officials of the Treasury Department; that upon the conclusion
of the facts and findings in this case tox the Collector of 
Customs at Port Townsend, and that said report and findings were forwarded
by Collector of Customs upon the 13th day of February, 1903, to 
the Secretary of the Tresury, by whom it will be determined to what
country the applicants should be deported; that pending said final determination 
by the Secretary of the Tresury your petioners, James P.
Lavin and Sister M. Angelique, by his direction and authority as such 
Immigrant Inspector, are for the purpose that these applicants may be 
held to answer the disposition that is made of thier case by the Secretary

-2-

<pb/>

of the Treasury, held and restrained of their liberty, and not 
otherwise; that they are so held and retrained at the express direction
and by the express warrant of the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>

<p>Wherefore, your petitioners pray that the writ of habeas corpus be 
denied, and that the applicants be remanded to their custody.</p>

<p>Edward E Cushman
Assistant United States Attorney</p>

<p>United States of America
District of Washington} ss</p>

<p>James P Lavin by facts does
sworn on oath say he is one of the 
petitioner above named and he
has read the foregoing <unclear></unclear> and 
<unclear></unclear> knows its contents <unclear>thereof</unclear>
and that the same is true</p>

<p>James P. Lavin</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before
me the 15th of Feb 1903</p>

<p>R M Hopkins
Clerk of the U.S. District Court,
District of Washington</p>

<figure></figure>

<p>-3-</p>

<pb/>

<p>Due and full service of within <gap></gap>
acknowledge this <gap></gap>day 
of, 189
Attorney for <gap></gap></p>

<p>TX</p>

<p>FORM NO.499
NO.1078</p>

<p>IN THE Circiut COURT
OF THE UNITED STATES 
FOR THE 
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
Northern Division.</p>

<p><del>THE UNITED STATES
VS.</del>

In re petition Lavin et al 
for Certiorari etc.</p>

<p>Anwer of US.</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U.S.Circuit Court,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
FEB 16 1903
A. REVES AYRES Clerkf
RM Hspkins Dep
Jesse A. Frye</p>

<p><del>WILSON R. GAY,</del>
UNITED STATES ATTORNEY,
SEATTLE, WASHINGTON.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>