<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0116.005"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Wiley v. Keokuk. Opinion</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0116.005</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Wiley v. Keokuk. Opinion</title>
<date when="1870-05-10">May 10, 1870</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1870-05">May 1870</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fowler, E.B.</term>
<term>Keokuk, Moses</term>
<term>Wiley, Albert</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term/>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Wiley, Albert</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Keokuk, Moses</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Christian, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Last, First</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Kingman, C.F.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> 
<placeName>Douglas County, Kansas</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="sab">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0116.005"/> 

<p>Be it remembered, that heretofore, to wit, on the 19th day of August A.D. 1869 Albert Wiley one of the Defendants in the case of Keokuk Chief of the Sac &amp; Fox Indians – against Charles E. Mix et al</p>

<p>filed in the office of the Clerk of the District Court of Douglas County his certain made case for the Supreme Court against Keokuk which said made case is in words as follows</p>

<p>Viz<lb/>
Keokuk Chief of the Sac &amp; Fox Indians<lb/>
against<lb/>
Charles E. Mix, Thomas<lb/>
Murphy, Albert Wiley<lb/>
Thomas Dorwin &amp;<lb/>
William P. Montogery Defts } 
<lb/>
Civil Action</p>

<p>In the District Court of Douglas Co. Kan.</p>

<p>The said plaintiff on the 19th day of December A.D. 1869 filed in office of the clerk of said District Court his petition the body of which is as follows.</p>

<p>The said Keokuk plaintiff complains of the said defendants Charles E. Mix Thomas Muphy, Albert Wiley Thomas Dorwin and William P. Montgomery for that at the said defendants on the 23rd day of November

<pb/>


A.D. 1868 at Lawrence in the County of Douglas unlawfully and with force assaulted the said plaintiff and beat bruised wounded and ill treated him and them and there imprisoned him and kept and detained him in prison in the county jail of Douglas County amongst a lot of theives until other vile characters without any reasonable or probable cause whatever for the space of one night and two days next following and other things then and there did to the said plaintiff to the damage of the said plaintiff Ten Thousand dollars. Wherefore the said plaintiff prays judgment against the said defendants for the sum of Ten Thousand dollars ($10.000) his damages so aforesaid sustained.</p>

<p>In the 15th day of February AD 1849 the defendant Albert Wiley filed his answer in said case the body of which answer is as follows.</p>

<p>1st def. And now comes the said Albert Wiley one of said defendants and from separate answer to the


<pb/>

<fw>2</fw>

plaintiff petition says that he denies each and very allegation there contained.</p>

<p>2d def. And the said defendant for a second defense to the plaintiff petition says that on and prior to the 23d day of November AD 1868 he was the United States Indian Agent for the Sac &amp; Fox Indians in the State of Kansas and for a long time previous thereto be had <unclear>acted</unclear> as such; That the said plaintiff is one of the Indians of said tribes and pretends to be a chief of said Indians and on the 23d day of November AD 1868 and for a long time previous thereto resided on the lands of said tribes in the county of Franklin in the state of Kansas.</p>

<p>That on or about the 21st day of October AD 1868 this defendant as such Indian Agent received from the said Thomas Murphy who then was the United States superintendent of Indian affairs in the state of Kansas an order of which a copy is hereto attached marked "A" and make a part of

<pb/>

this answer. This defendant further says that with said order he received a copy of an order given by Charles E. Mix who was then the acting commissioner of Indian affairs for the United States which order is dated October 16th AD 1868 a copy of said order is hereto attached marked "B" and made a part of this answer. That by the terms of said orders this defendant as such Indian Agent was required to prevent any Indians of said Tribes visiting Washington D.C. and was required by the order of said Murphy to notify said Murphy if any Indians of said Tribes intended visiting said city of Washington.</p>

<p>That on or about the 16th day of November AD 1868 this defendant caused the above mentioned orders to be read to the plaintiff and other Indians of said Tribes. That on or about the 19th day of November AD 1868 ths defendant informed Thomas Murphy that said plaintiff with others contemplated visiting the city of Washington in violation

<pb/>


of the order of the said Charles E Mix above mentioned, and the said Murphy <unclear/> as such superintendant of Indian affairs did then order and require this defendant in case said plaintiff should leave the Reserve of said Indians in said county of Franklin for the purpose of going to Washington is cause him to be arrested and put in jail or returned to his Reservation.</p>

<p>That on or about the 22d day of November AD 1868 this defendant was informed that said plaintiff with others had left said Reserve in said county of Franklin and was then in the city> of Lawrence Douglas County Kansas on his way to the city of Washington D.C., in violation of said order above mentioned. That this defendant on said day went before Hon. William P. Montgomery who then was the United States commissioner for the District and State of Kansas and made an affidavit in writing a copy of which is hereto attached marked "C" and made a part of this answer and that on the same day he gave his testimony

<pb/>

as a witness on the reading of said complaint <unclear/> said commission against the said plaintiff. That the above is a full statement of all that this defendant had to do with said plaintiff or the arrest assault or imprisonment of the said plaintiff.</p>

<p>That this defendant did not arrest touch or imprison said plaintiff, or in any manner interfere with him, and all he did do in the provisions was strictly in accordance with the instructions and orders he had received as above mentioned and which this defendant as an officer of the United States was bound by law to obey.</p>

<p>Wherefore this defendant asks judgment against the said plaintiff for his costs and that said suit as against him may be dismissed.</p>

<p>Copy of Order mentioned in the aforesaid answer marked "A" and made a part of the same.</p>

<p>Office Supt Indian affairs Atchison Kansas Oct 23d 1868</p>

<p>Sir. I transmit herewith for

<pb/>
<fw>3</fw>


your information and Government a copy of a letter of the 16th inst from Hon Charles E Mix actg commission. You will do all in your power to have the instructions of the actg Commission carried out and should any delegation from our tribe contemplate visiting Washington without special instructions given the Department you would promptly advise this office very Respectfully</p>

<p>Thomas Murphy actively U.S. Indian Agent Sac &amp; Fox agency Kansas.</p>

<p>Copy of Order mentioned in said answer marked B and made a part thereof.</p>

<p>Department of the Interior, office of Indian affairs Washington D.C.</p>

<p>Oct 16th 1868</p>
<p>Sir, I <unclear>have</unclear> to answer you that as Congress failed is make certain appropriations from which the <unclear>expenses</unclear> of delegations of Indians visiting this City have heretofore been paid. No delegation from any of the Tribes in your superintendency

<pb/>

will be allowed to visit this place during the present fiscal year unless specially directed to do so by this office for the reason that there are no funds at the disposal of the Department that can be used to defray their necessary expenses. You will inform the different agents under you of the foregoing and take <unclear></unclear> prevent any Indians coming here as may be necessary to accomplish the <unclear/>.</p>
<p>Very Respectfully<lb/>
Thomas Murphy <lb/>
Dept Ind Affairs<lb/>
Atchison Kansas}<lb/>
Charles E. Mix actg Comission</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
