<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>United States District Court
Western District of Washington
Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Ching Hing for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus } No. 2857
Memorandum Brief.</p>
<p>Statement of Facts.</p>
<p>In this case the sole reason for granting the Writ
of Habeas Corpus was that neither the Secretary of Labor
nor his Assistant reviewed the decision of the Commissioner
of Immigration, Henry M. White.</p>
<p>At the first hearing the petitioner asked that the
case be continued to take the deposition of the Secretary
of Labor and his Assistant in Washington, D.C., and the
Court issued an order granting a commission to take the
depositions. Before the depositions were returned the
Secretary of Labor himself reviewed the decision of Comissioner
White and affirmed it, and thereupon the respondent
moved the Court to cancel the order to take depositions
in Washington, on the ground that the depositiion
were made useless by the proper authorities rectifying the
alleged injustice done to the petitioner.</p>
<p>Law and Argument</p>
<p>The statute on this subject provides as follows:</p>
<p>"In every case where an alien is excluded from admission
into the United States under any law or
treaty now existing, or hereafter made, the decision
of the appropriate customs or immigration
officer, if adverse to the admission of such alien, 
shall be final, unless reversed on appeal to the
secretary of the treasury. 28 Stat. 390"</p>
<pb/>
<p>It seems to us that the statute settles the law, because
Commissioner White's decision is final unless reversed.
Even if the wrong oficers affirmed Commissioner
White's decision, the Court could not say that he was reversed,
but if the Court should take the view adopted by
Judge Dooling, and by the courtesy of Mr. Sulliven, filed
in this action, that the Secretary of Labor or his Assistant
must review the appeal, it seems to us that the Court
will follow the Judge along through and adopt the very
equitable course which he pursued.</p>
<p>It will be observed that though the Judge held that
the Secretary or his Assistant should review the case when
present in the office, he stated (page 4 of decision) -</p>
<p>"This being the first time that this question has
been presented to the court, the petitioners were
not discharged, but it was ordered that their deportation
be stayed until their appeal had been
heard and determined by competent authority, and
if such appeal was not so heard and determined
within fifteen days from October 5th, 1914, that 
they might apply to the court for further relief."</p>
<p>And even though the Department did not conform to the very
equitable decision of the Judge, yet he still refused to 
release the alien, and said that the case was still pending
on appeal at Washington, and the Court said (page 6 of
decision)-</p>
<p>"But it does not follow from this that the petitioners
here are entitled to an absolute discharge. As said
by Judge Gilbert in the case of Way Tai, 96 Fed. 484:</p>
<p>'If the Assistant Secretary had not the authority to
hear and determine the appeal, the appeal has not been
disposed of, but is still pending, and the detention
of the petitioner by the officer to whom he was intrusted
until the dispostition of his case on appeal is
not unlawful.'</p>
<p>The Department, however, while still holding the
petitioners in custody for deportation, is apparaently
indisposed to have the appeal heard by any one whom
<fw>(2)</fw>
<pb/>
the court believes to be authorized to hear it. The
Court is not disposed to land these aliens when the
local officers have decided against their right to
land, and while in the language of Judge Gilbert above 
quoted their appeal is still pending."</p>
<p>The Court will find the quotation from the Way Tai
case, made by Judge Dooling, in 96 Fed. 486, near the bottom
of the page, and will see that that decision absolutely
upholds Judge Dooling.</p>
<p>We submit that there is no distinction between that
case and this. We are not endeavoring to play fast and
loose with this Court. A petition for habeas corpus determines
whether or not the petitioner is in the legal 
custody of the Immigration authorities. This does not
suspend the appeal. It leaves the case of the Chinaman
in status quo and if the Immigration authorities desire
to make further orders therein they can do so. There is
no injunction by the court to stop them.</p>
<p>In this case the authorities at Washington evidently
decided that Judge Dooling might be right and they would
not contest the point, and so they said we will get the
proper man to review this case and rectify the alleged
injustices done to the petitioner.</p>
<p>We do not see why this Court should wait until the
depostitions come back from Washington and the determine
whether or not the Secretary of Labor or his Assistant
should hear the appeal, and then if he should rule that
the Secretary or his Assistant should hear the appeal, continue
the case as Judge Dooling did for fifteen or thirty
days until said Secretary or Assistant could give exactly
the same decision which we are offering in evidence.</p>
<p>The point we make is that by the action of the Secretary
<fw>(3)</fw>
<pb/>
of Labor in deciding this case in person, all the questions
raised in the petition are moot questions, and we are familiar
enough with the amount of work which this Court is
compeeled to perform to know that he will not decide any
question unless absolutely necessary to a fair decision
of the case.</p>
<p>Objection That Record Not At Washington
When Secretary Reviewed Decision.</p>
<p>It was strenously argued by the attorney on the other
side that the Secretary of Commerce and Labor could not 
have considered this case on appeal because we had the 
original record filed and made an exhibit in this cause.</p>
<p>The practice in these cases is that the Immigration
office makes out a duplicate record, the original and the
copy both being considered orginals by the Department.
When we make the record a part of our return we always use
what would be a carbon copy, according to state practice,
but what according to the Immigration office is considered
one of the originals.</p>
<p>In this case we used the carbon copy which was at
Commissioner White's office, adn the original of this
carbon wass in Washington. If the Court thinks it necessary
we can call this a copy and we will ask the Court that
we may amend our Return by inserting between the words
"that" and "the record" in line 15, on page 2, the words
"a copy of."</p>
<p>The Court will see that this is the case by reading
the second paragraph in the letter on page 48 of the
record which is as follows:</p>
<p>"As this case was decided upon the record as submitted
by you, and as you have been furnished a copy of the
<fw>(4)</fw>
<pb/>
Bureau's memorandum which was approved by the 
Department, it is not considered necessary to
forward you the record certified by the Department.
You can use your own copy in making return 
to the writ."</p>
<p>And also by the words occuring in the decision offered
in evidence by the governmnet as exhibit "B" in the following
language:</p>
<p>"It is believed that the inclosed will serve your
purpose, without withdrawing from the Bureau's
files the entire record, of which you already
possess a complete copy with the exception of
the notation on the memorandum of the Secretary's 
approval."</p>
<p>This habeas corpus proceedings is not an appeal. It is
merely to determine whether this Chinaman is properly held.
Until Commissioner White is reversed by the Secretary of
Labor one of two things is true, either that Commissioner
White's decision is still in force and no one can interfere
with it until it is reversed and properly by appeal, or
this case is pending on appeal before the Department in 
Washington and is awaiting the decision of the proper official
in order to sustain the petition. The petition has
to establish in direct language and by inference that the
Chinaman and the Chinaman's case is within the power and
jurisdiction and authority of the Immigration authorities,
otherwise he could not make them respondents to his action;
so the very petition itself says that we still have jurisdiction;
that the matter is still pending before us, and
there is no injunction, execution or order of a court of
record suspending the action of the Immigration authorities.</p>
<p>We believe that this answers all of the points raised
by opposing counsel, and respectfully submit that the petition
should be dismissed and the alien remanded to the
proper authorities.</p>
<ab>GP Fishburne
Assistant United States Attorney</ab>
<pb/>
<p>No. <del>2875</del> 2857</p>
<p>In the District Court
of the United States
for the
Western District of Washington</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Ching Hing 
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>
<p>Memorandum Brief.</p>
<p>Filed in the
U.S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington
Northern Division
APR 27 1915
Frank L. Crosby
By EML Deputy
2x</p>
<pb/>
<p>Recieved a copy of the within
Brief this
28 day of April 1915
Beeler &amp; Sullivan
Attorney for Petitioner</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>