<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0221.018">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chin Quock Wah vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0221.018</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Chin Quock Wah vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<date></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Beeler, Adam</term>    
<term>Chin, Quock Wah</term>
<term>Chin, Wing Hin</term>
<term>Conner</term>
<term>Lew, Ah Jung</term>
<term>McGettrick, Felix W.</term>
<term>Miller</term>
<term>Morton</term>
<term>Senter, John H.</term>
<term>Sullivan, John J.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>China</term>
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
<term>Boston, Massachusetts</term>
<term>Richford, Vermont</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Chin Quock Wah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Adam Beeler</persName>
<persName>John J. Sullivan</persName>    
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-03" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT, IN AND FOR THE WESTERN 
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the 
Application of CHIN QUOCK WAH, for 
a Writ of Habeas Corpus. )
No 2971
MEMORANDUM BRIEF.</p>

<p>This was an application by Chin Quock Wah, through his 
attorneys, Beeler &amp; Sullivan, for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, asking
that he be discharged,on the grounds that he was illegally detained
by the Commissioner of Immigration; that he had applied for admission
at the Port of Seattle, and was denied the same on the ground that he 
was not illegally entitled to be admitted therein. The petitioner set 
up his grounds that he was being deprived of his liberty without due
process of Law, and without being given a fair hearing; and among
other things, that he was not allowed to consult counsel, or was he 
advised of his right to have counsel; that he was further denied the 
right to have withness for and in his behalf, or was he advised of 
his right to have witnesses appear for and in his behalf; and that he 
was denied the right to face his witnesses; and further that he was
the minor son of an American citizen, and being so, to deny him the 
right to enter, deprives him of his liberty without due process of 
Lawand in violation of the Constitution of the United States.</p>
<p>The evidence in the case shows that Wing Hin, the father 
of the detained alien, was born in San Francisco, in or about the year
1877. He later went to China and returned to the United States in 
July, 1896, by way of Richford, Vt. On July 8th of the same year, he 
was detained on a deportation proceeding, and a hearing was had before 
Felix W. McGettrick, United States Commissioner for the District of 
Vermont. The Complaint was signed by John H. Senter, United States
Attorney for said District, and upon a hearing on July 9th, 1906, he 
was discharged, and a certificate issued which will be found in the 
record of this case, in Exhibit No. 29142, said certificate being the 
judicial finding of said United States Commissioner that Wing Hin, the 
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
father of your petitioner Chin Quock Wah, was a citizen of the United
States. And I respectfully ask your Honor to examine the Seattle
record 29142 covering the admission of Chin Wing Hin, or Wing Hin, 
as the record shows he is sometimes called, the father of Chin Quock 
Wah, when he arrived in Seattle from a visit to China, on January 
20th, 1914, at which time the question of the right of the father of 
your petitioner to enter was examined, and his status them made, which 
said record was made a part of this present case, and should be in the 
files and examined by your Honor in arriving at a proper decision of 
this case. In that record, as well as in the record here, your Honor
can easily discern the identity of your petitioner as being the minor
son of Chin Wing Hin, his father, who is a merchant in Boston and a 
citizen of the United States.</p>
<p>Taking up the questions in order, I will first present to 
your Honor the question of not being advised of the right to have
counsel or of facing his witnesses. If your Honor will examine the
record in this case, you will find that after a preliminary hearing
and a first hearing had occurred, upon receiving advice from one of 
the Inspectors in Boston, the local Inspectors arbitrarily examined 
your petitioner at the Seattle Immigration Station, and then and there 
without giving him the right to have counsel, proceeded to obtain from 
him such information as they saw fit in order that they might entangle
him in making contrary statements. This, in my opinion, is entirely 
in violation of Law and of the rights of a detained as set down by 
custom procedure, or on any construction of a fair hearing. I will 
grant that the Law provides that, preliminary to admission at the 
preliminary hearing touching the right of the alleged alien to admission, 
there need be no counsel; but after asking the detained if he 
wished counsel, to then want a further hearing and not grant him that
priviledge, then that is not a fair hearing, in my humble opinion.</p>
<p>Touching the question of the identity of the son: It seems
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
to me that there is no question that your petitioner is the son of 
Chin Wing Hin, and this Court is not going to lend itself to sanction 
any arbitrary finding that he is not, unless it be supported by 
evidence, which the record in this case does not show.</p>
<p>Therefore, we reach the question as to the legal effect 
of the McGettrick certificate granting the father of your petitioner
the right to enter in 1896 as an American citizen; for the statutes
granting the Secretary of Labor to reply only when there be evidence
showing that it is legal and proper under the existing Law, and it 
would be arbitrarily considered and sanctioned by the Court in the 
case of th ex-parte Lam Pui, 217 Federal, page 462. In the same case, 
Mr. Justice Conner, in determining the legal effect of a certificate , 
though it be a different certificate than the one in question, calls 
for the same kind of conclusion, states "While this certificate may 
be overcome by proper evidence and may not have the effect of a 
judicial determination, yet being made in conformity to the treaty, and 
upon it the Chinaman having been duly admitted to a residence in this 
country, he can not be deported, unless there is some competent 
evidence which would overcome the legal effect of the certificate". So 
in this case, in relation to this McGettrick certificate, unless there
is some competent evidence to show fraud or to overcome the legal
effect of it, I earnestly content that it is res judicata. As to the 
identity and statutes of the father of this petitioner as an American 
citizen, Mr. Justice Conner in the same case quotes abundant authorities, 
some of which are as follows:</p>
    <p>This ruling is abundantly sustained by the words of Mr. Justice
    Holmes in Chin Yow v. United States, 208 U. S. 8,28 Sup. Ct. 201, 58
    L. Ed. 369, and other cases cited in the opinion.</p>
    <p>In United States v. Redfern (D. C.) 210 Fed. 548, Foster, 
    District Judge, says:</p>
    <p>"Congress has, indeed, vested the immigration officers with 
    enormous power, subject to no check save their own consciences; but in 
    granting them discretion to arrest and deport any person charged with 
    being an alien and unlawfully in the country, I cannot believe that 
    it was ever intended that they could do so arbitrarily, and without
    some evidence upon which to base their decision".</p>
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
    <p>In United States v. Quan Wah (D. C.) 214 Fed. 462, Chatfield, 
    District Judge, Says:</p>
    <p>"Nor can the fact that the burden of proof to show right to be 
    in the United States is thrown upon the Chinaman necessitate his 
    further showing that the action of the authorities who decided he had 
    the right to enter was correct, unless the evidence shows that his 
    entry was fraudently obtained. - - - The decision of his right to 
    enter was presumptively correct, and unless the United States shows 
    persuasively to the contrary, the mere certificate of admission is 
    sufficient"</p>
    <p>In United States v. Williams, 200 Fed. 538 C. C. A. 632
    (C. C. A., 2nd Circuit) Judge Noyes wrote the opinion for the court.
    Judges Cox and Ward, thinking that their views upon this point were 
    not expressed clearly, concurring, said:</p>
    <p>"The opinion does not, however, make entirely clear our views
    upon a single point. We think that some evidence must be presented to 
    justify a judgment of deportation and that conclusions of law must
    have some facts upon which to rest. The immigrant may, in a sense, 
    have a fair hearing, although the conclusions drawn by the executive 
    officers be wholly unsupported by proof".</p>
    <p>Text-writers and judges have undertaken to define the word
    "evidence", as applicable to judicial investigation, with more or less 
    success. Probably no more satisfactory definition is found, for 
    practical purposes, than that given by Mr. Edward Livingstone:</p>
    <p>"Evidence is that which brings to the mind a just conviction of 
    the truth or falsehood of any substantive proposition which is asserted
    or denied"</p>
    <p>It is elementary that in judicial proceedings the question
    whether the record discloses any evidence is for the court. The weight
    to be given evidence is for the trier of the issue of fact. It is 
    also elementary that mere suspicion, conjecture, speculation, is not 
    evidence, neither can it be made the basis for finding a fact in the issue.
    The industry of counsel affords a number of illustrative expressions
    of courts. In People v. Van Zile, 143 N. Y. 372, 38 N. E. 381, 
    Andrews, Chief Justice, says:</p>
    <p>"Suspicion cannot give probative force to testimony which in 
    itself is insufficient to establish or to justify an inference of a 
    particular fact."</p>
    <p>Judge Caldwell, in Boyd v. Glucklich, 116 Fed. 131, 53 C. C. A. 
    451, well says:</p>
    <p>"The sea of suspicion has no shore, and the court <add>that</add> embarks upon
    it is without rudder or compass."</p>
<p>Having then, I think, established to your Honor's 
satisfaction, under the decisions of our Courts, the effect of said 
McGettrick certificate, unless fraud was shown which was not done in this 
case, I present to your Honor the case of Leung Jun v. the United 
States, 171 Fed. 413, where it was held that upon a hearing before 
the United States Commissioner, the petitioner, a Chinese person, 
presented a judgment of discharge by a United States Commissioner, 
and the only question presented was whether such judgment of discharge
construed conclusive ajudicatum of the Chinaman's right to remain in
<fw>-4-</fw>
<pb/>
the United States, and the entire Court held that it did, and ordered
the petitioner discharged.</p>
<p>This decision was followed by Mr. Justice Morton of the 
United States District Court for the District of Massachusetts on 
January 19th, 1915, in the case of Lew Ah Jung. The evidence in this 
case was as follows: Jung, the petitioner, was arrested on deportation
proceedings on the ground that he was in this country unlawfully.
The evidence showed that he was born in San Francisco about the year 
1884; that he went on a visit to China, and returned to the United 
States in 1897 by way of Richford, Vt. He was there arrested where 
hsi right to enter was questioned. His case was heard before Felix 
W. McGettrick, the United States Commissioner in Vermont, who, after
his statutes had been fixed, and the certificate being in conformity 
with Law. I respectfully ask your Honor to examine this decision 
which you will find enclosed in an envelope in the files of this case, 
bearing the seal of the Massachusetts District Court. As before stated, 
this certificate showing the status of the father of your 
petitioner, is before your Honor being a part of the files and record, and 
is the same kind of a certificate as was in the case decided by Mr. 
Justice Morton.</p>
<p>After examining the entire record and the authorities 
herein cited, I feel certain that your Honor will hold that as a matter 
of Law that the son's status was fixed by his father's status,
and that the son should be admitted to land, as being the son of an
American citizen. For, as suggested by Mr. Justice Miller in the 
slaughter-house cases, 16 Wall. 36: "Another privilege of a citizen
of the United States is to demand the care and protection of the 
Federal Government over his life, liberty and property when on the high 
seas, or within the jurisdiction of a Foreign Government."
<fw>-5-</fw>
<pb/>
And why, then also, should not your Honor grant to this minor son of 
an American citizen, even though he be of a different color than most 
citizens, the strong arm of your Court to give unto him the equal
rights and privileges which are accorded by the Constitution to all 
citizens; and instead of separating this young man from his father, 
allow him to be discharged and to proceed to join his father, who, as 
the record shows, has ample means,and intends,as expressed by him, to 
educate this young man and accord to him the benefits which every son 
has a right to expect from his father.</p>
<p>I feel certain that the construction of Law prepared by 
the learned counsel for the Government, does not apply in this case,
and that the petitioner should be discharged forthwith.</p>
<p>Respectfully submitted,</p>
<ab>Beeler Sullivan
Attorneys for Petitioner</ab>

<fw>-6-</fw>
<pb/>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>