<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the United States District Court, In and For the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Ching Hing, for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus. } No. 2857
Further Amended Petition
of Ching Hing, by and through
his attorney, John J. Sullivan</p>
<p>Comes now John J. Sullivan, as attorney for and in behalf
of Ching Hing, an alien, a subject of the Emperor of China,
and a son of Chin Shew, merchant of New York City, and respectfully
makes this application for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, and
alleges as follows:</p>
<p>I.
That said Ching Hing is imprisoned and restrained of
his liberty by the United States Commissioner of Immigration,
White, and the United States Chinese Inspector, Henry Monroe, or 
by person or persons acting through, by or under them, and that
said Ching Hing is imprisoned at the Detention House at the
Immigration Station, in the City of Seattle, under the charge that
the said Ching Hing had no lawful right to be admitted into the
United States, and that he should be deported according to law,
and your Petitioner further informs the Honorable Court that
said imprisonment, confinement, and restraint and Order of Deportation
is illegal and arises form the following facts, to-wit:
That Ching Hing arrived at the port of Seattle on a voyage from
China on the 5th day of August, 1914, and said Ching Hing was
denied admittance into the United States on the ground that he
was not legally entitled to be admitted therein; that said Ching
Hing was given a hearing by the Immigration Officials and upon
evidence being presented on August 27th, 1914, an order was issued
by the Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, finding that said
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
Ching Hing was not entitled to admission to the United States and
that he should be deported; that an appeal was given by said Ching
Hing, through his attorneys Stadden &amp; Stewart, of Washhington, D.
C., to the Secretary of Labor, and that on September 26th, 1914,
the said Order of Deportation and said Finding of Commissioner of
Immigration of Seattle, Washington, was affirmed and said Ching
Hing ordered deported.</p>
<p>II.
This Petitioner is informed and believes and so states
the fact to be that said Commissioner of Immigration White, in
charge of the District of Washington, and said Chinese Inspector
Henry Monroe, or officials or agents acting by, under or through 
them, or for the United States Government, are about to deport and
return the said Ching Hing to China, in violation of the treaty
relations between the United States and China, and in violation
of the laws and statutes of the United States relating to the
Chinese Exclusion Act, and in violation of the laws relating to
the acts and powers of the Secretary of Labor and the Assistant
Secretary of Labor, in that said Ching Hing is being deprived of
his liberty without due process of law and without being given a 
fair hearing by said Commissioner of Immigration White, and said
Chinese Inspector, Henry Monroe, or officials acting by, under or
through them or for the United States Government.</p>
<p>III. 
Your petitioner further alleges that the right of appeal
from said Finding of Commissioner of Immigration White and Chinese
Insepctor Henry Monroe, or officials acting by, under or through
them or for the United States Government in and for the District of
Washington, by the statutes in such cases made and provided for in
relation to the Chinese Exclusion Laws, has violated and that
his full rights have not been accorded to your Petitioner Ching
Hing in this: That W.B. Wilson is the Secretary of Labor and that
Louis Post is his only assistant Secretary of Labor; that both of
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
said officials, as your Petitioner alleges upon information and
belief, and knows to be the fact, were at their respective offices
in the capitol at Washington, doing the duties imposed upon them
on the day that the said appeal of Ching Hing was considered, and
that upon said day and at said time that the appeal of the said
Ching Hing to the Secretary of Labor, from the decision denying
the right of entry to the United States of Ching Hin, came up for
hearing and consideration, that said Secretary of Labor or Assistant
Secretary of Labor, under the statutes, should have considered
and determined the said appeal of Ching Hing from the said adverse 
decision of the Commissioner of Immigration and Chinese Inspector
Henry Monroe, but that said Secretary of Labor and Assistant
Secretary of Labor failed, neglected or refused so to do, and
hence the said Ching Hing has been denied his right of appeal.</p>
<p>IV.
Your Petitioner further alleges that one J.B. Denamore
is the Solicitor of the Department of Labor, and further alleges
that said J.B. Densmore attempted to perform the duties of the
Secretary of Labor or Assistant Secretary of Labor while they were
present in their respective offices, and the order of the President
of the United States, with due respect thereto, does not authorize
said J.B. Denamore, or such Solicitor of the Department of Labor
to perform the duties of the Secretary of Labor or the Assistant
Secretary of Labor during the presence of said officials then and
there, is a usurpation of the duties imposed upon the said Secretary 
of the Department of Labor and the said Assistant Secretary
of Labor, by Congress, and the said J.B. Densmore, in assuming
the duties of the said Secretary of Labor and the Assistant Secretary
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
of Labor and affirming the Finding of the Commissioner of
Immigration at Seattle, Washington, and the Chinese Inspector,
Henry Monroe, in relation to the case of Ching Hing, exceeded the
statute, and his action in sustaining the adverse decision in
relation to the right of entry of Ching Hing into the United
States, is null and the said Ching Hing has been denied the right
of appeal as provided by the statutes in such cases.</p>
<p>V.
Your Petitioner further states that he had not had a
fair and impartial trial before the Inspector in charge of
Immigration in Seattle, Washington; that there is no evidence in
the records to sustain the Department's Exclusion and Deportation
Order; that your Petitioner Ching Hing, after the Department had
illegally ordered his exclusion from entry to the United States
and his deportation thereform without any authority or law, to-wit,
by the illegal act of said Solicitor J.B. Denamore, who
had no authority to order said deportation, was denied a fair and
impartial trial in accordance with law, and that said Petitioner
was denied the right of having the counsel, Corry M. Stadden,
appear before the Commissioner General of Immigration, or the lawful
acting Secretary of Labor after said Petitioner Ching Hing had
appealled from the said illegal act of said Solicitor J.B. Denamore
or after said appeal had reached the Department of Labor, in order
that said counsel might present the case to the said Commissioner
General of Immigration, or the lawfully acting Secretary of Labor,
and bring to the attention of said officials the said illegal act
of said Solicitor J.B. Denamore, and place certain evidence before
said officials which would warrant a reversal of said order of
exclusion and deportation, or would warrant their consideration of
the appeal of your Petitioner.</p>
<p>Wherefore, your Petitioner prays that this Court find that
he had not been accorded the rights and privileges allowed by the
<fw>-4-</fw>
<pb/>
Constitution of the United States, and by the treaty between the
United States and China, and that he be discharged and allowed to
join his father who is a merchant in New York City.</p>
<ab>Dated this 22 day of Jan, 1915.</ab>
<ab>John J. Sullivan
Attorney for Petitioner
Ching Hing.</ab>
<p>State of Washington,
County of King. }ss</p>
<p>John J. Sullivan, being first duly sworn,
on oath deposes and says: That he is the Attorney for the Petitioner
Ching Hing; that he has read the foregoing Further Amended
Petitioner, knows the contents thereof, and that the same is true
of his own knowledge; that those facts which he does not know of
his own knowledge, he alleges upon information and belief to be
true.</p>
<ab>John J Sullivan
Subscribed and sworn to before me this 22 day of Jan, 1915.</ab>
<ab>Adam Beeler
Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</ab>
<figure><ab>Adam Beeler
State of Washington
Notary Public</ab></figure>
<pb/>
<p>2x No. 2875</p>
<p>In the District Court
of the United States
for the
Western District of Washington.
Northern Divison.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Ching Hing for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>Further Amended Petition
of Ching Hing</p>
<p>Filed in the
U.S. District Court
Western Dist. of Washington
Northern Division
Jan 25 1915
Frank L. Crosby, Clerk
By EML Deputy</p>
<p>John J. Sullivan
White Bldg.
Seattle, Wash.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>