<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0162.084">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ray Raymond v. Territory of Washington. Template</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
<name n="Hidalgo, Emily" xml:id="eh ">Emily Hidalgo</name>
<name n="Ham, Bethany" xml:id="brh">Bethany Ham</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0162.084</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ray Raymond v. Territory of Washington. Template</title>
<date when="1886"> July _, 1886</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Raymond, Ray</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Spokane County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Raymond, Ray</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-09" who="#lkw">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">
        
<pb facs="hc.case.0162.084"/>

<p>Territory of Washington} In the District Court 4th JuCounty 
of Spokane}ss dicial District holding
terms at County seat of
Spokane County</p>

<p>Territory of Washington
vs. Plaintiff
Ray Raymond Defendant</p>

<p>Territory of Washington}
County of Spokane}ss </p>

<p>Thomas C. Griffitts, J. Kennedy
Stout, N.T. Caton, and Frederick Stanford
being each individually duly sworn
depose and swear as follows:
That they and each of them are of counsel a
attorney for defendant Ray Raymond in
this cause that said defendant cannot
safely present to trial therein at this time
of this court for the following reasons:
The indictment against her eas returned
herein December 1, 1886, and the defendants
plea infered of not guilty on Dec. 1, 1886.
That immediately thereafter defendant
counsel made a motion for change of
venue herein and present the same to the
hearing at the earliest time the convenience
of the court and counsel for the Territory
permitted, and said motion was finally 
determined and awarded De.
14, 1886, defendant by her counsel immediately 

<pb/>

give in there this written for a continuance.
That this did question for a change of venue was
made by defendant and her counsel in the utmost 
good faith and they are greatly taken 
by surprise both by the affidavit filed herein
by the territory and on the said motion and at
the pending of the same and believing
their said motion were taken, they did not
show a motion for a continuance herein
would be necessary until the final determination 
of said motion for a change of
venue. That would the findind and presentment
of the indictment hererin neither affiant nor
defendant knew with what crime defendant
would be accused nor what the issue herein
would be whether she would be accused
of any offense whatsoever or of an offense
insodoing the issue of malice in the killing
of Finch. That at time such indictment
was presented this term of this court had
duly been in sworn and counsel for defendant
had been constant in attendance.
Then now and ever since said indictment
was returned into the court and
defendant counsel herein have been
in about constant attendance
at this court and expressed either in 
the trial of counsel therein or in watching

<pb/>

and waiting for the trial of pending course
or preparing for the trial of cause such
pending in this court and for trial
and of pursing importance and still
to be tried herein that considerable time
since the finding of said indictment have
been recopied by defendant counsel in
the preparation for and hearing of said
motion for a change of venue and since
its determination in the preparation
of a showing for the continuance; that
in addition to their other habeas as afore
detailed counsel immediately set
about making such preparation
as they could under the circumstances
for the trial of the cause attending to well
aware they could not fully prepare
thereupon and in fact counsel believes
that the later date in the term when
this indictment was presented, the
bona fide efforts they had made and the
parts directed in the showing for
change of venue made by them and which is here
referred to as part of the new herein and the continuation
of that cas at this <del>cause</del>term of court and the
return of the indictment herein and the great
expense and delay of procuring a jury
herein at this time, with the facts he afore

<pb/>

States in this affidavit would appear to the direction of this court and precinct there often being compilled to go to trial at this time, that from to the finding of the indictment herin defendant and affiants has said inquiry concerning an George Wycoff who affiant were informed living about 22 miles from Spokane Sea<del></del> and when affiant had been informed was in defendants' parlor in the night of the killing of Finch, and has been reliably informed that said Wycoff was temporarily absent from his home and from spokane County and about walla walla county somewhere but just when affiant could not hear, that shortly after the finding of the indictment-herein affiant directs a subpoena to issue herein for him, 
that they <unclear>use seeking worthy</unclear> informed he comes with be found and they have only <unclear>fiaound</unclear> within this days that he has been found and is somewhere in Spokane years on a <unclear>petition</unclear> for the prosecution that said Wycoff is wholly <unclear></unclear> to affiant <add>defendent</add> and her counsel by sight even they are unable to say wherefore in

<pb/>

with he was <del>for</del> in defendant's parlor as aforesaid at time of the killing is what he <del><unclear>has of his there</unclear></del> can <unclear>said review</unclear>to on said trial, but affiants have heard that he <unclear></unclear> to have been an eye=witness to the shooting. That since the finding of this indictment- affiant have also learned that the prosecution have still another witness by the name of Donalsm but whose given name is unknown to affaints, and who has not a witness upon the preliminary examination herein for before the 9 rounds jury and whose name is not in the indictment who also claims and intends to swear that he was present <add> at the time</add> <del>that height</del> of the Killing of Finch and <unclear>who</unclear> is defendant's parlor <unclear>at</unclear> the time and that he was an eye=witness to the shooting. That whether or not <unclear>says</unclear> Donalsm was present in defendents parlor at the time of the shooting of Finch affiants do not know <add> of this an knowledge the name heard of that effect</add> except from his statements, but affiants allege that-they are informed <del>for  <unclear></unclear></del> that if he even to juent in said parlor he reconpines a position therein which rendered is impossible for him to see the recarabees leading to and act of shooting of Finch, and that the same fact is true of the said George Wycoff and that he

<pb/>

if present at all in defendant's parlor at time of said 
killing also <unclear></unclear> position where 
he comes with see any verify the of fray 
out of which the killing arose or the act 
of killing. That within affiant's urn the defendant. Knew until since the 
finding of this indicment- that- the 
prosecution had welaimers to house 
such witness and affiants and camers 
that the prosecution had produced the 
witness Wycoff within the last two 
days. That within affiants urr defendant
know fully what the prosecution intends 
to prove by said witness in the trial 
of this cause and they are not oufficially 
aquiantes with said witnesses at this time
to be able fully to meet them and guan
agaisnt surprise on the trial of the
canseat this time <del></del> affiants have refen
to the affidavit of defendant herein filed
in support hereof, affiants further allege
that they have used ace pursible diligence
to prepare to hurt such witnesses since
they became aware that the Territory
had procunes there and would often
their Tichinoury and have been unable
to do so,

Affiants further allege as another <unclear></unclear> vthis petition;
<pb/>

That in ip the grounds of defense which they expect
to maintain in fact of defendant in their cause
is that <del>on the time</del> of insanity at the time
of the killing, that defendant is and for many years
mental disorder, <del>which</del> and that the same is
hereditary in her family, and that-at the time
of the killing, going Finch defendant was
insane and in such mental condition as
to be inegable of committing the crime
with which she is charged in this indictment
That on the trial of this cause affiants expect
to prove by me W. J. Wycoff of og din in
The Territory of Utah, That- he has known
defendant for about 15 years; That- he was
marries to defendant 14 years ago and
lived with her 5 or 6 years and by her
had two children; That- at the time she
was his wife and he living with her as such
she was afflicted with the disease of
<add></add> wisamly the same as that with which
she was afflicted at the time of the killing
alleged in the indictment-herein
but the details of what said witness <del></del> since Diular T. bearing upon this issues
affiants cannot fully state, but affiants 
expect to prove by him the facts above stated
and the fact that insanity is a hereditary Trait
in defendants family. That was better named

<pb/>

by one of defendants causes in the month of July, 1886
with the inuilare in which the same was eccinueds
is presented herwith marked
A. B. and made pail of this affidavit
That since the finding of this indictment 
it has been impossible to produce the alledged
of said witness <add>words</add> at this time of this  enerner to produce a deposition from him even
if his deposition <del><unclear></unclear></del> wreed be
proper and admissible but that from
information from and prinde disposition
of said witness towards defendant, and
from the fact that tdefendant has sufficient
money to pay the expense of said
witness from ogden after wins to depthand
Fracco of the plane upholding their court
and the expense of his attendance
herein, and that she wise fery the 
same to procure his attendance
all of which is have states as facts, suffiants
believes and have reasonable grounds
to believe, there they can procure the persual
attendance of sad witness at the 
next term of this court for the trial of this
cause-

Affiants further expect to prove and can
prove by said witness word that somewhere
in her sound minus and I said

<pb/>

intervals defendants is a placeable, kind=hearted 
woman, ex indingly tinies
and everwordly and afaid of assaults on
from of any kind and with in any manner
given to quaneling or the use of frivamnes,
This testimony is mentioned in nice of the 
fact that- defendant is charged with
maliciously and purposely killing James
Finch and that is in a fact that said
Finch was at the time of the killing of
Finch with which she is charged a total stranger
to her.

    That affiants expect to prove sales technically that
same facts as above stating concerning defendants
insanity <add>and probable disposition</add> by the <del><unclear>process</unclear></del> are
William Mc Dermott, who is now a 
resident-of Beetle City,, Montana
</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>