<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0370.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Nishikawa Mamoru v. T.W. Lynch. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0370.005</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Nishikawa Mamoru v. T.W. Lynch. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1921-11-25">November 25, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-11">November 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Mamoru, Nishikawa</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Lynch, T.W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Martin, Winter S.</persName>
<persName>Wardell</persName>
<persName>Allen</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Faulkner, Judson</persName>
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-08" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>No. 6414</p>

<p>Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of NISHIKAWA MAMORU For Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Nishikawa Mamoru, Petitioner,</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>T.W. Lynch, Acting Commissioner of Immigration, Respondent.</p>

<p>Comes now NISHIKAWA MAMORU by his attorney, Winter S. Martin, and respectfully shows to the Court:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That your petitioner is a citizen of the Empire of Japan, who came to the United States on board the Steamer "Fushimi Maru" arriving at the Port of Seattle October 9, 1918. That upon October 10th he was committed to the Providence Hospital for treatment and while there and without a passport or other permission to enter the United States, or to be or remain therein, left the hospital and did not return to his ship. That he remained continuously in the United States until the 3d day of November, 1921, when he was taken into custody upon a warrant for deportation by the Department of Labor at Cosmopolis, Washington.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>That a hearing was had upon the departmental warrant for</p>

<pb/>

<p>deportation, and your petitioner's deportation was ordered. That thereafter the record was made up and the papers forwarded to the Honorable Commissioner of Immigration at Washington, D.C.</p>

<p>III.</p>

<p>That thereafter said Honorable Commissioner and the Secretary of Labor ordered your petitioner's deportation pursuant to the hearing held at the Port of Seattle aforesaid.</p>

<p>IV.</p>

<p>That since your petitioner's arrest and detention on November 5th he has been detained in the United States Immigration Station at Seattle, where he now is. That under said warrant of deportation, unless restrained by this Honorable Court, your petitioner will be placed on board ship November 26, 1921, and will be by said Commissioner of Immigration and his deputies unlawfully deported to Japan.</p>

<p>V.</p>

<p>That in all respects his arrest, detention and imprisonment is illegal and without warrant or authority.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE your petitioner prays:</p>

<p>1. That a writ of habeas corpus may be issued to your said petitioner and that he may be discharged from said illegal restraint and unlawful arrest;</p>

<p>2, That pending a hearing upon an application for this writ of habeas corpus that said Thomas W. Lynch, Acting Commissioner of Immigration, and his deputies, be hereby enjoined and restrained from deporting your petitioner from Seattle to the Empire of Japan;</p>

<p>3. That an order to show cause issue forthwith directed  to the said Thomas W. Lynch, Acting Commissioner of Immigration, requiring him to be and appear in the above entitled Court, at a</p>

<p>(2)</p>

<pb/>

<p>time to be fixed by this Honorable Court, to show cause, if any he have, why the said writ of habeas corpus shall not be granted.</p>

<p>Mamoru Nishikawa</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>

<p>Winter S. Martin</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner.</p>

<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, Western District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>

<p>SS</p>

<p>NISHIKAWA MAMORU, being first duly sworn by and through an interpreter, upon his oath states:</p>

<p>That he has heard read to him this Petition for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, and that the facts therein stated are true.</p>

<p>Mamoru Nishikawa</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 25th day of November, 1921.</p>

<p>Winter S Martin</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

<p>(3)</p>

<pb/>

<p>6414</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Nov 25 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>