<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0212.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Taka Shibata v. Henry M. White. Memorandum Brief of the Respondent</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0212.005</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Taka Shibata v. Henry M. White. Memorandum Brief of the Respondent</title>
<date when="1920-07-23">July 23, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-07">July 1960</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Ying, Lum Lin</term>
<term>Hall, Calvin S.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>China</term>
<term>Japan</term>
<term>Nebraska</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Shibata, Taka</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Davis, P.V.</persName>
<persName>Kiefer, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
<persName>Rudkin, Frank H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-02" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Jul 30 1920</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger</p>
<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By <gap></gap> Deputy</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 5449</p>

<p>Memorandum Brief of the Respondent.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of Taka Shibata for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE FRANK H. RUDKIN, JUDGE OF SAID COURT:</p>

<p>A necessarily hasty, though reasonably diligent and thorough,search for authority upon the question of the validity of a marriage performed by proxy, or by the so-called "picture-bride" ceremony, has failed to unearth any decision definitely determining whether such a marriage is or is not valid in this country. The subject was touched upon in two cases, namely:</p>

<p>In re Lum Lin Ying (D.C., Oregon, 1894) 59 Federal, 682.</p>

<p>G.N. Ry. Co. v. Johnson (C.C.A., 8th Cir., 1918) 254 Fed. 683.</p>

<p>In neither decision, however, is the question satisfactorily settled, and, indeed, the remarks of the Court in each instance may reasonably be regarded as obiter dicta. In the first case cited, the wife was betrothed to her husband in China when an infant, and the marriage had been celebrated under Chinese custom some six months before the matter arose. The ceremony was by exchange of contracts, the woman being in China and the husband in America. The Court obs erved that "If the parties were married according to the laws of China, such marriage is valid here." But it is further said in the decision:</p>

<p>"At the time of the marriage in question in this case, the husband was domiciled in the United States. This raises a question as to whether China is the place of solemnization of the marriage. While the place of solemnization governs, by what rule shall such place be determined, when the parties are at the time within different jurisdictions? It is doubtful whether this is a China marriage. It is not enough, in my judgment, that such a marriage is valid under the laws of China. I am of opinion that is must not only be valid under such laws, but, to be valid elsewhere. must have been solemnized within the jurisdiction of those laws."</p>

<p>In the second case a somewhat similar state of facts existed. The parties were resident in different states, and the ceremony consisted of the man sending to the woman a written agreement of marriage, which was signed by her in the state of her residence. This was followed by cohabitation as man and wife. While the case was decided upon the ground that by the laws of both states common law marriages were recognized, and the marriage status would therefore be upheld upon that ground, the Court observes:</p>

<p>"Why should the physical presence of this parties be essential to the legality of this contract any more than of any other? It is not for us to devise ways of making common law marriages difficult. It is our duty to recognize the law as it exists. Nor is there any reason why the parties should be within the same jurisdiction. The existance and vality of the contract must be determined by the law of the place where it is legally regarded as made."</p>

<p>Neither of these cases appears ever to have been cited upon the question in issue, and neither refers to any previous holding on the matter; nor have we found any other holdings touching the subject.</p>

<p>Under date of July 18th, 1920, the Attorney General of Washington issued an opinion on the validity of marriages performed in Japan by the ceremony shown by the record to have been resorted to in this case. The opinion says in part:</p>

<pb/>

<p>"It is impossible to predict what view the courts of this state would take upon this question, with any degree of assurance. Our own personal view is that sound public policy would require the courts to declare such a marriage invalid. This system of entering into the marriage relation is at variance with American ideas of the nature of such a relation.</p>

<p>"In our opinion the true rule should be that residents of this state, while they remain within the borders of the state, can only enter into the marriage relation in the manner provided by our statutes. A marriage consummated by a Japanese resident of this state who does not leave the state, under the laws of Japan, should therefore be held illegal."</p>


<p>Very recently, in a default divorce suit pending before Judge Calvin S. Hall, of the local Superior Court, the question arose. No written opinion was rendered, but the writer of this brief took occassion to call upon Judge Hall this forenoon and discuss the matter with him. The Judge said that the evidence before him merely established the formalities connected with the marriage ceremony performed in Japan, and that there was no evidence whatever to show whether under Japanese law such formalities and such ceremony constituted a lawful marriage. For want of proof upon the legality of the marriages he dismissed the suit. He intimated, however, that had there been evidence showing such a marriage to be good under Japanese law, he would have heard  the case and would have adjudicated the divorce proceeding on the merits.</p>

<p>In the case before Your Honor the only issue is whether the record of the proceedings before the Immigration authorities presents any evidence upholding the order of the Secretary. That order recites the finding that the alien was a person who, at the time of her entry, was likely to become a public charge. The case cannot be determined upon matters arising subsequent to her entry. This we cheerfully and candidly concede. Thus, she cannot be deported, upon the one hand, because she and Shibata have separated since her entry, nor, upon the other, can she be allowed to remain because third persons have tendered bond to assure her not becoming a public charge. At the time she entered she was entitled to admission upon one ground only, namely, that she was married to a resident who was able to take care of her.</p>

<p>We suggest that the Court, in determining whether the Secretary acted arbitrarily or not, cannot go behind the record upon which the order of deportation was made. That record establishes that the petitioner was married only by Japanese custom, or, as it is referred to in the record, "by proxy." The record fails to disclose precisely what formalities were gone through with, nor does it show what the Japanese law on the validity of such a marriage is.</p>

<p>Did the alien have any person in this country from whom she legally could demand support? If she did not, then clearly the Secretary was justified in holding that she was at that time one likely to become a public charge. Who was such person owing her the duty of support? It is said that Shibata was he. But the record merely shows that some sort of marriage "by proxy" was performed in Japan while the petitioner was there and the man in Nebraska. Whether such a marriage was valid, either in Japan or Nebraska, is not shown by the record, nor has petitioner offered such evidence before this Court. There was, then, nothing before the Secretary establishing as a matter of fact or of law the existence of a marriage which, at the time and the place of debarkation of the alien, placed Shibata under the obligation of support. Suppose Shibata had refused to recognize the woman as his wife, and had declined to support her. Suppose, further, that the question of whether he owed those duties had arisen</p>

<pb/>

<p>in the Courts of Washington (to which courts alone, and not to the courts of either Nebraska or Japan, he was then subject) upon a state of facts precisely as shown by the record; would it or could it have been held that Shibata was the husband of the petitioner? Obviously not, because there would have been no evidence of the legality and binding effect of the alleged ceremony in Japan, or in Nebraska. In the absence of such proof, it is clear that, following rules too well established to require the citation of authority on the point, the local courts would have been compelled to hold that the laws of both Japan and Nebraska would be presumed to be the same as the local laws. Now, under the laws and decisions of Washington, as your Honor well knows, no marriage is valid unless performed in strict compliance with the formalities prescribed by our statutes. True enough, this State will, under rules of comity, and with certain exceptions immaterial to this discussion, recognize as valid in Washington marriages which are good contracts where performed, even though not in compliance with local statute. But the record in this case is complete, and it is devoid of any evidence establishing the legal validity anywhere of the so-called marriage. The petitioner was represented through the proceedings by counsel; opportunity to introduce such showing in the record was afforded; but the proof is wanting. Can the Court supply it by presumption surmise, or conjecture?</p>

<p>With the frank suggestion of authorities both favorable and unfavorable to the arguments here briefly advanced, the <del>matter</del> <add>case</add> is respectfully submitted to Your Honor for whatever view of the matter may to the Court seem right and proper.</p>

<p>Robt. C. Saunders</p>
<p>United States Attorney.</p>

<p>R.E.Capers</p>
<p>Assistant United States Attorney.</p>

<p>July 23/20</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>