<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0363.008">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Sam Gum v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0363.008</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Sam Gum v. Henry M. White. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1921-04-26">April 26, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-04">April 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Gum, Sam</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Sullivan, John J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the District Court of the United States, for the Western District of Washington,</p>
<p>Northern Division.</p>

<p>No. 5968</p>

<p>Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of SAM GUM, for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Comes now Sam Gum, both in person and through his attorneys, Beeler &amp; Sullivan, and respectfully makes this application for a writ of habeas corpus and alleges and represents as follows:-</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That said Sam Gum is in the Detention House, imprisoned and restrained of his liberty by the United States Commissioner of Immigration, Henry M. White, or by person or persons acting through, by or under them at the Detention House at the Immigration Station in the City of Seattle, under the charge that said Sam Gum has no lawful right to be in the United States and that he should be deported, and your Petitioner respectfully informs the Honorable Court that said imprisonment, confinement and restraint and order of deportation is illegal and not according to law; that your Petitioner was not granted a fair hearing before said Immigration officials; that there is no competent evidence in the record upon which to base the finding of the Secretary of Labor and that the same is arbitrary and not according to law; that your Petitioner has lived in the United States for many years and his occupation has been a cook; that he has given a hearing before William G. Strench at Ketchikan, Alaska, under a charge of the violation of the Act of Congress of February 5, 1917, to wit: that he has been found employed, by in or in connection with a house of prostitution; that your Petitioner was not given a hearing according to law in</p>

<p>-1-</p>

<pb/>
<p>that your Petitioner was not amenable to the Immigration Act under which he was charged and that having lived in the United States for many years he was entitled to have his rights to remain in the United States judicially determined and that he is not subject to executive action and decision and that he was not arrested upon a warrant issued or upon a warrant or complaint under oath filed by any party on behalf of the United States by any Justice Judge or Commissioner of any United States Court as provided for by law, and that his arrest by an Immigration Officer herein, before said Immigration Department for an Order of Deportation by the Honorable the Assistant Secretary of Labor as shown by the record is illegal and unlawful.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE your Petitioner prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus may be issued to the said Sam Gum and that your Petitioner may be discharged from such illegal restraint.</p>

<p>Beelr &amp; Sullivan</p>
<p>Attorneys for Petitioner</p>

<p>State of Washington</p>
<p>County of King</p>

<p>ss</p>

<p>SAM GUM being first duly sworn on oath deposes and says: That he is the Petitioner herein; that he has read the foregoing petition, knows the contents thereof, and that the same are true of his own knowledge, and that he believes said facts to be true.</p>

<p>Sam Gum</p>

<p>SUBSCRIBED and sworn to before me this 26th day of April, 1921.</p>

<p>V G <unclear>Frost</unclear></p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington residing at Seattle.</p>

<p>Received a copy of the within petition this 26th day of April, 1921.</p>

<p>Robt C. Saunders</p>
<p>Attorney for U.S. Attorney.</p>
<p>By E. D. Sutton</p>

<pb/>

<p>5968</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Apr 27 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>