<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0182.012">
    
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>K. Gregory et al. Type of document</title>
                <principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
                    <name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
                    <name n="Bruha, Ashley S" xml:id="asb">Ashley Bruha</name>
                    
                </respStmt>
                <sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
                <sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
            </titleStmt>
            
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2022</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Produce the Body</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0182.012</idno>
              
                <availability>
                    <licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
                    <p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title level="m" type="main">K. Gregory et al. Civil</title>
                    <date when="1914-01">January 1914</date>
                    <note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
                        <collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
                        <idno>2646KGregoryEtAl</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Case Papers</term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="original" n="type">
                    <term>Civil</term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="original" n="term">
                    <term><date when="1914-01">January 1914</date></term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Henry White</term>
                    <term>Frank Crosby</term>
                    <term>Clay Allen</term>
                    <term>G.F. Fishburne</term>
                    <term>Parker</term>
                    <term>Kalina</term>
                    <term>K. Gregory</term>
                    <term>M. Aloshin</term>
                    <term>I. Riaboff</term>
                    <term>P. Neanlin</term>
                    <term>I. Erelin</term>
                    <term>L. Orloff</term>
                    <term>G. Yakimoff</term>
                    <term>P. Yakimoff</term>
                    <term>Jeremiah Neterer</term>
                    
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
                    <term>Seattle, Washington</term>
                </keywords>
                
            </textClass>
            
            <particDesc>   
                <listPerson>            
                    <person role="petitioner">
                        <persName>K. Gregory</persName>
                        <persName>M. Aloshin</persName>
                        <persName>I. Riaboff</persName>
                        <persName>P. Neanlin</persName>
                        <persName>I. Erelin</persName>
                        <persName>L. Orloff</persName>
                        <persName>K. Yakimoff</persName>
                        <persName>P. Yakimoff</persName>
                    </person>
                    <person role="defendant">
                        <persName>Henry White</persName>
                    </person>
                    <person role="attorney_petitioner">
                        <persName>Parker</persName>
                        <persName>Kalina</persName>
                    </person>
                    <person role="attorney_defendant">
                        <persName>Clay Allen</persName>
                        <persName>GF Fishburne</persName>
                    </person>
                    <person role="judge">
                        <persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
                    </person>
                </listPerson>
                
                <listOrg>
                    <org>
                        <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
                        <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
                    </org>
                </listOrg>   
            </particDesc> 
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>         
            <change when="2022-02" who="#asb">transcribed and encoded</change>
        </revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>Seattle, Washington
December 22, 1913</p>
<p>At a meeting of the Board of Special Inquiry, convened pursuant to the instructions of the
Cammissioner composed of</p>
<p>Inspectors T.W. Lynch (Chairman)
J.E. Wilkes, and A.T. White</p>
<p>Stenographer     Trent Doser
Interpreter     Henry G. Gerome</p>
<p>In re cases of 
GREGORI KORNILIN,
MOISEI ALIOSHIN,
IVAN RIABOFF,
JAKOB EPHIMOFF,
PETER NEONILIN,
and
IVAN EMELIN,
ex SS. "Tamba Maru,"
December 19, 1913.
HEARING RESUMED:</p>
<p>FINDINGS:</p>
<p>These aliens were ticketed to Canada and were refused a landing in that country by the Dominion
Immigration Agent at Victoria B.C. They did not take an appeal from his decision but after having
been brought to this port on the same vessel by which they had arrived in Canada, applied for
admission. The steamship company manifested them as from Japan to Seattle, and collected a deposit
to cover head tax but did not collect any additional passage money.</p>
<p>These aliens in my judgement are persons likely to become public charges and therefore
inadmissible to the United States. They are common laborers or farm laborers and there is no workk
for them. They have but a limited amount of money, an amount insufficient to maintain them during
the winter and it has not been shown that they have any relatives in this country upon whom they
have a lawful claim for support or who are in a position to care for them even if disposed to do so.
There are at this time from 800 to 1,000 Russians unemployed in this city and there are thousands of
other nationalities in the same condition. Reports from the interior are uniformly to the effect
that the supply of common labor is far in excess of the demand. The City of Seattle is endeavoring
to relieve the situation by giving married men a few days employment each week on public work and
according to the public press the same methods are in vogue at Portland, Pregon, the point to which
these aliens are destined. Their admission under the circumstances would only increase the number of
unemployed and would tend to make greater the burden which will have to be borne by the state and by
charitable organiza-
<pb></pb>
tions during the coming winter months. The care of those now destitute is a problem sufficiently
great to tax the ingenuity and resources of the state and more fortunate public and any additiosn to
the army of unemployed should be guarded against by every possible means until such time as there is
work for them to do. Alien laborers should not be permitted to enter the United States.</p>
<p>Nine men constituted the party ticketed to Canada originally, although three of them contend that
they were so routed through a misunderstanding. Canada refused them admission and that Government is
therefore primarily responsible for any inconvenience or harships which they may suffer if deported.
I, therefore, move that these aliens be excluded as persons likely to become public charges and
ordered deported to the country whence they came at the expense of the importing vessel.</p>
<p>INSPECTOR WILKES: I second the motion.
INSPECTOR WHITE: The aliens are unanimously excluded.</p>
<p>Kornilin, Alioshin, Riaboff, Ephimoff, Neonilin, and Emelin you have been excluded by a Board of
Special inquiry which finds that you are inadmissible to the United States for the reason that you
are a person likely to become a public charge. Fro this decision you have the right to appeal to the
Secretary of Labor at Washington, D.C. If you elect to appeal notice should be given promptly.</p>
<p>You have been ordered deported to the country whence you came and you hereby advised that such
deportation will be at the expense of the importing vessel.</p>
<p>You are further advised that you may communicate with friends, relatives, your Consulor
representative, or attorney.</p>
<p>Seattle, Washington,
December 23, 1913.</p>
<p>STATEMENT BY GREGORI KORNILIN made through Interpreter Henry Gerome.</p>
<p>It would work a hardship on me to be turned back, because I have sold a horse, a cow and have
mortgaged my land. I came on the assurance of Paul Semenoff, a countryman and neighbor of mine, who
said that there was plenty of good workk in this country and not only that but I know that he is
sending for his wife to come here which proves to me that he must be doing well becuase he has only
beenin this country a short while. I would respectfully beg to be left in this country. I hereby
appeal to the Secretary of Labor at Washington D.C., from the excluding decision of the Board. I do
not want an attorney and I do not desire to submit any firther argument or evidence.</p>
<p>STATEMENT BY MOISEI ALIOSHIN made through INterpreter Henry Gerome.</p>
<p>I do not wish to be sent back for it will work a hardship upon me as I have sold a hrose a cow
and all my crop, consisting of a few acres, and was coming out to this country on the assurances of
two of my relatives one in Vancouver, B.C., and one at Portland, Oregon, that it is an easy matter
to make a living in this country, and relatively speaking the wages in this country are better than
at home and I would be able to earn money to send for my family to come here. I hereby apply to the
Secretary of Labor at Washington, D.C., from the excluding decision of the Board and do not desire
to submit any further argument or to submit any further evidence.</p>
<p>STATEMENT BY IVAN RIABOFF made through Interpreter Henry Gerome.</p>
<p>I wish to be left in this country and not deported back for I have not sufficient money to travel
about 6,000 miles to get to my homef rom Japan, and I have sold a horse, oats and rye in order to
come to this country and left enough for my wife to live on. I came out on the assurancec of my
broter-in-law, Stephen Philatoff, who makes his home in Portland, and he assured me that there is
plenty of work and good wages for an able bodied man, and assured me that if ti happens that in the
winter time there is little work he will aid me until spring and he also said that he is going to
send for his family, and after a matter of six months I would be able to send for mine. I hereby
appeal on the record as it stands to the Secretary of Labor at Washington, D.C., I do not desire an
attorney and do not desire to submit any further evidence or argument.</p>
<p>STATEMENT BY JAKOB EPHIMOFF made through Interpreter Henry Gerome.</p>
<p>I wish to be left in this country in order to be a ble to make a living fo rmyself and bring out
my wife, as I have not only sold a cow and horse but have rented my land for 12 years for $100. My
relative in Canada and here told me that I could make a living here and bring out my family and for
some reason the Canadian Immigration Department did not let me in so I would respectfully beg to be
left here, as I have another realtive in Portland, Oregon. I hereby appeal to the Secretary of
Labor, Washington D.C., from the excluding decision of the Board. I do not desire to be represented
by an attorney and I do not desire to submit any further evidence or argument.</p>
<p>STATEMENT BY PETER NEONILIN made through Interpreter henry Gerome.</p>
<p>It would work a hardship upon me to return home as I have a wife and five children there and I
have received assurance from my relative in Portland, Oregon that i would be able to make a living
for them and also in Canada. Otherwise I would not have sold my horse and my cow
<pb></pb>and soem oats and rye, because I would have kept them for seed and the horse to work the
land and the cow for milk for my children. I have not enough money to return home and if I had i
would not be able to make a living there as there is no work in the winter. I desire to appeal to
the Secretary of Labor at Washington, D.C., from the excluding decision of the Board and I do not
desire to be represented by an attorney. I do not desire to submit any firther evidence or to make
any firther argument.</p>
<p>STATEMENT BY IVAN EMELIN made through Interpreter Henry Gerome.</p>
<p>I would like to be left in this country for I have sold a horse and a cow at home and some of the
crop and it will work a hardship upon me to return home for I have not sufficient money to get to
the place I would have to travel to to get home it is winter and tere is no work there. I have
relatives and freinds both in Canada and Portland, Oregon and according to their letters and
information they are all making a living and I am sure they would help me out if I could not get
anything to do during the winter. From Yokohama to Valdivastok the fair is, in American money, $5.15
and from Valdivastok to my home costs anout $35.00 in American money. I wish to appeal from the
excluding decision of the Noard. I do not desire to submit any firther evidence. We all came on the
assurances of our friends and relatives in Canada and Portland,  Oregon, and as they are all making
a living we tood their word and thought we could make a good living here. I ahve no further argument
to make.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that the foregoing is a corect transcript of the testimony given in these cases.</p>
<p>Trent Doser
Stenographer</p>

<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>