<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0178.020.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Mac Fock v. State of Washington. Case Reference</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0178.020</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Mac Fock v. State of Washington. Case Reference</title>
<date when="1908">1908</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1908-07">July 1908</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Tang Tung</term>
<term>Leung Lum Wei</term>
<term>Can Pon</term>
<term>Sing Tuek</term>
<term>Ju Toy</term>
<term>Josiah Brewer</term>
<term>Josiah Hanford</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Mac Fock</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>State of Washington</persName>
<persName>Ellis De Bruler</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Victor Place</persName>
<persName>L. Frank Brown</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Earl B. Brockway</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
<persName>Edward Cushman</persName>
</person>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#AS">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>BUREAU OF 
IMMIGRATION AND NATURALIZATION</p>
<p>Washington July 23, 1908.</p>
<p>Nos. 14,610/104 -C
14,610/350 -C
15,200/8 -C</p>
<p>To be returned to U.S. 
Immigration Service, Seattle, 
after serving its purpose.</p>
<p>Chinese Inspector in Charge, 
Sumas, Washington</p>
<p>Sir:-</p>
<p>Referring to the decisions rendered in May last by the 
United States District Court for the Western District of Washington,
in the two cases of Tang Tung and his wife Leung Lum Wui and 
Can Pon, you are informed that the Bureau has given very careful 
consideration to the language in which said decisions are couched, 
the circumstances that surrounded the cases, and the evidence
developed before the Inspector in Charge and eventually placed before
the Department on appeal, and has endeavored to determine just
how far and in exactly what respects each of said decisions has
run counter to a fair interperation of the holdings of the
Supreme Court in the Sing Tuek, Ju Toy, and Chin Yow cases and the
prior opinons of said court that gradually led up to the stand 
taken in said cases. If time permitted, the Bureau should endeavor
to place its observations (or such of them as are susceptible of 
such use) in the form of a brief, so that they might be presented 
to the United States Attorney in better shape for his purposes; 
but the best it can do at present is to mention the points that
occur to it as the result of a study of those cases and its experience
in the enforcement of the Chinese exclusion law, and inclose</p>
<figure><p>3062-0 
for letter
sending purposes 
copy &amp; U.S. Atty</p></figure>
<p>209</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>a copy of this letter form which the United States Attorney may, 
perhaps, be able to select some suggestions of value.</p>
<p>In the first plaace it is evident that the Honorable Judge 
has approached these cases (as well as several others decided favorably 
to the Government) from a point of view diametrically opposed 
to the majority opinions in the Sing Tuck and Ju Toy cases; i.e., 
he has assumed as a premise from which to start (as Mr. Justice Brewer always does in the Supreme Court) that the person applying 
for admission, ostersibly an alien, and whether an alien or not, 
standing at our portals and knocking for admission, is as a matter
of fact an American citizen -- the very claim that remains yet to 
be proved. This attitude, however it may be disguised in judicial 
language, not only does not conform to the Supreme Court decisions, 
but in effect shifts the burden from the shoulders on which the law
as by those decisions constructed has placed it, or at least reduces 
the necessity that those alleging a failure to accord "due process 
of law" shall "affirmatively" show such failure (Ju Toy Case) to a 
requirement merely that they shall make a prima facie showing to 
that effect. "Of course, if the writ is granted the first issue 
to be tried is the truth of the allegations" of abuse of discretion
(Chin Yow Case).</p>
<p>Assuming this contrary attitude as a premis from which 
to proceed, it is only natural that the conduct of the cases throughout 
should be tinged with the same error of conception and conduct; 
that the next step should be a detailed scrutiny of the evidence</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>in an effort to weigh it and accurately determine the facts --some-
thing the court is not called upon to do at all until the affirmative 
showing of abuse has been made by the petitioner. "And, by way of 
caution, we mad add that jurisdiction would not established simply 
by proving that the Commissioner (immigration offical) and the 
Department of Commerce and Labor did not accept certain sworn statements
as true, even though no contrary or impeaching testimony was 
adduced;" and "the denial of a hearing cannot be established by 
proving that the decision was wrong" -- by proving, actually proving
affirmatively, that the decision on the facts, the weight accorded
the evidence, was erroneous. (Chin Yow Case). What could be a more 
clear and outright assertion that, by the very nature of these 
cases and the circumstances out of which evidence must be gathered, 
on the question of fact and the weight of the evidence the adminstrative
officers must be allowed absolute discretion? And this 
amounts, at any rate, to no more than a recognition of a variation 
of the general principle and idea, running through our law and 
system of jurisprudence, that questions of fact and of the credibility 
of evidence should be to the fullest extent possible to be left to the 
determination of those before whom the evidence is produced, who by
reason of that fact are best qualified to pass upon credibility and 
weight.</p>
<p>To take upon the two cases seperatly: 
CASE OF TANG TUN &amp; LEUNG LUM WUI:-</p>
<p>In this case the discharge of the petitioners from custody 
under the writ of habeas corpus is based upon two grounds: 1st, That
<pb></pb>
the Inspector in Charge was prejudiced against the petitioner Tang 
Tun and did not accord the evidence in his favor proper weight; and 
2nd, That the appeal of the petitioners was dismissed, not by the 
Secretary of Commerce and Labor, but by "some officer of the Department, acting for or in place of the Secretary" who "refused to entertain
the appeal and arbitrarily, without deigning to assing a reason, 
dismissed it."</p>
<p>The second reason assigned is the result of a gross misunderstanding 
combined with a failure to judicially notice the obvious 
fact that the person who signed the telegram "Murray" dismissing 
the appeal,was at the time of so signing and had been for 
several years the Assistant Secretary of Commerce and Labor, appointed 
as such by the President and as much by the Senate, and 
having full charge in the Department of all matters relating to 
Chinese appeals. Doubtless had the Honorable Judge not been laboring
under a missapprehension on this point, he would have been slower 
to have assigned as a cause for the discharge of the petitioners the 
first reason above mentioned. The difficulty that now confronts 
the Government is brought about by the stipulation entered into at
the time the case was submitted to the court containing the assertion 
that the telegram signed "Murray" was the only record covering
the dismissal of appeal and not explaining the offical capacity
of the signer. However, the Department could readily certify for the 
information of the higher court not only that the telegram was not an 
indication that an under offical of the Department denied 
privilege of appeal to the petitioners, but also that the telegram 
<pb></pb> 
was sent only after the appeal record had received the careful personal 
attention of the Assistant Secretary, and that its brief wording and
signature were the result only of a practice then obtaining in the 
Department whereby it was understood by the Inspectors in Charge at 
ports of entry that a telegram so worded and so signed indicated that
a review of the appeal record resulted in the affirmation of the 
findings of the Inspector in Charge to a sufficient extent to justify
the rejection of the appellant. Thus it will be seen that in this 
case the Inspector in Charge and the Assistant Secretary of Commerce 
and Labor both considered all of the evidence presented and the 
assertion by the court that the decision was the result of prejudice
necessarily carries the implication that the Assistant Secretary, as well
as the Inspector in Charge, was actuated by such prejudice. In taking 
up the record and considering the weight of the evidence and passing 
upon the facts, thus arriving at the first reason for dismissing 
the petitioners, the court therefore was doing nothing more nor less
than reviewing judically a decision on questions of fact rendered 
by the adminstrative officers clothed with exclusive jurisdiction 
concerning such questions. Any two persons examing evidence on a 
question of fact at all close are likely to reach different conclusions; 
and a judical officer in examining such evidence is almost certain, 
even unconsciously, to be governed by the strict rules of evidence applying
to judicial inquiries -- the very contingency that Congress intended 
to avoid by placing the decision of these cases in the adminstrative
officers who, by reason of their situation, the machinery at their
<pb></pb>
control, and their practial experience in the enforcement of the 
law are best qualified to reach a correct conclusion (at least 
so the Congress assumed) on such questions. Moreover, the Supreme 
Court has carefully guarded this point by the reiterated caution 
containted in the Chin Yow Case and the assertion therein that 
actual proof that the adminstrative decision is wrong is not 
sufficient to open the merits of the case in the court, much less the 
mere opinion of a judicial officer after reviewing the evidence that
such adminstrative decision is wrong. There was no intention 
that the hearing should be judicially conducted, in fact the intention
was the opposite as already seen, and all that is neccessary is 
that a fair opportunity to produce the evidence that he desired, 
or a fair though summary hearing, the case can proceed no farther." 
Chin Yow Case. On this point the latter part of the Japanese 
Immigrant Case (189 U. S. 86, 99-102) is not only interesting but 
absolutely conclusive.</p>
<p>CASE OF CAN PON:-</p>
<p>In this case all that has been said directly with respect 
to the first reason assigned for discharging the petitioners in the 
preceding case holds good. Under the Supreme Court decisions, the 
Honorable Judge should not have resorted to an examination of the 
evidence for the petitioner was born in the United States as claimed; 
that question was not before him in even the remotest degree. It 
<pb></pb> 
was his privilege and duty, of course, to examine the record and
pursue the evidence with a view to determine whether "due process
of law" had been observed in a necessarily summary and adminstrative, 
not judical, manner. If by such an examination he had reached the 
conclusion that a summary "due process of law" had not been accorded 
then, and only then, was he privilged to examine into the merits
of the case. But he did even more in this case. he proceeded to 
have evidence taken before a referee and used that evidence to the 
exclusion of that presented before the administrative officers, 
which it was his privilege to review for the above mentioned purpose, 
in reaching a conclusion ostensibly as to whether there had been due 
process of law but actually as to whether or not the petitioner 
was born in the United States, and being satisfied in his own mind 
that the petitioner was born in this country he throws out all of 
the evidence taken before the adminstrative officers and holds that 
petitioner is entitled to be discharged. In other words, he has 
approached the case from the wrong end by proceeding upon the 
theory "that the question of prime importance in this case is whether
the contestant is or is not a native born citizen of the United 
States" -- a question which was not before him at all. It is worthy 
of note in this connection that the practice followed by the Judge
was that best calculated to either overthrow the evidence taken
before the adminstrative officers or to explain away the discrepancies 
appearing therein; for when he called the witnesses before 
the referee and took their testimony they were, of course, fully 
<pb></pb> 
apprised and ample opportunity had been afforded for their coaching
and preparation. Aside from any other question, the ends of
justice are not likely to be met by such procedure.</p>
<p>In this case, as in the other, the Honorable Judge seems
to have labored under a misapprehension with respect to the care 
exercised in the Department in handling Chinese appeals. His criticism
with respect to the opinion of the Solicitor and the decision 
thereon of the Acting Secretary (both capacities happening in this 
particular case to have been filled by the same individual at the 
time the case was considered in the two offices, respectively) is 
wholly uncalled for and about as wide of the mark as anything possibly 
could be. In the first place he loses sight of the fact that the 
Solicitor of the Department is merely its legal adviser and could
not in any sense whatever be said to fill "the capacity of a Solicitor 
adversely to the appellant." He had no interest adverse to the 
appellant but was only interested to ascertain from the record the 
facts as there shown and point out to the Secretary the application
of the law to such facts. That he subsequently passed upon the case 
as Acting Secretary was not strange or unusual. He is designated 
by the President to act as Secretary on occasions when his services
are such required. The practice in the Department is to have 
the Chinese appeals carefully reviewed by the Bureau of Immigration 
and Naturalization after which they are re-reviewed by the 
Solicitor's office and finally reach the Assistant Secretary or 
Acting Secretary for personal consideration, which personal consideration</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>they always recieve. The very fact that the same person reviewed
the case in detail as Solicitor and later passed upon it as 
Acting Secretary is conclusive proof that in this instance the 
merits had the personal attention of the head of the Department -- 
the importance of which the court so emphatically declares. All of 
this can be shown by certificate of the Department if such a certificate 
is required and can be introduced in the higher court.</p>
<p>-------------------</p>
<p>It is needless to say that none of the foregoing is intended 
as a criticism of the District Court, for the Bureau has the 
highest respect for the opinions of the Judge thereof and would not
say or do anything that could be construed as disrespectful to him. 
It is merely an expression of views which the Bureau believes are 
sound, on matters which it is his privilege, of course, to regard
differently. If it were not for the fact that the decisions if 
allowed to stand are likely to produce uncalculable bad results, 
the Bureau would be disposed to ask that you, the Inspector in Charge
at Seattle, and the United States Attorney confer fully with Judge 
Hanford pointing out to him with the utmost courtesy wherein it is 
perceived that he is laboring under misapprehensions and assuring 
him of the desire of the adminstrative officers to decide all of these
cases with fairness both to the Chinese and the Government. It 
would be all the more disposed to do this because of the Honorable 
Judge's attitude as indicated in the last paragraph of his decision
in the Gon Ed case, which it takes to be an indication of a determination
on his part not to allow his court to be used as a means whereby 
<pb></pb>
the Chinese and their unscrupulous attorneys may effect their illegal ends. 
But the Bureau fears the effect that the decisions, especially that in the 
Can Pon case, might have upon other District Courts, if allowed to stand 
in the reports unreversed. It therefore hopes that the above argument, 
hastily prepared and it is realized extremely crude in construction and
arrangement, may be of at least some suggestive value to the United States
Attorney.</p>
<p>No harm could result, however, from a full discussion of the matter 
with Judge Hanford, even though appeals are taken from his decisions; and
nothing is more useful to the Service than a thorough understanding with the 
Judiciary. Perhaps the United States Attorney may think it well, therefore, 
to at least call the Judge's attention to the manner in which he misapprehended
the Department's action in the two appeal cases under discussion.</p>
<p>If the cases are not called for hearing in the Circuit Court of 
Appeals until late in the fall, and the Bureau can be of further assistance 
on any particular points, it will be glad to devote further time to the 
subject.
Respectfully, 
<figure><p>(Signed) F. E. Larned.</p></figure>
Acting Commissioner-General.
</p>
<p>AWP/CAS.</p>
<p>OFFICIAL COPY, respectfully referred to the 
Inspector in Charge, Seattle, Washn., for his informaton.</p>
<p>F. E. Larned
Acting Commissioner-General.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>