<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0181.013.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Seventy-six Hindus v. Seattle Department of Immigration. Return to the Order to Show Cause and Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0181.012</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Seventy-six Hindus v. Seattle Department of Immigration.  Return to the Order to Show Cause and Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="2022">2022</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-11">October 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Moola Singh</term>
<term>Seventy-two Hindoo Aliens</term>
<term>Jeremiah Neterer</term>
<term>Frank L. Crosby</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>United States District Court Western District of Washington Northern Division</term>
<term>Philippine Islands</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Manila, Philippine Islands</term>
<term>United States</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Moola Singh</persName>
<persName>Talok Singh</persName> 
<persName>Dalip Singh</persName>
<persName>Bhagwan Singh</persName>
<persName>Pala Singh</persName>
<persName>Ala Singh</persName>
<persName>Biahsn Singh</persName> 
<persName>Rulia Singh</persName>
<persName>Kishan Singh</persName>
<persName>Harijan Singh</persName>
<persName>Arjan Singh</persName>
<persName>Hire Singh</persName>
<persName>Bhag Singh</persName>
<persName>Amarao Singh</persName>
<persName>Duvan Singh</persName>
<persName>Puran Singh</persName>
<persName>Nuarang Singh</persName>
<persName>Dalip Singh</persName>
<persName>Vir Singh</persName>
<persName>Ratan Singh</persName>
<persName>Nama Singh</persName>
<persName>Bishan Singh</persName>
<persName>Bishan Singh</persName>
<persName>Rem Singh</persName>
<persName>Baboo Singh</persName>
<persName>Bhagat Singh</persName>
<persName>Thakar Singh</persName>
<persName>Variam Singh</persName>
<persName>Harnam Singh</persName>
<persName>Gurdit Singh</persName>
<persName>Kishan Singh</persName>
<persName>Gurbakhoh Singh</persName>
<persName>Khazan Singh</persName>
<persName>Paren Singh</persName>
<persName>Milkha Singh</persName>
<persName>Narnam Singh</persName>
<persName>Munshi Singh</persName>
<persName>Varian Singh</persName>
<persName>Sham Singh</persName>
<persName>Kakoo Singh</persName>
<persName>Basant Singh</persName>
<persName>Pooran Singh</persName>
<persName>Sher Singh</persName>
<persName>Santa Singh</persName>
<persName>Harnam Singh</persName>
<persName>Munshi Singh</persName>
<persName>Parem Singh</persName>
<persName>Partap Singh</persName>
<persName>Naurang Singh</persName>
<persName>Farzona Ali</persName>
<persName>Ahas Ali</persName>
<persName>Bahadar Shah</persName>
<persName>Mir Ahdylla</persName>
<persName>Nizam Din</persName>
<persName>Sultan Ali</persName>
<persName>Bagh Ali</persName>
<persName>Niaz Mohd</persName>
<persName>Rahmat Alla</persName>
<persName>Nayat Kahn</persName>
<persName>Amir Rhan</persName>
<persName>Amir Khan</persName>
<persName>Mohd Alam</persName>
<persName>Isay Khan</persName>
<persName>Amarat Khan</persName>
<persName>Sanday Khan</persName>
<persName>Shali Khar Khan</persName>
<persName>Namdar Khan</persName>
<persName>Gulam Modh</persName>
<persName>Sanday Khan</persName>
<persName>Baggn Khan</persName>
<persName>Umar Den</persName>
<persName>Ali But</persName>
<persName>Hanz Mohd</persName>
<persName>Chiragh Din</persName>
<persName>Madda Din</persName>
<persName>Ibrahim Din</persName>
<persName>Ismail Din</persName>
<persName>Rahmat Ali</persName>
<persName>Noor Khan</persName>
<persName>Ishar Singh</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Herbert Meyers</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>John J. Sullivan</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#AS">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>207 7-5 780</p>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In re Unlawful Detention 
of Moola Singh and Seventy-two 
other Hindoo Aliens.</p>
<p>) ) )</p>
<p>No. 2532 
Filed Sept.<gap></gap>, 1913.</p>
<p>Herbert W. Meyers, For Petitioners 
C. F. Riddell, E. B. Brockway, For Respondent. </p>
<p>NETERER, District Judge.</p>
<p>Moola Singh and seventy-two other Hindoos filed a petition
praying a writ of habeas corpus, and alleges: That they were
former residents of the Philippine Islands, and at this time 
are unlawfully detained by the immigration authorities at 
Seattle, Washington; that they have resided in the Phillippine
Islands for periods varying from several months to several
years; that they were lawfully admitted by the immigration 
officers at the city of Manila; that they came to the city of 
Seattle and were arrested, tried before the commissioner of 
immigration in Seattle, and the secretary of labor, denied 
admission and ordered deportation. They further alleged that they
were not accorded a fair trial, and pray that they may be discharged
from custody and permitted to enter. Notice of application
was served upon the United States Attorney, and the 
hearing came regularly before the court, both sides being
represented.</p>
<p>The question to be determined by this court is, were the 
petitioners accorded a trial, and is the action of the secretary 
of labor res judicata. Sec. 20 of the immigration act of 
Feb. 20, 1907, as amended by the Act of March 6, 1910, and 
March 4. 1913, provides:</p>
<p>"That any alien who shall enter the United States in 
violation of law, and such as becomes public charges from causes existing
prior to landing, shall, upon the warrant of the Secretary
of Labor, be taken into custody and deported to the country
whence he came at any time within three years after the date
of his entry into the United States..."</p>
<p>Sec. 21 provides:</p>
<p>"That in case the Secretary of Labor shall be satisfied 
that an alien has been found in the United States in violation</p>
<p>1.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>of this Act, or that an alien is subject to deportation under 
the provisions of this Act or of any law of the United States, 
he shall cause such alien within the period of three years
after landing or entry therein to be taken into custody and returned
to the country whence he came, as provided by section
twenty of this act.." </p>
<p>Sec. 25 provides:</p>
<p>".... That in every case where an alien is excluded from 
admission into the United States, under any law or treaty now 
existing or hereafter made, the decision of the appropriate 
immigration officers, if adverse to the admission of such alien, 
shall be final, unless reveresed on appeal to the Secretary of 
Labor."</p>
<p>The admission of aliens into the United States is regulated 
by congress. The supervision is confided to the department of 
immigration charged with the enforcement of laws regulating 
the admission. The final determination of all of the facts 
with relation to the qualification of aliens to enter the 
United States or their deportation within the time limit fixed 
by act of congress for reasons therein given is entrusted to the 
proper immigration officers "whose decision is final, unless
reversed on appeal to the Secretary of Labor." By the act
of congress these officers are made the sole and exclusive judges 
of the existence of the facts establishing qualification, and 
no other tribunal is vested with authority or power by congress 
to re-examine and consider the sufficiency of the evidence on 
which these officers acted. So long as the officers clothed
with this authority act within the limits placed by congress, 
courts have no right to enterfere. The authority of the 
immigration officers and the jurisdiction of the courts depend upon
power conferred by congress. It is a matter of legislation. No
discretion is vested in the courts. Congress has the right to
legislate upon the subject, prescribe rules and fix limits and
confer authority where it deems wise in legislating upon the 
subject at hand. The supreme authority is conferred upon the 
immigration officers. The jurisdiction of the court is limited 
to ascertaining whether the petitioners were denied a hearing.</p>
<p>Ekin v. United States, 142 U.S. 650; 
Yamataya v. Fisher, 189 U.S. 86; 
United States v. Ju Toy, 198 U.S. 253; 
Lee Moon Sing v. United States, 158 U.S. 538; 
Chin Yow v. United States, 208 U.S. 8.</p>
<p>An examination of the record which is presented upon this hearing</p>
<p>2.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>established to my mind conclusivly that a fair and 
full hearing was accorded to each and every one of the
petitioners. They were represented by counsel and given
every opportunity of presenting all facts bearing upon their 
qualification. A hearing having been accorded, the court is 
precluded from a re-examination of the issue presented, merely
because it is contended that the conclusion of the immigration 
officers, based upon the testimony presented, was wrong.
Chin You v. United States, supra. 
The petition for writ is denied.</p>
<p>Jeremiah Neterer 
Judge.</p>
<p>FILED IN THE 
U.S. DISTRICT COURT
Western Dist. of Washington. 
SEP of 1913 
Frank L. Crosby, Clerk 
By Emy Deputy</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>