<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>IN THE U.S. DISTRICT COURT OF THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON NORTHERN.DIVISION.</p>
<p>No. 2646</p>
<p>In the matter of the application of K. Gregory et al. for a writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>APPEAL BOND.</p>
<p>KNOW ALL MEN BY THESE PRESENTS: That P. Yakimoff as principal, and Samuel H. Weber, residing at
1509 E. Spruce St. in the City of Seattle, Washington, and Samuel Cohen, residing at 2205 E. Spruce
St. Seattle, Washington, as sureties are held and firmly bound into the United States of America in
the full sum of Two Hundred and Fifty Dollars ($250.00) to be paid to the United States, for which
payment well and truly made, we, and each of us, do bind ourselves, our heirs, executors, and
administrators, jointly and severally, firmly by these presents.</p>
<p>Sealed with our seals and dated this 24th day of Feb, 1914</p>
<p>WHEREAS: P. Yakimoff an alien, a native of Russia, who arrived at the Port of Seattle on 22 day
of Dec 1913 has been held by the Immigration Board ordered the said alien to be deported, and
WHEREAS: the United States District Court for the westen District of Washington, Northern Division
discharged the said alien on a Writ of Habeas Corpus, and WHEREAS: The Court ordered the said alien
be enlarged upon recognizance with surety, for appearance to answer judgement of the appelate Court;
NOW, THEREFORE, the condition of this obligation is such that if the above named principal P
Yakimoff appears to answer and carry out the Judgment of the United States Circuit COurt of Appeals
for the ninth Circuit, of the Appelate Court, then this obligation to be void otherwise to remain in
full force and effect.</p>
<p>Signed and sealed in the presence of </p>
<p></p>
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>