<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0238.004"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Choey et al v. Hamilton. Matter of Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0238.004</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Choey et al v. Hamilton. Matter of Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1888-06"></date>June 1888</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Big, Wong</term>
<term>Choey, Num</term>
<term>Chun, Al</term>
<term>Chung, Tin</term>
<term>Crockett, John S.</term>
<term>Ding</term>
<term>Gong</term>
<term>Jon, Ah</term>
<term>Juin, Ah</term>
<term>Kim, Wa</term>
<term>Kin</term>
<term>Kong</term>
<term>Ling, Chung</term>
<term>Ling, Hong</term>
<term>Pim, Lee</term>
<term>Ring</term>
<term>Sour, Ah</term>
<term>Su, Guan</term>
<term>Suin, Ah</term>
<term>Wie, Song</term>
<term>You, Jon-Ah</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>United States</term>
<term>Washington Territory</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Choey, Num</persName>
<persName>Big, Wong</persName>
<persName>Chun, Al</persName>
<persName>Ding</persName>
<persName>Gong</persName>
<persName>Jon, Ah</persName>
<persName>Juin, Ah</persName>
<persName>Kim, Wa</persName>
<persName>Kin</persName>
<persName>Kong</persName>
<persName>Ling, Chung</persName>
<persName>Ling, Hong</persName>
<persName>Pim Lee</persName>
<persName>Ring</persName>
<persName>Sour, Ah</persName>
<persName>Su, Guan</persName>
<persName>Wie, Song</persName>
<persName>You, Jon-Ah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Hamilton, T.J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Crockett, John S.</persName>
<persName>Newton, W.W.</persName>
<persName>Smittin</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court For The Western District of Washington Northern Division</orgName> 
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="#sab">transcribed, encoded.</change> 
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0238.004"/>

<!-- Almost illegible.  -->

<p>2307</p>

<p>In the District Court of the Second Judicial District of Washington Territory, holding Terms at Tacoma in Said Territory</p>
<p>In the Matter of 
Num Choey et al
On Application for
Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>To the Hon Judge of the above entitled Couch</p>
<p>Your petitioner John S Crockett appearing for <unclear></unclear> Kin, Ah Ring, Num Choey, Al Chun, Ah Jon-Ah You, On Ding-Ah Sour, Hon Ghorn, Ah Gong Ah Kong, Lee Pim, Tin Chung, Guan Su, Wong Big, Ah Juin, no 2 Hong Ling Song Wie Chung Ling, Wa Kim, Ah Yue, Ah Suin no (Chinamen).</p>
<p>Respectfully represents that on the 25 day of June 1888 the hon Judge of Dist Court, granted a writ of Habeas Corpus in a Case wherein one Num Choey Claimed to be illegally detained in the custody of the United States Marshal at McNerto

<!-- next page of the letter  -->

Island in the County of Pierce and Territory of Washington and after hearing the care and being fully admired <unclear></unclear> ordained the said Marshal to either depart said Num Choey to the County from whence the Easre or to release him from custody, Hert as the Thrine of malking said under, the other Chinamen whose names are herein given above were also illegally in the Custody of said Marshal, that while the order of the court was, that Num Choey only was to be deported or released as afore said. The said Marshal was instructed by the Court that he shamed deport, or release al the Chinamen herein named What following in order of the Court the said Marshal has made return showing that the <unclear>clis</unclear> on a day named <unclear></unclear> deport <unclear>said Num Choey</unclear>. What disposition has been made of the other Chinamen herein named your petitioner <unclear></unclear> not know, as no return 

<!-- next page of the letter  -->

has been made by Rad Marshal, concerning his conduct remember said <unclear>circtraetions</unclear></p>
<p>Your petitioner further over that he carried out reparate and district Writ of Habeas Corpus, in the case of Each of the above named Chinamenand that the Court <unclear>woned</unclear> not <unclear></unclear> the same to be filed in forms Panperas Stating that the cases were identical, with that of Nun Choey, aforeward and that in some between would be <unclear></unclear>, by the said Marshal with itn other Chinamen herein named, that would be <unclear></unclear> with Num Choey whose case showed that district as a test of the question mralned as all stand nessan itn same footing and <unclear>beted nepon</unclear> the same propositions of land.</p>
<p>Your petition further over <unclear></unclear> although it said Num Choey Wa, be he is informed deported persant is said order of Count, Many if not al of the above named Chinaman are still in the illegal Custody

<!-- next page of the letter  -->

of said Marshal, who has neither deported or set them free, your petitioner therefor moves the Court</p>
<p>First, that the order of the Court in the case of said Num Choey may be so encaged &amp; change and <unclear>correceter</unclear> as it embrace each and every one of the Chinamen above named.</p>
<p>Second- That the US District Setonary and the US Marshal be ordered by the Court, of the close mortice to be card appear before in said Court and should come <unclear></unclear> said order should not be so encaeged and altered &amp; why the res Marshal, disregarding the restrictions of said Court has neither deported or set at liberty in said Chinamen, excepting the said Num Choey and why he mae not return by ording his relieve in <unclear></unclear> premises, and why he has failed to furnish to said Chinamen, old changed by him the clothing and money required by law to be furnished by him.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
