<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0458.004">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0458.004</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1891">1891</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Richards, N. C.</term>
<term>Yuck, Moy</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Portland, Oregon</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-09" who="#lkw">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, FOR THE DISTRICT OF
WASHINGTON, WESTERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Wah Ni for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>State of Washington,
County of Pierce</p>

<p>:ss.</p>

<p>Moy Yuck being first duly sworn on his oath deposes and 
says:</p>

<p>That he has resided in Portland, Oregon, for over thirty
years last past, and is engaged in business in said city at 246
Yamhill St., as member of the firm of Hop Wah Lung; that he is well
and personally acquainted with Wah Ni and knows that the said Wah
Ni is a member of the firm of Yee Wah &amp; Co., dealers in Chinese
and Japanese merchandise at 254 Morrison Street in Portland, and
that he has been a member of said firm between three and four
years; and deponent further says that he is the Moy Yuck who made
application on behalf of said Wah Ni for a Writ of Habeas Corpus
in the Superior Court of the State of Washington, for the County
of Pierce, and that he made the same for the reason that the said
Wah Ni was not informed by the Collector of Customs or the depu-
ty in charge, that he would not be allowed to land until the night
of the 8th day of May, at about the hour of Five o ' clock, when he
was informed by said Collector of Customs or some other person in
charge that he would not be allowed to come ashore, but would be
forced to remain on said vessel Victoria and return to China and
that said vessel intended to leave on the morning of the 9th of
May at 4 o'clock; and deponent further says that the members of
said firm of which Wah Ni is a member are Moy Ham, Ne Yong and
Charlie Hing, and are doing buisiness at 254 Morrison Street and
have been for abou four years last past; and deponent further 
says that to his own personal knowlege, the said Wah Ni, is a good,
respectable and bona fide Chinese merchant of the United States</p>

<pb/>

<p>and has been for between <del>and</del> three and four years, deponent stat-
ing upon oath that he knows him that time as a merchant and knew him
at lease six years prior to that time and that he still has and re-
tains his interest in said firm and deponent frequently conversed
with him and the members of his saidbfirm, being intimately ac-
quanited with each of them and says that he is a joint owner in 
said firm and as deponent is informed and verily believes has an
interest to the extent of $1000, and that he is still <del>engaged</del> in-
terested in said business and deponent says that the said Wah Ni
is a good, honest, upright and bona fide Chinese merchant of the
United States.</p>

<p>Moy Yuck</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me 
this 7th day of June, 1893</p>

<p>N C Richards</p>

<p>Notary Public in and for Pierce County,
Residing at Tacoma, Washington.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>