<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON NORTHERN
DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE PETITION
OF K. GREGORY, et al.</p>
<p>No. 2646
BRIEF OF PETITIONERS.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Immigration Act of February 20, 1907 is as follows;</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That the decision of the Board of Special Inquiry, herein provided for based upon the
certificate of the examining medical officers shall be final as the the rejection of aliens
afflicted with tuberculosis, or woth a loathsome or dangerous contagious diesease, or with any
mental or physical disability which would bring such aliens within any of the classes excluded from
admission to the United States under this Act.</p>
<p>Sec. 29. of same act is as follows;</p>
<p>Sec. 29- That the Circuit and District Courts of the United States, are hereby invested with full
and concurrent jurisdiction of all causes, civil and criminal arising under the provisions of this
act.</p>
<p>An examination of Sec. 10. will show, that the decisions of teh examining board is final as to
facts which would bring such aliens within any of teh classes excluded by the statue and of course
the examining board could have no jurisdiction over any other facts. It is elementary that when the
Statute prescribes certain essential facts all other facts are excluded. In other words if these
petitioners are not excluded by the Statute they can not by lawfully excluded at all.</p>
<p>It is also elementary that the courts will take jurisdiction in all cases where the Constitution,
or the statuts are violated, and an act of Congress <add>excluding such jurisdiction</add> (if there
would be such an act) would be unconstitutional and void.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>It is also elementary, that an act of congress conferring arbitrary power upon the examining
board, or upon any body would be unconstitutional and void. Congress itself has no such power, but
all acts of congress are subject to the Constitution; arbitrary power cannot be lawfully exercized
within the United States.</p>
<p>Justice Matthew Slate of the Supreme Court of the United States says:</p>
<p>"Any act of the legislature which confers arbitrary power is void."</p>
<p>"The laws and principles upon which our Government rests; forbid the exercise of of arbitrary
power", 
"Acts conferring arbitrary powerr do not belong to the domain of law, <add>and are always
<unclear></unclear> and void."</add></p>
<p>Yick Hopkins, 118 U.S. 356.</p>
<p>There are no lawful grounds for excluding these immigrants. If they can be excluded all
immigrants may be excluded, and the Statute nullified.</p>
<p>All actions outside of the Statute is unwarranted, arbitrary and unconstitutional, and if such
things are permitted, our government ceases to be a government <add>of</add> law and becames a 
government of men.</p>
<p>1st. It appears upon the return that there are no Statutory grounds for excluding petitioners.</p>
<p>2nd. The decision of the board is based upon grounds that are irrelevant, and immaterial, and
outside of the jurisdiction of
<pb></pb>
of the board, and unsupported by evidence, and not true, and it may be added that the assumed facts
are contrary to the knowledge of all well informed persons.</p>
<p>As for instance the Statute does not exclude "because they are farm laborers and there is no work
for them in the United States" This is absurd and foolish. it is a matter of common knowledge that
there is a scarcity of farm laborers in the United States. And of like character is the second
ground. "Because they have but a limited amount of money, insufficient to maintain them during the
winter".</p>
<p>This is an arbitrary assumtion not warranted by facts.</p>
<p>And 3rd- and 4th, grounds are the same. "Because that 800, to a 1000 Russians are unemployed in
Seattle, and thousands of other nationalities in the same conditions, and reports from the Interior
are to the same effect that the supply of common labor is far in excess of demand".</p>
<p>This is discriminating against the Russians, which is unconstitutional, and seeks to charge them
with things they are not responsible. It is also a mistake to assume that farm laborers are common
laborers. They are specialists much needed in the United States.</p>
<p>This is discriminating against the Russians, which is unconstitutional, and seeks to charge them
with things they are not responsible. It is also a mistake to assume that farm laborers are common
laborers. They are specialists much needed in the United States.</p>
<p>"That any addidtion to the unemployed should be guarded against, and alien laborers should not be
permitted to enter the United States at these times".</p>
<p>This is most extraordinary: It is userping all the powers and <add>Function</add> of our
government. It is entirely outside the domain of law, and in the realm of the lawless. If statury
officials are despots, we are in bad shape. The Immigration officers have made this a political
question, and the alleged grounds for excluding the petitioners are politics and not law.</p>
<p>The brief of the respondents contain no authority in conflict
<pb></pb>
with Sec. <add>10</add> of the Statut, Supra.</p>
<p>Your Honor has very properly decided in the Mullah Sing case that, "The jurisdiction of the Court
is limited to ascertaining whether the petitioners were denied a lawful hearing, and whether they
were excluded upon Statutory grounds".</p>
<p>And of like import are all the authorities cited, so far as they are in point. An examination
will show that they conform to Sec. <add>10</add> of the Statute, Supra.</p>
<p>Of course a "HEARING", means a lawful hearing upon statutory grounds.</p>
<p>The contention of the learned counsel for respondents on page 2, and 3, of their brief "THAT IF
PETITIONERS HAVE HAD A HEARING TAHT IS ALL THERE IS TO BE DONE, THAT IT MAKES NO DIFFFERENCE WHETERH
THE HEARING WAS FAIR, OR UNFAIR, LAWFUL OR UNLAWFUL, AND THAT THE STATUTE AND CONSTITUTION ARE
INOPERATIVE, AND DOES NOT CONTROL THE ACTS OF THE RESPONDENT, AND THE PETITIONERS HAVE NO RIGHT
WHICH THE RESPONDENT IS BOUND TO RESPECT".</p>
<p>In other words, the learned counsel content for anarcy lawless ness and uncontrolled action of
Statutory officials.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. of the Immigration act applies to case where the alien has been excluded from admission
to the United States by any law or treaty. (Respondents' brief, page 4)</p>
<p>The learned counsel ignores the provision of the Statute, that an alien must be excluded under
some law of the United States, and he Seems to contend that an alien may be excluded by the
arbitrary act of the examining board, or commissioner. The learned counsel fails to discriminate
between the arbitrary and vicious acts of the Statutory officials, and the just and humane processes
of the law, based
<pb></pb>
on natural justice and the constitution and the laws of the land.</p>
<p>Such reasoning is not in point and not in harmony with the law-the petitioners must be excluded
by the law, if at all and the proceedings prescribed by the immigration acts must be substancially
followed.</p>
<p>There can be no controversy as to the law governing, this case sec. <add>10</add> Supra, states
the law concisely. If the petitionaries were excluded upon statutory grounds there would be no
question about the law in this case; but we contend that they were not excluded upon statutory
grounds. As appears from the return of the respondent, and if our contention is true thee can be no
doubt about the law in the case, and the only issue in this case is as to validity of the grounds of
exclusion as stated in the return of the respondent, and it seems to us that the law is so plain
that citations are superflous.</p>
<p>The learned counsel for respondents say on page 6 7 and 8 of their brief that it is admitted that
petitioners had a lawful hearing before the examining board. This we deny most emphatically, and
contend that the alleged hearing wa not within the law, but entirely outside of the law, and in
contemplation of the law it was no hearing at all. The allege grounds of exclusion are not statutory
nor lawful., Sec <add>10</add>, Supra and not amon the grounds specified by Statute, upon which
aliens may be excluded.</p>
<p>This is the vital issue in the case at bar-.</p>
<p>When Statutory officials go outside of their authority, they cease to be officials, and are
responsible for their acts to the same extend as though they were not officials, but the acts of
wrong doers over which it is the duty of the Courts to exercize supervision
<pb></pb>
Sheriffs, Marshalls, and all persons acting under lawful authority must conform to their lawful
authority., and they exceed their authority at their peril.</p>
<p>ALWAYS IN OPERATION</p>
<p>The constitution and the laws of the land are always in operation, They can not be suspended at
all by <add>any known</add> individual. Niether the government itself-not congress, nor the courts,
nor the Statutory officials, can suspend the law of the land for one instant. They are always in
operation for the protection of all persons within the jurisdiction of the U.S. including aliens,
and it is the duty of the courts first, to enforce the constitution and the laws <add><unclear>alien
under the law</unclear></add> just as sacred as the rigts of others, and if they are excluded upon
any but statutory grounds in the constitution and the laws of the land are violated.</p>
<p>Respectfully submitted,
Parker and Kalina
Attorneys for Petitioners</p>

<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>