<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0162.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Testimony of Dr JM.Morgan </title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
<name n="Hidalgo, Emily" xml:id="he">Emily Hidalgo</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0162.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Testimony of Dr J. M. Morgan </title>
<date when="1886-06-29">June 29, 1886</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Morgan, J.M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-06" who="#eh">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<p>Dr JM.Morgan Sworn</p>

<p> I was called to see a man
lying in the Hall of the house called the
Bay windows <del></del> lying upon his 
back in the North hall of the building
there is two front door to the hall his 
head, part of the shouders underside 
the inner door he head a pillow under 
his head, the man had a wound upon
the right side of his neck he was unconsious 
He breath was laboring there
was no pusation of the radial artery 
by passing my hand on the region 
of the heart there was a very faint flutter 
scarcely perceptiable, I remained until
he died and saw his body after death 
in my opinion the wound caused his 
death did not hear the shot dont know 
how long after when I arrived It <add>was</add> 8 minutes 
of one oclock when <add>a</add> man came to my 
office to go there, he died at one fifty five
oclock</p>

<p>Cross Ex</p>

<p> It <del>was</del> acrosss one block and one <unclear>dead</unclear>
as fast as possible I think not <unclear>our</unclear> three
Minutes after I was called before I got there</p>

<p>The man was lying as follows <add> head rested on</add> outside 
the inner door his body extending East 
reast with a pillow under his head 
saw then <unclear>when</unclear> I first went about 20 
persons and do not know that I can name 
any particular one I paid particular attention

<pb/>

to the Wounded Man I might add by way of 
Correction that I said <unclear>Ruby</unclear> standing in the 
door leaning into the Middle Parlor,</p>

<p>Door in the outside of the hall was open
when I arrived, Saw a Man 5 foot- 8to
10 In - heighth Would weigh aout 160 pounds 
rather broad shoulder hair Sndy X Cardose, 
quite heavy sandy Moustache some gray hair 
in it, balance face shaven smooth appeared to be
fresh showered <unclear></unclear> and  <add>or frontal<unclear></unclear></add> any <unclear></unclear> heavy
the lower jaw, was aso heary, the whole face 
was heary and from the appearance of the
Man I juded him to be rather a rough 
character at the time He had on a pair 
Cheap blue overals, a dark colored coat
had <unclear></unclear> a little ligth thread running through 
the Material flannel shirt had been 
laced up in front, was not when I 
first saw him his Boots were well 
worn one ripped in the eye seem and
heels were worn of upon side as I remmeber
them I dont think the Overalls were
rolled up at the bottom he had no <del></del> hat 
and I saw none in the Hall I passed
a probe in the wound and found that the 
ball passed from the right side across 
and down and inwords beneath the Sternum</p>

<p> I can describe the position of the assailant 
and assailed <del>the wound</del> at the time he
<del></del> received the wound</p>

<p> The assailant was to the right and 

<pb/>

in front it <add> the ball</add> ranged cross and downwards 
<del>crossed and breaking I ha</del> (illustratio to the 
court positiones)</p>

<p> I remaind wath the 
man died which was 1;55 O'Clock Am</p>

<p>As I stated before there was quite 
a crowd there I was working with the 
Man, My first efforts was to see if 
there was no external hemorage or from 
any vessels within reach, Next to restore
the action of the heart failing in that the 
Man died there were several there most of 
them were stranges to me they brougth 
everything I asked for, I was furnished 
with brandy there the party was a stranger
that broughth to me I do not know 
his nane, one man I do know his 
features but not his name </p>

<p>JM Morgan</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me June 29
1886</p>

<p>JJL Peel</p>

<p>Justice of the Peace</p>























<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>