<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0181.035">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Seventy-six Hindus v. Seattle Department of Immigration. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-10">October 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>No. 2532</p>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES
DISTRICT COURT FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF 
WASHINGTON NORTHERN 
DIVISION.
-----
IN THE MATTER OF THE 
UNLAWFUL DETENTION OF 76
HINDOO ALIENS.
-----
BRIEF.</p>
<p>HERBERT W. MEYERS 
ATTORNEY AT LAW 
430-431-432-433 PIONEER BUILDING 
PHONE MAIN 1278 
SEATTLE, WASH. 
Merchants Printing Co., Times Bldg., Seattle</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON 
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the 
Unlawful Detention of 
Seventy-Six Hindoos. : : : No. 2532</p>
<p>. . . . . . . . . .</p>
<p>MEMORANDUM BRIEF OF RESPONDENT.
. . . . . . . . . .</p>
<p>The rule applicable.</p>
<p>We rely upon the decisions of the Supreme Court, cited 
below, as establishing the following propositions, and
respectfully urge that if any case cited by petitioners 
contravenes these doctrines, it is overruled and superseded 
by the decisions of the Supreme Court. We contend the rule 
to be as follows:</p>
<p>The law having confided to the Department and Secretary 
of Labor authority to hear and determine this matter, the 
decision by the Secretary as to every question involved 
is conclusive, and the record of the hearing maybe examined 
by the court in this proceeding only to determine whether 
the hearing contemplated by the statute has been allowed
and whether at said hearing some evidence has been secured 
tending to support the adminstrative decision.
- Ekin v. United, 142 U.S. 650, 35 L. Ed. 1146; 
- Kamataya v. Fisher (Japanese Immigrant Case) 189 U.S. 86, 47 L. Ed. 721;
- United States v. JuToy, 198 U.S. 253, 49 L. Ed. 721; 
- Chin You v. United States, 208 U.S. 8, 52 L. Ed. 369; 
- See also Lem Moore Sing v. United States, 158 U.S. 538, 39 L. Ed. 1082.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>Right to deport on ground that alien 
was likely to become a public charge 
at time of entry.</p>
<p>Section 2 of the Immigration Law forbids the entry of 
any alien "likely to become a public charge". Sections 20 
and 21 provide for the deportation of any alien "who shall 
enter the United States in violation of law, and such as 
become public charges from causes existing prior to landing." 
I am aware of no decision questioning the authority of the 
Secretary of Labor to deport under these Sections any alien
who was "likely" to become a public charge at time of entry", 
whether they had yet actually become a public charge or not. 
So often is this procedure adopted by the Department, as 
appears by the record in this case, has found it necessary 
to adopt the code word "liken" as an abbreviation of the 
phrase "likely to become a public charge at time of entry". 
In the Japanese Immigrant Case, 189 U.S. 86, it appeared 
that the immigrant had been formally admitted several days 
prior to her arrest and deportation. There was nothing to 
show that she had actually become a public charge in the 
meanwhile. Nevertheless she was arrested and deported under
the same procedure followed in this case, as "a pauper and 
person likley to become a public charge", not one who had 
become a public charge. Had she been deportated as an alien
seeking admission into the United States, the procedure 
would have been entirely different (See Sections 24 and 25). 
It can make no difference as to the legal right of the 
Secretary to deport under this charge, that the time 
elapsed in the case just cited was only a few days. The 
<pb></pb>
alien in such case was in the country and if to be deported 
at all it had to be under the provisions of the law looking
to the deportation of an alien already in the country. 
Section 11 of the Act of 1891 (Stat. at Large Vol. 26, 
pp. 1084, 1085) contained very similar provisions to section 
20 of the present act, so the case is directly applicable 
to the present case and is direct authority for the practice 
of the department to deport aliens as "likely to become a 
public charge at time of entry", even though they have not 
actually become public charges.</p>
<p>So also in United States v. Freeman,  175 Fed. 274, 
while other matters were alleged, the decision of the court 
sustaining the deportation of an alien already in the United 
States under the procedure outlined by Sections 20 and 21, 
was based upon the fact the aline was "likely to become 
a public charge at time of entry". And indeed if such is 
the fact, the alien is undoubtedly in the United States "In 
violation of law" and there would no reason why the 
government should wait to until the danger has developed into 
an actual happening. The insertion of the clause as to 
those who do become public charges was doubtless meant to 
meet cases where it could not be said that there was any 
likelyhood of becoming a public charge at time of entry, 
but where such a condition does nevertheless develop from 
circumstances existing at the time of entry.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>The cases cited by petitioner in support of his contention
that Section 20 does not authorize deportation within
three years on the charge of liability to become 
a public charge at time of entry are all beside the 
mark. Gonzales v. Williams, 192 U.S. 1, merely 
determines the status of one who was a native of Porto 
Rico prior to its acquisition by the United States. 
Sprung v. Morton, 182 Fed. 330, Ex parte Saraceno, 182 
Fed. 955, Lewis v. Frick, 189 Fed. 146, United States 
v. Tsuji Suekichi, 199 Fed. 750, all relate to the 
right of aliens who had been domiciled in this country
for over three years, and who were seeking to return 
here after a temporary absence. The holding that the 
immigration law does not apply to them on their reentry, 
has obviously no bearing on the correct interpertation 
of Section 20 explicitly authorizing deportation
for illegal entry (including original liability 
to become a public charge) at any time within three
years from the date of the original entry.</p>
<pb></pb> 
<p>The Cedula or Head Tax and other documentary 
evidence touching entry or residence in Manilla.</p>
<p>At the time of drawing up the return, and until just 
before argument, I did not have an opportunity to examine 
the warrants of the Secretary ordering deportation, and
therefore placed an undue emphasis on the charge of an 
original entry into the Philippines without examination. 
The final warrants of deportation, on which the aliens 
are now held, show that the Secretary did not base his 
ruling upon this, but upon the liability to become a public 
charge at time of entry. Thus the question as to examination
at that time is of minor importance and if they were examined 
it is only entitled to such weight as it may carry as tending
to show that at such time they were not likely to become 
public charges. Nevertheless the presumption arising from 
the absence of the certificate still holds, and in every 
instance the Secretary was entitled to consider this absence 
as a circumstance tending to show an irregular entry and 
hence doing away with any favorable presumption as to 
earning ability which might arise from a regular entry.</p>
<p>I have been unable to secure a copy of the local laws 
government this matter, but by a conversation with Frank A. 
Greene, Esq., an attorney of this city , who practiced for 
several years in the Philippines, and who was connected 
with the War Department which had charge of the collection 
of this tax, I am informed that this was a tax levied on 
every male person, having no connection by law with the
entry or regularity of the entry of the person into the
Islands. This being true, I do not think this court has any
<pb></pb> 
further concern with the matter. Its collection was not by 
the immigration service and any custom which may have grownn 
up by which those collecting it accepted a certificate of the 
immigration officers as proof of the period of residence of 
an alien paying the tax was a matter of evidence which 
respondents failed to present to the Department at the 
time of hearing and of which they certainly cannot avail 
themselves at this hearing. But as Your Honor asked for 
information at that point, I will say that as nearly as I 
can ascertain, there did exist in Manilla, even prior to 
the promulgation of Rule 14 of the Rules, November 1911 
(See p. 32), a custom of giving an alien on landing an 
informal certificate, and that the collecters of the cedula 
or internal revenue head tax, would often ask an alien for 
this certificate at the time of collecting the head tax in 
order to ascertain for how long a period they should collect 
the head tax. But Mr. Green informs me that any one whatsoever 
could get a cedula or head tax receipt by paying for 
the same.</p>
<p>This tax which applies to every one in the Philippines 
and is confined to the Philippines is of course to be 
carefully distinguished from the head tax imposed by Section 
1 of the Immigration Act, which is in a different amount 
imposed on all aliens entering the United States, is a
alien on the vessel bringing in the alien, and which as a 
matter of fact is generally paid to the Government in a 
lump sum by the transportation company.</p>
<p>Attached to petitioners' brief presented to this court 
are various documents tending more or less clearly to show 
<pb></pb>
that the aliens referred to therein had been before the 
immigration authorities at Manilla. Similar documents are
contained in the affidavits which he forwarded to the
Secretary at Washington. They are also referred to, though
not set out at length in the transcript of the evidence 
which was forwarded to Washington. It must therefore be
assumed that they were given what weight they were entitled
to in reaching the decision of the Secretary. But as noted
before this whole question is of minor importance in view
of the fact that the warrants of deportation did not give 
clandestine entry as their basis, but liability to become
a public charge at time of entry. </p>
<p>The evidence.</p>
<p>While the ultimate decision in this matter was made
by the Secretary of Labor from the transcript of the
evidence and proceedings at the Seattle hearings, and from 
the affidavits contained in the brief of the petitioners
addressed to the Secretary, yet there is in the record a
resume of the evidence from the standpoint of the
Commissiner, which resume was transmitted to the Secretary, 
and which is borne out by the transcript of the actual 
evidence heard. This resume does not of course contain or 
refer to all the evidence, but for the purposes of Your
Honor at the present time this is not necessary. It does
show all that need be shown, to-wit: that there was some
evidence that each one of these Hindus at the time of his
entry into the United States (the Philippine Islands) was 
likely to become a public charge. There having been a
<pb></pb> 
hearing and an opportunity for the petitioners to be heard
and to present their evidence, and some evidence, however
slight, having been introduced in support of the ruling of
the Secretary of Labor, the matter is settled and the writ
of habeas corpus will not issue out of this court, any more
than it would to review a conviction and sentence of a state 
court in a matter in which it had jurisdiction. Under the
decisions of the Supreme Court, the hearing before the 
Secretary is as much due process of law, as the hearing
before any court.</p>
<p>Respectfully submitted,</p>
<p>C.F. Riddell 
United States Attorney.</p>
<p>E B Brockway</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>