<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the United States District Court in and for the Western District
of Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the 
Petition of Albert H. Young
and Kamasaburo Sugiuro alias
B.K. Sugiurd for a writ of 
habeas corpus. } No. 2504
Petition for Writ of
Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>To the Honorable Edward E. Cushman, Judge of the above entitled
court:</p>
<p>The petition of Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro,
alias B.K. Sugiuro, for a writ of habeas corpus in the above entitled
casue respectfully shows, to-wit:</p>
<p>I.
That the defendants and each of them are unlawfully imprisoned,
detained, confined and restrained of their liberty by
Joseph R.H. Joacoby, United States Marshall in and for the Western
District of Washington, at the County Jail of King County in the
State of Washington within said district, under an alleged, pretended
and illegal commitment under process in the above entitled
court.</p>
<p>II.
That said imprisonment, detention, confinement and
restraint are illegal and in violation of the Constitution of the
United States and of the several treasties between the sovereignties
of the United States and Japan in this, to-wit: That at Seattle
within the district and court aforesaid on or about the 4th day
of December 1912, the petitioners were indicted by the
Grand Jury sitting in and for said district for an alleged violation
of the White Slave Traffic Act, that your said petitioners
were charged in that indictment, first, with a consumtated violation
of the act itself as the same is set forth in counts one and two
thereof, and secondly, with a conspiracy between themselves and
the other defendants mentioned herein to violate the said act.
That said indictment was number 2347 in the files of the
above entitled court and was in words and figures as follows, to wit:</p>
<fw>1</fw>
<pb/>
<p>"United States of America
Northern Division 
Western District of Washington } ss. No. 2347</p>
<p>The Grand Jurors of the United States of America, duly
expaneled, sworn and charged to enguire within and for the
Northern Division of the Western District of Washington, upon
their oaths, present:</p>
<p>Count I
That heretofore, <del><unclear/></del> <add>to-wit</add> on or about the 13th day of August,
A.D. 1912, one Albert H. Young, one Kamasaburo Sugiuro, alias 
B. K. Sugiuro, one Shotoro Washio, one Kayama Ito and one K. Uneda,
did wilfully, unlawfully, and feloniously and knowing transport
and cause to be transported, and aid and assist in obtaining transportation
for, and in transpoerting in Inter State Commerce, from
the city of Seattle in the State and Northern Division of Washington,
District of Washington, to San Francisco, in the State of
Californi, by means of a certain common carrier engaged in interstate
commerce, to wit: by means of the ships of the Pacific
Steamship Company, a corporation, a certain women, to-wit: One Hana
Sato, for the purpose of prostitution, whereby the said woman Hana
Ito was transported in interstate commerce from said city of
Seattle, State of Washington, to the said city of San Francisco,
in the state of California for the purpose of prostitution; contrary
to the form of the statute in such case made and provided
against the peace and dignity of the United States of America.</p>
<p>Count II.
And the Grand Jurors aforesaid, upon their oaths aforesaid,
do further present:</p>
<p>That heretofore, <add>to-wit</add> on or about the 13th day of August,
A.D. 1912, Albert H. Young, Kamasburo Sugiuro, alias B.K.
Sugiuro, Shotoro Washio, Kayama Ito and K. Uneda did wilfully,
unlawfully and feloniously, knowingly persuade, induce, entice
and coerce, and cause to be persuaded, <add>induced</add>, enticed and coercing, a certian
woman, to-wit: Hana Sato, to go from the city of Seattle, in
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
the state of Washington, and in the Northern Division, District
of Washington, to the city of San Francisco, in the state of California,
in interstate commerce, for the purpose of prostitution,
and with the intent and purpose on the part of the said Albert H. 
Young, Kamasaburo Sujiuro, alias B.K. Sugiuro, Shotoro Washio,
Kayama Ito and K., Uneda, that the said women Hana Sato should
engage in adn giver herself up to the practice of prostitution, and
that the said Albert H. Young, Kamasaburo Sugiuro, alias B.K. 
Sugiro, Shotoro Washio, Kayama Ito, and K. Uneda, did thereby
knowingly cause and <del>did</del> <add>aid and</add> assist in causing said women, Hana Sato,
to go and be transported and carried as a passenger in interstate
commerce over the steamship line of the said Pacific Coast steamship
Company, a corporation, from the city of Seattle, State of
Washington to the city of San Francisco, state of California, for
the purpose of prostitution; that the said Pacific Coast Steamship
Companh is and then and there was, as the said Albert H, Young,
<add>Kamasaburo Sugiuro, alias B.K. Sugiuro, Shotoro Washio, Kayama Ito, and K. Uneda <unclear/></add>
well know a common carrier engaged in the business of transporting
and carrying passengers in interstate commerce from the state of
Washington to the state of California, and did act in such capacity
in bringing said Hana Sato from said city of Seattlee and state of
Washington, to <add>said city</add> San Francisco in the state of California, which is
contrary to the form and statutes in such cases made and provided
and against the peace and dignity of the United States of America.</p>
<p>Count III.
And the grand jurors aforesaid, upon their oaths aforesaid,
do further present:</p>
<p>That heretofore, and on or about the 25th day of July,
A.D. 1912, one Albert Young, one Kamasburo Sugiuro, alias B.K.
Sugiuro, Shotoro Washio, Kayama Ito and K. Uneda did knowingly,
wilfully, wickedly, unlawfully, corruptly and feloniously, conspire,
combine, confederate, and agree among themselves, and with divers
other persons, whose names are to the grand jurors unknown, and
whose names for that reason cannot be herein stated, to commit an
offence against the United States, to-wit: that the said Albert H. 
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
Young, Kamasburo Sugiuro, alias S.K. Sugiuro, Shotoro Washio
Yakama Ito and K. Uneda, then and there knowingly, wilfully,
wickedly, and unlawfully, corruptly and feloniously, did conspire,
combine, confederate and agree among themselves and with divers
other persons, whose names are to the grand jurors unknown, knowingly,
wilfully, wickedly, unlawfully and feloniously, to persuade,
induce, entice and coerce, and to cause to be persuaded, induced,
enticed and coercing and to aid and assist in persuading, inducing,
enticing and coercing, and to transport and cause to be transported
and to aid and assist in obtaining transportation and transporting
a women, to-wit: one Hana Sato to go as a passengar in interstate
commerce from the city of Seattle in the state of Washington, to
the city of San Francisco, in the state of California, for the
purpose of prostitution, and with the intent on the part of the
said Albert H. Young, Kamasburo Sugiuro, alias B.K. Sugiuro,
Shotoro Washio, Kayama Ito and K. Uneda, that the said woman
Hana Sato should engage in the practice of prostitution.</p>
<p>Count IV.
And the grand jurors aforesaid upon their oaths aforesaid
do further present:</p>
<p>That during the continuance and in accordance with and
in pursuance <add>to</add> and to effect the object of, said conspiracy, the
said Albert Young, Kamasaburo Sugiuro,alias B.K. Sugiuro, Shotoro
Washio, Kayama Ito and K. Uneda, on or about the 12th day of
August A.D. 1912, did go to the ticket office of the Pacific Coast
Steamship Company, in the city of Seattle, county of King and
state of Washington, and Northern Division of the Western District 
of Washington, to arrange with the said ticket agent for transportation
and ticket from the city of Seattle, Washington to San
Francisco, California, on the steamship line of the said Pacific
Coast Steamship Company, to be used by <del>one</del> <add>said</add>, Hana Sato, and did
then and there purchase and obtain transportation and tickets,
whereby the said woman Hana Sato, was transported and carried as
a passenger in interstate commerce from the said city of Seattle
<fw>4</fw>
<pb/>
in the state of Washington, Northern Divison of the Western District 
of Washington, to the city of San Francisco, in the
state of California for the purposes of prostitution, contrary to
the form of the statute in such cases made and provided and against
the peace and dignity of the United States of America."</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>