<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0487.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>In Re: Petition of Ham Hung Wah by Tom Sing for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Yu, Jingming." xml:id="jy">Jingming Yu</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0487.002</idno>
<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">In Re: Petition of Ham Hung Wah by Tom Sing for Writ of Habeas Corpus. </title>
<date when="2022-06-07">June 7, 2022</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Immigration</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1904-10">October 1904</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Ham Hung Wah</term>
<term>Tom Sing</term>
<term>Thomas M. Fisher</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Washington</term>
<term>Ford Townsend, Washington</term>
<term>304 Wyoming St, Butte, Silver Bow County, Montana</term>
<term>Montana</term>
<term>Utah</term>
<term>Boseman, Montana</term>
<term>China</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Tom Sing</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Ham Hung Wah</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Gilbert, W. B.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Ninth Judicial Circuit Court</orgName> 
<placeName>District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#jy">transcribed and encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>  

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0487.002"/>

<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, NINTH CIRCUIT. &amp;c</p>

<p>To the Honorable William B. Gilbert, Judge of the Circuit Court of the Ninth Circuit
Ham Hung Wah, by Tom Sing, his Guardian in this behalf respectfully shows, That he the said Ham Hung Wah is now unlawfully detained, confined and restrained of his liberty by Thomas M. Fisher, Chinese Inspector at Fort Townsend in the State of Washington in the said Ninth Circuit.
That the said detention, confinement and restraint are illegal in this that Your Petitioner Ham Hung Wah is a <del/> native born citisen of the United States, having been born of parents domiciled in the United States and subject to the jurisdiction thereof at three hundred and four (304) Wyoming Street in the City of Butte, Silver Bow County <add>State of Montana,</add> in said Circuit, in 1893. That his parents were then permanently domiciled in the United States as alien residents therein, not appointed, employed or engaged in any diplomatic or other service of any foreign Prince, Potentate, Republic or Government but that the said Tom Sing who is the Father of him the said Ham Hung Wah was then a laborer residing in the United States of Chinese descent and by virtue of having complied with the requirements of the Treaties between the United States and China and the <unclear>Iowa</unclear> in such case made and provided and having the Laborer's Certificate therein required was and is entitled to be and remain lawfully within the United States.
That the said Ham Hung Wah in the year 1900 at the request of his grand parents was sent to China for the purpose of visiting them and entering a Chinese school where he remained until 1904 when he returned to his native country as he well might and where he is entitled to all the rights and privileges of all other American Citizens and your petitioner says taht his Father Tom Sing with his <unclear>wife Is</unclear> lay since his birth have resided in Utah and Montana <unclear>continuously</unclear> far and now reside in Bozeman, Montana.
And your petitioner further says that upon his return from China in 1904, to Fort Townsend in the State of Washington he was arrested and detained by the Chinese Inspector in Charge at said Fort Townsaid in the said State of Washington in said Circuit under some pretense of right or authority so to do by virtue of some law of the United States and is now so held, imprisoned, detained and confined unlawfully by him the said Thomas M. Fisher who is now such Chinese Inspector in Charge and acting as such and who assumes by virtue of some pretended authority of the United States to have the right not only to so detain and imprison him <del/> without bail or mainprise and forcibly and against the will of your petitioner to depart him from the United Stataes to the Chinese Empire as being an alien Chinese person seeking unlawfully to land in the United States whereas in truth and in fact said Chinese Inspector has no such right or authority because your petitioner says he was born in the United States, is subject to the jurisdiction thereof and is citizen of the same and entitled upon Writ of Habeas Corpus or otherwise to have his said citizenship judicially determined by due process of law and not arbitrarily by executive or ministeral officers.
And your petitioner says that he is not advised as to what petitioner inquisition has been made or upon what evidence the said Thomas M. Fisher has arrived at his conclusion that your petitioner was unlawfully seeking to enter the United States nor has he had any opportunity to hear the testimony of or cross examine any witnesses upon that subject nor has any hearing been accorded him before any competent tribunal to establish to its satisfaction his citizenship of an right to enter the United States and the said Thomas M. Fisher is threatening to and will unless restrained by the <unclear/> of the Writ of Habeas Corpus or some other appropriate remedy deport your petitioner from his native land without giving him an opportunity to establish before a competent tribunal his lawful right to enter and remain therein.
Your Petitioner says that he was informed by the said Chinese Inspector or his assitants that his right to enter the United States was denied and his application therefor rejected and that he had two days in which to appeal, that he was more than eight hundred (800) miles from his home, was detained by the said Inspector, that he telegraphed to his Father at Bozeman, Montana the fact os his rejection but did not receive an answer to his despatch in time to avail himself of such right to appeal within the two days designated and his effort to appeal <unclear>come</unclear> too late.
That he was a child twelve years old, without parents, guardian or lawyer by reason whereof his desire to show his right to enter the United States before asid<!--Spelling error in document--> Executive officer, came to naught.
Wherefore your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus may be granted, directed to Thomas M. Fisher, Chinese Inspector in Charge at Fort Townsend in the State of Washington. <del/> as aforesaid, commanding him to have the body of said Ham Hung Wah before Your Honor at a time anad place <add>therein to be specified,</add> or before a Judge Holding the Circuit Cour tof the United Stataes for the District of Montana, at Helena, in mid District, to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by the Judge hearing the same, concerning said Ham Hung Wah, together with the time and cause of his detention, and said writ, and that he, the said Ham Hung Wah may be restored to his liberty
Dated this <unclear>13th</unclear> day of October, 1904.</p>

<p>Tom Sing <!--Signed,-->
PETITIONER.</p> 

<p>United States of America,
District of Montana,</p>

<p>Tom Sing, father of the foregoing Ham Hung Wah, and his natural guardian, upon his corporal oath doth say and swear; That is has heard read the foregoing petition, of Ham Hung Wah by this <unclear>affiant,</unclear> as his guardian, and knows the con- <del/> tents thereof, and <add>that</add> upon his information and belief so much of the <unclear>names</unclear> sets forth the unlawful detention and restraint of his liberty by Thomas M. Fisher, and so much of the same as sets forth the length of time said Ham Hung Wah resided in China, and so much of the same as states the law applicable to the rights of the said Ham Hung Wah, and so much of the same as states the intent to deport him the said Ham Hung Wah, is true; and so to the other matters set forth in the said petition, the same is true of his own knowledge, and that, if an opportunity shall be afforded, he will be able, by indubitable proof from Anglo-Saxon and Chinese witnesses, to establish to the satisfaction of the court the right of the said Ham Hung Wah to enter and remain in the United States.
And further sayeth not.</p> 
<p><!--Signed--> Tom Sing</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before as this Third day of October, 1904.
<unclear>A.B. McPharson</unclear><!--Signed-->
U.S. Commissions</p>

<p>United States of America,
District of Washington.</p>

<p>Ham Hung Wah, petitioner in the foregoing matter, being first duly sworn, on his oath deposed and says: That so much of said petition as sets forth the detention, confinement and restraint of his liberty, and that he was sent from the United States to China in the year 1900, and remained there until 1904, and so much thereof as relates to his arrest and detention by the Chinese Inspector at Fort Townsend, Washington; and so much thereof as sets forth his ignorance of any trial or testimony had against this petitoner, and that he has had no hearing before any court, and that he is threatened to be deported from the United States, and that his right to enter the same has been denied, and his application rejected, and that he had two days within which to appeal, and that he was distant from his home, and that he telegraphed to his father the fact of his rejection, and did not receive an answer to his dispatch in time to avail himself of such right of appeal, is true, of his own knowledge, and that as to the other matters and things set forth in asid<!--spelling error in document--> petition, the same is true to his best knowledge, information and belief; and if an opportunity shall be afforded, your petitioner, he believes he will be able to establish by competent, credible and conclusive proof his citizenship of the United States, and his right to enter therein, and remain without let or hindrance from any ministerial or executive officer or any other authority or person whatsoever. And further sayeth not.</p>
<p>同和<!--Signed(Tong He)--></p>

<p>Subscribed and sword to before me this Second day of October, 1904.
<unclear/>
ROTARY PUBLIC IN AND FOR THE STATE OF WASHINGTON RESIDING AT PORT TOWNSEND</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>