<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0233.013"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Sam Plastino v. Henry M. White. Testimony Evidence</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0233.013</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Sam Plastino v. Henry M. White. Testimony Evidence.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1912-02-07">February 7, 1912</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1912-02"></date>February 1912</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Walter P. Harris</term>
<term>Thomas M. Fisher</term>
<term>Sam Plastino</term>
<term>Joseph Plastino</term>
<term>Michele Plastino</term>  
<term>Golide Cardiff</term>
<term>W.H. Han</term>
<!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Spokane, Washington</term> 
<term>Naples, Italy</term>
<term>New York</term>
<term>Altilia, Italy</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>San Francisco, California</term><!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sam Plastino</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known --> 
<persName>Adam Beeler</persName>
<persName>John J. Sullivan</persName>
<persName>Jospeh M. Glasgow</persName>
<persName>John King</persName>
<persName>Tolman</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Clay Allen</persName>
<persName>Albert Moodie</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022" who="AS">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0233.013"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE AND LABOR</p>
<p>Immigration Service.</p> 
<p>Spokane, Washington, Feb 7, 1912.</p> 
<p>Walter P. Harris,
Stenographer.</p> 
<p>Thomas M. Fisher,
Examining Inspector</p> 
<p>-----</p>
<p>In the matter of the arrest of 
SAM PLASTINO</p> 
<p>------</p> 
<p>Brother of above called as a witness:</p> 
<p>Witness, sworn, testified as follows:</p> 
<p>Q BY INSPECTOR FISHER. (To Joe Plastino, brother of Sam Plastino).
Your brother, Sam Plastino, has been given a hearing to show his right
to be in, or remin in the United States. He states that he wanted
an attorney to prepresent him, provided you will furnish the same?
A (By Joe Plastion) I am through with him for good and will have
nothing to do with hiring an attorney for him.</p>

<p>MICHELE PLASTINO, (father of Sam Plastino), called
and sworn, testified as follows:</p> 
<p>Joe Plastino, Interpreter in Italian.</p> 
<p>Q What is your name? A Michele Plastino.</p> 
<p>Q Where were you born? A Italy.</p>
<p>Q Of what country are you now a citizen or subject? A I have taken my
first papers as a United States citizen.</p> 
<p>Q When did you take those papers? A About twenty years ago.</p> 
<pb></pb> 
<p>Michele Plastino
(Sam Plastino Case)</p>
<p>Q Have you those paprs now? A Yes, they are home.
(Witness agrees to bring papers to Inspector Richardson's office at a lat-
er date).</p>
<p>Q Did you ever take any steps towards getting your final papers?
A I was going to try but I went back to Italy and then back to the
United States again.</p> 
<p>Q When did you first come to the United States? A I think in 1881.</p> 
<p>Q When did you go back to Italy? A I went back to Italy to sell some
property which is still there and a little later returned to the United
States at the port of New York about twelve years ago.</p> 
<p>Q On what boat did you come to the United States at that time? A I
don't know the name but it was a German boat.</p> 
<p>Q Who accompanied you at that time? A My son, Sam Plastino.</p>
<p>Q Any one else? A Also my wife.</p> 
<p>Q How was Sam Plastino at that time? A About eleven I think.</p>
<p>Q How old is he now? A About 24.</p> 
<p>Q Of what country is Sam Plastino a citizen? A He took out first papers
in this country; I don't know just when.</p>
<p>Q Has Sam Plastino to your knowledge ever been out of the United States
since he entered with out? A No, not to my knowledge.</p> 

<p>STATEMENT BY INSPECTOR FISHER:</p>  
<p>I examined the naturalization records in U. S. District Court for the
Eastern District of Washington and find that the record shows that Sam
Plastino claimed he was born in Altilia, Italy, September 7, 1886, and came from
Naples, Italy, on the s. s. "Abriundra" to the port of New York about the 10th
day of June, 1897, and declared his intention to become a citizen of the
United States before W. H. Han, Clerk of the U. S. District Court at Spokane,
Washington, March 22, 1911.</p> 
<p>Sam Plastino was convicted after a hearing in the U. S. District Court
at Tacoma, Washington, for violating the White-Slave Traffic Act in that he
assisted in the transportation of one Goldie Cardiff from Seattle, Washington,
to San Francisco, California, for purposes of prostitution. The evidence
adduced at the hearing showed that Sam Plastino had received the earnings of
Goldie Cardiff, prostitute, for several years; that he had also received the
earnings of two other prostitutes prior and subsequent to his meeting Goldie
Cardiff.</p> 
<p>After considering the testimony adduced in this case, I find Sam Plastino
is an Alien, a citizen of Italy; that he entered the United States through the
port of New York during the year 1897; that he has been found receiving,
sharing in, and deriving benefit in whole, or in part, from the earnings of
a prostitute after his entry into the United States. I therefore respect-
fully recommend his deportation to the country whence he came or of which he
is a citizen or subject, in conformity with law.</p>
<pb></pb> 
<p>SAM PLASTINO</p> 
<p>I hereby certify that the foregoing is a true transcript of the testimony
as dictated to me by Inspector Fisher.</p> 
<p>(Sg) Walter P. Harris 
S t e n o g r a p h e r.</p> 
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>