<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0217.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ng Kew Tung vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0217.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ng Kew Tung vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-01">January 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Brewer</term>    
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Day</term>
<term>Fishburne, George P.</term>
<term>Landon, Daniel</term>
<term>Laube, William T.</term>
<term>Monroe, H. A.</term>
<term>Peckham</term>
<term>Tock, Get</term>
<term>White, Henry M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Walla Walla, Washington</term>
<term>King County, Washington</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Ng Kew</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Daniel Landon</persName>
<persName>William T. Laube</persName>    
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>George P. Fishburne</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western District Court of the United States, Northern Division.</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In re the Application of 
Ng Kew Tung, for admission
to the United States. )
NO. 2897
BRIEF.</p>

<p>In the above case, a Chinese boy, 15 years old, was 
refused admission to the United States by Henry M. White, 
Immigration Commissioner; an appeal was taken to the Secretary 
of Commerce and Labor and the decision of the said Commissioner
was affirmed. Get Tock,  a Chinese merchant of Walla Walla,
Washington and the father of the applicant then made application
for a writ of habeas corpus, alleging among other irregularities 
that the finding was not sustrained by the evidence and that 
the proceeding was not fairly conducted.</p>
<p>Permit us to state, that at the original hearing of the 
application for admission by the Commissioner of Immigration, 
the applicant was without counsel and it was only after the 
application had been denied that he was represented.</p>
<p>In support of the petition for a writ of habeas corpus, 
the petitioner offered to show by the Commissioner of 
Immigration, that a fair and impartial hearing had not been 
given the applicant; that in fact, the matter had never been 
brought to the attention of the Commissioner; also offered 
to show by H. A. Monroe, Chinese Inspector, who had immediate
charge of this case, that in his opinion, the applicant looked 
like a son of Get Tock, but that he was compelled to refuse the 
application on account of certain alleged statements, as shown 
by an interpretation many years ago; petitioner also offered
to show by the record that the applicant was not given a fair 
<pb/>
or impartial hearimg; that there was no evidence from which 
the Commissioner could make his finding and that any conclusion
reached by him was not taken from the record, but only fro 
mere suspicion and speculation; that the Commissioner of 
Immigration in refusing to consider the record and testimony 
of the case in order to support an erroneous interpretation made 
by a Chinese Interpreter over eight years ago was guilty of an 
abuse of discretion.</p>
<p>The attorneys for the Government objected to any 
testimony as above suggested, holding that the Court had no 
power whatever to consider the same unless the offer was one 
which would show a fraud and conspiracy by the Government 
officials in denying the application for admission.</p>
<p>The first case cited was that of the United States vs.
Ju Toy, reported in 49 Law. Ed. opinions of the Supreme Court
of the United States, p. 1040, being 198 United States reports,
p. 252. This is probably the leading case in support of the 
Government's contention, but it surely goes no further than to 
hold that a finding of the Commissioner of Immigration and the 
Secretary of Commerce and Labor can not be reviewed unless there 
has been some abuse of authority or that there has not been a 
fair and impartial proceeding.</p>
<p>The other case cited by the Government is in the matter 
of Tang Tun et ux, reported in vol. 168 of Fed. Reports, p. 488.
This case only holds that a Court can not entertain habeas corpus
proceedings based solely upon the merit of the applicant's 
case, but there must also be shown an abuse of discretion. A 
reading of the case, however, will show that the Court went into 
the record very fully, examined the evidence carefully, to 
ascertain whether or not there had been an abuse of discretion by 
the Commissioner.</p>
<p>And the only matter before the Court at this time is, 
whether or not the petitioner should have the opportunity to 
show that there was not a fair proceeding and hearing and 
<pb/>
whether or not there was any abuse or discretion on the part 
of the Commissioner.</p>
<p>Again in the case of Chin Low vs. the United States, 
(52 Law. Ed. 369) which at first glance might support the 
Government's objection, a more careful examination shows that 
the case only decides that the Court should not go into the 
merits until it becomes apparent that there was not a fair and 
full hearing of the application.</p>
<p>In the later case of Tang Tun and Leung Kum Wui, 
petitioners, vs. Harry Edsell, Chinese Inspector, (56 Law. Ed. 672)
the case was heard on the question of whether from the record, 
including statements, comments and references thereto, there had 
been a fair and impartial hearing and whether or not there 
had been any abuse of discretion on the part of the Commissioner.</p>
<p>In the case of Lewis vs. Frick, reported in 58 Law. Ed.
p. 967, the finding of the Secretary of Commerce and Labor was 
held binding only because there had been no allegation or 
showing that the hearing was not fairly and impartially conducted.</p>
<p>Any examination of these later cases shows that there is a 
growing tendency on the part of the Courts to insist that 
applicants be given a fair and full hearing and that the 
Commissioner of Immigration should base his decision upon the 
records, and evidence rather than <add>upon</add> hearsay and mere suspicion. In 
the first case cited, the United State vs. Ju Toy, in the dissenting
opinion of Justice Brewer, which was concurred in by Justices 
Peckham and Day, the reason for this is made obvious. The rules
of the department, as explained by Justice Brewer, tend to 
limit the rights of the applicants for citizenship. Hence, the 
Courts are insisting more strictly to the proposition that an  
impartial hearing be had and that the record show that there is 
no abuse of discretion on the part of the Commissioner.</p>
<pb/>
<p>We call attention particularly to the case of ex parte 
Lam Pui, 217 Fed. 456, reported in the advance sheet issued Dec. 
24, 1914, which we attach hereto. This case not only supports teh 
contention made that a finding of the Secretary of Commerce and 
Labor for deportation is final only when the proceeding is 
fairly conducted as shown by the record, and otherwise, but also 
sets out that the finding must be sustained by the evidence 
and that the Court on habeas corpus, though it may not weigh the 
evidence may determine whether, when tested by sound and well 
settled principles, there was sufficient evidence to show 
that the proceeding was not conducted in an arbitrary 
and summary manner and that the applicant, at least had a fair 
hearing in accordance with the elementary rules of procedure, 
obtaining in civilized nations.</p>
<ab>Respectfully submitted,
Daniel Landon <lb/>
William F Laube</ab>
<pb/>

<p>SERVICE of the witing Brief by delivery of a 
copy to the undersigned is hereby acknowledged this 4th day of January 1915</p>
<ab>G. P. Fishburne <lb/>
Attorney for Respondent</ab>    

<p>No 2897.</p>

<p>IN THE 
District Court
Of the United States
of Washington
Western Division</p>
<p>In re the Application of 
Ng Kew Tung, for admission 
to the United States. Plaintiff 
vs. 
<gap/>
Defendant</p>

<p>BRIEF.</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. District Court, 
Western Dist. of Washington, 
NORTHERN DIVISION
JAN 5 - 1915</p>
<ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk
By <gap/> Deputy</ab>

<p>SERVICE OF PAPERS IN THIS CASE MAY BE MADE ON 
DANIEL LANDON
Attorney for 
Proctor for }
1054-5-6 EMPIRE BLDG.,
SEATTLE, KING COUNTY, WASHINGTON
PHONE MAIN 4602</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>