<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0433.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>In the matter of James A. Balch on Habeas Corpus Proceedings. Complaint and Commitment</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>
<name n="Ham, Bethany R." xml:id="brh">Bethany R. Ham</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0433.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">In the matter of James A. Balch on Habeas Corpus Proceedings. Complaint and Commitment</title>
<date when="1888-06-20">June 2nd, 1888</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Puget Sound Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>King Frontier Justice</collection>
<idno>Case No 6023</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1883-06">June 1883</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Guilland, David</term>
<term>Morrison, W. F.</term>
<term>Clark, J. O.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Yakima County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Balch, James A.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Waughop, J. W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Navarre, J. A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the Third Judicial District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
<change when="2022-07" who="#brh">reviewed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">
<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0433.013"/>
<p>COMPLAINT. <add>AND COMMITMENT</add></p>

<p>TERRITORY OF WASHINGTON,
County of Yakima
<del>In the matter of <gap></gap> an insane person</del></p>

<p>David Guilland, being duly sworn, on oath, says there is in said county an
insane <del>(idiotic)</del> person, whose name is James A. Balch, who, by reason of insanity <del>(or idiocy )</del>, is
unsafe to be at large (or is suffering under mental derangement) ; and affiant therefore asks that said person be arrested and taken
before a Judge of Probate within said county for examination.</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 2nd day
of June A.D. 1883
J.A. Navarre, Probate Judge.</p>

<p>D. Guilland</p>

<p>COMMITMENT.</p>

<p>James A. Balch the person named in the foregoing affidavit, being this day brought
before me, Judge of the Probate Court Yakima county, for examination on a charge of
insanity, and no jury being demanded either by him or by anyone in his behalf, and having heard the testimony of
David Guilland <del>and</del> <add>in Yakima City</add>witness<del>es</del> who has
been acquinted with the accused during the time of the alleged insanity; and Drs. W. F. Morrison
and J. O. Clark who <add>respectable and</add> legally qualified physicians, after hearing the testimony of witnesses,
after a personal examination of the accused, having made the certificate by law required; and being myself satisfied that the
said James A. Balch is insane <del>(or idiotic)</del> and being further satisfied of the truth of all
the matters set forth in the certificate of said Physicians, I do hereby order the said James A. Balch
to be confined in the Hospital for the Insane at Fort Steilacoom, and
the Sheriff of this county is charged with the execution of this order.</p>

<p>The seal of the said probate court
Witness my hand and seal this 2nd day of June 1883
James A. Navarre
Probate Judge of Yakima County W.T.</p>

<figure><p>Yakima County
W. T.
Probate Court</p></figure>

<p>FORM TO BE USED IN CASE A JURY IS DEMANDED.</p>
<p><gap></gap>, the person named in the foregoing affidavit being this day broguht
before me, Judge of the Probate Court of <gap></gap> County, for examination on a charge of insanity,
and a trail by jury being demanded by <gap></gap>, a jury was thereupon duly
impaneled. The said jury, having heard the testimony of <gap></gap> and
<gap></gap>, witnesses who have been acquainted with the accused during the
time of the alleged insanity, and Drs. <gap></gap> and <gap></gap>
legally qualified physicians, having made the certificate by law required, after due consideration
rendered a verdict of insanity, as charged in the complaint. The said <gap></gap>
have been declared insane,...he is hereby ordered to be confined in the Hospital for the Insane at Fort Steilacoom, and the
Sheriff of this county is charged with the execution of this order.
Witness my hand and seal this <gap></gap> day of <gap></gap> 188<gap></gap>
Probate Judge of <gap></gap> County, W. T.</p>


<p>After inquiry as by law required, I find the said James A. Balch, is unable to pay
his expenses in the hospital at the rate of forty five 00/100 Dollars for over
two months, he has relatives who - viz (see code sec. 1632, 1655, 2697-8) have
some property in Klickilat County and he has a wife Mrs. Hattie M. Balch
in Lyle Klickilat Co. W.T. Whereas my hand and seal this 2nd day of June 1883
<unclear>Seal of the Probate Court Yakima Co.</unclear> <unclear></unclear></p>

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0433.014"/>

<p>No. 342</p>

<p>Copy of order of
COMMITMENT
of James A Balch of
Yakima County to the
HOSPITAL + FOR + THE + INSANE,
AT FORT STEILACOOM,
Washington Territory</p>

<p><del>To <gap></gap>
From <gap></gap>
<gap></gap>County.</del></p>

<p>Date of admission June 8 1883</p>

<p><del>I hereby certify that the within are true and correct copies of
the original Complaint, Physicians Certificate and Commitment
in the matter of . . . . .
an insane (or idiotic) person, this day committed by me to the
Hospital for the Insane of Washington Territory.</del></p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>