<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0149.011">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Lee Fong v. John Sullivan. Petitioner's Brief</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0149.011</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Lee Fong v. John Sullivan. Petitioner's Brief</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Lee, Wo</term>
<term>Yick, Wo</term>
<term>Loy, Tie</term>
<term>Hanford</term>
<term>Matthews</term>
<term>Kee, Sam</term>
<term>Sawyer</term>
<term>McGilloway</term>
<term>Grice</term>
<term>Fundling, Harry</term>
<term>Miller, John</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
<term>Minneapolis</term>
<term>Chicago, Illinoise</term>
<term>China</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Fong, Lee</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Sullivan, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wiestling, J. M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Buller, Ellis E.</persName>
<persName>Sillian, Micheal</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanfod, C. H.</persName>
<persName>George, R. R.</persName>
<persName>Gilber, William B.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court for the District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<ab>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT, FOR THE NINTH CIRCUIT.</ab>

<ab>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION
OF LEE FONG FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS
CORPUS. </ab>

<ab>PETITIONER'S BRIEF.</ab>


<p>The Petitioner Lee Fong was arrested and detained in the
custody of the Chief of Police of the city of Seattle, upon a
charge made against him of having violated the provisions of 
Sections 6 and 7 of Ordinance 710 of the City of Seattle, approved
by the Mayor on the 6th day of February, 1886; and which is
entitled, "An Ordinance regulating the establishment and maintenance 
of Public Laundries and Public Washhouses within the 
limits of the City of Seattle". </p>

<p>Said Section 6 referred to in in language as follows, towit:
"Section 6. It shall be unlawful, from and after the passage 
of this ordinance for any person or persons to establish, maintain,
or carry on a laundry within the corporate limits of the
City of Seattle, without having first obtained the consent of 
the common council, except the same be located in a building
constructed either of brick or stone and covered with a metal roof."
And so much of said Section 7 as provides for the punishment for
all violation of provisions of said Section 6, is in language
following, towit: "And any person who shall violate any of the
provisions of Section 6 of this ordinance shall be guilty of a 
misdemanor, and upon conviction thereof shall be punished bya
fine or not less than Five Dollars nor more than One Hundred
Dollars; or by <del>punis</del> imprisonment for not more than thirty days;
or by both said fine and imprisonment."</p>

<ab>-1-</ab>

<pb/>

<p>The complaint upon which the petitioner herein was arrested
and detained, charges the ofense alleged to have been 
committed in the language of said Section 6 of said Ordinance;
and that said alleged offense of the petitioner is contrary to
Ordinance No. 710, towit: Sections 6 and 7 hereinbefore quoted.
It will be observed that pursuant to the provisions of said
Section 6 of said recited ordinance, the consent of the Council
for the establishment, maintainance and carrying on of all laundries
within the corporate limits of the City of Seattle, is not 
required when said laundry is located or to be located in a 
building constructed either of brick or stone, and covered with
a metal roof. Buildings so constructed are exempt from the
requirements of said Section of said ordinance; but in the case 
of a laundry to be carried on in a frame building or other such
than is embraced in the exception to said section, the consent
of the council is demanded; and that consent is not conditioned 
upon any reference to the fitness of the building in which a proposed
laundry is to be established, for such purpose, nor upon
its protection against the dangers of fire or its satisfactory
sanatary conditions; but that such consent is dependent entirely
on the arbitrary will of council.</p>

<p>So that it follows, that if the person applying for such
consent is in all respects entirely worthy and deserving, and
that his building, intended for his laundry business, is possessd
of every possible sanatary provision; that all precautions 
and care has been taken to guard against the danger of fire, and
in every other respect fitted for the purpose of his business
and entirely free from objectionable features of whatever kind,
yet not withstanding all this, the Section puts it in the power
of council arbitrarily, without any reason and for prejudicial
or whimsocal causes, entirely, to withold the required. consent.</p>

<ab>-2-</ab>

<pb/>

<p>This, we contend, is in direct conflict with the provisions
of the Constitution of the United States, and especially of the
Fifth and Fourteenth Amendments thereto.</p>

<p>Fortunately for the petitioner herein, who has expnded
practically his entire means on the preperation of the building
for his proposed laundry, and that too upon an expressed permit
to do so from the Building Inspector of the City of Seattle, 
the constitutional question involved in this contention has been 
decided in his favor by the Supreme Court of the United States,
as will be shown by a citation of authorities contained in this 
brief.</p>

<p>The Honorable Court is first referred to the case reported
in 13th Federal Reporter, pages 229 and 233; being the case of "In
Re Quong," decided by Circuit Court of the District of California
in August 1882. In that case Justice Field, who delivered
the opinion, held on Writ of Habeas Corpus that "An ordinance
which makes it unlawful for any person to establish, maintain
or carry on any laundry within certain limits without first obtaining
the consent of the Board of Supervisors, which shall
only be granted upon the recommendation of not less than twelve
citizens and tax payers in the block in which the laundry is
proposed to be established, and which punishes by fine or imprisonment
for a violation of its provisions, is invalid.</p>

<ab>In Re Wo Lee 26 Federal Reporter 471,

The Circuit Court of the District of California.</ab>

<p>On January 26 1886, Justice Sawyer in delivering the opinion,
refers to the Laundry Ordinance cases in 13 Federal Reporter
229, the first case herein cited, and says: "That after that
decision, the Ordinance passed upon therein was amended by omitting
the requirement of the assent of twelve citizens and tax
payers in the block, but it still prohibited carrying on a
laundry business, after complying with numerous <del>monerous</del> conditions,
without in addition having first obtained a license,</p>

<ab>-3-</ab>

<p>or permit therefor, duly granted by resolution of Board of 
Supervisors, and it prescribed no specific conditions, the performance
of which should entitle the party to a license or permit,
but the license or permit, after performance of all the 
other  prescribed conditions, still depended upon the will of
pleasure of the Board of Supervisors. It simply struck out the
consent of the twelve tax payers in the block and left it to
rest upon the consent of the Board alone, thereby limiting the
number of parties to the consent,without abandoning the principle. 
For this reason in Jom Jong's case, the Circuit Judge 
thought the objection still remained unobviated. On this point
we think he is also sustained by authorities." The quotation
is from Judge Sawyer's opinion found on pade 427 of 26 Federal 
Reporter. After citing a number of cases therein upon the
question involved, Judge Sawyer says on page 473 of said case:
"If the court was right in those cases, then it seems to us that
the ordinance now in question must be void upon similar grounds."</p>

<p>"Section 1 provides that "It shall be unlawful, from and
after the passage of this order, for any person, or persons,
to establish, maintain or carry on a laundry within the corporate
limits of the city and county of San Francisco without having
first obtained the consent of the Board of Supervisors, except
the same be located in a building constructed of either brick
or stone".</p>

<p>In quite a lengthy opinion by Justice Sawyer in the case
just mentioned, he argues and holds on pages 474 and 475, "That
the ordinance passed upon by him in said case, (and of which the
Seattle Ordinance, alleged to have been violated in this case,
is a literal transcript, except as to the City and the body
whose consent is required,) is unconstitutional and in conflict
with the 14th Amendment of the United States Constiution. 
The Supreme Court of the State of California having, however,</p>

<ab>-4-</ab>

<p>previous to Judge Sawyer's opinion in the case just cited, held
in the case of Yick Wo, that the ordinance passed upon by Judge
Sawyer was not in conflict with <del>the</del> constitutional provisions;
he, Judge Sawyer, in deference to the previous adjudication of
the question involved by the Supreme Court of the State, discharged
the Writ of Habeas Corpus in the case before him and 
remanded the petitioner to the custody of the officer having him
in charge.</p>

<p>On appeal of the case just cited of Wo Lee from the decision
of Judge Sawyer, and also from the judgment of the Supreme
Court of the State of California, in the case of Yick Wo, the
Supreme Court of the United States, in an opinion delivered by 
Justice Matters, reversed both cases, that of Yick Wo vs
Hopkins, sheriff of the City and County of San Francisco, and
that of Wo Lee vs same, and held the California ordinance (which
as stated, is precisely like the Seattle ordinance under review,
in this case), to be unconstitutional. In the last mentioned
cases, towit: of Yick wo vs Hopkins and Wo Lee vs same, reported
in 118th United States Supreme Court Reporter from pages
356 to 374, Justice Matthews in the third paragraph of his
opinion, speaking of the ordinance referred to, said, "They seem
intended to confer and actually do confer, not a discretion to
be exercised upon a consideration of the circumstances of each
case, but a <del>marked</del> naked and arbatrary power to give or withold
consent, not only as to places, but as to persons. So that,
if an applicant for such consent being in every was a competent
and qualified person, and having complied with every reasonable 
condition demanded by any public interest, should, failing to
obtain the requisite consent of the Supervisors to the prosecution
of his business, apply for a redress by the judicial process 
of Mandamus to require the Supervisors to consider and act upon</p>

<ab>-5-</ab>

<pb/>

<p>his case, it would be a sufficient answer for them to say that
the law had conferred upon them authority to withold their assent,
without reason and without responsibility. The power given them
is not confided to their discretion in the legal sense of that
term, but is granted to their mere will. It is purely arbitrarily
and acknowledges neither guidance or restraint."</p>

<p>In quite a lengthy opinion on this subject, Justice Matthews
in the recited case, held the ordinance, (which as stated, is in language
similar to the Seattle ordinance on the subject), to be in
violation of the 14th Amendment of the United States constitution,
and reversed the decision both of the Supreme Court of the State
of Washington, and that of Judge Sawyer of the Circuit Court of
California, and directed the discharge of the petitioners from
custody and imprisonment.</p>

<p>It is unneccessary for petitioner's council to quote at
leangth from the opinion of Justice Matthews in the case just cited,
but the full text thereof is respectfully referred to the Honorable
Judge passing upon the petition herein; and especiallly to the
point made by his Honor Justice Matthews, that though said ordinance
on its face be fair, yet in giving to a board of supervisors an
arbitrary power, it made it possible for such a board to discriminate
and that it is obnoxious to the provisions of the 14th Amendment
to the constitution of the United States, <del>and</del> in that it has such
a tendency, and possibility; and although in the cases mentioned,
Justice Matthews sets forth that such discrimination in the cases
before him was actually shown and exercised on the laundrymen,
of chinense birth, yet the broad ground upon which he passes
his adjudication, is the fact that the ordinance referred to,
puts it in the power of a board, to grant or refuse consent arbitrarily.</p>

<pb/>

<p>By a comparison of dates it will be found, that his Honor
Judge Hanford, who whilst City Attorney of te City of Seattle,
framed Ordinance 710 of that City, which is being passed in review
in this case, wrote said ordinance, admittedly copying it
from the San Francisco ordinance, after the later had been held
by the Supreme Court of California to be invalid, but prior to
the adjudication upon appeal, of its unconstitutionality by the
Supreme Court of the United States, in the opinion by Mr. Justice
Matthews herein last <del>case</del> cited, the Seattle ordinance having
been approved February 6, 1886, and the opinion rendered by Justice 
Matthews on April 14 of the same year. </p>

<p>In the Stockton Laundry case-in re Tie Loy- reported
in 26 Federal Reporter 611 to 616 (in which Justice Sawyer delivered 
the opinion) the syllabus is "A City ordinance that makes 
it an offense for any person to carry on a laundry where clothes
are washed for pay, within the habitable portion of the City is
unconstitutional, and that a party who is held in custody for 
the violation of a city ordinance that is in conflict with the
14th Amendment of the United States Constitution, is entitled
to be discharged on Habeas Corpus; and in said case the Court
held it to be a violation of the United States constitution
within the meaning of Section 733 of the revised statute which 
provides that the discharge of a person by habeas corpus, who
is illedgally held in custody or imprisonment, Said statute
giving jurisdiction to the United States District and Circuit
Courts to grant such relief. in</p>

<p>In re Sam Kee reported in 31st Federal Reporter 680 to 681, 
Justice Sawyer held that a city ordinance which makes it an
offense to keep a laundry wherein clothes are clensed for hire,
within the limits of the larger part of a city, without regard
to the character of the structure, or the appliances used for
the purpose, or the manner in which occupation is carried
on, is unconstitutional on various grounds, and void, and that</p>

<ab>-7-</ab>

<pb/>

<p>"to make an occupation, indispensable to the health and comfort
of civilized man, and the use of the property necessary to carry
it on a nuisance, by a mere arbitrary declaration in a city
ordinance, and suppress it as such, is simply to confiscate
the property and deprive its owner of it without due process
of law; and that it also abridges the liberty of the owner to
select his own occupation, and his own methods in the pursuit
of happiness, and thereby prevents him from enjoying his rights,
privileges and immunities, and deprives him of equal protection
of the laws secured to every person by the constitution of the
United," citing the case of In Re Tie Loy 26 Federal Reporter
page 611, and Yick Wo vs Hopkins 118 United States Reporter 356, 
in support of his position upon the reasons therein given, and
Justice Sawyer ordered the discharge of habeas corpus of San Kee,
the petitioner therein.</p>

<p>Reference is made in the foot note to the last entitled 
cases, to the various adjudicated cases on the point ruled on
the subject, In Re Hong Wah reported in 82 Federal Reporter
623, the District Court of the Northern District of California
held, on September 7, 1897, District Judge D. Haven delivering
the opinion, that a city ordinance which provides that it should
be unlawful for any person to establish, maintain or carry on
the business of a public laundry, where articles are washing
and clensed for hire, within the City, except in certain
designated localities, and declared any such laundry established
or carried on in violation of said provision, a public nuisance,
and the violation of the ordinance a misdemeanor, punishable
by fine or imprisonment, was in contravention of the 14th Amendment
of the Constitution of the United States; and that the
ownership of property, no matter where located, carries with it
the right to use, and to permit the use of ushc property in the
prosecution of any legitimate business which is not a nuisance</p>

<ab>-8-</ab>

<pb/>

<p>in itself, and the exclusion of any such lawful business from
a particular locality can only be justified upon the ground that
the health, safety or comfort of the surrounding community
requires such exclusion, and that a public laundry is not a 
nuisance per se, and cannot be made so by the legislative declaration
of a city council; nor can the right of any person to 
engage in any such useful occupation, not a nuisance per se at
such place as he may choose for that purpose, be denied by any 
law or ordinance, and the court in that case, it being a habeas
corpus hearing, discharged the petitioner from his imprisonment. </p>

<p>In re Grice 79 Federal Reporter 627, 633, the Circuit 
Court Northern District of Texas in a Habeas Corpus hearing, 
held that even if the writ is not autorized in behalf of a 
person at large on bail, yet if he surrenders himself, or is
surrendered by his sureties, and is in actual confinement, the
writ may issue and the Court will not consider an objection, that
he was surrendered by collusion with his sureties, and that a 
Federal Court has the power to grant a writ of habeas corpus
in advance of the trials of a person confined on a charge of having
committed an offense. It has been, however, stipulated 
by the counsel for the petitioner and the city attorney in this 
case, that no advantage shall be taken <del>or question shall be taken</del>
or question raised from the fact that after Judge Hanford had
granted the rule to show cause in this case, the petitioner
Lee Fong was released from custody on bail.</p>

<p>The Court's attention is also respectfully called to the
case of Mineapolis Brewing Company vs McGilloway, reported in
104 Feferal Reporter 258, where it was ruled that the constitutionality
of a statute is not determined by what has actually
been done thereunder, but by what may be done thereunder, but
by what may be done by virtue of its provisions.</p>

<p>Applying that doctrine to the case in hand, and it follows</p>

<ab>9. </ab>

<pb/>
<p>that the fact that under the ordinance for the alleged violation
of which the petitioner herein was arrested and imprisoned, a
discrimination may be arbitrarily made by the city council of
Seattle, of itself, establishes and unconstitutionality of the
ordinance.</p>

<p>The case of Harry Fundling vs the City of Chicago reported
in Vol. 177 of the United States Supreme Court Reporter, bottom
page, 725, relied upon by the City Attorney in this case,
as an autority in support of the constitutionality of the ordinance
involved herein, will be found upon examination to give
no support to the City's contention. The syllabus therein
is that "An ordinance giving the mayor power to determine whether
a person applying for a license to sell cigarettes, has a good
character and reputation and is a suitable person to be intrusted
with their sale, but requiring him to grant a license to every
person fulfilling these conditions, does not vest in him any
arbitrary power to grant or refuse a license, in violation of
the provisions of the United States constitution, 14th Amendment,
either in regard to the clause requiring due process of law,
or in that requiring equal protection of the law. </p>

<p>It will readily be observed that the case referred to is
no authority in the case under consideration; the Court itself
therein points out the clear distinction between it and that of
Yick Wo vs Hopkins 118 United States Reporter 356, cited in behalf
of the petitioner. The Court says "The ordinance in question
in that case was held to be illegal and to be violation of 
the 14th Amendment, because with reference to the subject upon 
which it touched, it conferred upon the municipal authorities
arbitrary power, at their will, and without regard to discretion
in the legal sense of the term, to give or withold consent as
to persons or place for carrying on a laundry with<unclear>out</unclear>, reference
to the compentency of the person applying or of the propriety
of the place selected." And the court <add>in this <unclear></unclear> case referring to the Yick Wo <unclear>case</unclear></add> say, "The ordinance in </p>

<ab>10</ab>

<pb/>
<p>question here does not grant to the mayor arbitrary power such
as mentioned in the above mentioned laundry case. In the case
at bar the license is to be issued if the mayor is satisified
that the person applying is of good character and reputation
and a suitable person to be entrusted with the sale of cigarettes,
and that the mayor is bound to grant the license to
every person fulfilling these conditions." </p>

<p>A careful examination of the authorities herein cited,
it is confidentially contended, will establish clearly the claim
made in behalf of the petitioner herein, that the 6th Section of
Ordinance No. 710 of the city of Seattle under <del>a writ</del> which he was
arrested, is in conflict with both the 5th and the 14th Amendments
to te constitution of the United States; indeed the case of 
Yick Wo vs Hopkins 118 United States has of itself expressly
determined and fixed the unconstitutionality of Sections 6 and 7
of Ordinance 710 of the <del>Act</del> City of Seattle, the ordinance adjudicated
in said case being as already shown in language identical with
the Seattle ordinance, the one being a copy of the other.</p>

<p>As indicated by Justice Matthews in the case of Yick Wo in
118 United States Supreme Court Reporter herein cited, the section
held in said case to be unconstitutional and of which the one herein
under consideration is a copy, is unconstitutional, in that
first it discriminates between buildings for laundry purposes,
which are constructed of brick or stone, and those that are not
so constructed; and secondly, between such as are not so constructed
but obtain the consent of the Board, and those who fail
by the <del>arbitrary will</del> arbitrary will of the Board to obtain such 
consent; and the objection theretio was founded upon the fact that
said ordinance makes it possible for the body whose consent was
necessary to withold such consent without reason and without
conditiion, and that under its provisions one class of persons could</p>

<ab>-11-</ab>

<pb/>
<p>arbritarily be given such consent, and another class be refused 
the same.</p>

<p>It was the possibility of a municipal body of men withholding
consent arbitrarily, which was pronounced to be unconstitutional.
The Supreme Court of the United States in the case mentioned, made
its ruling upon the provisions of the 14th Amendment to the constitution 
independently of and without reference to the fact that
the petitioners for habeas corpus were Chinamen. The adjudication
in principle would have been the same if the petitioners had
been of the white or Caucasion race. The unconstitutionality
of the ordinance in that case as also in the case at hand, made no mention
of the ract or nationality to which the person maintaining a 
laundry belongs. </p>

<p>But in addition to the ordinance passed upon being held to
be in conflict with the 14th Amendment to the United States
Constitution, it was held to also be, in the application to the case
of the petitioner, a violation of the treaty between the United 
States and the Empire of China, in that, the facts in the case
show that the ordinance was being used in such manner as to be a 
violation of said treaty. The petitioners in that case were
Chinamen, as he is also in the case now being considered, and as, 
in the application of the ordinance to the petitioners in the 
Yick Wo case, it was held to be not only in conflict with the
United States constitution but also a violation of the treaty between
the United States and China, so in like manner, the petitioner
said Lee Fong, for a writ of habeas corpus in this case, alleges
that his arrest and confinement under the 6th and 7th sections of
ordinance No. 710 of the City of Seattle, is in conflict with both
the constitution of the United States and the treaty with China.</p>

<p>In support of the last mentioned allegation, the Court's attention
is especially called to the following facts in this case,</p>

<ab>-12-</ab>

<pb/>

<p>First, that when an application was made to the city of Seattle
for a permit to change the premises Number 1410 East Fir Street,
into a laundry, the builders specifications for said change which
was expressly designated" to be for LAUNDRY purposes" were examined
by the Building Inspector and duly approved and a permit granted,
authorizing the proposed change of said premises, no reference
was made in said specifications to the fact that the laundry was
to be conducted by a Chinaman; it being simply stated, to be "for 
a LAUNDRY;" that at the same time, that said laundry permit was
granted, the Health Officer of the City of Seattle, after inspecting
the same specifications on June 18th 1802, gave his official certificate
in which he said, "Permission is given John Miller to build
a laundry at 1410 East Fir Street, he having complied with the City 
ordinance," the said John Miller, a white man, being the owner of 
the premises referred to, and no mention having been made at the
time of the fact that the petitioner LEE FONG, herein, or any other
Chinaman, was, as the lessee of said premises from said Miller, to
conduct said laundry. Pursuant to these respective permits the
petitioner Lee Fong expended upwards of $600. in having made according
to said specifications, the necessary changes, whereby said premises
were converted into a building suitable for laundry purposes, and
at the conclsion of the work of making such changes in said premises
te Health Officer of the City of Seattle, towit: on August 2nd, 1902,
gave a certificate as follows: "This is to certify that I inspected 
the premises at 1410 East Fir Street, and found them properly
and sufficiently drained; and that proper arrangemtns as to the
sanatary conditions has been complied with". And on July 30th
1902, the City Inspector of Plumbing, for said City certified that
the plumbing in said building had been inspected, completed and 
found to be in accordance with the ordinance of the City of Seattle. </p>

<ab>-13-</ab>
<pb/>

<p>That notwithstanding the facts herein last mentioned and
set forth certain persons, at, or about the time when the said
premises had been converted into a laundry building at the expense
herein metioned to the petitioner herein, petitioned the Common
Council of the city of Seattle, setting forth that they were legal
voters and resided in the vicinity of said premises, and protesting
against having a "CHINESE LAUNDRY"; designating it as stated, "A 
CHINESE LAUNDRY" and asking the Council to withhold their consent
for the same. This petition was endorsed "A remonstrance against
locating of "A Chinese Laundry" at No. 1410 East Fir Street; was
referred to the Committee of the Councils, who reported withot having
given the petitioner herein a hearing, recommending that the
Council refuse to grant its consent to said laundry; which report
was adopted by the said Council, whereby the petitioner Lee Fong
was refused to consent of the Council to establish and maintain
his proposed laundry, after having expended nearly $600. under a 
permit from said City..</p>

<p>Secondly: That upon said petitioner's counsel applying to one of the 
committee of said Council, who had reported adversely to the granting
of the Council's consent to such laundry, asking for a reconsideration
of the council's action in the premises, he was informed
by said committeeman of said Council, that he would never under
any circumstances or conditions give his consent for establishing
of "A Chinese Laundry" at the locality mentioned, emphasizing his 
objection as being to a granting of a CHINESE LAUNDRY thereat.</p>

<p>Thirdly: That when said petitioner's counsel applied to the Chief of 
the Fire Department of the City of Seattle for his inspection of
the premises referred to, so as to determine whether or not it had 
been so constructed as to provide against dangers from fire, said</p>

<ab>-14-</ab>

<pb/>
<p>Chief of Fire Department in like manner expressed himself strongly
in opposition to the granting of a permit for a laundry, to be 
conducted in the premises mentioned by a Chinaman;" that afterwards,
however, upon being told that it was his duty to make said inspection,
he complied with said request, and afterwards stated upon oath
that the only feature of the building which he regared as involving
any risk from fire was the fact that the gront of a cookstove in
said premises had not before it upon the floor a zinc protection, and 
some objection to the brick work at the entrance to the said stove;
that the fact is, that said cookstove was in no manner essential
to, or any part of the laundry arrangements of said premises, yet, 
nevertheless, the petitioner Lee Fong placed upon the floor in
front of said stove ample covering of zinc, fastened to said floor,
adjusted the brick in the entrance to said stove, so as to meet
fully the objections of the Chief of Fire Deparment. That the
having fully met the objections of the Chief of Fire Department, 
and made the part he had objected to entirely safe against fire, 
said Chief of Fire Department was asked to again inspect said premises
so as to determine the satisfactory condition thereof; he, the
said Chief of Fire Department entirely neglected and refused to
make said inspection. That is was after all this was done, and
said premises was securely arranged both in a sanatary point of
ciew and against danger from fire, he, the petitioner, being engaged
in his business of a laundryman on said premises, was arrested,
charged with violation of the provisions of Sections 6 and 7 of 
ordinance 710 of the City of Seattle. Hence it is claimed that
petitioner's arrest and imprisonment was in violation both of the
constitution of the United States and the treaty with China. </p>

<p>It being manifest from the facts stated, that the real objection
to the granting of council's consent for the maintenance of said
laundry was the ascertainment of the fact that it was to be conducted
by a Chinaman. Hence, it is claimed that a discrimination was </p>

<ab>-15</ab>

<p>made against Lee Fong, the petitioner in this case, for no other
reason than that he is a Chinaman, it thus being, like the case of
Yick Wo ruled by the Supreme Court of the United States in 118
U. S. Reports, a violation of the treaty within China. The primary
and chief contention is, however, that the ordinance is itself unconstitutonal
and that of itself entitles the petitioner to his 
dischaarge under habeas corpus, to say nothing of the infringement
by said arrest and confinement of the provisions of the Chinese 
treaty. </p>

<p>After completing the foregoiing, the brief of 
respondent was received. The position that
Section 6 of the Seattle ordinance  No 710
must be <unclear>continued</unclear> together with Section
2 and 3 or in conditioned upon them, 
in <unclear></unclear> for the very obvious 
reason that even with the provisions of 
Section 2 and 3 being literally complied 
with, Section 6 of this the council the 
power to certified to consent, notwithstanding
such compliance; nor does it appear nor
can it be claimed that in the case of 
the petitioner Lee Fong, the action of the council 
in reference its consent was <unclear></unclear> upon
and, <unclear></unclear> of or relation to Sections
2 and 3, nor was the charge aforesaid petitioner <unclear>made</unclear>
<unclear></unclear> reference to 
Section 2 and 3</p>

<p>Respectfully, submitted by</p>

<ab>J M Wiestling
Attorney for Petitioner</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>No.</ab>

<ab>In the United States
Circuit Court
FOR THE 9TH DISTRICT  </ab>

<ab>In the matter of the application 
of Lee Fong for a writ of 
Habeas Corpus</ab>

<ab>Petitioner's Brief</ab>

<ab>J M Wiestling</ab>
<ab>Attorney for Petitioner</ab>

<ab>SEP 25 1902</ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Received Copy of petitioner Brief this `17th day of 
Sept 1902</ab>

<ab>Ellis E Bulle</ab>
<ab>Atty for Respondent</ab>





</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>