<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0207.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Nora Sullivan v. Henry M. White. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0207.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Nora Sullivan v. Henry M. White. Petition</title>
<date when="1919-08-14">August 14, 1919</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1919-08">August 1919</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Ireland</term>
<term>Butte, Montana</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sullivan, Nora</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Costello, M.J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Unknown</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2019-12" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="#hc.case.0207.003"/>

<p>In the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washinton, Northern Division.</p>

<p>No. 4764</p>
<p>Petition.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Nora Sullivan for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>To the Honorable Jeremiah Neterer,</p>
<p>Judge of the Above Court:</p>

<p>THE PETITION AND COMPLAINT OF NORA SULLIVAN respectfully shows to the Court as follows:</p>

<p>I That the above-named Nora Sullivan, now residing in the City of Seattle, State of Washington, District and Division aforesaid, is unlawfully deprived and distrained of her liberty by the Commissioner of Immigration, orother official administering the affairs of the Bureau of Immigration within this District and in the Cith of Seattle and Division aforesaid.</p>

<p>II. that said deprivation and restraint is illegal, and that the illegality consists in this:</p>

<p>III. That Your Petitioner, while engaged in her lawful occupation and acting in all respects in conformity with the law of the United States and of the State of Washington has <del>been</del> without any offense been taken into custody and removed to the Detention Station of said Bureau or Commissioner situate in the City of Seattle, where she now is, <add>and</add> is liable, if not protected by this Court, to be, as she is informed and believes, deported to her native country, towit: Ireland, on the false and unfounded claim that she is insane, and an insane alien.</p>

<p>IV. That Your Petitioner has resided in the City of Seattle s since April of the present year, whither she came from the City of Butte in the State of Montana, where she had resided since her arrival from Ireland on or about July I. I9I6. that she has atall times been employed in active calling during her residence in the United States, and has lived decently and respectably on the product of her own labor, both here and in said City of Butte.</p>

<p>V. That during the months of Jan. &amp; Feb. I9I7, shebecame painfully ill from rheumatism and suffered great pain as the result thereof. That ever since her arrival in the United States, as the result no doubt of change of climate, she had been troubled by the discontinuance of her menses or monthly flows, until <del>her</del> she entered St. Mary's hospital at Butte aforesaid. By reason of the intense pain that she endured from her rheumatic attacks, and the consequent derangement of her system as the result of the stoppage of her menses she became extremely sick, depressed and nervous, and, while still in said hospital, was, at the suggestion of her brother then in Butte, and to insure her, as she since is infromed, more perfect quiet, was taken to the Warm Springs Hospital, from which she was duly discharged cured on or about July Ist. I9I7.</p>

<p>VI. That since her discharge as aforesaid she has been in perfect health, and now is in perfect health, mental and physical, and has never except while sick as above stated, and never at any time since her arrival in Seattle, been in the slightest degree ill, but has worked steadily day by day at her work in the Seattle Empire Laundry, and for a short period as a waitress.</p>

<p>VII. That at no time during her illness, either while in hospital, or otherwise, has she not been in full possession and exercise of her memory; and during all of said illness she knew what was transpiring around her, and can now recall all the chief events connected with her illness, both in hospital. If she was not in full possession of her faculties during her illness at any time, it was the result of the intense pain which she at times endured, and, as she is informed and believes, the natural outcomes medically of her monthly troubles. There is not taint of insanity in her family; if there were she would be aware of it. She alleges as a fact that the claim, which she is informed and believes is now being put forward, that she was discharged from Warm Springs Hospital before being fully cured is false and unfounded; indeed, it has not the slightest foundation in fact, and is disproved by the fact, which she hereby alleges, that at no time since, either here or in Butte, has she been for a moment ill, either from rheumatism or the constitutional trouble referred to, but has worked without interruption at her calling.</p>

<p>VIII. Your Petitioner avers that she has always looked forward and still continues to look forward to spending her life in the United States, and has no desire or intention to return to her native place or to live in any country except the United States,; and the fact that she has not applied for naturalization is due solely to the general belief and practice among her sex, that in course of time, through becoming married,she would become invested with American citizenship. To deport her at this time as an insane alien, or for any other reason, would be in violation of every personal right which she has acquired through her residence and domicile in the United States.</p>

<p><del>Subscribed and Sworn to before me this 14th day of August, 1919.</del></p>

<p>Nora Sullivan</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>

<pb/>

<p>United States of America State of Washington County of King</p>
<p>SS;</p>

<p>NORA SULLIVAN, being first duly sworn deposes and says that she has read the foregoing Petition and knows the contents thereof, and that the same is true of her own knowledge; and that she is the Petitioner therein named and who was subscribed to the same.</p>

<p>Nora Sullivan</p>

<p>SUBSCRIBED AND SWORN TO before me this I4th day of August, I9I9.</p>

<p>Joseph M. Taylor</p>
<p>Notary Public In and for the State of Washington, residing in Seattle.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>