<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Harry Smith v. United States. Brief.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Byrd, Samantha." xml:id="slb">Samantha Byrd</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0493.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Harry Smith v. United States. Brief.</title>
<date when="1916">1916</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1916">1916</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Smith, Harry</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Sullivan, J. J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington North Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#slb">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT, IN AND FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, Plaintiff, vs. Harry Smith, Defendant. No. <del>3375</del>3376 BRIEF.</p>

<p>At your Honor's suggestion, I herewith present a few salient reasons why the contention, as presented by the petitioners, should be upheld, and why they should be discharged from imprisonment.</p>

<p>In a conversation with Mr. Martin, the Assistant United States Attorney, who prepared the Brief in this matter, it is conceded by him, and I herewith state it, that if the indictment upon which these men were tried and sentenced was void, your Honor has the right and it is your duty, under the law to discharge the prisoners. If the indictments are not void, <del><unclear></unclear></del><add>but</add> voidable, the defendants should avail themselves, by means of appeal or writ of error, or motion to quash, arrest of judgment, etc,. and writ of habeas corpus will not lie.</p>

<p>Counsel for the Government, however, contends that this indictment is voidable, and not void, and that it does state a cause of action, and that, therefore, my clients should have availed themselves of one of the foregoing remedies, other than the writ of habeas corpus, and practically states that if his position be well founded, my clients have, by reason of the fact that their counsel did not so act, no recourse, and must serve out their sentence.</p>

<p>I challenge the contention of counsel. It is not founded on the record, but is only the imaginative ingenuity of the District Attorney, upon an assumption of an implied charge in the indictment which does not exist. He claims that because the indictment charged</p>

<pb/>

<p><del><unclear></unclear></del> a volation of the Harrison Act, that that charge is an offense. Let us see. It is true the indictment charges a violation of the Harrison Act, but what violation of the Harrison Act, to-wit: having in possession certain derivative of morphine. etc., without having so registered. I contend that the Supreme Court in the Gin Fung Moy case, recently decided, through Mr. Justice Hughes, specifically held that this was not an offense. In other words, counsel cannot say because they charge a violation of an act, that that charges an offense. It is the facts in relation to the violation of the act, that make the offense, and the Supreme Court, having held that those facts, to-wit:"having in possession", which are no charged in the indictment, as being a violation of the Harrison Act, is not, indeed a violation of the Harrison Act, and is not an offense. Therefore, the indictment, stripped of the facts of having these drugs in possession, leaves nothing but a mere allegation of the violation of the act, which means nothing; inasmuch, as the facts in relation to said act, which were so charged by reason of the Supreme Court decision, viciates and makes void the whole indictment, and being void, makes their sentence under said indictment and committment illegal.</p>

<p>As was stated by Mr. Justice Field, in one of the decisions which your Honor has, and was aptly stated by this court in my argument the other day, the Government might just as well have charged these people with having in possession some innocent thing, or as your Honor said, a lead pencil. Your Honor has the cases before him which I presented in argument, after a most diligent search, and I am adding herewith a few more.</p>

<p>My clients have taken a Forma Pauperis. Their lawyers who had represented them, and who had saved no safeguard for them having taken all their money, but being interested in the point, and feeling the justice of their cause, I have aimed, fairly and impartially, to lay my cards upon the table for the District Attorney, in order that</p>

<pb/>

<p>justice might prevail; and I trust your Honor will understand that I am not trying to burden him with law for the purpose of allowing guilty ment to escape punishment, but am only aiming to present reasons why men who, in my estimation, are guilty of no offense, should be released.</p>

<p>It is conceded by the Government that if the judgment is void, your Honor has a right to discharge it. I will present further authorities on that point. I quote from the Encyclopedia of the Laws of England, Vol. 6, p. 472, on this point, which should have much bearing with this court for the reason that it is from the English law that the habeas corpus originated. It there states: "Purposes for which Writ of Habeas Corpus is Granted: Under the writ of habeas corpus, the court may examine into the legality of any commitment for a criminal or supposed criminal matter. No unlawful detention of an individual or deprivation of the liberty of an individual, whether the alleged cause be civil or criminal, or if there is no ground at all alleged for the detention may be inquired into by means of the issue of a writ of habeas corpus." The jurisdiction of a court on habeas corpus in such cases has been thus expressed: "If it appears clearly that the fact for which the party is committed is no rime, or that it is a crime, but that he is committed for it by a person that has no jurisdiction, the court discharges." Citing, Wilmot's Opinions, P. 106; Bacon, Abr., tit. Habeas Corpus, and the Bushel's case, 1670, Vaugh. 136. which last mention case is cited and approved in several Supreme Court cases which your Honor has before him.</p>

<p>As to your Honor's power to set aside or vacate a judgment which is void, I quote the following: "The court may at any time vacate or set aside a judgment which is void." Cyc., p. 825. "It has frequently been held that a judgment which is absolutely void may be vacated at any time, and that the right to have such judgment set aside is not lost by delay, regardless of whether or not the time for making the application is limited by statute." Cyc., p/ 842.</p>

<pb/>

<p>Quoting from Thomas vs. American Freehold Land Co., etc., 47 Fed., p. 556: "The defendant insists that the term having ended, we have no control over the judgment. In numerous cases cited by the defendant, to-wit: Bank vs. Moss, 6 Howard, 31; Sibbald vs. United States, 12 Pet., 492; United states vs. Bank, 6 Pet., p. 8, wherein it is held that after a Circuit Court has rendered judgment, it cannot set aside one of its own judgments upon motion, even for want of jurisdiction over the cause, were all decided upon cases where the court itself did not exceed its jurisdiction. It is true, however that where the court has jurisdiction of the parties and subject matter, if it makes a judgment or decree which is not within the power granted to it by the law of its organization, its decree of judgment is void."</p>

<p>Mr Justice Field in Windsor vs. McFay, 93 U.S., 282, said: "Courts must adjudicate in all things and cannot transcend the power confeerred by law."</p>

<p>"Where a court transcends the minutes prescribed for it by law, and assumes to act where it has no jurisdiction, its adjudications will be utterly void." Cyc., p. 358 R.D.</p>

<p>"No court of the United States can revise or amend its own final judgment or decrees for errors of fact or of law, The present motion, however, is not directed to the correction of any error of law or fact on the part of the court rendering the judgment, but counsel has intimated that he can show that the judgment is void. The court has jurisdition over this question." U.S. vs. Wallace, 46 Fed., 570.</p>

<p>"No judgment of a court is due process, if rendered without urisdiction in the court." Scott vs. McNeil, 38 Law Edition, 896.</p>

<p>"Sentence not within the jurisdiction of the court to impose is not merely unlawful, but is wholly void."Emery <unclear>VK.</unclear> U.S. Supreme Court Reps., p. 1093.</p>

<p>The unbroken voice of authority holds that a sentence of imprisonment, without jurisdiction, is void. The question reduced to its logical sequence, this is: "What is jurisdiction?" Jurisdiction means jurisdiction over the nature of the cause of action and the relief nought. Cyc. Supreme Court Reps., p. 709. "In order to give abiding effect to a judgment, it is essential that the court have jurisdiction of the person and of the subject matter. The want of jurisdiction is a matter that may be set up at any time." Emery Supreme Court Reps., p. 740 - (Jurisdiction)</p>

<pb/>

<p>"If the court has no general jurisdiction, or exceeds its jurisdiction, custody under its judgment is void, and will be released by habeas corpus."</p>

<p>Want of jurisdiction to render a particular judgment, party is entitle to habeas corpus, not merely where the court is without jurisdiction of the cause, but where it has no constitutional authority to render the particular judgment, a sentence without indictment is void, and a prisoner will be released on habeas corpus." Cyc. Supreme Court Reps., p. 650. (Habeas Corpus)</p>

<p>An amendment of the United States Consitution provides that no person may be held to answer for an infamous charge, save by an indictment by a grand jury. An indictment by a grand jury is an accusation setting forth the facts of the offense charged. If the accusation does not charge a crime against the Government. The defendant had not been indicted by a grand jury in this action. The defendant is not charged with any crime against the Government, and therefore, he has never been indicted by a grand jury.</p>

<p>Now, as to the fact that the record shows that no offense was ommitted, and that your Honor should discharge, read what our own Circuit Court of Appeals says in the case of Mackay v. Miller, 126 Fed., p. 161: "If it be true that the acts committed by the appellants which are set forth in the indictment in this case, are not within th intendment of Section 5447 of the Revised Statutes (U.S. Comp. St., 1901, page 3678) they do not constitute an offense against that statute, or against any other statute of the United States. Such being the case, it appears affirmatively from the return that the appellants are held in custody under a judgment which upon its face is void." I also call your attention to Ex parte Coy, 127 U.S., 731; 32 Law Ed., 247, holding: "The writ of habeas corpus, in case of a person held a prisoner by sentnece of court, can only release the prisoner when it is shown that the court HAD NO JURISIDICTION TO TRY AND PUNISH HIM FOR THE OFFENSE. The inquiry in such case is not whether there is in the indictment such specific allegation of the details of the charge as would make it good on demurrer, but whether the indictment described a class of offenses of which the court has jurisdiction, and alleges the defendant to be guilty. If the record of the case in which Judgment of imprisonment is pronounced CONTAINS NO CHARGE OF SUCH OFFENSE, HE SHOULD BE DISCHARGED."</p>

<pb/>

<p>Also Ex parte Bain, 121 U.S., 1; 30 Law Ed., 849, in which it is said: "There was nothing before the court on which it could hear evidence or pronounce sentence. The case comes within the principles laid down by this court in Ex parte Lange, 18 Wall, 163; Ex parte Parks, 93 U.S., 18; Ex parte Wilson, 114 U.S., 417, and other cases."</p>





</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>