<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0180.018.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Response.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Turner, Grace E." xml:id="GET">Grace E. Turner</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0180.018</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Albert H. Young and Kamasaburo Sugiuro v. United States. Response.</title>
<date when="1913-07-19">July 19, 1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno>2628AlbertYoung&amp;KamasaburoSugiura</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-07">July 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Holmes</term>
<term>Washio, Shotaro</term>
<term>Saito, Hana</term>
<term>Ito, K.</term>
<term>Umeda, K.</term>
<term>Gardner</term>
<term>Gassounis, Lewis</term>
<term>Johnson, Maida</term>
<term>Ellsworth</term>
<term>Donahue</term>
<term>Dupont</term>
<term>Baker, Julia</term>
<term>Denamore, J. B.</term>
<term>Larned, F. H.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Oakland, California</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Young, Albert H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sugiuro, Kamasaburo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States of America</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Myers, H. A. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>McClellan, R. W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Johnstone, Walter L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, G. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western Washington District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington State</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#GET">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States, for the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the matter of the Deportation 
of Albert H. Young and B.K.
Sugiura. } No. <gap reason="blank"/>
Brief.</p>
<p>The Rule.</p>
<p>The order of this brief will be to take up the
rule of procedure first and afterwards the evidence only
in so far as it bears on the rule.</p>
<p>The matter for consideration in this case seems
to us to be res adjudicata until the case of In Re
Unlawful Dentention of Mullah Singh and Seventy-two other
Hindu Aliens, Case No. 2532, has been reversed by the 
Supreme Court. In that case the court says:</p>
<p>"The jurisdiction of the court is limited to
ascertaining whether the pertitioners were denied
a hearing."</p>
<p>And the Court cites to sustain the proposition the following:</p>
<p>Ekin v. United States, 142 U.S.651;<add>35 L Ed 1146</add>
Yamataya v. Fisher, 189 U.S.86;
United States v. Ju Toy, 198 U.S. 253;
Lee Moon Sing v. United States, 158 U.S.538;
Chin Yow v. United States, 208 U.S. 8.</p>
<p>The Court further says:</p>
<p>"A hearing having been accorded, the court
is precluded from a re-examination of the issue
presented, merely because it is contended that
the conclusion of the immigration officers, based
upon the testimony presented, was wrong."</p>
<p>The Court's decision is borne out by the reasoning
and the exact language of our Supreme Court cases. Thus, in
Chin Yow v. United States, 52 L.Ed. 369, the Court says:</p>
<fw>1</fw>
<pb/>
<p>"But unless and until it is proved to the
satisfaction of the judge that a hearing properly
so called was denied, the merits of the case are
not open, and, we may add the denial of a hearing
cannot be establsihed by proving that the decision
was wrong."</p>
<p>And in the case of De Bruler v. Gallo, 184 Fed.
566, at page 569, that court follows the reasoning of
this court, saying at 569,</p>
<p>"The contention being that the only question
then properly before the court was whether or not
the appellee had been given a fair hearing by the
officers of the Department of Commerce and Labor
upon the order to show cause why she should not
be deported to the country from which she came.
The position of the government in this respect
must be sustained."</p>
<p>Again the court states the rule in another way
in United States vs. Ju Toy, 49 L. Ed. 1040, 1043, where
it says in giving the ruling in Lem Moon Sing vs. U.S.
39 L.Ed. 1082:</p>
<p>"Where the petitioner for habeas corpus
alleged facts which, if true, gave him a 
right to enter and remain in the country,
it was held that the decision of the collector
was final as to whether or not he belonged
to the privileged class."</p>
<p>Again, Chief Justice Holmes states <del>a</del> <add>the</add> rule in a 
case in which a writ of habeas corpus was allowed. Thus
he says in the case of Chin Yow vs. United States, 52
<del>L.</del> Ed. 369:</p>
<p>"Of course, if the writ is granted, the
first issue to be tried is the truth of the
allegations last mentioned. If the petitioner
was not denied a fair opportunity to produce
the evidence that he desired, or a fair
though summary hearing, the case can proceed
no farther. Those facts are the foundation
of the jurisdiction of the district court, if
it has any jurisdiction at all. It must not
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
be supposed that the mere allegation of the facts
opens the merits of the case, whether those facts
are proved or not. And, by way of caution, we
may add the jurisdiction would not be established
simply by proving that the commissioner and the
Department of Commerce and Labor did not accept
certain sworn statements as true, even though no
contrary or impeaching testimony was adduced."</p>
<p>Reason of the Rule.</p>
<p>The reason of this rule is that the determination
as to the rights of aliens to remain in or be exvluded
from the United States is one within the jurisdiction of
Congress alone. It belongs to the political <del>determinant</del> <add>department</add>
of the government <add>alone</add> and the final determination as to who
shall be entitled to enter the United States may be
entrusted to Congress to executive officers. (See a 
statement of the reason of the rule in the case of Lem Moon
Sing vs. U.S., 39 L.Ed. 1084 in last paragraph of first
column of page; and also see the same reason of the rule
laid down in U.S. vs. Ju Toy, 49 L. Ed. 1043 last part
of page). <add>The counts have to none right to interfere than
they wared if these aliens were in their own country
petitioners admission to Courts.</add></p>
<p>Part of Immigration Act Involved.</p>
<p>These two aliens are being deported under that 
portion of Section 3 as mended by the Act of March 26,
1910, which provides that "any alien ***********who in
any ways assists, protects or promises to protect from
arrest, any prostitute, shall be deemed to be unlawfully
within the United States and shall be deported in the
manner provided by Sections 20 and 21 of this Act."
Section 20 provides that any alien who shall enter the
United States in violation of law, etc., shall upon the
warrant of the Secretary of Labor, be taken into custody
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
and deported to the country whence he came. The rules of
the Department, Subdivision 4(a), provide that upon receipt
of a warrant of arrest, the alien shall be taken before
an immigration officer and granted a hearing to enable
him to show cause why he should not be deported; Subdivision
(b) provides that he may inspect the warrant and examine 
the evidence from which it was issued and, at such stage
of the proceedings as the officer before whom the hearing
is held shall deem proper, be apprized that he may be
represented by counsel; Subdivision (c) provides that at
the close of the hearing a full record shall be forwarded
to the bureau, together with any written arguments submitted
by counsel and recommendations of the examining officer
as to whether a warrant for deportation shall issue.</p>
<p>The Proceeding And Evidence in this Case.</p>
<p>In acoordance with these instructions a warrant 
was issued which was marked Exhibit "A" and will be found
in the record after the testimony of Shotaro Washio.</p>
<p>On this warrant, in the manner provided by the 
rules, a hearing was had on November 3, 1913, and the two
aliens, Young and Sugiura, were presented by counsel;
after the testimony, including the brief of the attorney
R.W. McClelland, was sent back to the Secretary of Labor.
The statement of Shotaro Washio shows that Young and 
Sugiura knowingly assisted a prostitute (see page 1 of
testimony of Shotaro Washio which is in the following 
language:</p>
<p>Q. Are you the same Shotaro Washio that testified in the
<fw>4</fw>
<pb/>
trial of Albert H. Young and B.K. Sugiura for
transporting a girl named Hana Saito from Seattle
to San Francisco? A. Yes.</p>
<p>Q. Did they assist you in taking her to San Francisco? 
A. Yes.</p>
<p>Q. What was that woman's occupation? A. That that time
or after she got there.</p>
<p>Q. Before she left San Francisco to come here and after
she returned to San Francisco? A. Prior to her
departure from San Francisco  she was sick and didn't 
do anything and after her return to Frisco she was
a prostitute.</p>
<p>Q. Did Mr. Young and Sugiura know what her character
was then they helped you to take her to San Francisco?
A. Yes.</p>
<p>Q. How did they know it? A. I told them.</p>
<p>Q. Did you tell both of them or only one? a. I told
Sugiura and whether he told Young or not I don't know.).</p>
<p>Also the testimony of Hana Saito (page 2 of her
testimony) is to the same effect. Thus note the following
language thereof:</p>
<p>Q. Did you at any time prior to your departure from Seattle
for San Francisco tell Young and Sugiura or either of 
them that you had formerly practiced prostitution at
the house at 1020 Stockton St.?</p>
<p>A. No, but Sugiura said while we were on board the ship
that they would take me back to the house where I 
had been practicing prostitution before. They knew
I had been a prostitute because Washio told them.</p>
<p>Q. Do you know who purchased your transportation to San 
Francisco?</p>
<p>A. Young and Sugiura did. They bought tickets on a boat
sailing earlier and took me to the ticket office to
get the tickets cancelled.</p>
<p>Q. Do you know if they recieved any money for taking you to
San Francisco?</p>
<p>A. I heard later that they got $250.00 from Ito and Umeda.</p>
<p>The testimony further shows that Young and Sugiura
promised to protect a prostitute from arrest (See the
<fw>5</fw>
<pb/>
testimony of Hana Saito on page 1 thereof which is as
follows:</p>
<p>"Young said they were going to put me into
jail and I thought I was arrested because Saito
and I ran away from San Francisco. I asked if
they were from the Immigration office at San Francisco
or from the police and Young said they were from
the police; I asked him if he had anything to do
with the Immigration Office and he said 'If you don't 
come with us you will be turned over to the Immigration
officers.'")</p>
<p>Again see the testimony of K. Ito on page 2 and 3
thereof which is as follows:</p>
<p>Q. What else did Young, Sugiura or Washio say at that 
time? A. Young and Sugiura said the agreement with
Washio was to pay them $800 for bringing the girl
down here but that things didn't go just right so
they were willing to settle and take $400 and wanted
me to pay them that. Sugiura said he had passed
as an interpreter and that Young had passed as an
Immigration officer and the woman believed them
came without much trouble. Young and Sugiura told
me it was worth $800 to take the chances of bringing
this woman here to a house of prostitution and that
they wanted their mnoney. They told me later that
they had been to see Mr. Gardner of the Immigration
office and had fixed things with him so there would
be no trouble but that we must come through with the
money to them. Young and Sugiura and went to the
Imperial hotel, Washio and Hana stayed in my house. 
The next day, I think it was, Umeda and I were sent
for by Young and Sugiura went over their agreement
with Washio and said they couldn't wait for their
money and must getback to Seattle and that Umeda
and I must raise the money for them. Later in the 
day Young and Sugiura came to my house Umeda was
present also and there I paid them $200 and later
I paid them $50 more.</p>
<p>Application of Test to this Case.</p>
<p>This is sufficient to show that there was a
sointilla of evidence for the immigration authorities
and this under the law if sufficient. But there seems
to be more than that. The stories of Young and Sugiura
are not as probable as those of the government witnesses.
<fw>6</fw>
<pb/>
We do not, however, enter into this case under the rules
as laid down by our Supreme Court and Judge Neterer
in this district. The only question for consideration
is whether a hearing was denied. There can be no pretense
that this was done because Attorney McClelland represented
the aliens before the immigration officer and sent a 
brief back to Washington (see his brief and also notice
on page 6 of his brief at the point beginning at line 9
and ending at line 16 where he takes up the testimony and
argues on it). Now he says that the testimony was not
comptenet. Before the immigration authorities he did
not object to the admission of any of these affidavits
(see page 5 of the testimony of Sugiura wehre the
testimony was offered without objection and see the
examination of McClelland wehre he examines as to these
various statements). Again it will be observed that
McClelland, on behalf of the aliens, put in a lot of 
exparty affidavits which would be no more admissible
than those of the government; but if the court was
reviewing a lower court, he could not reverse it if the
court let in testimony when there was no objection made
to it, and if a court lets in such testimony, it is acting
within its jurisdiction to consider the testimony after
admitted. So this is bound to be considered as fair
testimony and Mr. McClelland, the attorney for the aliens,
reviews poritons of it in his brief. The inspection
officers were fair. They allowed Mr. McClelland to have
as much latitude as themseleves in putting in testimony
and there is no showing in the record that the officers
refused to allow him to put in any testimony on behalf of
<fw>7</fw>
<pb/>
his clients.</p>
<p>Meaning of the Word "Assists".</p>
<p>The word "assists" as used in this statute applies
to cases where the prostitutes are assisted in the promotion
of the practice or business of prostitution, but not cases
where prostitutes may be given assistance which is in no
way connected with the promotion or forwarding of said
unlawful business (See the opinion of the solicitor of
the Department of Labor which is attached to the <del>next</del> <add>last</add> page
and made a part of this brief). But suppose the attorney
will say that the consturction of the statute is for <add>the Court</add>
<del>Congress</del> and not for the Immigration officers. Under the
rule stated above and the reasons given therefor we can not
agree with counsel because language in the Lem Moon Sing
case seems to seetle this question. There the court says
(39 L. Ed. 1085) that <add>"</add> it is contended that if an alien
is entitled by law or treaty to enter this country and is
nevertheless excluded by immigration officers, the latter
exceed their jurisdiction and their action should be
reviewed by the courts<add>"</add>, but that such a contention cannot
be sustained and that if it were, it would bring into the
courts every case of an alien claiming the right to come
into the United States under some law or treaty who was
prevented from doing so by the executive branch of the
government.</p>
<p>It is clear that the construction of the law 
given by the immigration authorities should control the
court because if they have jurisdiction to enforce the
law and to pass rules and regulations for the enforcement
<fw>8</fw>
<pb/>
thereof, they certainly have jurisdiction to interpret
the law and Congress certainly intended this to be the
case because otherwise the immigration laws would not
be uniform through the United States. The Secretary of
Labor enforces these laws and the meaning that he places
on them is to be followed by the immigration officers 
all over the United States. If the courts could
interpret the law, the District Courts and Circuit Courts
of Appeal of the various districts would have different
rules for admission and a man that would be excluded by 
the law as interpreted in New York City would probably
be admitted in Seattle, Washington, so there would be no
uniformity of the law over the United States. Suppose
a lower court says a statute means one thing and an upper 
couert says it means another, would the lower court be
without jurisdiction in interpreting the meaning of the
statute? If it interpreted the statute wrong, would it
be lacking in jurisdiction?</p>
<p>Here the immigration authorities have a hearing
and from the evidence introduced at this hearing the
immigrants should be deported according to their construction
of the law. Does any one maintain that in doing this they
act outside of their jurisdiction? If so, there are
many points in the immigration laws where the courts would
doubtless differ form the immigration authorities as to the
construction of the law.</p>
<p>The only matter for this court to consider is
whther these aliens who are being deported have been
denied a hearing, and it seems to us that it is clear that
<fw>9</fw>
<pb/>
they have not.</p>
<ab>Respectfully submitted,
Clay Allen
United States Attorney.
G.P. Fishburne
Assistant United States Attorney.</ab>
<p>See also Frick v. Seemis 195  Fed 693
&amp; Williams v. U.S. 186 Fed 479
cases cited at argument.</p>
<pb/>
<p>Department of Labor
Office of the Solicitor</p>
<p>Jule 9, 1913</p>
<p>In RE the meaning and effect of the word "assist" as used in
section 3 of the Immigration Act of 1907, as amended March 26, 1910.</p>
<p>I am requested to express an opinion as to the meaning of that
portion of section 3 of the Immigration Act of March 26, 1910,
(36 Stat. 264) which reads as follows:</p>
<p>"that any alien who in any way assists, protects, or promises to
protect from arrest any prostitute, shall be deemed to be unlawfully
within the United States ans shall be deported in the manner provided
by sections twenty and twenty-one of this Act".</p>
<p>The question is raised in connection with the case of Louis
Gassounis, alias Leoieli Kassumis. It appears from the papers submitted
that Gassounis, an alien and a Greek by birth, lived for over
six years in Oakland, California, where he owned half interest in
two barber shops, yielding him an icome of about $125 per month.
He bore a good reputation for honesty, morality, and integrity until
he met a young woman named Maida Johnson. He made a date with her,
and the result was one or more acts of sexual intercourse between them.
Thereafter he rented a room and lived with the woman as his wife. Then
she insisted on becoming an inmate of a house of prostitution. He
tried to persuade her not to take up such a life, but she insisted,
and told him she would not speak to him unless he did what he could
to secure her a place in a house of prostitution. Then, uoting
form a statment signed by Judge Ellsworth and District Attorney
Donahue, "He thereupon went to the house of a woman named Dupont and
secured a place for the girl there. She was there for some days and
then left and again asked the defendant to secure a place for her.
He went out the second time and secured another place for her in the
house of Julia Baker, where she stayed for some ten or twelve days,
and where he came to visit her, remaining, according to his own admission,
all night on five or six occasions."</p>
<p>He was arrested charged with the violation of a state statute
known as the "Pandering Law", convicted and sentenced to two years
in the State Penitentiary.</p>
<p>In November last, shortly after he had begun to serve his term
in the State prison, the Acting Secretary of Commerce and Labor issued
a warrant for his arrest on the ground that he was unlawfully in the
United States, being an alien found receiving, sharing in or deriving
benefit from the earnings of a prostitute. The record contained no
evidence to support such a charge and the Acting Secretary of Labor,
under date of June 12, 1913, cancelled the warrant.</p>
<p>In reference to this action the Commissioner of Immigration at
San Francisco wrote the Commissioner-General of Immigration under
date of June 20, as follows:</p>
<p>"When this case was presented to the Bureau in my letter of
November 5th, 1912, the offense with which the man was charged was
indicated, and was that he had been convicted for a violation of the
State Law of Pandering. It was not contended that he received,
shared in, or derived any benefit form this woman's earnings, but it
would seem that he assisted and protected her, which is a part of the
same section. In other words assisting and protecting a prositute
is a violation of the Immigration Act, and there is evidence that this
alien assisted a prostitute and protected her to the extent of placing
her in an immoral house, and was convicted under the State Law of
Pandering. Therefore it would seem that assisting and protecting a 
prositute under the Immigration Law has as its equivalent the Pandering
Act of the State of California."</p>
<p>The law which is to be contrued in connection with this particular
case is very awkwardly worded. It says "that any alien who
in anuyway assists, protects, or promises to protect from arrest any
prostitute, shall be deemed to be unlawfully within the United States."
Was it the intention of Congress that the word "assists" should be
given effect only in connection with the word "arrest"? If so, the
statute would have to be construed as though it read "any alien who in
any way assists from arrest any prostitute". Besided being poor 
English, such a construction would practically eliminate the word
"assists" from the statute for the expression "protects from arrest"
is just as broad as the expression "assists from arrest".</p>
<p>Such a construction would not, I am sure, give effect to the
plain intention of Congress. It would permit prostitutes to receive
and profit by the assistance of aliens and to carry on and extend the
immoral practices against which the section in question is aimed.
The immigration authorities could exercise no restraining or preventive
power over aliens rendering such assistance. There is no
other provision of law that would apply to all such cases. I cannot
think that Congress used the word "assists" merely as a qualification
of the words "from arrest".</p>
<p>The only other view which occurs to me is that the word "assists"
is to be given effect in connection with the words "any prostitute".
According to this view, the statute would have to be <del><unclear/></del> constured
as though it read "any alien who in any ways assists any prostitute".
This view is open to the objection that, literally, it would subject
to deportation any alien who might try to save a fallen woman by
taking care of her and assisting her to obtain honorable employment,
and would apply to aliens connected with Christian Missions, the
Salvation Army, and other like organizations whose activities in
assiting prostitutes are most praiseworthy.</p>
<p>But I do not think it necessary to give the statute such a literal
construction.</p>
<p>It is fundamental law that the intent of the legislature must be
gathered from the language used, but that, in case of ambiguity, particular
words must be so construed as to give a reasonable and sensible
effect to the statute as a whole.</p>
<pb/>
<p>Sutherland on Statutory Consturction (Vol.2, p. 913) quotes
from the case of People vs. Chicago, 1`52 Ill. 546-552 as follows:</p>
<p>"When the literal enforcement of a statute would
result in great inconvenience and cause great injustice,
and lead to consequences which are absurd and which the
legislature could not have contemplated, the courts are
bound to presume that such consequences were not intended,
and adopt a construction which will promote the ends of
justice and avoid the absurdity."</p>
<p>X See also the case of Holy Trinity vs. U.S., 143 U.S. 457.</p>
<p>In the chapter on statutory construction in volume 1 of the
Federal Statutes Annotated at page LXXVLLL, it is stated, "It has
been laid down again and again that "a thing which is within the
intention of a statute is as much within the statute as if it were
within the letter; and a thing whihc is within the letter of the
statute is not within the statute unless it is within the intention
of the makers!"</p>
<p>A careful reading of the entire Immigration Law and a consideration
of its general purpose and the mischief to be supressed,
lead to the conclusion that Congress intended that the word "assists"
should be given a broader application that a mere qualification of
the words "from arrest"; that it should apply to cases where prostitutes
are assisted in the promotion of the practice or business
of prostitution, but not to cases where prostitutes may be given
assistance which is in no way connected with the practice or
business of prostitution or assistance which, on the other hand,
may be calculated to suppress or discourage such practice or business.</p>
<p>If the Secretary finds the record in the case of Mr.
Gassounis that the alien assisted a prostitute in the sense indicated
in this opinion, I have to advise that the law justified the
deportation of such alien.</p>
<ab>Respectfully,
(signed) J.B. Denamore,
Solicitor.</ab>
<p>The Honorable,
The Secretary of Labor.
M-k
No. 53,510/337</p>
<p>July 19th, 1913.</p>
<p>Respectfully furnished to all Commissioners of Immigration and
Inspectors in Charge of Districrts, for their information and guidance
in handling cases of this class.</p>
<ab>(signed) F. H. Larned,
Acting Commissioner-General.</ab>
<p>Mc
Copy
D</p>
<figure/>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>