<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the District Court of the United States
For the Western District of Washington
Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Amended
Application for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus for Gwoo Shee
Ah Look. | 2649</p>
<p>To the Hon. Jeremiah Neterer, Judge of said Court:</p>
<p>Your petitioner respectfully shows to the Court that Gwoo
Shee Ah Look, who has been termed, Ah. Sing, Alias Gwoo Shee, alias
Gwoo Ah Look, by the United States Immigration authorities, is a
Chinese woman born in China, but has been domiciled and has been 
an actual bona fide resident of the United States for a number of
years; that said Gwoo Shee Ah Look has been ordered deported from
the United States to China by the Secretary of Commerce and Labor
of the United States, and that said Secretary of Commerce and Labor
has issued his warrant directed to R.P. Bonham, Acting Inspector of
Immigration Services at Portland, Oregon, for the deportation of said
Gwoo Shee Ah Look from the United States to China;</p>
<p>Pursuant to said writ and order of deportation your petitioner
further shows that in the month of January, 1914, the said R.P.
Bonham, as such Acting Inspector of Immigration Service at Portland,
Oregon, to the City of Seattle, State of Washington, where 
she was delievered to the Immigration authorities at that time and
there detained in the Immigration House of Detention pursuant to
said writ and order of deportation; that the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look
was unlawfully restrained, imprisoned and detained of her liberty
by the said R.P. Bonham, Acting Immigration Inspector of Portland,
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
Oregon, byt the Immigration authorities of the United States at
Seattle, Washington in the said House of Detention; that the said
R.P. Bonham clandestinely, secretly, and without authority of law
removed the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look from the County Jail of the
County of Multnomah, State of Oregon, and clandestinely and secretly
detained her and has refused upon the application of the said
Gwoo Shee Ah Look, as well as that of her husband, Wong Sing Lung, 
to let it be known where she was detained, but on the contrary her
location and whereabouts was ascertained through the efforts of
the said Wong Sing Lung at Seattle, Washington.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that after ascertaining the
whereabouts of said Gwoo Shee Ah Look, to-wit, in the Immigration
House of Detention in Seattle, Washington, tht he for and on behalf
of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look filed a petition in the United
States District Court for the Western District of Washington,
Northern Division, praying for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, and that
such proceedings and action was had upon upon said petition, that
the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look is now being detained at said House of
Detention of said Immigration authorities upon a Writ issued pursuant
to the said petition for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, requiring
the official having said Gwoo Shee Ah Look in charge and custody
to appear and show cause why a Writ of Habeas Corpus should not
issue.</p>
<p>Your petitioner shows that the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look
arrived in the United States at the City of San Francisco on the
Steamer "Siberia", during the year 1907, the exact date of which is 
unknown to your petitioner, since which time she has been continuously
domiciled within the United States, and your petitioner further
shows that the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look is unlawfully imprisioned, detained
and confined and restrained of her liberty by the Immigration
authorities of the United States at the Immigration House of Dentention
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
in the City of Seattle, Washington, as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look
came to the State of Oregon from the State of California during the 
early part of October, 1913, and that shortly after her arrival
in said City she was arrested and charged by the Immigration authorities
under a provisions of a statute of the United States with
being unlawfully within the United States, in that since her arrival
and domicile within the United States she had been found practicing 
prostitution and that she was a prostitute.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look
was arrested by the police officers in the City of Portland on the
4th day of November, 1913, in a certain raid conducted by the police
officers and thereafter turned over to the Inspector of Immigration
J.H. Barbour, who on the 5th day of November, 1913, at the Police
Station conducted an investigation and examination of the said Gwoo
Shee Ah Look secretly and without allowing the presence of any person
at the time of the taking of such statements, and that thereafter
the said J.H. Barbour caused the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look to be imprisioned
and confined in the County Jail of the County of Mulnomah,
State of Oregon, upon the said charge; that thereafter the said J.H.
Barbour caused a further examination to be made and had Gwoo Shee
Ah Look brought before his and her statements were taken by the said
J.H. Barbour relative to the charge which had theretofore been
placed against her, to-wit, of being unlawfully within the United
States, in that she had been found practicing prostitution while
domiciled therein and that she was a prostitute.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that thereafter the said J.H.
Barbour caused the testimony of L.A. Harms and J.M. Wise, two
police officers, to be taken in his office and that said two witnesses
testified relative to the said charge against the said Gwoo
Shee Ah Look; that the said testimony of the said L.A. Harms and
J.M. Wise was conducted secretly without the presence of the said
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
Gwoo Shee Ah Look and without the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look being
allowed the privilege of having an attorney or ccounsel present to
examine and cross-examine said witnesses, likewise Gwoo Shee Ah
Look was unable to have counsel present at the time she was examined
by the said J.H. Barbour, and that the said manner of conducting
said examination of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look and said
L.A. Harms and J.M. Wise was in violation of Rule 22 of the
Department of Commerce and Labor, Clause B of Sub-division 4,
which provides:</p>
<p>"During the course of the hearings the alien shall be allowed
to inspect the warrant of arrest and all the evidence 
on which it was issued; and at such stage thereof
as the officer before whom the hearing is held shall
deem proper, he shall be apprised that he may thereafter
be represented by counsel and shall be required then and
there to state whether he desires counsel or waives the
same, and his reply shall be entered on the record. If
counsel be selected, he shall be permitted to be present
during the further conduct of the hearing, to inspect
and make a copy of minutes of the hearing, so far as
it has proceeded, and to offer evidence to meet any evidence
theretofore or thereafter presented by the government.
Objections and exceptions of counsel shall not be
entered on the record, but may be dealt with in an accompanying
brief."</p>
<p>That said Gwoo Shee Ah Look does not speak the English
language and that all communication with her was had through an
interpreter, and that she is ignorant in the ways of the world
and protection of her rights, and that when her examination as
well as that of the other witnesses was being conducted she did
not understand her rights or understand the dangers which she was
encountering wihout having counsel present to conduct the examination
in her behalf and look after her rights.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that the second day after
the arrest of said Gwoo Shee Ah Look and before the said J.H. 
Barbour as such Inspector of Immigration had conducted his second 
examination of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look and before he had
conducted his examination of the said L.A. Harms and J.M. Wise that
he employed the law firm of Wilbur &amp; Spencer and A. L. Clark of the
City of Portland, Oregon, to represent and look after the interests 
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<fw>-4-</fw>
<pb/>
of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look; that at said time the said J.H. 
Barbour, Inspector of Immigration Office at Portland, Oregon,
conferred with the said A.L. Clark who requested of the said
J.H. Barbour permission to visit the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look,
who was then confined in the County Jail, and that at said time
the said Barbour was informed that said persons represented the
said Gwoo Shee Ah Look; that the said J.H. Barbour thereupon refused
counsel so requesting permission the right or privilege at
that time to see or consult with the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look; that
thereafter on several occasions and before the examination of said
Gwoo Shee Ah Look and other witnesses had been completed the said
A.L. Clark requested of said J.H. Barbour that he be notified
when said hearing was conducted and requested the privilege of being
present at such examination and cross-examination of the witnesses,
which request was regused and although having promised so to do the
said J.H. Barbour failed and neglected to notify the attorneys for
said Gwoo Shee Ah Look of the time and place of conducting such
examination; that thereafter after the said examination had been
made of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Loo by J.H. Barbour and the testimony
reduced to writing on the 19th day of November, 1913, the said J.H.
Barbour delivered a transcript of the testimony taken in said manner
to the attorneys of said Gwoo Shee Ah Look with the suggestion that
such evidence could then be presented by way of affidavit as was
deemed proper, and that there was no opportunity given or granted
to the said attorneys for Gwoo Shee Ah Look, who were known to be
the attorneys for the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look, to be present at any
of said examinations conducted to cross-examine any of the witnesses,
whose testimony was being taken; that thereafter the said
attorneys for the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look procured such affidavits
as they were able to procure and filed the same with the said J.H.
Barbour, who thereafter transmitted the same with his record to
the Secretary of Commerce and Labor, who has order the said Gwoo
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<fw>-5-</fw>
<pb/>
Shee Ah Look's deportation to China and found that the said alien
is a prostitute and has been found practicing prostitution subsequent
to her entry into the United States.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further alleges that the said order of deportation
and the said imprisionment and restraint of the liberty
of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look is unlawful and illegal, in that
said Gwoo Shee Ah Look was not granted the rights and privileges 
insured to her in the manner in which the said hearings and testimony
were taken by the said J.H. Barbour, Inspector of Immigration,
because she was not granted the privilege of having her attorneys
present at such examination.</p>
<p>Yor petitioner further alleges that said restraint and order
of deportation are illegal in that there was no evidence before the 
Commissioner or Secretary of Commerce and Labor authorizing the 
order for said Gwoo Shee Ah Look's deportation. The only evidence
before either the Commissioner or the Secretary of Commerce and
Labor, save and except the statement of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look
which the said parties had before then, was so far as the virtue of
Gwoo Shee Ah Look is concerned as follows:</p>
<p>"Q When and where did you first see this woman? (Gwoo Shee Ah Look)</p>
<p>"A About three weeks ago, about two weeks before her arrest was
made, upstairs, second floor, in a building on the southwest
corner of Fourth and Flanders Streets, this City.</p>
<p>"Q Under what circumstances did you see her at that time?</p>
<p>"A We were investigating that place, knowing that there were Chinese
prostitutes up there, about two or three weeks before the arrest
was made; we were up there three or four times; Officer Wise and
myself.</p>
<p>"Q State briefly what you saw on the occasion of these two investigations,
so far as your observation is limited to this woman.</p>
<p>"A in the first plce, we had information from different sources
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<fw>-6-</fw>
<pb/>
that there were Chinese prostitutes up there. We watched the place 
on several different occasions and saw Chinese going up there in the
rooms that the women were in. We went up there and talked to the 
women the best we could. At different times we found different men
in this woman's room. Finally, about 4:30 in the morning November
4th, we went up with the purpose of making her arrest and we found
a Chinese in bed with her.</p>
<p>"Q In your capacity, experience, and observation as a police officer
in the Chinese quarter on North Fourth Street, Portland, what have
you found to be the reputation of the place out of which this woman 
was arrested?</p>
<p>"A It has the reputation of being a bawdyhouse where prostitutes
ply their trade."</p>
<p>And the testimony of J.M. Wise, who is a police officer of
the City of Portland, whose testimony, so far as the virtue of said
Gwoo Shee Ah Look is concerned, is substantially as follows:</p>
<p>"Q When, where, and under what circumstances did you first see or 
meet this woman? (Gwoo Shee Ah Look)</p>
<p>"A Along about the 20th of October, this year, in room 17 of a 
building on the southwest corner of Fourth and Flanders Street,
this City." (Portland)</p>
<p>"Q Under what circumstances did you first see her?</p>
<p>"A Investigating the place, gaining evidence as to this place being
a house of prostitution and as to this woman being a prositute.</p>
<p>"Q Did you arrest this woman?</p>
<p>"A Yes, on the 4th day of November, about 4:30 in the morning."</p>
<p>That there was no other testimony relative to the character or acts
or prostitution of the said Gwoo Shee Ah Look.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that she said Gwoo Shee Ah Look
is not a prostitute and that she has not practiced prostitution
within the United States or at any other place.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that said Gwoo Shee Ah Look
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<fw>-7-</fw>
<pb/>
came to this country in company with her husband, Lau Wing Chew,
who she married in China, according to the Chinese customs; that
after her arrival within the United States said Lau Wing Chew deserted
said Gwoo Shee Ah Look and that thereafter she was married
to your petitioner, Wong Sing Lung, at Croville, California, some 
time during the year 1912, since which time she has lived with your
petitioner, Wong Sing Lung, as his wife;</p>
<p>Your petitoner further shows that the evidence before the
said commissioner and the secretary of Commerce and Labor showed
in substance that Gwoo Shee Ah Look came to the State of Oregon
on the 8th day of October, 1913, when said Gwoo Shee Ah Look went to live
with a respectable Chinese family, where she remained until the
first day of November, 1913, at which time, she, together with her
husband, rented a room at the place where said Gwoo Shee Ah Lok
was arrested.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further above that the affidavits in behalf
of said Gwoo Shee Ah Look showed in substance that she had not been
in the room or at the place where she was arrested until the first 
day of November, 1913, when she moved there with her husband.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that the facts as above detailed
were showsn in the affidavits of Wong Sing Lung, Sue Key Line, Wong
Shee, Wong Ark, D.L. Huston and Wlater Bartholemew, all of which
were filed with the Commissioner in the City of Portland, attached 
to the record, and before the said Secretary of Commerce and Labor.</p>
<p>Your petitioner further shows that the sole and only testimony
upon which the said Secretary of Commerce and Labor has ordered the
deportation of said Gwoo Shee Ah Look was the testimony of said two
policemen, the substance of which has been set out herein, and that
their testimony that they saw her at the place of her arrest prior
to the first day of November, 1913., is untrue and case of mistaken
<figure><ab>Wilbur &amp; Spencer
Attorneys-At-Law
Portland Oregon</ab></figure>
<fw>-8-</fw>
<pb/>
identity.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>