<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN
DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the matter of the Petition
of K. Gregory, M. 
Aloshin, I Riaboff, P.
Neanlin I Emelin, L. Orloff
G. Yakimoff, and P. Yakimoff,
aliens, for a WRIT OF HABEAS
CORPUS</p>
<p>No. 2646 
BRIEF</p>
<p>The matter for consideration in this case seems to me to be res adjudicata until the case of In
Re Unlawful Dentention of Mullah Singh and Seventy-two other Hindu Aliens, Case No. 2532, has been
reversed by the Supreme Court. In that case the court says:
"The Jurisdiction of the court is limited to ascertaining whether the petitioners were denied a
hearing."</p>
<p>And the Court cites to sustain the proposition on the following:
Ekin v. united States, 142 U.S. 650;
Yamataya v. Fisher, 189 U.S. 66;
United States v. Ju Toy, 198 U.S. 253;
Lee Moon Sing v. United States, 158 U.S. 538;
Chin Yow v. United States, 208 U.S. 8.</p>
<p>The Court further says:
"A hearing having been accorded, the court is precluded from a repexamination of the issue
presented, merely because it is contented that the conclusion of the immigration officers, based
upon the testimony presented was wrong."</p>
<p>The Court's decision is borne out by the resoning and the exact language of our Supreme Court
cases. Thus, in  Chin Yow v. United States, 52 L.Ed. 369, the Court says:
"But unless and until it is proved to the satisfaction of the judge that a hearing properly so
called was denied, the merits of the case are not open, and, we may add the denial of a hearing
cannot be established by proving that the decision was wrong."</p>
<p>And in the case of De Bruler v. Gallo, 184 Fed. 566, at page 569, that court follows the
reasoning of this court, saying at 569,
"The contention being that the only question then properly before the court was whether or not the
appellee had been given a fair hearing by the officers of the Department of Commerce and Labor upon
the order to show cause why she should not be deported to the country from which she came. The
position of the government in this respect must be sustained."</p>
<p>It is the contention of the Government in this case that if these Russions were given any hearing
at all, it makes no difference whether the immigration authorities erred in either an interpretation
of the law or in the finding of their facts, the courts have no authority whatsoever to interfere in
the premises. In short, it is our contention that the administration of this law is placed
exclusively in the hands of the immigration authorities and that the courts have no more authority
to interfere with their actions, whether their error be in law or fact, than they would to interfere
with the action of a consul or ambassador. the introduction of foreigners into our country is a
matter which concerns international relations alone. There is no guarantee of the Consitution of the
United States to which an alien who has never been admitted to America is entitled, and it would be
as disasterous for the court to interfere with the administration of the immigration law as ti would
in the case of the dealings with foreign countries, because this is a matter which concerns our
dealings with a foreign nation. In this particular case it is shown that the fact that the alien was
excluded from Canada was given consideration on account of the fact that from a courtesy existing
between the two countries it has been customary for Canadians to exclude any one not allowed to
enter the United States, and vice versa.</p>
<p>We are borne out in this case by that of Ekiu v. United States, 35 L. Ed. 1146, 1150, 139-142
U.S.Sup.Ct. Rep. 1146, where the Act of 1891 was under consideration. Section 1 of that Act was in
substance the same as ours; it provided that all idiots, insane persons, paupers or persons likely
to become a public charge, etc., should be excluded. Under Section 1 a woman was being detained on
the grounds that she was liable to become a public charge and was therefore prohibited from landing,
and she went to the courtsand had a writ of habeas corpus issued, and in considering whether she was
entitled to it, the court, at page 1150, says:
"Section 7 of the Act of 1891 establishes the office of superintendent of immigration, and enacts
that he '"shall be an officer in the Treasury Department, under the control and supervision of the
Secretary of the Treasury."' By Sec. 8 '"the proper inspection officers"' are required to go on
board any vessel brining alien immigrants and to inspect and examin them, and may for this purpose
remove and detain them on shore, without such removal being considered a landing; and '"shall have
power to administer oaths, and to take and consider testimony touching the right of any such aliens
to enter the United States, all of which shall be entered of record;"' '"all decisions made by the
inspection officers or their assistants touching the right of any alien to land, when adverse to
such right, shall be final unless appeal be taken to the superintendent of immigration, whose action
shall be subject to review by the Secretary of the Treasury."'</p>
<p>And again the Court says:
</p>

<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>