<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0362.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Hosaye Sakaguchi v. Henry M. White. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0362.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Hosaye Sakaguchi v. Henry M. White. Type of document</title>
<date when="1921-04">April 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-04">April 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Hunter, B.A.</term>
<term>Pacterson, Wilbur</term>
<term>Harshberger, F.M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sakaguchi, Hosaye</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Kiefer, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Cushman, Edward E.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES,
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the matter of the
Petition of                     No.5959
Hosaye Sakaguchi,               <unclear>MEMORANDUM OF </unclear>
for a Writ of habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>We desire to add to the contencion set out in the petition
herein, the further contentions that the Board of Special Inquiry was
not legally constituted. It appears from the record in the body of
the return that the Board was composed of Frank S. Mounlion and
B.A. Hunter, inspectors, and Wilbur S. Pacterson, stenographer,</p>

<p>Section 17 of the Immigration Act of Feb. 5 1917, provinces:</p>

<p>"That each Board of Special Inquiry skill consists of three
members who shall be selected from such of the immigrant officers
in the service as the Commissioner General of Immigration with the
approval of the Secretary of Labor, shall from time to time designate
as quialified to serve or such Boards."</p>

<p>The Board in the insuant cause appears to have been composed
of two inpectors and a stenographer. We submit that this does not
constitute a legal Board.</p>

<p>J.S. vs Redfern, 150 Fed. 500.</p>

<p>The statute uses the term officer, We submit that a
stenographer is not an officer.</p>

<p>A pension <unclear></unclear> clerk i not an official of the United
States so as to disqualify him from membership in the state
legislature.</p>

<p>State vs. Mason, 55 N.E. 167</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>A clerk in the office of the Supervisor of Internal
Revenue under Revised Statutes Sec. 3130 is not an officer of the
United States and as such required to take the Oath of Office
prescribed by Section 1756 R.S.U.S.</p>

<p>Hedrick vs. U.S. 16 St. Claims page 55-100
U.S. vs. Schlierholz, 137 Fed. 316
Martin vs. U.S., 168 Fed. 198
U.S. vs. Haus, 157 Fed. 211</p>

<p>If the Board was illegaly constituted as we contend it
was, it was without power to hear or determine the matter, and this
sets the whole matter at large, and the court will determine the
status of the petitioner upon the record as- to law and facts.</p>

<p>U.S. vs. Smith, 124 U.S. 525 31 L. Ed. 534.</p>

<p>Under the treaty between the United States and Japan, there
is no impediment to the landing of the petitioner. The only
restriction upon the landing and entry of Japanese immigrants is what
of <unclear></unclear> Agreement that no passports will be issued by the
Japanese Government to laborers. It follows, therefore, that if
the passport of petitioner was regular, she is entitled to land,
unless some valid objections appears. No objection appears except
the pretext that because the husbanf of the petitioner declined to
have more to do with her, she was likely to become a public charge.</p>

<p>A few words as to the fact that the husband refused to
have anything more to do with the petitioner. </p>

<p>The marriage of the petitioner and her husband is valid
in Japan, and therfore valid everywhere else. The husband can not
avoid his legal liability to support his wife by merely declining
to have any more to do with her.</p>

<p>By general laws of the land the husband is bound to
support his wife, and requires no argument that he can not divest
himself of this liability by merely refusing to receive his wife
after causing her to be brought to the United States.</p>

<p>The finding of a majority of the Board of Special Inquiry
(2)</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>that petitioner is liable to become a public charge is not born out
by the evidence. The brother-in-law and the sister of the petitioner
have in the most unqualified terms undertaken the support petitioner.</p>

<p>It appears from Sec. 5375 Rem. &amp; Bal. Code, that a sister
is liable for the support of a poor <del>relative-</del> <add>sister</add>. It follows, wherefore,
that independently of the desire and willingness of petitioner's
sister and brother-in-law to take care of her, they are under legal
liability so to do. The finding of a majority of the Board of Special
Inquiry ignores this feature of the case, and is to that extent a
denial of a fair trial.</p>

<p>It is judicially settled that the Court will look into the
record and will determine from the facts in the record of the
immigrant office whether there is any legal ground to support the
finding of liability to become a public charge.</p>

<p>Gegiow vs. Uhl, 239 U.S. 3
30 L Ed. 114</p>

<p>To the same effect is</p>

<p>Pazos vs. Redfern, 150 Fed. 500
U.S. vs. Martin, 193 Fed. 759
Sprung vs. Martin, 152 Fed. 230
U.S. vs Nakashima, 160 Fed. 842</p>

<p>A reading of these cases will disclose that rulings of
the Court are to the effect that where a person is in good health,
has sufficient apparent earning ability to support himself or herself,
they can not be adjudged likely to become a public charge.</p>

<p>The same effect is 
U.S. vs. Suekichi, 199 Fed. 751</p>

<p>In the case at her, in addition to the support offered
by the brother and sister, it appears from the record that the
petitioner is skilled in sewing and in the making of artificial flowers,
and that she is able to suport herself in these occupations.</p>

<p>We submit that the finding of the Board of Special Inquiry
(3)</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>is arbitrary, and does violence to the admitted and proven facts, and
denies to petitioner a fair trial, and the writ should be granted
and the petitioner permitted to enter.</p>

<p>James Kiefer
Attorney for petitioner.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>FILED IN THE
UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
Western District of Washington
NORTHEN DIVISION</p>

<p>APR 21 1921
F.M. HARSHBERGER, CLERK.</p>

<pb></pb>
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>