<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0153.004.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Earnest Hutchinson v. State of Washington. Exhibit C</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Czapla, Ethan P." xml:id="epc">Ethan P. Czapla</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0153.004</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Earnest Hutchinson v. State of Washington. Exhibit C</title>
<date when="1905-07-25">July 25, 1905</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno>1183ErnestHutchinson</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1905-07">July 1905</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>London, E.</term>
<term>Springer, O.H.</term>
<term>Corliss, Fred G.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County</term>

</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hutchinson, Earnest</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>State of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Carroll and Carroll</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Mackintosh, Kenneth</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C.H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court of the Ninth Circuit</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#epc">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Exhibit "C".</p>

<p>In the Superior Court of the State of Washington For King County.</p>

<p>State of Washington, Plaintiff</p>
<p>v.</p>
<p>Earnest Hutchinson, Defendant.</p>

<p>Information. No. 3455.</p>

<p>I, Kenneth Mackintosh, prosecuting attorney in and for the County of King, state of Washington, now here in the name of and by the authority
       of the State of Washington, and gives the court to understand and to be informed, and now on oath by this information do accuse Earnest
       Hutchinson fo the crime of selling Trading Stamps, commiteed as follows, to-wit:</p>

<p>He, the said Earnest Hutchinson, in the County of King, State of Washington, on the 3rd day of July, A. D., 1905, did then and there sell four thousand
       (4000) trading stamps to one E. London for the sum of twenty dollars ($20.00) in lawful money of the United States, upon a contarct to enable said E. London
       to sell or exchange property upon a representation, advertisement, notice or inducement that aid trading stamps would entitle a person purchasing goods
       of said E. London to demand or receive from said Earnest Hutchinson other property unselected by or unidentified by said purchaser to receive from said
       Earnest Hutchinson other property unselected by or unidentified by said puchaser to reeive from said earnest Hutchinson property whose selection would
       depend upon chance or hazard, said property ot be delivered and received as a part of the transaction as a prize, premium, or premium gift contrary to the
       form of the statute is said case made and provided, and against the peace and dignity of the State of Washington.

       Dated at Seattle in the County and state aforesaid, this 25th day of July, 1905.</p>

<p>Kenneth Mackintosh. Prosecuting Attorney in and for the County of King, State of Washington.</p>

<p>State of Washington. County of King</p>

<p>Kenneth Mackintosh, being first duly sworn on oath, deposes and says, that he is prosecuting attorney in and for the county of King, State of Washington;
       that he ahs read the foregoing in-formation, knows the contents thereof, and believes the same to be true.</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 25th day of July, 1905. Otto A. Case.
       Clerk of the Superior Court in and for the County of King, State of Washington.</p>

<p>By O. H. Springer, Deputy. Witnesses for the State: Fred G. Corliss. E. London. </p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>