<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0189.009"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Charles Jackson v. Henry M. White. Return and Answer of Respondent</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>

<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0189.009</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Charles Jackson v. Henry M. White. Return and Answer of Respondent</title>
<date when="1918-11-25">November 25, 1918</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1918-11">November 1918</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Henry M. White</term>
<term>W.P. Callaghan</term>
<term>S. J. Benford</term>
<term>Trent Dozer</term>
<term>John H. Sargent</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Jackson, Charles</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court For The Western District of Washington Northern Division</orgName> 
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>   
<change when="2019" who="#lkw">reviewed.</change>        
<change when="2019-09" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded.</change> 
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<ab>No.</ab>
<p>In the District Court of the United States For the Western District of Washington. Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the matter of the application of Charles Jackson for a writ of habeas corpus.</p>
<p>Return and answer of Respondent, Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration.</p>
<p>Filed in the United States District Court Western District of Washington Northern Division Nov 25 1918</p>
<p>F. M. Harshberger, Clerk by <unclear/> Deputy</p>
<pb facs="hc.case.0189.009"/> 

<p>In the District Court of the United States Western District of Washington Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application of CHARLES JACKSON for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>No. 4356 Return and Answer of Respondent, Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration.</p>
<p>Comes now the respondent herein, Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington, and responding to the order to show cause heretofore entered by the court herein and answering the petition of the above named applicant for a Writ of Habeas Corpus herein respectfully certifies and shows to the Court as follows:</p>
<p>That this respondent denies each and every allegation of the petition or complaint herein of the above named applicant, Charles Jackson, except as hereinafter admitted,</p>
<p>And this respondent further certifies and respectfully shows to the court as follows:</p>
<p>1.  That Henry M. White is now and at all of the times mentioned herein and in the petitioner's complaint has been United States Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington.</p>
<p>2.  That the said petitioner, Charles Jackson, was duly and regularly arrested and detained under and by virtue of a warrant duly and regularly issued by the Assistant Secretary of Labor on the 26th day of January, 1918, which said warrant is included within and shown as

<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
 a part of Exhibit "A" hereinafter referred to and hereto attached and made a part hereof; that the said Charles Jackson was thereafter duly and regularly detained in custody under and by virtue of said warrant of arrest until the issuance and service of the warrant of the Acting Secretary of Labor for the deportation of said Charles Jackson.</p>
<p>3.  That on to-writ:- January 25, 1918, the said Charles Jackson, who is also known as Charles Peterson, was examined by and had a hearing before the United States Immigration Inspector, W.P. Callaghan, with relation to the matters and facts set forth in said warrant of arrest.</p>
<p>4.  That thereafter on to wit:- the 15th day of June, 1918, the said applicant, Charles Jackson, was given a hearing before a special board of inquiry convened pursuant to the instructions of the Commissioner of Immigration and composed of Inspectors S. J. Benford, Trent Dozer and W.P Callaghan, at which said hearing the said Charles Jackson was represented by counsel and testimony was heard with relation to the charges set forth in said warrant of arrest and with relation to the liability of said Charles Jackson to deportation under the laws of the United States.</p>
<p>5.  That the said applicant, Charles Jackson, had a fair hearing before said board as aforesaid and that upon the conclusion of said hearing the said board duly made its findings and rejected the said Charles Jackson on the ground that he had entered the United

<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>

States within three years preceding said hearing without inspection required by law and that at the time of the entry of the said Charles Jackson he was an alien of the inadmissible class in that he was then suffering from a loathesome, dangerous and contagious disease and that at said time of said entry the said Charles Jackson was a person likely to become a public charge, and upon the further ground that the said Charles Jackson was affiliated with an organization which advocated and taught the unlawful destruction of property.</p>
<p>6.  That the record in said proceedings, including said record of examination before Inspector Callaghan on said January 25, 1918, and which said record of examination was incorporated in and as a part of the said hearing before the said board of enquiry, was duly transmitted to the Secretary of Labor for action thereon; that thereafter upon due consideration of said matter and of the proceedings therein, the findings and recommendation of said board of inquiry were duly and regularly approved, and on to wit:- the 2nd day of October, 1918, under said findings and approval thereof warrant of deportation was duly and regularly issued by the Acting Secretary of Labor, which said warrant directed that the said Charles Jackson be deported in accordance therewith; that ever since the said 2nd day of October 1918, the respondent, Henry M. White, as Commissioner aforesaid held and

<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
detained and does now hold and detain said Charles Jackson under and by virtue ofsaid warrant of deportaion, which said warrant is set forth and included in Exhibit "A" hereto attached and made a part hereof.</p>
<p>7.  That the said Charles Jackson has had a full and fair hearing as provided by law and that a record of the proceedings had with relation to the deportation of said Charles Jackson as aforesaid, including transcript of testimony aduced in said proceedings and including the warrant of arrest and the warrant of deportation hereinabove mentioned is set forth in Exhibit "A" hereto attached and by reference made a part hereof.</p>
<p>Wherefore this respondent prays that said order to show cause be discharged; that the said application for a writ of habeas corpus be denied and that the said Charles Jackson be remanded to the custody of this respondent to be dealt with according to law and according to the terms and directions of said warrant of deportation.</p>

<p>Joh H. Sargent<lb/>
Actg Commissioner of Immigration<lb/>
Rob't E. Saunders<lb/>
United States Attorney<lb/>
H. D. Folson Jr<lb/>
Attorney, Dept, of Justice<lb/>
Ben L. Moore<lb/>
Assistant United States Attorney
</p>

<fw>-4-</fw>
<pb/>

<p>The United States of America Western District of Washington Northern Division}</p>
<p>ss.</p>
<p>John H Sargent being first duly sworn on oath deposes and says that he is Acting Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington; that he has read the foregoing return and answer, is familiar with the contents thereof and that the matters and facts therein set forth and alleged are true.</p>
<p>John H. Sargent</p>
<p>subscribed and sworn to before me this 25th day of November 1918.</p>
<p>F. M. Harshberger<lb/>
Clerk, U. S. Dist. Court, Western Dist. of Washington</p>




</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>