<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0492.008">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Khattak, Janana" xml:id="jk">Janana Khattak</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
                    
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
            
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0492.008</idno>
                
<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">IntheMatterofthePetitionofFrancisStephenMedcrafforWritofHabeasCorpus</title>
<date when="1915-09-24">September 24,1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
                
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>
                
<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>
                
<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>
                
<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-09">September 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
                
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Francis Stephen Medcraft</term>
<term>Ed M Lakin</term>
<term>Jeremia Neterer</term>
<term>Alfred H. Lundin</term>
<term>Geo. D Emery</term>
<term>Frank P Helsell</term>
<term>Frank L. Crosby</term>
</keywords>
                
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>United States District Court For the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</term>
</keywords>
                
</textClass>
      
<particDesc>         
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Medcraf, Francis Stephen</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Ludin, Alfred H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Helsell, Frank P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremia</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
                              
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of The United States For THe Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName> 
<placeName>/Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg> 
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-09" who="#jk">transcribed and encoded.</change> 
</revisionDesc>
        
</teiHeader>
<text>  
  
<body>
<div1 type="case"> 

<p>Original
No. </p>

<p>In the District Court 
of the United States for 
the Western District of Washington, 
Division</p>

<figure><p>Filed In The
U.S. District Court,
Western Dist. of Washington,
Northern Division
Sep241915
Frank L. Crosby, Clerk
By <signatures>Ed. M Lakin</signatures> deputy
<add>2x</add></p></figure>

<p>Geo. D. Emery
Attorney for</p>

<p>Telephone:
Elliot 4606</p>

<p>419 Central Building
Seattle, Wash.</p>

<p>At which office they consent that serivce of all 
subsequent papers, except writs and processes,
may be made upon them</p>

<p >Bull Bros. "Just Printers"</p>

<p>Service of within 
this<gap></gap> day of <gap></gap>191
and recepit of a copy thereof, admitted,
Attorneys for </p>

<pb></pb>

<p>In the United States District Court For The
Western District of Washinton, Northern 
Division</p>

<p><add>3038</add></p>

<p> In the Matter of the 
application of Francis Stephen Medcraf
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Brief For Petitioner.</p>

<p>MR GEO. D. EMERY, for the Petitioner</p>

<p>THE PETITIONER was charged and conviced before a Justice of the
Peace with the 'crime' of practicing dentistry without a certificate'
contrary to the provisions of the Dental Code of Washington.</p>

<p>Having been committed to prison under this conviction he brings
this proceeding to enquire into the lawfulness of the imprisonment.</p>

<p>He alleges that the statute under which these proceedings were 
had and the conviction was entered is void because in conflict with 
the provisions of Section 1 of the Fourteenth Amendment to the U.S.
Constitution, in that he is deprived of his liberty and property
without due process of law and that the Act in question denys to him
(a person within the jurisdiction of the State) the 'equal protection
of the laws'.</p>

<p>The amendment in question provides,
"nor shall any state deprive any person of life, liberty or 
property, without due process of law, nor deny to any person
within its jurisdiction the equal protectoin of the laws."</p>

<p>Sec. 1977 of the Comp. Laws of the U.S. guarantees equal rights
under the law to all 'persons' within the jurisdiction of the States
and under the laws of every state. Such 'persons' shall have the 
right "in every state and territory- - to the full and equal benefit
of all laws and proceedings for the security of persons and property"</p>

<p>The citizenship of the 'person' is therefore of no consequence.
The pledge of 'equal protection of the laws' is a pledge of the 
protection of 'equal' laws. <add>Yick Wo vs Hopkins 118 U.S. 356.</add></p>

<p>THE FIRST DENTAL CODE of Washington is found in Hills Statutes
&amp; Codes of Wash. Sec. 2854 et seq. being the Act of Jany 1888.</p>

<p><add>1</add></p>

<pb></pb>

<p>It provides;
"--it shall be unlawful for any person to engage in the 
practice of dentistry in the state of Washington, unless said 
person has graduated and received a diploma from the faculty of a dental 
college chartered under the authority of some one of the United
States or foreign governments, or shall have obtained a certificate
from a board of dentists duly authorized and appointed by the 
provisions of this chapter to issue such certificates."</p>

<p>A board of 5 dentists is provides for to be appointed by
the Governor who are to be "practicing dentists" and take an oath 
of office.</p>

<p>Persons practicing dentistry in the state at the passage of
the Act must enroll their names with the Board within 3 months and 
shall thereupon-without examination- receive a certificate as a 
practitioner of dentistry within the state.</p>

<p>All others desiring to practice dentistry must submit to an 
examination before the Board and must show the posession of skill in
dental surgery 'satisfactory to said Board', and shall thereupon
receive such certificate to practice.</p>

<p>IN 1893 this law was amended; The new act provided for
A slight change in the system of appontents of the Board.</p>

<p>Examination of those desiring to practice dentistry in the 
state, prescribing a standard of qualifications and requiring that 
"no person shall be eligible for such examination unless he or she
shall be of good moral character and shall present to said board his
or her diploma from some dental college in good standing and shall
give satisfactory evidence of his or her rightful possession of the 
same; PROVIDED, That the said Board may admit to examination such
other persons of good moral character as shall give satisfactory evidence
of having been engaged in the practice of dentistry ten years
prior to the date of the application for examination."</p>

<p>All persons authorized to practice under the former law and 
still engaged in practice are to be enrolled and licensed without 
further examination.</p>

<p>Students enrolled in a regular dental college and studying
in a licensed dentists office in the state are exempted from the 
penal provisions and might practice under their preceptor.</p>

<p>(N.B. There was then, as now, no 'dental college' in the State
so the regular attendance thereon required by the act was of no 
value or efffect in fact)</p>

<p>IN 1901 this law materially amended and all its provisions
inconsistent with the new act were repealed. This act is Chap 152 of
the Laws of 1901. Section 4 of this act provides;</p>

<p>"Any person or persons seeking to practice dentistry in the state
of Washington, or to own, operate or cause to be operated or run,
or manage a dental office or place for the practice of dentistry in
the State of Washington, after the passage of this Act, shall file
his or her name, together with an application for examination, with

<add>2</add>

<pb></pb>

the Secretary of the State Board of Dental Examiners at the time
of making such application, shall pay to the secretary of such Board
a fee of twnty-five dollars nd present him or herself at the first
regular meeting thereafter of said Board to undergo examination 
before that body.</p>

<p>No person shall be eligible for such examination unless he or
she shall present to said Board his or her diploma from some Dental
College in good standing and shall give satisfactory evidence of his 
or her rightful possession of the same; PROVIDED, this section shall
not apply to persons engaged in the practice of dentistry at the 
time of the passage of this act who are bona fide citizens of the 
State of Washington."</p>

<p>Provision is made for the issue of licence or certificate to the 
successful applicant and for recording such certificate and the practice
without such record of dentistry is made penal under fine of
$50.00 to $200.00 or imprisonment in the County Jail for not more
than six months.</p>

<p>It appears by the record that the state Board of Dental Examiners 
employed one Conover to go the office of petitioner and secure
his professional services to remove two decayed teeth and paid him
therefor. Thereupon Conver - by direction of the Board - filed a 
complaint with the Justice, secured a warrant thereon and the arrest 
of petitoner for 'practicing dentistry without having a certificate
of admission to practice recorded with the County Auditor', contrary
to said Act. <add>(State Board Prosecuting Case)</add></p>

<p>Upon the trial, petitioner duly raised all the constitutional
questions here presented but his objections being overruled, the
evidence was taken. It thereby appeared that petitioner had served
five years as an apprentice to a competent and reuptable dentists in
London, Eng; had continuously thereafter practiced dentistry in the 
employ of competent dentists in England, France and Greece for 8
years: thereafter continued suchc practiced for himself in London, 
Canada and the United States for 7 years and thereafter in Seattle for 
7 years, making a continuous practice of 27 years-including his
apprenticeship. That he had, before commencing practice in Seattle,
duly applied to the said Board of Dental Examiners, tendered the fee
and requested and appeared for examination but such examination was
refused on the ground that petititoner had no diploma from a dental
college. Whereupon and for that reason a certificate and licence 
were refused. His conviction and sentence followed.</p>

<p><add>3</add></p>

<pb></pb>

<p>ARGUMENT</p>

<p>THE POWER OF POLICE REGULATION of the practice of DENTISTRY by the
State being conceded, it is contended by the Petitioner that this
Act far transcends the powers of the State in that particular.</p>

<p>It is unreasonable in its provisions; an unnecessary and improper
restricction of and infringement upon the rights of the individual to 
practice his profession for his livelihood; unnecessarily deprives
him of property and restrains his liberty, contrary to the constitutional
provision referred to; and constitutes unlawful discrimination, 
and is therefore VOID.</p>

<p>"In the exercise of the police power in the regulation of 
business, the legislature may not arbitrarily impose any vexatious 
burdens upon the pursuit of any of these avocations."</p>


<p>People vs Steele 14 L.R.E. (NS) 368.
Kan. City Gas Co. vs Kan. City 198 Fed. 500
Harmon vs State 66 Oh. St. Rep 254</p>

<p>"The public power to regulare railroads and the private right 
of ownership of such property co-exist; they do not destroy each one
the other; and where the power to regulate is so arbitrarily 
exercised as to infringe upon the rights of ownership, the exertion is
void because it is repugnant to the due process and equal protection
clauses of the Fourteenth Amendment."</p>

<p>Atlantic Coast Line RR. vs North Car. 206 U.S. 1</p>

<p>"There is no easier nor more tempting opportunity for the 
practices of tyranny than in the police control of occupations. Good and 
bad motives often combine to accomplish this kind of tyranny. The 
seal of the reformer as well as cupidity and self interest must
alike be guarded against. Both are apt to prompt the employment of
means to attain an end desired, which the constitution prohibits."</p>

<p>---"if the business is not inherently harmful, the prosecution
of it cannot rightfully be prohibited to one who will conduct it in 
a proper and circumspect manner. Such an one would be 'deprived of
his liberty without due process of law'."</p>

<p>Tiedman on Police Powers Sec. 102.</p>

<p>"Any prohibition which extends further than to prevent the 
mission of incompetent men, will be unconstitutional."</p>

<p>Ib. Sec. 87</p>

<p>"If under the guise of the police power, the legislature unreasonably 
and capriciously restrains one's liberty or property, the 
Court may interpose the Constitution and declare the law void."</p>

<p>State vs Smith 33 L.R.A. (NS) 187. (Mo.)</p>

<p>A law wich unnecessrily and oppressively restrains a citizen
from engaging in any traffic or disposing of his property as he may
see fit, though passed under the specious pretext of a preservative
of the health of the inhabitants, would be void."</p>

<p>State vs Fischer 52 Mo. 174</p>

<p>The right to practice one's profession is 'property' of which he may
not be unnecessarily or arbitrarily deprived.</p>

<p><add>6</add></p>

<pb></pb>

<p>State vs Sachs 2 Wash 373</p>

<p>The practice of the profession of Dental Surgery or Dentistry is
a profitable employment, an honorable profession and an important
one both to the petitioner and to the public. The sole element
of danger and the sole point at which the police power pproches it 
is in the admission to practice of incompetent persons. The health
of the public demands that due precautions be exercised by the state
in admitting to practice dentistry only those who are qualified and
possess good moral character and the requisite technical kill.</p>

<p>Beyond this the State has no right or power to go. In prescribing 
the standard of qualification it must look to the true purpose which
it is authorized to conserve. It may not, under the pretext of a 
police regulation, create and protect a select and favored class, to
the exclusion of others equally well qualified to practice the 
profession. Wherein does a diploma entitle a man to undergo an 
examination to test his fitness, any more than long years of active and
arduous practice and practical experience under qualified tutors></p>

<p>Why may the boy or girl fresh from the halls of some Dental 
college, be admitted to display his or her qualifications by examination
while the actual practitioner of 27 years standing, of wide and 
valuable actual practice and experience, is debarred therefrom?</p>

<p>Is such a requirement 'reasonably necessary' to the health of the 
inhabitants? Or is it not rather valuable in that it will restrict
the number of practitioners that may come in from other states to the
possible detriment of the present local practitioners?</p>

<p>It is said that the legislature is the best judge of the neccessity 
for the exrcise of the police power and the means of accomplishing 
that exercise. This may possess some merit but it must not be
carried too far. The moment that the legislature transcends the 
limit of 'reasonable and necessary requirement' it comes in conflict
with the Constitutional provision and must fall.</p>

<p>In Eastman vs State 10 N.E. 97 cited by the respondent here, the 
supreme court of Indiana announced the strange doctrine that the 
question of whether the eact was reasonable or not was a legislative
<add>5</add>

<pb></pb>

and not a judicial question. Strange assumption. If this were
true, how could the courts ever determine a law to be unconstitutional</p>

<p>The legislature having adopted it, must be presumed to have found
it necessary, <add>and reasonable</add> therefore it is constitutional!</p>

<p>Again and again the Supreme Court of the United States has 
contradicted this doctrine and held that the reasonbleness of the law
and its necessit are for the Court to pass upon and if found 
unreasonably and unnecessary as an exercise of the police power, it is
void.</p>

<p>"To justify the state in thus interposing its authority in behalf 
of the public, it must appear, first, that the interests of the public
generally, as distinguished from those of a particular class, 
requries such interferance: and, second that the means are reasonably 
necessary for the accomplishment of ther purpose and not unduly oppressive
upon individuals: The legislature may not, under the guise of 
protecting the public interests, arbirtrarily interfere with private
business, or impose unusual and unnecessary restrictions upon lawful
occupations. In other words, its determination at to what is a proper
exercise of its police powers is not final or conclusive, but is
subject to the supervision of the Courts." Afteer citing numerous case
the court continues;</p>

<p>"In all these cases the acts were held to be invalid as involving
an unnecessary invasion of the rights of property and a practical 
inhibition of certain occupations, harmless in themselves, and which 
might be carrie don without detriment to the public interest."</p>

<p>Sanitary Dist. vs C. &amp; A. R. Co. 108 N.E. 314</p>

<p>The exercise of the police powere must be necessary and its 
methods reasonable in their provisions and must not unnecessarily nor
arbitrarily interface with the inherent rights of the citizens. When
they go beyond these limits, the are in conflict with the Constitution
and have no validity.</p>

<p>State vs Florida E.C. RR. 67 So. 911
Atlantic C.Eine RR vs North Car. 206 U.S. 1</p>

<p>THE OBJECT OF THE LAW is the protection of thehealth of the 
inhabitants. To that end, the qualifications of those who assume to 
practice dentistry are material and of importance. Reasonable tests and
regulations to secure the end are lawful and if such interfere with 
the right of the individual to practice, they are still valid. But
when they go beyond the line of reason or necessity and are no longer
regulative of the practice of the profession but undly restrict that
right in a qualified individual, they are prohibited by the Federal 
Constitution.<add>6</add></p>

<pb></pb>

<p>7</p>

<p>Every citizen has a right to engage in any lawful pursuit.
This is a natural right. The practice of Dentistry could not lawfully
be prohibited by the State nor could it be materially hampered
without great inconvenience and injurty to the public. Like the 
practice of law or medicine it is essential to the health and well
being of the people. When the State has taken reasonable and proper
measures to protect the pople from impositon and want of skill
on part of its practitioners, it has fulfilled its duty and
exhausted its power. It is fitting that practitioners be required to 
possess good moral character and to be skilled in their profession.
Such skill may be attained, in a perfunctory way, by a course in a 
dental college, but without practical experience, the graduate is
not thoroughly competent to practice. He is only beginning his
experience. It is idle to compare the skill of a youthful graduate
just from his college with the ripened experience of the practitioner
of 27 years actual practice of his profession. Why should the one 
be admitted to the test of an examination as to fitness and not the 
other?</p>

<p>At common law the field of dental practice was open to all. The 
practitoner was held liable in damages for any act or neglect not 
justified by his professions. A system of apprenticeship was 
recognized and became an established custom. This of course was long
before any Dental College was founded. The custom grew into a law
and the greatest dental practitioners of modern times obtained their 
first professional shcooling through the apprenticehsip to some
dentist. The custom still prevails in almost every stte and is recognized
in our own. There is not and never was a dental college 
in this State. How then can an apprentice or student be enrolled 
in and attend lectures in such a college and at the same time gain
anything of knowledge froma  dental preceptor in this state?</p>

<p>Such a provision of law is meaningless in view of the conditions.
In almost every state there exists an association of dentists 
under various names, constituting a state dental society. This 
ystem of societies is bound together by a National organization.</p>

<p>In purusit of its own purposes, this society has framed and 
pressed to enactment the laws governing the practice of dentistry <add>7</add>

<pb></pb>

<add>8</add>
in may of the states, notably in New York, Minneota, Michigan, 
Wisconsin, the Carolinas, North Dakota, Oregon, California, and
Washington.</p>

<p>In the states where such society has secured legislation, the 
requirement of a diploma is made a pre-requisite to an examination,
always excepting those in actual practice when such acts were passed</p>

<p>In some of these states the Courts have been led into sustaining
such laws though it is apparent frome examination of the deccisons
that the constitutional questions has rarely been raised and 
never upon such a state of facts as here exists. Little authority
is cited to sustain such decisons. The reasons given in support of
them are unsatisfactory and in many cases the question decided is
entirely obiter dictum. </p>

<p>An examination of the statutes of all the states shows;
19 states provide for diploma as pre-requisite to examination.</p>

<p>Arizona, California, Colorado, Florida, Georgia, Iowa,
Kentucky, Maryland, Michigan, Minnesota, Missouri, New
York, North Carolina, North Dakota, Oregon, Pennsylvania,
Wisconsin, Washington and Wyoming.</p>

<p>17 states require either a diploma or an examination</p>

<p>Arkansas, Alaska, Connecticut, Delaware, Idaho, Illinois,
Indiana, Kansas, Massachusetts, Mississippi, Montana,
Nevada, Nebraska, New Jersey, Ohio, South Dakota and Utah.</p>

<p>30 prescribe a standard of qualification in specified branchs 
of learning.</p>

<p>18 require an examination "satisfactory to the Board"</p>

<p>A majority of the states providing for both diploma and examination make some provisions whereby the Board of Examiners must consist of 
members of the State Dental Society.</p>

<p>The same states provide, generally, for the admission without
examination upon the certificates of Dental Boards of such states
as admit their practicioners on like certificates-in other words
a reciprocal law.</p>

<p>The New York law is noticable as an example of the influence of
this society. <add>The applicant must have passed 4 years in
a High School and be a graduate of school"</add>
school or its equivalent or must have received as a gradute a dental
degree or have pursued a course of dental study and hold  degree
from some dental colelge or Foreign Country or must have practiced <add>8</add>

<pb></pb>

<add>9</add>
dentistry for 25 years in some state other than New York.</p>

<p>These condtions give much force to the suggestion that the
laws in question are framed with the design to protect the Dental
Society from competition rather than the public. They rank with 
the legislation influenced and secured by Manufacturers, Plumbers,
and declare generally which ostensibly protect the public yet in 
truth serve more perfectly to foster monopolies and combinations.</p>

<p>It would be perfectly easy to enact laws that would really protect
the inhabitants from quacks and unskillful practitioners and 
at the same time give to honest and competent dentists the right to 
live and practice their vocation.</p>

<p>The act of 1901 discriminates against apprentices, no matter 
how skillful they may have become by years of subsequent practice, and 
requires them to go through a dental college in order to be 
entitled to show their qualifications. In othere words, they must
expatriate themselves and taken three years of a dental college
course to learn just what they know already, before they can be even
examined as to their skill and knowledge. To state the case is to 
point its unreason.</p>

<p>OUR OWN SUPREME COURT, in Brown vs State 37 Wash. 105 held this
very act void in part. The act provides that the owner or manager
of a dental office must ve a licensed dentist. This portion was 
held in conflict with the state constitution. The court said;</p>

<p>"We fell that a court should be reluctant to pronounce a statute
invalid except where its plain duty impels such action,. Conceiving
this to be such a case, we are led to declare that part of 
the stature requiring an examination and license in order to 'own,
run or manage' a dental office or department, void."</p>

<p>If this part of the act is void, why not the whole act? Can it 
be presumed tht the legislature would have passed then rest o the 
act, repealing the 'standard' and confining the license privilege to
graduates only, if it had believed the portion stricken to be void?.</p>

<p>The mutilated act is much less valuable to the public than the
act which is supplants. The act of 1893 provides a fixed standard
to which practitioners must conform -  a required amount of skill <add>9</add>

<pb></pb>

10.
<add>42 had Dec 82</add>
which they must possess. This might be show either by a diploma 
from some recognized dental college or by an examination upon certain
fixed subjects, constituting a standard, to which all must attain.</p>

<p>In the same decsion the court further says;</p>

<p>"The police power does not justify the withholding from one 
individual of a natural privilege or right, in order that a corresponding
advantge may be added to the rights or privileges of another.</p>

<p>The restriction is permissible only as a preventive of evil reults 
reasonably to be expected without such limitation.Russell on 
Police Power pp 34,35 says; 'To justify the statute in thus interposing 
its authority, in behalf of the public generally as distinguished from those of
a particular class, require such interferance, and second, that the 
means are reasonably necessary for the accomplishment of the purpose,
and not unduly oppressive upon individuals.'"</p>

<p>The true test of those who assume to practice dentistry must
necessarily be, not the mere posession of a diploma from some college, 
but the "posession of the actual technical skill nd knowledge
peculiar to the study and practice of dentistry".</p>

<p>It may be proper to provide that the possesssion of such diploma
shall be competent evidence of the possession of suh skill but it 
is manifestly unfair and oppressive to exclude those who possess
this skill, gained from expereience and practice without having
procured a diploma. It is the 'skill and knowledge' which protects
the public -  not the diploma. It is common knowlede that there
are many competent dentists in this country who have obtained their
skill and knowledge from long study and practice in some dentists
office and who never passed through a dental college. The practice 
of apprenticeship prevails in this as in most foreign countries.</p>

<p>Shall all such be excluded from practice-nay, even from 
examination as to their fitness? Must they go to a dental college to 
learn that which they already know?</p>

<p>Again in State vs Calusen 65 Wash. 178, the supreme court of 
this state referring to the police power says;</p>

<p>It is not meant to be asserted that this power is above the 
Constitution, or that everything done in the name of the Police power is
lawfully done. It is meant only to be asserted that a law which 
interferes with personal liberty and property rights is valid only
when it tends reasonably to correct some existing evil or promote
some interest of the state, and is not in violation of any direct
and positive mandate of the Constitution. The caluse of the Constitution
now under consideration was intended to prevent the arbitrary
exercise of power, or undue, unjust, and capricious interferances
with personal rights; not to prevent those reasonable regulations
that all must submit to as a condition of remaining a member of <add>10</add>

<pb></pb>

11.
society. In other words, the tests of a police regulations, when measured
by this clause of the constitution is reasonableness as 
contra distinguished from arbitrary or capricious action."</p>

<p>Measured by this test, does not this stature violate the constitutional 
provision? Why exclude the large class of competent
apprentice-made dentists for the sole benefit of the college 
graduates who are even far less competnet in point of fact?</p>

<p>Is it reasonable to exclude the large clss of dentists who gained 
their skill and knowledge without the aid of a college education?
Do petitioners 27 1/2 years of apprenticeship and active practice count
for nothing? Is it reasonable to forbid him to demonstrate to the
Board his competency, to exhibit his knowledge and skill, because
he did not obtain them at some dental colege? Or because he did
not live in the state at the time of the passage of the act?</p> 














<pb></pb> 
</div1></body>
</text>
</TEI>
