<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0181.050">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Seventy-six Hindus v. Seattle Department of Immigration. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Seventy-six Hindus v. Seattle Department of Immigration. Type of document</title>
<date when="2021">2021</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-10">October 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE SUPREME COURT OF THE UNITES STATES.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE UNLAWFUL 
DENTENTION OF SEVENTY-THREE
HINDOO ALIENS.</p>
<p>No. 2532 
ASSIGNMENT OF ERROR</p>
<p>Come now the petitioning aliens and file the following
assignment of errors on which they will rely in the prosecution
of their appeal in the above entitled cause to the Supreme Court
of the United States from the District Court of the Western Dis-
trict of Washington.</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to grant the writ of
habeas corpus.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>The court erred in holding the decision of the
immigration department final, and that the court would not inter-
fere to see justice done where injustice was alleged, as the
allegation was made that there was no evidence and that the con-
struction of a statute was involved and a legal matter was at
issue as to the construction of Section 20, and in holding the
immigration decision final and in refusing to examine the evi-
dence for the purpose of testing the correctness of petitioners'
<pb></pb>
allegations</p>
<p>III.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to find that the
petitioners had been deprived of their constitutional rights
under Articles 5, 6, 8, and 14 of the amendments of the
Constitution of the United States.</p>
<p>IV.</p>
<p>The court erred in not holding that the examination 
at Seattle, Washington, after a due and proper exami-
nation by the immigration authorities at Manila, after resi-
dence in the Philippine Islands for several years, was not
an improper examination and an abuse of authority and discre-
tion.</p>
<p>V.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to hold that the exami-
nation and admission at Manila, a regular port of entry,
was not final and sufficient.</p>
<p>VI.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to find that the warrant
of arrest on authority of which the aliens were threatened
with deportation, was not faulty and contrary to law and not a
sufficient warrant on which to deport the aliens under author-
ity of the Act of February 20, 1907, and Section 20 thereof.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>VII.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to find that the
examination was not fair and impartial and in refusing
and failing to find that the immigration authorities
went outside of the law and acted contrary to law in
issuing the warrant and in threatening to deport.</p>
<p>VIII.</p>
<p>That the court erred in refusing to find and
failing to find that the immigration department violated
the Act of February 20, 1907, and particularly Section
20 thereof, in that no evidence was ever produced show-
ing that the aliens came within the confines or within
the provisions of said law.</p>
<p>IX.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to find that the
aliens had never violated any of the provisions of the
said Act of February, 20, 1907, and refusing to fina
that the immigration department officials transcended the
bound of their authority in holding that the aliens had
violated the provisions of the Act and came within the
provisions thereof.</p>
<p>X.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the de-
cision of the immigration department and the issuing of
the warrants was all contrary to law and in direct violation
of the Act of February 20, 1907.</p>
<p>XI</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the 
<pb></pb> 
Commissioner of Immigration and the Secretary of Labor, 
in denying petitioners right to land, when there was no
evidence on which to base said decision, was not an
abuse of authority and discretion.</p>
<p>XII.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the 
petitioners had once been duly examined and passed and
could not again be lawfully examined.</p> 
<p>XIII.</p> 
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the
petitioners had never become public charges and had
never entered the country unlawfully or surreptitious-
ly as intended in the Act of February 20, 1907, and there-
fore were not subject to arrest and deportation.</p>
<p>XIV.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to find that there
was no proper, material or substantial evidence, showing 
the aliens to come within the confines of Act of February
20, 1907.</p>
<p>XV.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing and failing to find
that as the aliens had lived under the protection of the
American flag in the Philippine Islands, their detention
at Seattle, Washington, was improper.</p>
<p>XVI.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that when
the aliens testified that they had been properly ex-
amined and passed by the immigration authority at Manila, 
and when they presented official documents stamped by the
<pb></pb>
immigration department in Manila, showing them to have
been properly landed there, that that was sufficient
proof to demand at lest some proof, showing a surrep-
titious landing or an unlawful entry at Manila, in order
to come within the Act of February 20, 1907 of the
Immigration Act.</p> 
<p>XVII.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the
warrants were improperly issued contrary to law and 
erred in not quashing the same.</p>
<p>XVIII.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the four
aliens, Moola Singh, Ram Singh, Ali Bux and Boggu Khan,
having had certificates, were not entitled to immediate
landing at Seattle, and that they were not improperly
detained at said port.</p>
<p>XIX.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the 
petitioners had had no hearing on the ground on which the 
exclusion was based.</p>
<p>XX.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the
aliens were not amenable to the law which was the basis
for the issuance of the warrants.</p>
<p>XXI.</p>
<p>The court erred in finding that the district
court had no jurisdiction to examine into the matter, as
<pb></pb>
the aliens had shown that no evidence was produced on the
ground of the deportation, and that there was a question
of law involved in that they were not amenable to the Act
of February 20, 1907, and that Section 20, on authority
of which they were arrested, did not apply to them. </p>
<p>XXII.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to grant the writ
of habeas corpus and in failing to release the peti-
tioners.</p>
<p>XXIII.</p>
<p>The court erred in refusing to order the aliens 
released and in quashing the warrants or arrest, as be-
ing unlawfully issued.</p>
<p>XXLV.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that there
had been no hearing accorded the aliens on the ground of
the deportation.</p>
<p>XXV.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the
testimony, under oath, of the aliens and the exhibits
furnished by aliens, showing them to have been in the
hands of the immigration officers at Manila did not over-
come any presumption as indicated in the ruling of the
department under Rule 14, sub-division 4.</p> 
<p>XXVI.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that Section 
20 was mandatory.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>XXVII.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the
immigration authorities abused their authority and they
did not fairly exercise their discretion in ordering
deportation of aliens when no evidence was produced on
the point of the deportation.</p>
<p>XXVIII.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the
allegation of unlawful entry was not proven and no
evidence was produced on the point.</p> 
<p>XXIX.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that Rule
22, sub-division 2 of the Immigration Act, had not
been complied with, as said provision requires that the
best evidence should be obtained and as the government
could have obtained the evidence from their own records
at Manila, and as they produced no evidence.</p>
<p>XXX.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the
immigration authorities had not complied with Rule 22.
Section 4, in that that provision provides for the confine-
ment of aliens in alms houses, hospitals and jails, and
that no such proof was ever offered.</p>
<p>XXXI.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that under
Rule 14, Sub division 4 of the Immigration Rules of
November 15, 1911, that the immigration officials vio-
<pb></pb>
lated said provision and that said presumption did not
apply to the aliens in this case, as a lawful entry at
Manila had been shown and no evidence introduced to over-
come said definite testimony.</p>
<p>XXXII.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that
Section 25 had no application in these cases and refers,
so far as the finality of decision goes, to cases where
the aliens were making their first entry and not those
resident in the country, as in this case.</p>
<p>XXXIII.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to find that the
violation of the Act as is outlined in Section 21 refers
to Section 20 as to unlawful entry and becoming charges,
which were not proven in these cases.</p>
<p>XXXIV.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to strictly construe
Section 20.</p>
<p>XXXV.</p>
<p>The court erred in failing to release the aliens
as prayed for in their petition.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE the said petitioners pray that the
judgment of the said trial court be reversed and that the
said District Court of the United States for the Western
District of Washington, Northern Division, be directed to
release the aliens and that they be released from custody
and given their freedom, in accordamce with justice and law.</p>
<p>Herbert W. Meyers
Attorney for petitioners.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>No. 2532 Tx</p>
<p>IN THE SUPREME COURT OF THE
UNITED STATES.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE UNLAWFUL 
DETENTION OF SEVENTY-
THREE HINDOO ALIENS.</p>
<p>ASSIGNMENT OF ERRORS.</p>
<p>Received Copy
Sept 30, 1913
EBBrockway
Asst U.S. Atty</p>
<p>FILED IN THE
U.S. District Court, 
Western Dist. of Washington.
OCT 4 1913 
FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk, 
By <unclear>BD</unclear> Wright Deputy</p>
<p>HERBERT W. MEYERS
ATTORNEY AT LAW
430-431-432-433 PIONEER BUILDING
PHONE MAIN 1278
SEATTLE, WASH.</p>
<p>MERCHANTS PRINTING CO., TIMES BLDG., SEATTLE</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>