<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0116.031"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Wiley v. Keokuk. Kansas Reports</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0116.031</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Wiley v. Keokuk. Kansas Reports</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1870-01">January 1870</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Horne</term>
<term>Keokuk, Moses</term>
<term>Malone</term>
<term>Murphy</term>
<term>Wiley, Albert</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Indiana</term>
<term>Kansas</term>
<term>Massachusetts</term>
<term>North Carolina</term>
<term>United States</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Wiley, Albert</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Keokuk, Moses</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Christian, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Nevison</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Rigg</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fonte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Kingman, C.F.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Douglas District Court</orgName> 
<placeName>Douglas County, Kansas</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="sab">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0116.031"/>

<p>66</p>
<p>KANSAS REPORTS.</p>

<p>ligence, or oppression mingle in the controversy, the law allows the jury to give what is called exemplary or vindictive damages." (8) "In cases of torts, and actions for false imprisonment, the jury are the only proper judges of how much the plaintiff ought to recover." The instructions raise the question, so much discussed of late by writers upon law, as to whether such damages as are called exemplary, vindictive or punitive ought ever to be allowed. We content ourselves with following the current of authorities, and decide that the instructions go no further than such authorities, and decide that the law is wrong, let the law-making power correct it. The rule, as laid down by the court below, has already received the sanction of this court. Malone v. Murphy, 2 Kan. 250. The whole subject is discussed pro and con, and the authorities referred to, in Greenl. Ev. 253, and note, and sections 254, 255; and Sedg. Dam. (4th Ed.) 533, and note. And, after all this discussion, the supreme court of the United States decide the law as laid down in these instructions. Mr. Justice GRIER, delivering the opinion of the court, well says: "If repeated judicial decision for more than a century are [*107] to be received as *the best exposition of what the law is, the question will not admit of argument. By the common as well as by statute law, men are often punished for aggravated misconduct or lawless acts by means of a civil action, and the damages inflicted by way of penalty or punishment given to the party injured." We have no doubt that such is the law. Whether it be founded in sound reason or not, it is not so much our province to say, as to determine if it be law. The writer hereof believes it to be not only good law, but founded on sound principles, and beneficial in its application. It often furnishes the only restraint upon a bad man, who cares little for his neighbors character, his person, or his property. The party injured pursues the wrong-doer to punishment, when society is too careless to do so.</p>
<p>It is claimed, however, in this case, that the action being for assault and battery, which is punishable by criminal proceedings, if exemplary damages are allowed then the wrong-doer is liable to be punished twice. To this two answers may be made, each of which is satisfactory. While the action is for assault and battery, and false imprisonment, the evidence only showed a false imprisonment; and the plaintiff fails to show how that is made a criminal offense. Second, the great weight of authorities is against such a modification of the doctrine. In Massachusetts, Indiana, and North Carolina such limitation has been ingrafted upon the doctrine of exemplary damages; but in most of the states it has been rejected, and we think rightfully.</p>
<p>These reasons render it unnecessary to consider at length the instructions asked by the defendant and refused, for they are the direct converse of those given, *asking the court to say that the jury could only give a verdict for the damages sustained, or "actually sustained." The petition contained the usual averment formerly found in actions for assault and battery, and false imprisonment, and the jury were authorized under it to give exemplary damages. As we understand the law, the instructions</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
