<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0268.011">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ernest Hutchinson v. City of Seattle. Brief. </title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Tecca, Lauryn" xml:id="lnt">Lauryn Tecca</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022-06</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0268.011</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ernest Hutchinson v. City of Seattle. Brief.</title>
<date when="1904">1904</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1904">1904</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hutchinson, Ernest</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>City of Seattle</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>William, Mitchell</persName>
<persName>Wilson, H.A.</persName>
<persName> de Bruler, Ellis</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#lnt">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES CIRCUIT COURT OF THE NINTH CIRCUIT
IN AND FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE PETITION
OF
ERNEST HUTCHINSON for a Writ 
of Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>BRIEF of RESPONDENT.</p>

<p>The petitioner in this cause insists that Sec. 7 of Ordinance
No. 6036 is unconstitutional and void, because of the license imposed
upon the business of selling goods by the use of trading stamps. The
same question was before the Supreme Court of the State of Washington
in the case of T.J. Fleetwood v. J.H. Read, 21 Wash., page 547. This
was a case involving the validity of an ordinance of the City of Tacoma,
which requires mechants using trading stamps for the sale of goods to 
pay an annual license of one hundred dollars, Sections one and two of
said Ordinance, which are found on pages 550 and 551 - 21 Wash., are as
follows: </p>

<p>"Section 1. Every person, firm or corporation within the City 
of Tacoma who shall use and stamps, coupons, tickets, cards or other
devices for the sale of goods, wares, and merchandise, which said stamps,
coupons, tickets or other similar devices shall entitle the purchaser
receiving the same to procure from any other firm or corporation, any 
goods, wares or merchandise free of charge upon production of any nu,ber
of said stamps, tickets, coupons, cards or other similar devices,
shall, be using the same, obtain a license, therefor from the city
clerk.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>"Sec. 2. Before obtaining such license the person applying 
therefor shall pay to the city treasurer the sum of one hundred dollars;
and upon such payment being made and filing a receipt therefor with the
city clerk, the city clerk shall issue to the firm or corporation making
such payment a license to use, for one year, the stamps, coupons,
tickets, cards or other similar devices mentioned in Section 1 of this ordinance."</p>

<p>Subdivisions one and two of Sec. 7 of Ordinance No. 6036, of
the City of Seattle, are as follows:</p>

<p>"Sec. 7. Subdivision 1. It shall be for any one to
sell, offer or attempt to sell goods and merchandise by selling trading 
stamps, checks, tickets or other thing of whatever name to merchants,
the same by such merchants being delivered to customers upon the purchase 
of goods and merchandise, and then exchanged by such customers with the
person selling such trading stamps, checks, tickets or other thing of
whatever name for his goods and merchandise, without first paying into
the city treasury the sum of six hundred dollars, and upon receipt
showing such payment, procuring a license, issued by the city comptroller,
authorizing the same. Such license shall be issued for the period 
of twelve months. </p>

<p>"Subdivision 2.Any merchant who deals in or uses any trading
stamps, checks or tickets mentioned in subdivision one of this section
must also firs pay into the City Treasury the sum of one hundred dollars,
 and upon receipt showing such payment, procure a license, issued
by the City Comptroller, authorizing the same. Such license shall be
issued for the period of twelve months.</p>

<p>It will be noticed that there is no difference between the
two ordinances, excepting that the Seattle ordinance requires the payment 
of a license of six hundred dollars a year by the person who sells
the trading stamps to the merchants. The exact principle involved 
in each case, and as it is not contended that the amount of license is 
unreasonable, the position of respondent must be upheld or the case cited
overruled.</p>

<p>We contend that the position of respondent is correct and that
Sec. 7 of Ordinance No. 6036 should be upheld.</p>

<p>Our State Supreme Court also upheld an ordinance of New Whatcom
requiring a license of twenty-five dollars per day for selling
stocks of merchandise: W.C. Stull v. J.P. DeMattos, et al., 23 Wash.,
page 71; and also a license fee of one hundred dollars per year upon 
the bsuiness of pawnbroking was upheld in the case of the City of Seattle
v. R.W. Barto, 31 Wash., page 141. In this last case, the title</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>of the same ordinance, 6036, was involved, as well as the license imposed
and the contention of the City upheld.</p>

<p>Repsectfully submitted,
Mitchell William, Ellis De Bruler and
H.A. Wilson.
Attorney for Respondent.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>Original
No. 1183</p>

<p>In the United States Circuit Court 
FOR THE DISTRICT OF Washington
Northern Division</p>

<p>In the petition 
of Ernest Hutchinson for 
a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Brief of Respondent</p>

<figure><p>Seal</p></figure>

<p>Mitchell WIlliam
Ellis DeBruler
H.A. Wilson
Attorney for Respondent</p>




</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>