<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0359.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>A. C. Hallam v. Henry M. White. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0359.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">A. C. Hallam v. Henry M. White. Petition</title>
<date when="1921-01-07">January 7, 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-01">January 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hallam, A. C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Garland, Marion</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-06" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>No. 5779</p>
<p>Petition.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of A. C. Hallam for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>To the Honorable, the Judges of the above entitled court:</p>

<p>The petition of A. C. Hallam respectfully shows:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That the said A. C. Hallam is a resident and citizen of the State of Washington and resides at the Navy Yard Hotel, in Kitsap County, Washington.</p>

<p>II</p>

<p>That the Navy Yard Hotel is a building located upon United States Government property and owned by the United States government, and is connected with and used for housing and caring for the employes of the Puget Sound Navy Yard.</p>

<p>III</p>

<p>That your petitioner is the agent for the United States of America acting under and through the Secretary of the Navy and the Commandant of the Navy Yard, and as such is managing and operating said hotel for the Navy Department.</p>

<p>IV</p>

<p>That on the 18th day of November, 1920, your petitioner was arrested by one Fred A. Watrous, Chief of Police of the City of Bremerton, Kitsap Country, Washington, upon a</p>

<pb/>

<p>warrant issued by James W. Carr, police judge in and for the said City of Bremerton, charging your petitioner with operating, conducting and maintaining a dance hall at the Navy Yard Hotel, and that thereafter, on the 27th day of December, 1920, and amended criminal complaint was filed wherein your petitioner was charged with committing a misdemeansor on the 15th day of November, 1920, in this:- That he the said A. C. Hallam did then and there operate <add>conduct</add> and maintain a public dance hall at the Navy Yard Hotel, a building then and there located on U. S. Government property, and then and there owned by the U. S. Government, and managed by the said A. C. Hallam under lease with the Navy Department, of the U. S. Government, being within the City of Bremerton, without having then and therepaid a license fee therefor, as provided by Ordinance No. 465, contrary <add>to</add> and in violation of the ordinances of the City of Bremerton in such case made and provided, and against the peace and dignity of the State of Washington.</p>

<p>V.</p>

<p>That on the 29th day of December, 1920, a hearing was had before said James W. Carr, police judge of the said City of Bremerton, and on said day said police judge entered a judgment fining your petitioner $10.00 and costs.</p>

<p>VI</p>

<p>That your petitioner refused to pay said costs, and on the 11th day of January, 1921, by an order of the police judge of the said City of Bremerton, your petitioner was ordered committed to the custody of the chief of police of the City of Bremerton, Kitsap County, Washington, until said fine was paid.</p>

<p>-2-</p>

<pb/>

<p>VII</p>

<p>That the detention of your petitioner is unlawful and an invasion of his rights upon the following ground: - That the police court of the City of Bremerton, Kitsap Country, Washington, had no jurisdiction over the person of your petitioner or over the subject matter as alleged in the amended criminal complaint, a copy of which is hereto attached.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus may be issued to E.H. Bowdin, Mayor, Chief of Police <add>ex officio</add> of the City of Bremerton, Kitsap County, Washington, commanding him to produce the body of your petitioner before this Honorable Court there to submit to and receive whatever the court shall order in the premises.</p>

<p>A. c. Hallam</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>

<p>Robt C. Saunders</p>
<p>United States Attorney</p>

<p>F. C. <unclear></unclear></p>
<p>Assistant United States Attorney</p>

<p>Attorneys for Petitioner</p>
<p>Federal Building, Seattle, Washington.</p>

<p>United States of America</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>ss:</p>

<p>This is to certify that on this 11th day of January, 1921, before me, the subscriber and notary public in and for the State of Washington, duly commissioned and sworn, personally came A.C.Hallam, the petitioner above named, who being by me first duly sworn, deposes and says that he is the petitioner above named; that he has heard the foregoing petition read, and that the facts therein stated are true.</p>

<p>Marion Garland</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State of Washington, residing at Seattle</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>