<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0365.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John Matthews v. Henry M. White. Decision</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0365.005</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">John Matthews v. Henry M. White. Decision</title>
<date when="1921-10">October 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-10">October 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Harshberger, F.C.</term>
<term>Leitch, S.E.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Matthews, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT
OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION OF  } NO. 6203
JOHN MATTHEWS                           } D E C I S I O N.
FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.            } Filed Oct.__.1921.</p>

<p>Geo. F. Vanderveer and Ralph S. Pierce, Attorneys for
Petitioner.
Robert C. Saunders, U.S. Atty, and Charlotte Kolmitz, Asst.
U.S. Atty, Attorneys for United States
NETERER, District Judge, - - - -</p>

<p>The petitioner under oath <unclear>charges</unclear> that:</p>

<p>"Under the provisions of the United States
Immigration Statute on the 19th day of February, 1921,
after a due hearing it was determined by said Secretary
of Labor for the United States that your petitioner had
been born in and was a citizen of Ukranis aforesaid and
should be deported thence under the provisions of the
immigration statute above referred to. That ever since
said date your petitioner has been and still is unlawfully
and unreasonably restrained of his liberty in the
County Jail **** under the pretended authority of said
warrant or order of deportation and that said restraint
is unreasonable and unlawful in this: that the government
of the United States, as your deponent is informed
and believes, has no diplomatic relations with the
government of Ukranis and is unable to execute its order
or warrant of deportation aforesaid and is unable to
deport your petitioner to said Ukranis and is making no
attempt to do so and has no intention in so doing, and
that unless the said Henry M. White, Commissioner of
Immigration aforesaid, is prevented from so doing he will
continue unlawfully and unreasonably to restrain your
petitioner of his liberty and confine him as a prisoner
in the county jail of King County aforesaid, all in
violation of your petitioner's right under the Constitution
and laws of the United States;" and prays a Writ.</p>

<p>A writ was issued and a return and supplemental return
made in which the record taken before the Commissioner of
Immigration is set out, from which it appears that the department
is unable to source a "Polish Passport" for the petitioner for
the reason "that no satisfactory information has been furnished
as to alien's place of birth." The order is to deport the
petitioner "to his home in Ukranis." This was entered on the</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>19th day of February, 1921. A supplemental return is presented
stating that the warrant of the deportation has been amended
directing the deportation of petitioner to "Eastern Galacia"
to which is attached a telegram from the Assistant Secretary
of Labor as follows:</p>

<p>"Ukranis and Eastern Galacia two seperate
countries with seperate and distinct governments of
their own STOP Not recognized by United States STOP
Town of which Jack Matthews is native is now in Eastern
Galacia and passport had to be secured from Eastern
Galacian representative before deportation could take
place STOP Warrant of deportation is hereby amended
directing deportation of alien to Eastern Galacia."</p>

<p>The testimony shows that the Bureau of Immigration
had determined as a fact that the petitioner was a
native of Ukrania. A party may not be deported to any
county other than of his nativity or of his allegiance. There
is no established fact in the record and name has been
presented before the court upon which to predicate an order of
deportation to Easter Galacia. It appears that Ukrania,
Galacia and Eastern Galacia are distinct sovereignties, that:</p>

<p>"The Galacian Republic is now temporarily in exile
outside the boudaries of its coutry because Galacia in
1919****was militarily occupied by Poland and that Eastern
Galacia is a seperate state." The Eastern Galacian
Government it appears in the record is contending against the
occupation by Poland.</p>

<p>It further appears that Eastern Galacia is
regarded as a distinct entity whose political status has not
yet been determined. "The Supreme Council by its decision
of December 8, 1919, defined the so-called Curzon-Pope line
as the extreme eastern temporary boundry of Poland."
(Italics nine). This boundary line excludes all of Eastern
Galacia, together with Lemberg, capital of that country.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>There is no evidence as to the location of this line and it
is admitted that Poland is the de facto military occupant of
Eastern Galacia, and the Galacian Government so-called is in
exile. It is stated that the petitioner was born in Kaminetz,
Podolska Province, Ukrania, that he left his place of birth
when fifteen years age, came to Ontario, Canada with his
parents where he resided until his entry into the United States
in 1917. There is no testimony (the telegram is not evidence)
in the record or produced upon this hearing which would warrant
the deportation of the petitioner to "Eastern Galacia."</p>

<p>It appearing that the petitioner cannot be deported
to Ukrania, he will be discharged unless within ten days
an appeal is prosecuted, panding which he may be released on his
recognizance in the sum of $1,000.00, with sufficient sureties
and the usual conditions.</p>

<p>Jeremiah Neterer
JUDGE</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>FILED IN THE
UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
Western District of Washington
Northen Division</p>

<p>OCT 3 1921</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk
By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<pb></pb>
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>