<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0115.001"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Sam Pong v. William Billings</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0115.001</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Sam Pong v. William Billings</title>
<date when="1885-04-22">April 22, 1885</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note>
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1885-06">June 1885</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Billings, William</term>
<term>Hong, Sam</term>
<term>Hoyt, John</term>
<term>Keady, W.T.</term>
<term>Yuk, Hong</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Olympia, Washington</term>
<term>Thurston County, Washington</term> 
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hong, Sam</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Yuk, Hong</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Last, First</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Last, First</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hoyt, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Keady, W.T.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the 2nd Judicial of Washington Territory</orgName> 
<placeName>Olympia, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018" who="nl">transcribed.</change>
<change when="2019" who="sab">encoded, edited transcription.</change> 
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0115.001"/> 

<note>2459</note>

<p>In the District Court of the 2d Judicial of Washington Territory holding terms at Olympia</p>

<p>In the matter of the application<lb/>
of<lb/>
<unclear>Sam Hong</unclear>
for a writ of habeas corpus to the Honorable John Hoyt Judge of said Court. The petition of Sam <unclear>Hong</unclear> respectfully shows that he is unlawfully restrained of his liberty and imprisoned detained and confined by William Billings Sheriff of Thurston County W.T. at Olympia Washington Territory. That said imprisonment detention confinement and restraint are illegal and that the illegality thereof consists of this to wit-: On the 22 day of April 1888 are <unclear>Kang Jik</unclear> made a complaint as statement in writing charging this petition with the crime of <unclear></unclear> being

<pb/>

property committed to <unclear></unclear> his <unclear></unclear> alleged to be committed, at Thurston Count W.T. on or about the 20th April 1888 <unclear></unclear> that charge the following is a true copy to wit-:</p>

<p>Territory of Washington County of Thurston} SS</p>

<p>In the Justice Court of Olympia Precinct before W.T. <unclear>Keady</unclear> Justice of the Peace Territory of Washington</p>

<p>Plaintiff</p>

<p>Sam Hung vs Defendant Hong Yuk being first duly sworn <unclear>avfores</unclear> and says that on or about the 20th day of April 1885 at Olympia Thurston County Washington Territory the above named Sam Hung committed the offense of <unclear>vandelizing</unclear> property entrusted to <unclear/> for five <del>one</del> in this <del>towit</del> that the said Sam Hung did then and there <unclear/> in the

<pb/>

and petitioner further shows, that thereupon a warrent was issued and petitioner was arrested and taken before the said Justice and duly appeared in said Court by his attorney and filed a <unclear>ducumence</unclear> to said complaint which was argued by counsel and the objections to said complaint issue by said Court overruled and defendant by his counsel duly excepted the objections to said complaint <unclear>argued</unclear> by petitioners were that the same did not state facts constituting any crime thereafter the examination of petitioner proceeded in said court and witnesses were sworn and examined and their testominy reduced to writing and which testimony is as follows: "April 23 1883 10 o'clock AM court called <unclear>NS Torter</unclear> for territory, <unclear>JC McFadden</unclear> &amp; <unclear>A.W. Bartmane</unclear> &amp; for Defendant</p>

<p>here follows the evidence</p>

<p>evidence</p>

<pb/>

<p><unclear>lawfully events</unclear> of one <unclear>Kong Mck</unclear> for a specific pupose towit for the collection of a certian draft fraudulently uncarefully and designedly <unclear>concuth</unclear> his <unclear>cut</unclear> use and embezzled the sum of $60.05 of said draft, the property of said <unclear>Kong Mck</unclear> within <unclear>that to</unclear> steal and comment <unclear>larcery</unclear> of said sum of money, all of which is contrary to the form and <unclear>effect</unclear> of the stattute in such case made and provided and against the peace and dignity of the People of Washington Territory. Wherefore the said <unclear>Haing Yek</unclear> prays that a warrant may issue for the <unclear>avers</unclear> of <del>the</del> said Sam Hung and that he may be dealt with according to law.</p>

<p>(Signed in <unclear/> <unclear/></p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 22d day of April 1885 (signed) W.T. <unclear>Keady</unclear> Justice of the Peace</p>

<pb/>

<p>And the said examination being concluded and argument of counsel cleared the said Justice of the Peace committed your petitioner to the County jail of Thurston County in default of bail <unclear/> the sum of $15.00 to await the acting of the Grand Jury upon said charge, and thereupon, ussed a warrant in words and by me as follows to wit-</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>