<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0216.047">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chin Hing v. United States of America. Digest of Evidence</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Russell, Ellie" xml:id="edr">Ellie Russell</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0216.047</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Chin Hing v. United States of America. Digest of Evidence</title>
<date when="1914-09-20">September 20, 1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-09">September 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hing, Chin</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Government, United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Sullivan, John J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen, Clay</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Fishburne, GP</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#edr">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>(Copy)</p>
<p>53817/43
Washington, D.C.
September 20, 1914.</p>

<p>Digest of evidence, case of Chin Hing.</p>
<p>The applicant in this instance is almost a major, having been
20 years and 8 months old at time of arrival. Nevertheless, he seeks 
admission by virtue of his minority and the claimed status of his
alleged father. The officials at New York and Seattle hve conceded
the mercantile status of the alleged father, Chin Shew, but the Bureau
does not agree with them.</p>

<p>It appears that Chin Shew claimed he has a $200 interest
in the Quong Wo Chong Co., 25 Pell Street, New York City, and is
employed there as bookkeeper. His assertions are corroborated by the
testimony of the manager of said firm and two white witnesses who deal
with him in the store conductedby said firm. the officials in 
New York have known Chin Shew in connection with the business of Quong
Wo Chong Co. Admitting the employment of Chin Shew in a mercantile
establishment at a salary of $30 or $40 a month, it is not believed
that his ownership of an interest of $200 out of a total capitalization
of $11000 (shown by a prior record, but not stated here) is sufficient 
to make him a merchant within the meaning of the law. It is also
showen by the record that there are 14 active partners out of a total of
68, but the investigating oficer fialed to report whether they were
all engaged in the store and whther the business was able to support 
that number of employees. Altogether, the Bureau cannot get away 
from the impression that Chin Shew's investment in this business was
made and is retained for the sole purpose of securing a status that
will enable him to bring "sons" to this country.</p>

<p>The evidence on the issue of relationship consists of the
statements of Chin Shew, the applicant and a Chinese witness. the
particular point urged against the proof by the Commissioner is that
Chin Shew has failed to show he was in China at a time to permit of
his paternity of a son the age given for applicant. The unsatisfactory
testimony of the applicant, though in agreement in most respects
with that of the alleged father, and one serious descrepancy which has
been overlooked at the port, constitue, in the Bureau's judgement, just
as strong a ground for holding that the relationship has not been
reasonably established. The discrepancy is wit respect to the
paternal grandfather,applicant having stated, in effect, that this
relative is dead and he has never seen him, while the alleged father 
said his father died at his home in 1900, which would be within the
memory of applicant. Concerning his presence in China at the 
essential time, the alleged father claimed he left his home in 1893,
going to Havana, Cuba; and that he was admitted at New York about
December, 1893, as a Section Six merchant. The arrival records
fail to verify admission at New York. It is possible that Chin
Shew entered this country in the manner claimed, although he has not given
<pb/>

the correct date, intentionally or otherwise, but if he did he was not
entitled to admission. The Bureau and Department have seen a 
number of cases of Chinese who were permitted to go in transit through
this country to Havana, Cuba, in the early nineties, and who later were
erroneously permitted to enter this country from that place by
virtue of Section Six certificates issued to them by the Chinese
Consul there as merchants of some city in China, and visaed by
American consular officers without the investigaton contemplated
by the law having been made.</p>

<p>Local counsel, Corry m. Stadden, Esq., has requested a
reexamination of the New York records in an attempt to verify the
landing of Chin Shew in December, 1893. He has given additional 
names by which this man might have been recorded. In view of 
what has been said hereinbefore as to the relationship and the
mercantile status, there woule be nothing grained by withholding
decision for the result of another search of the records to show
that Chin Shew was admitted in December, 1893, or about that time,
since that is not a decisive factor in the case. The request has,
accordingly, been denied.</p>

<p>Brief filed by counsel is next hereunder. His request that decision be 
withheld a few days for a report on a reexamination of the records of 
arrivals at New York should have been withdrawn by counsel in view of
the Bureau's denial of his application for a reexamination of said records.</p>

<p>The statement he was not "permitted to see the Finding or
Decree upon which the officers at the port denied admission." is intentionally 
erroneous. The Commissioner at Seattle designates his excluding
decision "order rejecting applicant." Counsel was shown the order
in this case on the basis of the Secretary's letter to him in the Yu
Sher Suek case (53817/42). His attention was called to the erroneous
nature of his statement, which he declined to change.</p>

<p>The rule of evidence which counsel cites to support his
contention that the failure of the alleged father to prove his admission
in December, 1893, does not affect the question of paternity, if applicable,
would not help him in this instance. The alleged father, not having
shown he entered this country from Cuba at the time stated, has not
proven he was in China at the essential time to make access possible, so
there is no presumption favorable to the claimed relationship.</p>

<p>The alleged father does assert he has been a merchant since
entering this country in 1893. It is noted, however, that until
about a year ago his interest in the store where he is now employed
is said to have been only $100.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>