<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0187.029">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0187.029</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1914">1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Brown</term>
<term>Gray</term>    
<term>Grayson, Marie Robina</term>    
<term>Hand</term>    
<term>Lacombe</term>    
<term>Merrick, Louis A.</term>
<term>Shakespeare, Noah</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Everett, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Marie Robina Grayson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Noah Shakespeare</persName>
<persName>Louis A. Merrick</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
    <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT, WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application 
of MARIE ROBINA GRAYSON, alias
MARIE ROBINA, for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus. )
n.g.
No. 2780
ANSWERING BRIEF OF 
PETITIONER.</p>

<p>The petitioner now at the earliest opportunity <del>of</del> calls 
the attention of the Court to points made and authorities citied 
in Memorandum brief of respondent.</p>
<p>Under title "Facts in the record" counsel refers to one
or two lone questions and answers, and stops. We would 
respectfully refer your Honor to the entire record and particularly 
that part thereof taken before the Immigrant Inspector at 
Everett, Washington, bearing date February 6th 1914 which in 
our opinion covers the principal facts for the consideration 
of this Court.</p>
<p>Referring to respondent's brief, that portion entitled 
"Meaning of statute" we disagree with counsel as to his claim
that the statute in force at the time of the opinion in Kelly 
vs Owen (Kahoe) was different from that in force now. The 
statute has always required that the applicant be a free white 
person or of African descent or nativity, have resided in the 
United States for five years, must have good moral character, 
be attached to the principles of the Constitution of the United 
States, &amp;c. True the moral character requirement does not appear
to have been discussed  in Kelly vs.Owen (Kahoe), but such 
requirement was nevertheless included in the statute then in 
force and in all naturalization statutes down to the present
time.</p>
<p>Careful examination of United States vs. Williams 132 Fed.
page 894, discloses the line distinguishing it from the case
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
at bar and from the cases cited by petitioner. United States
vs. Williams was an Immigration case where two minor children 
of a former alien attempted to procure entrance into this 
country.At the time of the arrival of the minors at Ellis Island 
their father had only taken out his first papers. They were
both afflicted with trachoma; the Board of enquiry directed 
their deportation; six days after such order of deportation
the father took out his final papers, applied for and obtained
a rehearing of the minors' case. The board differed, an appeal 
was taken to the Department where both minors were ordered
excluded. Thereupon a Writ of Habeas Corpus was issued by 
Judge Lacombe. The judge bases his conclusion clearly and 
unequivocally upon the ground that the minors were born without
the limits of the United States before their father became a 
citizen. Therefore they were aliens before they arrived at 
Ellis Island. The father's naturalization did not affect their 
status, for congress had limited such naturalization in that 
respect by this language, "The children of persons who have 
been duly naturalized under any laws of the United States being 
under the age of twenty-one at the time of naturalization of 
their parents, shall, if dwelling in the United States, be 
considered as citizens thereof." These minors never dwelt 
within the United States; their arrival at Ellis Island was not 
an entry into this country, hence the conditions prescribed by 
congress never existed. Petitioner does not in any way question
the correctness of the rule laid down in that case, but it has 
no possible bearing upon the one before our Honor. Here the 
petitioner concedely entered the country lawfully; thereafter 
remained within the country lawfully for twelve years; while 
lawfully in the country concedely married a native born American
citizen. The rule is entirely different in exclusion cases 
from that in deportation cases. In the one the applicant for 
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
admission must show the existence of every qualification 
prescribed by law; in the other the government assumes the burden 
of showing that the person sought to be deported is upon some 
statutory ground not entitled to remain within the country which 
she has entered, and the reason for the distinction is so plain 
it is unecessary for us to enlarge upon it. We reiterate that 
the citizenship of this petitioner became absolutely fixed as of 
the date of her marriage to Grayson, and the status acquired by 
marriage can only be changed by a direct proceeding to dissolve 
the marriage relation.</p>
<p>Another case cited by counsel is United States Vs. 
Rogers, 185 Federal 334. The distinction between this case
and the present case is substantially the same distinction 
that exists between the case of U.S. vs. Williams and present 
case. United States vs. Rodgers is an exclusion case and 
differs in principles as the Court will observe by a reading
of the opinion of Judge Gray. The person sought to be excluded
in the Rodgers case never succeeded in entering this country, 
hence acquired no rights, and so the difference in principle 
and result.</p>
<p>Another case cited by counsel is Re Rustigian 165 Fed. 
980 is a naturalization case of final hearing. Upon that final 
hearing Judge Brown continued the matter and we have no record
of the final result; apparently the petitioner was not granted 
his final papers for the reaosn, that if granted, his wife (who
was then in the custody of the Immigration Officer at New York
never having entered the country and suffering from trachoma)
might thereby become entitled to admission to this country.
The opinion discusses an apparent conflict between the Immigration
and Naturalization Laws the sole question in that case to 
be passed upon was whether the petitioner was entitled to be 
naturalized; discussion of such question is a discussion of a 
matter of law involved in a pending proceeding, discussion of 
anything else is mere obiter and is not authority. It is 
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
respectfully submitted that a large portion of the opinion of 
Judge Brown was not germane to the question before him, and 
while entitled to such weight as is the opinion of any lawyer, 
is entitled to none as the opinion of a judge <del>who may</del> <add>in a</add> cause
and on a question depending before him. We however ask the 
court to read the entire opinion of Judge Brown in this case 
for it will be observed that the question discussed by Judge
Brown was as to the effect of the naturalization of an alien 
upon that alien's wife who had never entered the country,and as 
to whether or not ipso facto the naturalization of the husband 
the non-resident alien wife gained the husband's political 
status. It is not necessary for us in this case to go to that
extent or to make that claim which is far beyond any claim made 
by petitioner necessary to the decision of this cause; and yet
counsel for petitioner and for United States in the Rustigian 
case agreed that the naturalization of the husband would entitle 
to entry into this country his non-resident alien wife who was 
suffering from trachoma.</p>
<p>Counsel cites the opinion of your Honor in re Moola 
Singh 207 Fed. 780. This was an exclusion case; petitioners 
never gained an entrance into this country and this court held
that the finding of the Immigration Officer was conclusive. 
We have no occasion to question the correctness of the rule in
that opinion. There was no claim in that case that petitioners
were American citizens, but on the contrary they were aliens 
seeking admission into this country. In such cases we concede 
that the holding of the Department, based upon a fair hearing 
is conclusive; but not so in the case of one having lawfully 
entered the country, remained therein lawfully for many years 
and during such lawful residence having married an American
citizen; under those circumstances the holding of the courts 
is uniform that <add>where</add> the rights of an American citizen are involved
and where there is no controversy as to the facts as in this 
<fw>-4-</fw>
<pb/>
case, the courts will determine the question of law without
regard to any Departmental ruling, and such is the language of 
Judge Hand in United States vs. Williams 173 Fed. 626 "Where
allegiance depends wholly upon a question of law the court must 
review that question and decide upon it." Nothing need be said 
here as to the eminent ability of Judge Hand, and this opinion
was affirmed by the Circuit Court of Appeals for the 2nd 
circuit in a unanimous opinion, 184 Fed. 322.</p>
<p>Something was said as to De Bruler vs. Gallo 184 Fed. 
566; the opinion in that case proceeds upon the theory that the 
facts were in dispute and the petitioner had not shown to the 
satisfaction of the appellate court the existence of American 
citizenship, and that the decision of the Department as to the 
facts would not therefore be reviewed by the courts. The court
uses this language "Mistakes of law by executive officers are of 
cource re-examinable by the courts". The court further say 
"but mere questions of facts such as the case before us where 
they have been <add>fairly</add> examined by the executive officers designated 
by congress for that purpose and their conclusions of fact 
reached upon, conflicting evidence will not be judicially 
reviewd"; we assent in every way to this statement of the law. 
it is unquestioned; but that is not this case; here there is 
no conflict upon the evidence, it is here simply a question of 
applying the law to the conceded facts, and the claim is that 
a mistake of law was made by the Department. If there was it 
is the duty of this court to review and correct that mistake.</p>
<p>The holding of our own Circuit Court of Appeals in 
Hopkins vs. Fachant, 130 Fed. 839 has never been modified, 
distinguished or reversed. It is still the settled law throughout 
the 9th circuit. Law as announced in that case undoubtedly 
formed the basis for the opinion in re Larcher so that we have 
the doctrine announced by the highest court in this circuit 
in harmony with the holdings in other circuits, in <del>holdings</del> <add>harmony</add>
<fw>-5-</fw>
<pb/>
with the decisions of the Supreme Court of the United States, 
and followed and applied by a distinguished District Judge of 
this Circuit, and not in any way conflicting with the prior 
holdings of your Honor in re Moola Singh. Can the rights of 
an American citizen, rights which have been jealously guarded 
for a century past be taken away by mere executive order? 
An American citizen is entitled to her day in court to have her 
rights determined under the Constitution by the judiciary and 
not by an executive department.</p>
<p>These remarks are submitted for the reason that 
petitioner's Attorneys were not in possession of the return 
until a few moments before the argument, nor had they been 
served with any points and authorities on behalf of respondent.</p>

<ab>Respectfully submitted, 
Noah Shakespeare 
and Louis A. Merrick
Attorneys for petitioner</ab>

<pb/>

<p>No. 2780</p>

<p>In re:
Marie Robina Grayson</p>

<p>Answering 
Brief</p>

<gap/>

<p>NOAH SHAKESPEARE <add>and</add>
ATTORNEY AT LAW 
<add>L. A. Merrick</add>
EVERETT, WASHINGTON
PUGET PRESS EVERETT, WASH.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>