<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0151.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ferdinand Marino and Carolina B. Marino v. D. H. McCalla. Order</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Silva, Salma J" xml:id="sjs">Salma Silva</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0151.005</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ferdinand Marino and Carolina B. Marino v. D. H. McCalla. Order</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Marino, Joseph</term>
<term>Mayo, H. T.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Ferdinand Marino</persName>
<persName>Marino, Carolina Beluscia</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>McCalla, D. H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Preston</persName>
<persName>Carr</persName>
<persName>Gilman</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName/>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The Circuit Court of the United States for the District of Washington, Northern Divison</orgName>
<placeName>District of Washington, Northern Division</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<ab>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE DISTRICT OF 
WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</ab>

<ab>FERDIKAND MARINO and CAROLINA
BELUSCIA MARINO, his wife, 
Petitioners,
vs.
D.H. McCALLA, 
Defendant.</ab>

<p>The petitioners herein having on the 31st day of December,
A. D. 1902, filed in this court their petition alleging
that they were entitled to the custody of one Joseph Marino, a
minor, and the son of siad Ferdinand Marino and Carolina Beluscia
Marino, and further alleging that said Joseph Marino was unlawfully
restrained of his liberty and detained from their custody
by D. H. McCalla as commanding officer of the United States' Steamship
Wisconsin, and the court, on said date, having ordered a 
writ of habeas corpus to issue to the said D. H. McCalla, or such
other person or officer as might be in charge or command of said
steamship Wisconsin, directing the production of the body of said
Joseph Marino before said court of the fifth day of January, A. D.
1903; and said writ having been duly served upon Captain Mayo
the commanding officer of said steamship Wisconsin, and said Captain
Mayo, in obedience to said writ, having on the fifth day of
January, 1903, produced the body of said Joseph Marino before
this court and made his return to said writ showing by what authority
he claimed to detain said Joseph Marino from the custody
of the petitioners herein, and the court having heard and considered
the evidence in said cause and the petition of the petitioners,
and ther return of said Mayo, and being now fully advised in 
the premises, find-</p>
<pb/>

<p>That the petitioners herein are the parents of the said
Joseph Marino; that said Joseph Marino is a minor and the petitioners
are entitled to the custody of said minor; that the pretended
enlistment of said Joseph Marino in the United States'
Navy, set up in the return herein, is voidable at the instance
of said petitioners, and the petitioners have taken the proper
course to avoid the same, and that said enlistment should be 
cancelled;</p>

<p>IT IS THEREFORE ORDERED that said Joseph Marino be,
and he hereby is, discharged from the custody of said Captain
Mayo and of the naval authorities of the United States, and custody
of the person of said minor is given to the petitioners
herein, Ferdinand Marino and Carolina Beluscia Marino.</p>

<p>Done in open court this 5th day of January, A. D. 1902.</p>
<ab>C. H. Hanford,
Judge. </ab>

<pb/>

<ab>Tx</ab>

<ab>(ORIGINAL)</ab>

<ab>No. 1073</ab>

<ab>GOB 7-319</ab>

<ab>In the Circuit Court
OF THE 
UNITED STATES 
District of Washington, Northern Division</ab>

<ab>Ferdinand Marino and Carolina
Beluscia Marino, 
Petitioner

vs. 

D. H. McCalla
Defendant</ab>

<ab>ORDER</ab>
<ab>Filed this 6th day of 
January 1903

A Reeves Ayres Clerk
By A. N. Moore. Deputy</ab>

<ab>PRESTON, CARR &amp; GILMAN</ab>

<ab>ROOM . 304 PIONEER BLOCK
Corner First Ave. and James St., - SEATTLE WASH.</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>