<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0368.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Matoba Watari v. T.W. Lynch. Habeas Corpus Petitions</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0368.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Matoba Watari v. T.W. Lynch. Habeas Corpus Petitions</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date/></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Watari, Matoba</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Lynch, T.W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Allen</persName>
<persName>Martin</persName>
<persName>Wardall</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Faulkner, Judson</persName>
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-07" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Habeas Corpus Petitions of Matoba and Terramoto</p>

<p>Matoba came to the United States under a passport and remained here twenty years, shipped on the "Cross Keys", went to Japan and left the ship under special permission with authority to hire a substitute in his place during the time the ship remained at Japanese Ports. Without any intention of deserting he was left on shore and unlawfully logged as a deserter by the master of the ship when the "Cross Keys" left Japan for China Ports. Desertion is not established by such proof. See Pages 11 and 12 and 13 and 14 of our Brief submitted to the Department in this case and now part of the record herein.</p>

<p>For a good statement of the case see the San Maroos, 27 Fed. 567, the Charles K. Schull, 176 Fed. 374.</p>

<p>There must be an intention not to return to the ship. Desertion cannot be made out under the facts.</p>

<p>Arriving in the United States on board the ship "Cross Keys" he was charged with having a loathsome disease and being a stowaway not entitled to land. Rejection following a finding against him by the Board of Special Inquiry. The Government is intending to treat this man's entry into the United States as an original entry, and if not such as a re-entry with all of the restrictions placed upon the entering or re-entering alien.</p>

<pb/>

<p>We contend that having the status of an American citizen, who is on American territory, when he failed to join his ship under circumstances not indicating desertion, he was therefore entitled as a matter of law to return upon the same ship as an articled bound seaman, and so returning, could not be classed as an entering alien, nor as a re-entering alien. He was the member of the crew of an American ship unlawfully left on shore in the Port of Japan. He could of course have applied to his own Government for a new passport and to the Consul for assistance to send him back to an American Port, but he cannot have said to have waived his rights in these respects merely because he returned on board his ship even though he would have been a stowaway but for the fact that he was entitled to be and remain upon the ship's articles.</p>

<p>Terramoto came to the United States in 1911 without a passport and had remained here beyond the period of time for which he could have been deported. While here he joined the "Cross Keys" as an American seaman, which in view of his non-deportable status and his legal status as an American seaman, entitled him to return to the United States, where but for the fact that he had been logged as a deserter he could have entered without interference.</p>

<p>Taylor vs. United States, 207 U.S. 120, 52 L. Ed. 130, holds that (quoting from the Syllabus) the ordinary case of a sailor deserting while on shore leave not comprehended by the provisions of the Immigration Act of March 3, 1903 so as to render the master</p>

<p>-2-</p>

<pb/>

<p>liable because the saman in that instance being an alien went ashore and did not return. The alien seaman was distinguished from an entering alien. Having the status of a seaman the captain could not be charged with unlawfully bringing him into the Country because he gave him permission to go ashore expecting him to return. Under the present Immigration Act the seaman is defined as,</p>

<p>"shall include every person signed on the ship's articles and employed in any capacity on board any vessel arriving in the United States from any foreign port or place."</p>

<p>Section 3 of the Act covers the class of aliens who may be rejected. Nothing in Section 3 applies to the petitioners except this clause:</p>

<p>"Stowaways, except that any such stowaway, if otherwise admissible, may be admitted at the discretion of the Secretary of Labor."</p>

<p>Returning upon his own ship he is not a stowaway, merely because the master regards him as such, if in fact he was an articled seaman. A snip's logbook entry upon the direct issue of the fact between the master and the seaman is merely a self-serving declaration, and cannot stand against the real facts showing no desertion and no right to remove the petitioner from the crew list of the ship. See Section 32 touching the entry of an alien seaman:</p>

<p>"That no alien excluded from admission into the United States by any law, convention or treaty of the United States regulating the Immigration of Aliens and employed on any vessel arriving in the United States from any other port or place, shall be permitted to land in the United States except temporarily."</p>

<p>Clearly this covers alien seamen who come within the class of persons within Section 3 of the present Act. See Sections 3 and 32, Act of February 5, 1917.</p>

<p>-3-</p>

<pb/>

<p>The aliens in this case had the status of domestic seamen entitled to return to the United States and be discharged therein. They are not even in the class of alien seamen coming to the United States from a foreign port or place as described in Section 32. These facts are clearly shown:</p>

<p>a) Matoba duly passported had a twenty year status as a resident alien;</p>

<p>b) Lawfully employed on an American ship under Shipping Articles required him to be returned to a Port of Discharge in the United States;</p>

<p>c) He was not a deserter at sea;</p>

<p>d) He was not a stowaway because if the captain had no right to log him as a deserter he was still on the ship's articles as a seaman and the ship would have been liable for his wages as he voluntarily returned to perform his contract;</p>

<p>e) He was not an entering alien, nor was he a re-entering alien under the Immigration Act, nor was he a foreign seaman under Section 32 of the Act</p>

<p>f) The disease mentioned was acquired in the United States and would not affect his seaman status.</p>

<p>See The Santa Elena, 271 Fed. 350,</p>

<p>"Now, being on the ship's articles, even though formally, Anderson was, for the purposes of the Immigration Act, a seaman. Indeed, under Judge Foster's decision in Laura M. lunt (D.C). 170 Fed. 204, he was an "American seaman," and under no possible construction, I think, can the ship be held to an accountability more strict than that set forth in section 32."</p>

<p>The Terramoto case is different in distinguishing facts only in the following facts:</p>

<p>He was free from disease but did not have a passport when he came into the United States in 1911. His case is even stronger</p>

<p>-4-</p>

<pb/>

<p>in that being told to return to his ship seasonable before she left at 5:00 A.M. in the morning, returned in time and found that the ship had left at midnight.</p>

<p>Bearing on the intent of each petitioner they were told at the American Consul's Office to go on board their ship as they were lawfully entitled to return upon her, which advice from the Consul's Office was eminently sound in our judgment. The petition should be granted in each instance.</p>

<p>Respectfully submitted,</p>
<p>Winton V Marliu.</p>

<pb/>

<p>No.</p>

<p>In the United States District Court for the Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Petition of Matoba <unclear></unclear> for a writ of habeas corpus</p>

<p>Memo of pet and Authorities</p>

<p>Allen, Martin &amp; Wardall</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>