<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0362.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Hosaye Sakaguchi v. Henry M. White. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0362.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Hosaye Sakaguchi v. Henry M. White. Petition</title>
<date when="1921-04">April 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-04">April 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Sakaguchi, Kyunoemon</term>
<term>Horikowa, Sakaguchi</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sakaguchi, Hosaye</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Kiefer, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Cushman, Edward E.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES IN AND FOR THE WESTERN
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the
Petition of                     No. 5959
Hoyase Sakaguchi,               PETITION
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>TO THE HONORABLE, THE JUDGES OF THE ABOVE ENTITLED COURT:-</p>

<p>The petition of Hosaye Sakaguchi respectfully represents:
That she is a subject of Japan; that she arrived in the
United States of America on the Africa Maru on the 23rd day of
December, 1919; that she had a passport issued by the proper authorities
of the Government of the Empire of Japan bearing date the 10th
day of the 10th month of the 8th year of Taisho, and that she is the
wife of Kyunoemon Sakaguchi, who resides in the City of Seattle and
has lived in the United States for about twenty-two years.</p>

<p>That she was, upon landing, denied admission to the
United States because of being afflicted with hookworm, and upon
application your petitioner was granted treatment for said disease
and on January 24, 1920, a certificate was made by the United States
Public Health Service, through its surgeons, that your petitioner had
been cured of said disease, and thereupon your petitioner was, on
February 27, 1920, by a majority of the Board of Special Inquiry,
refused admission to the United States because of trouble arising
between her husband and petitioner subsequent to the landing, and
upon the ground that she was likely to become a public charge, and
upon the ground that her passport was not in proper form.</p>

<p>That thereafter your petitioner appealed from said holding</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>and finding of the majority of said Special Board of Inquiry to the
Commissioner of Labor; that said official permitted your petitioner
to remain in the United States under bond against becoming a public
charge, and again thereafter permitted your petitioner to remain in
the United States under the recognizance of the Japanese Imperial
Consul at the Port of Seattle. That the appeal of your petitioner
has been finally denied, and your petitioner is to be deported on
the African Maru on April 22, 1921.</p>

<p>That your petitioner was refused a fair and impartial
trial in this: (a) That a majority of the Board of Special Inquiry
and the Secretary of Labor ignored the passport of your petitioner
and treated it as irregular, when in truth and in fact it is regular
in all respects;</p>

<p>(b) In that a majority of the Board of Special Inquiry
and the Secretary of Labor disposed of the case of your petitioner
on the bases of and as id she were an unmarried woman, ignored the
rights of your petitioner as the wife of Kyunoemon Sakaguchi, and
ignoring the liability of the husband of your petitioner for her
support;</p>

<p>(c) In that a majority of the Board of Special Inquiry
and the Secretary of Labor held that your petitioner was liable to
become a public charge notwithstanding the fact that your petitioner
has a sister, Mrs. Komakachi Horikawa, who lives in the City of
Seattle and whose husband keeps a hardware store and empty aisle to
support petitioner and willing to do so, and liable so to do under
the Statues of the State of Washington;</p>

<p>(d) In that a majority of said Board of Special Inquiry
and the Secretary of Labor held your petitioner to be a person likely
to become a public charge notwithstanding the fact that petitioner is
in good health and capable of supporting herself either by sewing or
in domestic labor, all of which appears upon the record in the office</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>of the Commissioner of Immigration.</p>

<p>That your petitioner is in the custody of Henry M. White,
United States Commissioner of Immigration at the Port of Seattle for
deportation on April 22, 1921.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE, your petitioner prays that an order may be
made, herein requiring said Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration
for the Port of Seattle, to show cause why a writ of habeas
corpus should not be issued herein requiring the said Henry M. White
as Commisioner of Immigration aforesaid to produce your petitioner
before this Court, and why your petitioner should not be discharged
and your petitioner allowed to remain in the United States.</p>

<p>Hosaye Sakaguchi
Petitioner</p>

<p>James Kiefer
Attorney for Petitioner.
327 Colman Blvd.
Seattle, Washington.</p>

<p>United States of America,
Western District of Washington } ss.
County of King</p>

<p>Hosaye Sakaguchi, the petitioner,
being duly sworn on oath says: That she has heard the foregoing
petition read, knows the contents thereof, and the facts therein
stated are true.

Hosaye Sakaguchi</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 18th day of April, 1921</p>

<p>James Kiefer
Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>

               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>