<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0154.001"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla E." xml:id="meg">Mikayla E. Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0154.001</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">October 14, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date></term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Clifford, Peter A.
Long (Clifford, Williams), Grace E.
Clifford, Alice B.
Burt. J.  J.
White, W. H. 
DeLang, James
Hanford, C. H.
Ayres, A. Reeves
Matthew, H. M.
Herice, Deevnay 
Fuller, Melville W.  
Hopkins, C. B.
Stringer, John
Heade, Matthew H.
Tallman, Boyd J.
Humphreys, William P.</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Georgetown, King County, Washington
San Francisco, California
Seattle, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Clifford, Peter A.</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Long (Williams, Clifford), Grace E.
Williams, Herbert O.</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>White, W. H.
Burt, J. J. 
Steiner, G. E.
Sweeney
</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>
Humphreys, William P.</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.
Tallman, Boyd J.</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0154.001"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL CIRCUIT,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>PETER A. CLIFFORD,
PETITIONER,
vs.
HERBERT O. WILLIAMS and
GRACE E. WILLIAMS,
Respondents.</p>
<p>Petition for Writ of 
Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>To the Honorable the Circuit Court
of the United States for the District of Washington, Northern
Division:-</p>
<p>The petition of Peter A. Clifford respectfully shows:</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>That at all the times herein stated he was and now is a citizen
and resident of the State of California, and that respon-
dents are and for more than eight months last past have been
citizens and residents of the State of Washington, in the 
County of King.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>That on the 17th day of October, A. D. 1899, one Grace E.
Long was a citizen and resident of the State of California, and
on that day your petitioner and the said Grace E. Long, at the
City and County of San Francisco, in the said State of Califor-
nia, intermarried, and bacame husband and wife, and the said
Grace E. Long thereby became Grace E. Clifford.</p>
<p>III.</p>
<p>That thereafter your petitioner and his said wife lived
together in the City and County of San Francisco, State of Cal-
ifornia until about the 7th day of March, A. D. 1901, and
that on or about the said last named day the said Grace E. Clif-
ford deserted and abandoned your petitioner without any just cause
and without his consent.
</p>
<p>IV.</p>
<p>That during the marriage of your petitioner and the said
Grace E. Clifford, there was born to them, as the issue of said
marriage, a female child, now living, and of the age of four
years, named Alice B. Clifford.</p>
<p>V.</p>
<p>That on the 24th day of March, A. D. 1902, the said Grace E.
Cliffored commenced an action in the Superior Court in and for
the City and County of San Francisco, State of California, for
an absolute divorce from your petitioner, and therein prayed
for the custody of said child of said mariage, and your petit-
ioner appeared in said action and filed his answer, and also a
cross-complaint for a divorce from said Grace E. Clifford there-
in, and in said cross-complaint prayed that the custody of said
child should be awarded to him by said Court.</p>
<p>VI.</p>
<p>That thereafter such proceedings were had in such action
and cross-action that the judgment of said court was given, made and
entered therein, denying a divorce to said Grace E. Clifford and
granting a divorce to your petitioner, and awarding the custody
of said child to said Grace E. Clifford until the further order
of the court; and providing that your petitioner should be al-
lowed to see said child once a week and to take the same out
with him once in every two weeks.</p>
<p>VII.</p>
<p>That at the time of the commencement of said action and from
thenoe on down and including the time of the entry of said judg-
ment, your petitioner, thhe said Grace E. Clifford, and said 
child were all citizens and bona fide residents of the said City
and County of San Francisco, in said State of California, and
actually present therein, and your petitioner and the said Grace
E. Clifford had been such citizens and residents of said City
and County continuously since the date of their said marriage,
and said child had been such citizen and resident continuously
since the date of her birth, and within the jurisdiction of said
Superior Court in said acion and cross-section, and said Superior
Court was then and yet is a court of record and of superior jur-
isdiction.</p>
<p>VIII.</p>
<p>That after the date of entry of said judgment by said
Superior Court, the said Grace E. Clifford continued to reside
in said City and County of San Francisco until some time in 
September, A. D. 1903, the exact time being unknown to your
petitioner, and that during said moth she secretly and surrepti-
tiously and without the permission of said Superior Court,
and in contempt thereof, and without the knowledge or consent
of your petitioner, took said child out of the State of Califor-
nia.</p>
<p>IX.</p>
<p>That on the 27th day of November, A. D. 1903, your petition-
er fled in said Superior Court a verified petition in said ac-
tion and cross-action for a modification of the judgment there-
in by taking away from the custody of the said Grace E. Clifford
the said child and awarding the custody thereof to your petit-
ioner, and such proceedings were thereupon had that an order was
made and entered therein modifying and changing said judgment
and taking the custody of said child from said Grace E. Clifford
 and awarding the same to your petitioner until the further order
of the said Superior Court, and said order ever since has been
and still is standing and not set aside, and in full force and
effect, and under the laws of the State of California, at the 
time of the commencement of said action, and at the time of the 
entry of said judgment, and at the time of the making of the
said order, said child was a ward of said Court and under the 
control thereof; and it is provided by the laws of the said
State that said Court could at any tme after the entry of said
judgment make any order with or without notice modifyig said
judgmet as to the custody of said child.</p>
<p>X.</p>
<p>That since the said judgment of divorce, the said Grace E.
Clifford and one Herbert O. Williams above named, intermarried
in said State of California, and became and ever since have
been and now are husband and wife and evrer since their
said marriage have had in the State of California and elsewhere
and now at the town of Georgetown, in said County of King,
saod child in their custody and posession.</p>
<p>XI.</p>
<p>That on the 19th day of January, 1904, at the said town of
Georgetown, your petitioner presented to the said Herbet O.
Williams and also to the said Grace E. Williams, a copy of the
record and proceedings of the said Superior Court of said City
and County of San Francisco, in said acion and cross-section,
certified under and in pursuance of an Act of the Congress of
the United Sates in such case made and provided, and demanded
from them and eachof them the immediate delivery of the said
child to him, said petitioner, but they refused and still do 
refuse to give up said child, and said child ever since has been
and now is imprisoned and restrained of her liberty by them at 
said town of Georgettown, and that according to the best of your
petitioner's knowledge and belief, the cause of pretense of the
aforesaid confinement or restraint of the said child, Alice B.
Clifford, is that under the said judgment of said Superior Court
of said City and County of San Francisco, the custody of said
child was given to said Grace E. Clifford, now Grace E. Williams,
umtil further order of the Court, and that after she took said
child beyond the limits of said State of California, as afore-
saod, said Superior Court lost all jurisdiction to make any fur-
ther order in said action and cross-section in regard to any mod-
ification of said judgment as to the custody of said child, and
that she had the right to take said child beyond the jurisdic-
tion of the State of California without first obtaining therefor
the permission of said Court, and that after said child was
taken into said State of Washington said Herbet O. Williams
and without the knowledge or consent of said Superior Court of
said City and County of San Francisco, and without giving any
notice thereof, undertook, under the laws of the said State of
Washington, to adpot said child as husband and wife, as theor
own. And your petitioner further states that he believes and
therefore alleges, ad he is advised by counsel W. H. White, Esq.,
residing at the City of Seattle, State of Washington, and J. J. 
Burt, Esq., residing at the City and County of San Francisco,
State of California, that the said imprisonment of the said
child, Alice B, Clifford, is illegal, and that the illegality
consists in this, to-wit:-
</p>
<p>That said Superior Court of the said City and County of San
Francisco had jurisdiction under the laws of the State of Calif-
ornia, to award the custody of said child upon the fact here-
onbefore alleged until the further order of that Court, and to
thereinafter change and modify the judgment as to the custody
of said child with or without notice to any or either of the 
parties to said action, and that the said Grace E. Williams and 
Herbert O. Williams had no, nor had either of them any, right or 
power under the laws of California, to remove said child from
the State of California or change its placee of residence there-
from to any other place without the permission of said Superior
Court of said City and County of San Francisco, and that under
Art. IV, Sec 1 of the Constitution of the United States, and
Section 905 Revised statutes if the United States enacted i
pursuance thereof, full faith and credit must be given in the
State of Washington to the acts and proceedings of said Super-
ior Court of the City and County of San Francisco, and all per-
sons and courts must recognize the petitioner's right to the
custody of said child under said order in said State of Washing-
ton; as wel as under the laws of commity existing between
said State of Washington and said State of California; and that
also under the laws of Washington said attempted adpotion was
illegal and void, for the reason thar there is no provision
in the laws of Washington authorizing any person to adopt hi
or her own legitimate child by birth, and that under the laws of
the State of Washington there is no provision allowing or permit-
ing a woman who has married again to consent to or permir
the adoption of any child which she may have had by her first
husband and from whom she has been divorced, and that the con
sent given by Grace E. Williams for the adoption of said 
child and said adoption proceedings was given to its adoption
by herself and the said Herbert O. Williams, and not to the said
Herbert O. Williams, with whom she was at the time living as her
husband, alone. </p>
<p>XIII.</p>
<p>And your petitioner further states that there is danger
that the said Herbet O. Willliams and the said Grace E. Wil-
liams will take or send the said child out of the jurisdiction
of this court, from the fact that they secret;y, and without
the permission of the saodd Court in the City and County of
</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford
Petitioner.</p>
<p>W H White
J. J. Burt,
Co Counsil.</p>
<p>ting a woman when she has married again to consent to or permit
the adoption of any child which she have had by her first
husband and from whom she has been divorced, and that the con
sent given by said Grace E. Williams for the adoption of said
child and said adoption proceedings was given to its adoption
by herself and the said Herbet O. Williams, and not to the said
Herbert O. Williams, with whom she was at the time living as her
husband, alone.</p>
<p>XII.</p>
<p>And your petitioner further states that there is danger
that the said Herbet O. Williams and the said Grace E. Wil-
liams will take or send the said child out of the jurisdiction
of this court, from the fact that they secretly, and without 
the permission of the said Court in the City and County of 
San Fracisco, and in contempt thereof, took said child be-
yond the limits of the State of California. </p>
<p>WHEREFORE, your Petitioner set up and claims, upon the fore-
going facts set out in this petition, under the said Article
IV., Section I, of the Constiution of the United States and
Section 905 of the Revised Statutes of the United States, the
right to the immediate custody of said child Alice B. Clifford
to be taken back, and restored, to the jurisdiction of the
Superior Court of City and County of San Francisco, State 
of California, and prays a writ of habeas corps directed to
the said Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams commanding them to bring up the
body of the said child, Alice B. Clifford, to abide such order
as your Honor may make, and that also a warrant issue to the
marshal of the Untied States for this District commanding him
to take said child into his cusotdy and to hold the same in his
custody until the final determination of this petition.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford
Petitioner.</p>
<p>W H White
Attorney for Peitioner
J. J. Burt
Of Counsil.</p>
<p>State of California, )
)ss.
City and County of San Francisco )
</p>
<p>Peter A, Clifford,  being first duly sworn, on his oath
deposes and says:</p>
<p>I am the petitioner in the above entitled cause; I
have read the foregoing petition, know the contents thereof,
and verily believe the same to be true.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 3rd day of June, A. D. 1904
James DeLang
Commissioner for Washington
in San Francisco, California.</p>
<p>Upon reading and filing the foregoing petition, verified by
the petitioner, whereby it appears that Alice B. Clifford is
illegally imprisionmented restrained of her liberty by Herbert
O. Williams and Grace E. Williams at the town of Georgetown,
County of King, State of Washington, and stating wherein the il-
legality consists, from which it appears to me that a writ of
habeas corpus should issue;</p>
<p>IT IS ORDERED: That a writ of habeas corpus issue out of
and under the seal of the above named Circuit Court, directed to
the said Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams, commanding
them and each of them to have the body of Alice B. Clifford be-
fore me on the 9th day of June A. D. 1904, at the hour
of ten o'clock A. M., at the Court room of the said Court
in the City of Seattle, State of Washington, to do and receive
what shall then and there be considered concerning the said
Alice B. Cliffordm together with the time and cause of her de-
tention, and that they have then and there the said writ.</p>
<p>It further appearing that there is good reason to believe
that said Alice B. Clifford will be carried out of and beyond
the jurisdiction of said Court, it is ordered that a warrant
issue out of and under the seal of said court to the marshal of
said District commanding him to take the said Alice B. Clifford
and to hold her in custody until the determination of said pe-
tition.</p>
<p>Dated, June 7th 1904.</p>
<p>C. H. Hanford
Judge.</p>
<p>No. 1204 Tx
IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED
STATES, FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASH-
INGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>PETER A. CLIFFORD,
Petitioner,</p>
<p>vs.
HERBERT O. WILLIAMS and
GRACE E. WILLIAMS,
Respondents.</p>
<p>PETITION FOR WRIT OF HABEAS
CORPUS.
Order</p>
<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JUN 7 1904
A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk
H. M. Matthew
Deputy.</p>
<p>W. H White
ATTORNEY- AT- LAW
SAVINGS UNION BUILDING
530 California Street, SAN FRANSISCO, CAL.
J. J. Burt;
Co Counsil.</p>
<p>United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington.
</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford
Petitioner
vs.
HO. Williams et al.
No. 1204
Appearance</p>
<p>To the Clerk of the above Entitled Court:
You will please enter our appearance as attorneys
for Petitioner
in the above entitled cause
W. H. White
J. J. Burt
NOTICE.- Attorneys will please endorse their own Filings. Rule 47.</p>
<p>GoB 8-103.
No. 1204 Tx
United States Circuit Court
District of Washington.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford
Petitioner
vs.
HO. Williams et al.
Appearance
Filed FILED IN THE 
U. S. Circuit Court, 190
JUN 7 1904 Clerk
A. Reeves Ayres, Clerk.
HM Matthew
Deputy Clerk</p>
<p>W. H. White
JJ Burt.
Petitioner
order on petitioner.</p>
<p>United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington.
Peter A. Clifford
vs.
Herbert O Williams 
et. al</p>
<p>No. 1204
Appearance</p>
<p>To the Clerk of the above Entitled Court:
You will please enter Our appearance as attorneys
for Referendants
in the above entitled cause
Sweeney <unclear></unclear>
NOTICE.- Attorneys will please endorse their own Filings. Rule 47.</p>
<p>GOB 8-108
10 pd
Tx
no. 1204
United States Circuit Court
District of Washington.
</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford
Pet
vs.
Herert O. Williams
Ref
Appearance
Filed FILED IN THE 
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON. 
190
JUN 9 1904 Clerk
A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk
HM Matthew
Deputy Deputy Clerk
Sweeney <unclear></unclear>
Attys
For Ref</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES , NINTH JUDICIAL 
CIRCUIT, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.
</p>
<p>Peter A, Clifford,
Petitioner
vs.
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>
<p>The President of the United States of America to Herbet O.
Williams and Grace E. Williams, G r e e t i n g :
</p>
<p>We command you that you have the body of Alice B. Clifford,
now held by you in illegal custody and detention, as it is said,
together with the time and cause of such detention, by whatso-
ever name the said Alice B. Clifford shall be called before the
above named Court, at the 
court room of said court in the City of Seattle, County of King,
State of Washington, on the 9th day of June 1904, at 10
o'clock A. M. of said day, to do and receive what shall then
and there be considered and determined concerning the said Alice
B. Clifford, and that you have then and there this writ.</p>
<p>WITNESS the HONORABLE Melville W. Fuller, Chief Justice of
the United States, this 7th day of June, A. D. 1904.
A. Revees Ayres
Clerk.
By HM Matthew
Deputy Clerk.</p>
<p>Form No. 282. RETURN ON SERVICE OF WRIT.
United States of America, )
DISTRICT OF WASH) ss.</p>
<p>I hereby certify that I served the annexed Writ of Habeas
Corpus on the therein-named Grace E. Williams
by handing to and leaving a true and correct copy thereof with Grace E. Williams
personally
at Georgetown in said District on the 8 day of
June , A. D. 190</p>
<p>Marshals for
service 6.00
1.50
7.50
Service 
Expenses</p>
<p>C. B, HOPKINS,
U. S. Marshal.</p>
<p>By John Stringer 
Deputy.</p>
<p>DISTRICT OF Wash ) ss:</p>
<p>I hereby certify that I served the annexed writ. of. Habeas
Corpus on the therein-named Herbert O. Williams
By delivering to and leaving with his
wife Grace E. Williams at his usual place
of abode She being a resident therein
and a person of suitable age and decision
at Georgetown in said District on the 8 day of
June, A. D. 190X
C. B, HOPKINS,
U. S. Marshal.
By John Stringer
Deputy.</p>
<p>No., 1204 Tx
</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED
STATES, FOR THE DISTRICT OF WASH-
INGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>PETER A. CLIFFORD,
Petitioner</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>HERBERT O. WILLIAMS,
GRACE E. WILLIAMS
Respondents.</p>
<p>WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>
<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. Circuit Court
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JUN 9 1904
A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk
HM Matthew
Deputy.</p>
<p>W. H White
ATTORNEY- AT- LAW
SAVINGS UNION BUILDING
530 California Street, SAN FRANSISCO, CAL.
J. J. Burt;
Co Counsil.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, NINTH JUDICIAL
CIRCUIT, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs.
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
W A R R A N T.</p>
<p>To C. B. HOPKINS, Marshal of the United States for the Dis-
trict of Washington, Northern Division:</p>
<p>WHEREAS, Peter A. Clifford as applied to me for a warrant to
take Alice B. Clifford, alleged to be in the custody of Herbert
O. Williams and Grace E. Williams; and</p>
<p>WHEREAS, it appears from the proof before me on such applica-
tion that the said Alice B. Clifford is held in illegal custody
by the said Herbert O. Williams and Grace E Williams, and that
there is good reason to believe that she will be carried out
of the jurisdiction of this Court before she can be relieved by
a writ of habeas corpus, and this warrant having been ordered
to issue by the Honorable the above named 
Court.</p>
<p>THESE ARE THEREFORE TO COMMAND YOU, in the name of the Pres-
ident of the United States of America, that you forthwith take
the said Alice B. Clifford and bring her before the Honorable
above named Court, at the Court room there-
of, in the City of Seattle, State of Washington, on the 9th 
day of June 1904, at Ten o'clock A M. of said day
to be dealt with according to law.</p>
<p>WITNESS Melville W. Fuller, Chief Justice of the United 
States, the 7th day of June 1904.</p>
<p>A. Reeves Ayres Clerk.
By, HM Matthew
Deputy Clerk.</p>
<p>W H White
Attorney for Petitioner.
J. J. Burt,
Co Counsil.</p>
<p>United States of America, )
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON. ) ss.</p>
<p>I, C. B. Hopkin U. S. Marshal for the District of Washington, do hereby
certify that I received the within Warrant on the 7 day of June 1904 and in
pursuance thereof have the said Alice B. Clifford, before
this Honorable Court as eviction
I am commanded this 9 day of June 1904</p>
<p>CB Hopkins U. S. Marshal,
By John Stringer Deputy.</p>
<p>No. 1204. Tx</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED
STATES, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTH-
ERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>PETER A. CLIFFORD,
Petitioner,
vs.
HERBERT O. WILLIAMS and
GRACE E. WILLIAMS,
Respondents.
W A R R A N T.</p>
<p>FILED IN THE
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JUN 9 1904
A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk.
HM Matthew 
Deputy</p>
<p>W. H. White
ATTORNEY-AT-LAW
SAVINGS UNION BUILDING
530 California Street, SAN FRANCISCO, CAL.
J. J. Burt,
Co Counsil.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL DISTRICT
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION </p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams.
Respondents.</p>
<p>No. 1804.
APPLICATION FOR CONTINUANCE.</p>
<p>Comes now the respondents, Herbet O. Williams and Grace
E. Williams, by Sweeneyy and Steiner, their attorneys and moved the
Court for a continuance herein from the 9th day of June, 1904, at
the hour of ten o'clock, for the period of ten days or until such
time as this Honorable Court may deem just and proper.</p>
<p>This motion is based upon the affidavits of G. E. Steiner
and respondents, Herbert O. Williams and Grace E. Williams.</p>
<p>Sweeney <unclear></unclear> </p>
<p>No. 1204. Tx
</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE 
UNITED STATES.
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner
vs.
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams.
Respondents.
Motion for continuance.</p>
<p>FILED IN THE
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JUN 9 1904
A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk.
HM Matthew
Deputy</p>
<p>Sweeney and Steiner,
Attorneys for Respondents.
Haller Buiding, Seattle, Wn. </p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL DISTRICT
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION. </p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs
Herbert O. Williams, and
Grace E. Williams.
Respondents.
No. 1204.
 A F F I D A V I T.
</p>
<p>United States of America )
District of Washington, ) SS.
Northern Division. )</p>
<p>Herbert O. Williams, being first duly sworn on oath, de-
poses and says:</p>
<p>That he is a resident of King County, State of Washington;
one of the respondents in the above entitled action, and the husband
of respondent, Grace E. Williams.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL DISTRICT
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs
Herbert O. Williams, and 
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
United States of America
District of Washington, )SS.
Northern Division.</p>
<p>No. 1204.
A F F I D A V I T .</p>
<p>Herbert O. Williams, being first duly sworn on oath, de-
poses and says:</p>
<p>That he is a resident of King County, State of Washington;
one of the respondents in the above entitled action, and the husband
of respondent, Grace E. Williams.</p>
<p>That the petition herein was served upon respondents by
leaving a copy thereof at the residence of respondents with saiid
Grace E. Williams, in Georgetown, Washington, on the 8th day of
June, 1904, at about the hour of ;</p>
<p>The deponent is a carpenter by occupation and was working
at his trade in Seattle, Washington on the 8th. day of June, 1904,
and knew nothing of the service of said papers until informed by his
counsel, Sweeney and Steiner, on the evening of the 8th. day of June,
1904, at about the house of P. M. ; that he had previously had no 
intimation or notice of the commencements of this action; that he has
submitted the facts of the case to his counsel and is advised and
believes that he has a complete defense to said writ; that said writ
is maade returnable on the 8th, day of June, 1904, at the hour of ten
o'clock A.M., and that it has been imposaible in the time between the
service of said writ and the return thereof prepare respondent's
defense; that he has used due dilligence in an effort to prepare his
return to said writ on the day and hour designated by this Honorable
Court; and he has found it impossible in so short a space of time to
prepare a proper return to said writ; that if the petition herein
is heard on its merits on the 9th. day of June, 1904, at the hour of
ten o'clock, depondent will be deprived of an opportunity to properly
inform this Court of the facts in this cause.</p>
<p>Herbert O. Williams
Subscribed and sworn to before me this 9 day of June, 1904.</p>
<p>G. E. Steiner
Notary Public in and for the
State of Washingtion, residing at
Seattle.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL DISTRICT
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs
Herbert O. Williams, and 
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
United States of America
District of Washington, )SS.
Northern Division.</p>
<p>No. 1204.
A F F I D A V I T .</p>
<p>Grace E. Williams, being first duly sworn on oath, deponses
and says:</p>
<p>That she is a resident in King County, Washington, the wife
of the respondent, Herbert O. Williams, and one of the respondents
herein.</p>
<p>That the petition and writ herein were served upon her at
her residence in Georgetown, on the 8th, day of June, 1904, at about
the hour of A.M.;</p>
<p>That respondent, Herbert O. Williams, her husband, is a
carpenter by trade and was, at the time of service of said papers was
made, at work on a building in Seattle; that deponent had no communi-
cation with said Herbert O. Williams by telephone or otherwise and
it was impossible to inform him of the service of said papers; that
deponent requested the Marshall serving said papers, to inform re-
spondents' counsel, Sweeney and Steiner of said service; that at about
the hour of A.M., G.E. Steiner, one of our attorneys, called at
deponent's residence in response to the notice given by said marshall
and secured papers; that deponent has been diligent in the
preparation of her defense to this writ and that she is advised by
her counsel and believes that it will be impossible to prepare an
adequate return to said writ within the time limited by this Honorable
Court.
Grace E. Williams
 </p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 9 day of June, 1904.</p>
<p>G. E. Steiner
Notary Public in and for the
State of Washingtion, residing at
Seattle.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES NINTH JUDICIAL DISTRICT
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
vs
Herbert O. Williams, and 
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
United States of America
District of Washington, )SS.
Northern Division.</p>
<p>No. 1204.
A F F I D A V I T .</p>
<p>G.E. Steiner, being first duly sworn on oath, deposes and says:</p>
<p>That he is one of the attorneys for respondents herein
and is conversant with the facts in this cause.</p>
<p>That the petition and writ issued herein were served upon
respondents at the family residence at Georgetown, Washington, on
the 9th. day of June, 1904, at about the hour of A.M. That deponent
was informed of this fact by the Deputy United States
Marshall who had made said service. Whereupon, deponent proceeded
at once to the residence of said respondents to obtain said papers
with a view to preparing a return thereon. That deponent then
discovered that said writ was made returnable at ten o'clock on
the day after the service thereof or at ten o'clock June 9, 1904. </p>
<p>That it is impossible to prepare an adequate return to
said writ within the time allotted respondents' attorneys, and if
this writ is heard o its merits on the day and hour designated for
the return thereof, if will work a great hardship upon respondents
and respondents' attorneys and deeat the ends of justice, in that
said attorneys will not be prepared to adequately present the case
to this Honorable Court.</p>
<p>G. E. Steiner
Subscribed and sworn to before me this 9 day of June, 1904.
Matthew H. Heade
Notary Public in and for the State 
of Washington, residing in Seattle.</p>
<p>No. 1204.
IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE
UNITED STATES,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.
NORTHERN DIVISION.
Peter A. Clifford, 
Petitioner,
vs.
Herbert O. Williams and
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
FILED IN THE U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON.
JUN 9 1904
A. Reeves Ayres, Clerk
HM Matthew 
Deputy</p>
<p>Affidavits of G. E. Steiner;
Herbert O. Williams and 
Grace E. Williams</p>
<p>Sweeney and Steiner,
Attorneys for Respondents.
Haller Building, Seattle, Wash.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, NINTH JUDICIAL CIRCUIT,
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN
DIVISION.</p>
<p>Peter A. Clifford,
Petitioner,
Vs
Herbert O. Williams and 
Grace E. Williams,
Respondents.
No.
R e p l y . </p>
<p>Comes now the Petitioner herein and replying to the answer
of the respondents herein, replies as follows:</p>
<p>Said Petitioner denies that by any reason of the writ of habeas
corpus in Number 41787, or of any proceedings, or of any adjudica-
tion of the Superior Court of the County of King, State of
Washington, or of any Judges thereof, referred to in the answer of
respondents, or by reason of any thingtherein, or any proceedings
between the parties hereot, or any other persons or parties, he is 
estopped from further questioning any right or rights claimed by 
said respondents, or either of them, as to the custody of said
child, Alice B. Clifford.</p>
<p>And in further reply said Petitioner avers and alleges:</p>
<p>That upon the hearing of said proceeding in said Superior
Court and before the Honorable Boyd J. Tallman, the Judge before
whom said hearing of said habeas corpus proceeding was had, said
Petitioner presented and put in evidence a copy of the judicial
records and proceedings of the Superior Court of the City
and in the notion granting the divorce referred to in his petition herein
County of San Francisco, State of California, 
authentioated a provided i Section 905 of the Revised Statutes 
of the United States, and claimed the right to the custody of
said child upon the ground that is was being imprisoned and
detained by respondents, and each of them, in violation of Article
exemplified and
IV, Section 1 of the United States and Section 905 of the Revised
Statutes of the United States, and demanded that in pursuance of
said provision of said Constitution and said provision of said
Revised Statutes if the United States, full faith and credit to
said records of said Superior Court of California should be given
by said Court of Washington and the respondents herein, and that
said child should be released from the imprisionment and detention
by said respondents, and each of them, and delivered into the
custody of your Petitioner, to be by him taken back to the juris-
diction of said Court of California; but said Superior Court of
 Washington refused, and it appears upon the face of the records and
proceedings of said Superior Court of Washington, in said habeas
corpus proceedings therein, that said Court refused, to give any
faith or credit to the records or proceedings of the said Court of
California; and your Petitioner sets up and claims under said
Article IV, Section 1, of the Constitution of the United States,
and said Section 905 of the Revised Statutes of the United States,
that said record and proceedings of said Superior Court of Wash-
ington in the application therein for a writ of habeas corpus should
be disregarded by this Court and held to be of no force or effect
whatever.
 </p>
<p>Further replying to the answer of the respondents herein, as
to the adoption of said child by proceedings in Number 5262 of
said Superior Court of the State of Washington, said Petitioner
avers and alleges that by reason of the facts set out in his
petition herein, said child at the time said adoption proceedings
were commended and had, and ever since, has been, a resident of and
at all of said time had and yet has her domicile in the State of
California, and that the facts of such residence and domicile and
her being a ward of said Superior Court of California and subject
to the control and jurisdiction thereof, were made to appear before
the said Superior Court of Washington when said proceedings for
the adoption of said child were taken and had therein, and said
domicile and said wardship of said child appear upon the face of
the records and proceedings of said Superior Court of said State of
Washington in the matter of the adoption of said child, which
consist of a petition by the respondents herein to be allowed to
adopt said child, a copy of which is hereto attached marked
"Exhibit A" and made a part hereof, a written consent to the
adoption of said child, a copt of which is hereto attached, marked
"Exhibit B" and made a part hereof, and an order for the adoption
of said child, a copy of which is attached to the answer of the
respondents herein marked "Exhibit E", and which is hereby
referred to and made a part hereof, and of them alone; but
nevertheless the said Court of Washington refused to give any
faith or credit to the said records or proceedings of said Court
of California, and made and entered said order allowing said
adoption of said child; and your Petitioner hereby sets up and
claims that under said Article IV, Section 1 of the Constitution
of the United States and Section 905 of the Revised Statutes
thereof, said order allowing said adoption is void, and of no
force or effect.</p>
<p>And further replying as to the now pending in the
Superior Court of the State of Washington in and for the County of
King to set aside said order of adoption, said Petitioner alleges
that said proceeding is nothing more than to have expunged from
the records of that Court an order claimed by said Petitioner to 
be void and of no affect, and presents to reason why this appli-
cation should be denied, abated or continued</p>
<p>And further replying to Exhibit C of respondents' answer,
reffered to and adopted by them as a portion of their answer 
herein, said petitioner denies, as alleged in Parahraph IX thereof,
that no notice whatever was served upon them, or either of them, or
that they, or either of them, received no information as to the
change of the decree of the Court of California as to this custody
of said child; and on the contrary alleges that eight days' notice of the 
motion to modify the decree was given and served upon William P.
Humphreys. Esq., who was and yet is the attorney of record for
Grace E. Williams in the action wherein said decree was made and
entered.</p>
<p>Futher replying to Paragraoh I of the affirmative defense of respondents' Exhibit C
adopted as a portion of their answer herein, said Petitioner
alleges and avers that all of thematters and things therein set up
and alleged were set upp ad alleged in the complaints in actions
brought by Grace E. Williams, as Grace E. Clifford, against your
Petitioner in the said Court of California, wherein your Petitioner
was granted a divore from her, and all of such matters and things
were adjudged and decreed by said Court against her and in favor
of your Petitioner, and are barred by the judgments therein, one
which is the judgment granting said divorce; and further
replying as to the matters and things set out in said paragraph,
said Petitioner avers and alleges that they are beyond the jurisdiction of
this Court upon this application, and are solely and exclusively
within the jurisdiction of said Superior Court of California.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, Petitioner objects to the consideration by this
Court of any of the matters or things set out in this answer of
the respondents herein, and respondents are notified hereby that
upon the calling of this matter for hearing herein Petitioner will
move the Court for judgment upon the pleadings herein, and for the
granting of the prayer of his Petition herein; and in the case of the
Court's refusal to grant said motion Petitioner will then offer
evidence in support of his Petition herein, and of this Reply.
W H White
J. J. Burt
Attorneys for Petitioner.</p>
<p></p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>