<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0177.008">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Tonka Bajlo vs. United States. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0177.008</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Tonka Bajlo vs. United States. Criminal.</title>
<date when="1000">1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">April 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Bajlo, Tonka</term>
<term>Ennis, Charles H.</term>    
<term>Bilin, Paska</term>
<term>Jurin, John</term>
<term>Madison, Fany</term>
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Tonka Bajlo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Charles H. Ennis</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName> 
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
        
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>EXHIBIT E.</p>

<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Tonka Bajlo for the Writ of 
Habeas Corpus. )</p>

<p>2459
No. 1328</p>

<p>AFFIDAVIT OF FANY MADISON.</p>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON
COUNTY OF KING ) SS.</p>

<p>Fany Madison resideing at 810 Charles Street, 
Seattle, Washington, on oath deposes and says: That she is
a resident of Seattle, King County, Washington, residing at
810 Charles Street, and has known Tonka Bajlo for the past
nine months; that she lived across the street from her as
a neighbor for the past three months; that during said time she
was employed as housekeeper and cook at 815 Charles Street for
some four or five Austrian laborers; that during the time I 
have known her I have never heard anything ill of her in any
manner whatsoever; that I am a married woman and live with my 
husband at 810 Charles Street, Seattle, Washington; that I know
it is customary for Austrian women and women from the old country
among the class of people that I was raised with to accept employment
as cooks and housekeepers for me who are employed as construction
laborers on the streets of the cities and in the camps of
railroad and logging companies; that employment of that 
character is looked upon by our people as honorable and one 
who accepts such employment is not looked upon with suspicion
or subjected to criticism by her fellow countrymen; that when
I first became acquainted with her my husband employed her to
act as cook when we were married; that I know she has been ill
while living at 815 Charles Street and that she was unable to do 
much work; that ever since I have known her she has been acting
as cook and housekeeper for Austrians who kept boarding houses,
or rather boarded themselves; That I have never heard anything
wrong about her connection with Paska Bilin, John Jurin, or any 
other man; that I only know her as a hard working woman earning
her own living; that she has complained to me that her husband
beat her and that she could not live with him because he beat her
so often; that Tonka Bajlo's husband has visited my home at 810
Charles Street; that I run a boarding house and he is acquainted 
with boarders living in my house; that I heard him say he had beat
his wife several times, but would not beat her any more if she would
live with him; that my husband is a molder by trade and works for
on 4th Avenue, Seattle, Washington;
that I have been over to the home of Tonka Bajlo, 815 Charles
Street, Seattle, Washington, several times and have been in the 
room she occupied and know that she had a room of her own; that
there are two outside entrances to the house, one on one side of the
house facing the alley, and another on the other side of the
house which leads into the kitchen from the street; that Tonka
Bajlo's room was the front room facing on the street, and the
entrance to said room was through the next room to it, and from
there on to the alley; that there are three bedrooms in the house
and the kitchen; that the house is a small house in a regrade
district and has been raised up.</p>
<ab>Fany Madison.</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 15th day of April, 1913.</p>
<ab>Chas. H. Ennis.
Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</ab>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>