<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0221.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chin Quock Wah vs. Henry M. White.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0221.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Chin Quock Wah vs. Henry M. White</title>
<date when="1915">1915</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-03">March 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Allen, Clay</term>    
<term>Beeler, Adam</term>
<term>Chin, Quock Wah</term>
<term>Chin, We Hue</term>
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Densmore, J. B.</term>
<term>Doyle, James H.</term>
<term>Fishburne, George P.</term>    
<term>Lakin, Edward M.</term>
<term>Post, Louis</term>
<term>White, Henry M.</term>
<term>Wilson, W. B.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>China</term>
<term>Boston, Massachusetts</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Chin Quock Wah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Adam Beeler</persName>
<persName>Sullivan</persName>    
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Clay Allen</persName>
<persName>George P. Fishburne</persName>    
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-03" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT, IN AN FOR THE WESTERN
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application 
of CHIN QUOCK WAH, for 
a Writ of Habeas Corpus )
No. 2971
Stipulation</p>

<p>IT IS HEREBY AGREED AND STIPULATED by and between 
Adam Beeler, Attorney for Petitioner Chin Quock Wah, and Clay
Allen and George B. Fishburn, United States District Attorney 
and Assistant United States District Attorney for the United
States Government, that the Petitioner, by and through his
attorney Adam Beeler, may file a Further Amended Petition in 
the above entitled case.</p>
<p>Dated this 9 day of March, 1915.</p>
<ab>Clay Allen
Attorneys for United States 
Government.
Adam Beeler
Attorney for Petitioner
Chin Quock Wah.</ab>

<pb/>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT, IN AND FOR THE WESTERN 
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the 
Application of CHIN QUOCK WAH, 
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus. )
No. 2971
Further amended Petition of 
CHIN QUOCK WAH, by and through 
Adam Beeler, of the Law Firm of 
Beeler &amp; Sullivan, his attorney.</p>

<p>Comes now Adam Beeler, of the Firm of Beeler &amp; Sullivan, 
as Attorney for and in behalf, of Chin Quock Wah, an alleged alien, 
an alleged subject of the Emperor of China, and a son of Chin
We Hue, a Merchant of the City of Boston, State of Massachusetts, 
and respectfully makes this application for a Writ of Habeas
Corpus, and alleges as follows:</p>
<p>I.
That the said Chin Quock Wah, is imprisoned and 
restrained of his liberty, by the U. S. Commissioner of Immigration, 
Henry M. White, or by some person or persons acting through, by 
or under him, and that said Chin Quock Wah, is imprisoned at the 
Detention House at the Immigration Station, in the City of Seattle, 
King County,,State of Washington, and within the jurisdiction of 
the above entitled Court, under the charge that the said Chin Quock
Wah, is an alien, a subject to the Emperor of China, and has no
lawful right to be admitted into the United States, and that he
should be deported according to law, and your petitioner further
informs the Honorable Court that said imprisonment, confinement
and restraint and Order of Deportation is illegal, and arises
from the following gacts, to-wit: That the said Chin Quock Wah,
arrived at the Port of Seattle, on voyage from China, on the 
14th day of September, 1914, and said Chin Quock Wah, was denied
admittance into the United States on the ground that he was not
legally entitled to be admitted therein; that said Chin Quock Wah
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
was given a hearing by the by the Immigration Officials, on or 
about the 15th or 16th days of September, 19154; that further
evidence was taken in said case by the Department of Labor,
through the Immigration Officials, on the 25th day of November, 
and an order was issued by the Commissioner of Immigration, 
at Seattle, finding that said Chin Quock Wah, was not entitled 
to remain in the United States, and that he should be deported;
that about November 25, 1914, an appeal was taken by said Chin
Quock Wah, through his attorney, and that on February 20, 1915, 
the said Order of Deportation was affirmed, and said Chin Quock 
Wah, ordered deported.</p>
<p>II
Your petitioner is informed and believes and so states
the fact to be, that said Commissioner of Immigration, Henry M. 
White, of Seattle, Washington, in charge of the District of 
Washington, or his agent or agents, official or officials, 
acting by, under or through him, or for the United States Government,
is about to deport and return the said Chin Quock Wah to 
China, in violation of the Treaty relations between the United 
States and China, and in violation of the laws and statutes of 
the United States relation to the Chinese Exclusion Act, and in
violation of the laws relation to the acts and powers of the 
Secretary of Labor and the Assistant Secretary of Labor, in that
said Chin Quock Wah is being deprived of his liberty without due 
progress of law and without being given a fair hearing by said 
Commissioner of Immigration, Henry M. White, or his agents or 
officials acting by and under or through him, or for the United 
States Government.</p>
<p>III
Your Petitioner further alleges that the right of appeal
from said Finding of Commissioner of Immigration, Henry M. White, 
or his agents or officials acting by, under or through him, or 
for the United States Government in and for the District of 
Washington, by the statutes in such cases made and provided for in
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
relation to the Chinese Exclusion Laws, has been violated and 
that his full rights have not been accorded to your Petitioner
Chin Quock Wah in this: That W. B. Wilson is the Secretary of 
Labor, and that Louis Post is his only Assistant Secretary of 
Labor; that both of said officials, as your petitioner alleges
upon information and belief, and believes the fact to be, were
at their respective offices in the Capitol at Washington, doing
the duties imposed upon them on the day that the said appeal of 
Chin Quock Wah was considered, and that upon said day andat
said time that the appeal of the said Chin Quock Wah, to the 
Secretary of Labor, from the decision denying the right to 
enter and remain in the United States of Chin Quock Wah, came 
up for hearing and consideration, that said Secretary of Labor 
and the Assistant Secretary of Labor, were then and there present
in their respective offices, and that the said Secretary of Labor
or Assistant Secretary of Labor, under the statutes, should have
considered and determined the said appeal of Chin Quock Wah, from 
the said adverse decision of the said Commissioner of Immigration,
but that said Secretary of Labor and Assistant Secretary of Labor
failed, neglected or refused so to do, and hence the said Chin 
Quock Wah, has been denied his right of appeal, according to law.</p>
<p>IV.
Your Petitioner further alleges that one J. B. Densmore 
is the Solicitor of the Department of Labor, and further alleges 
that said J. B. Densmore attempted to perform the duties of the
Secretary of Labor or Assistant Secretary of Labor while they 
were present in their respective offices, and the order of the 
President of the United States, with due respect thereto, does
not authorize said J. B. Densmore, or such Solicitor of the
Department of Labor, to perform the duties of the Secretary of 
Labor or the Assistant Secretary of Labor, save and except in 
their absence, and therefore, the action of said J. B. Densmore 
in claiming to be the acting Secretary of Labor, during the 
presence of said officials then and there, is a usurption of the duties
imposed upon the said Secretary of Labor, by Congress, and the 
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>
said J. B. Densmore, in assuming the duties of the said Secretary 
of Labor, and the Assistant Secretary of Labor, and affirming
the Finding of the Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, 
Washington, in relation to the case of Chin Quock Wah, exceeded the 
statute, and his action in sustaining the adverse decision in 
relation to the right to enter and remain, of Chin Quock Wah, in 
the United States, is null and the said Chin Quock Wah, has been 
denied the right of appeal as provided by the statutes in such 
cases.</p>
<p>V
Your Petitioner on information and belief, further states 
that the said Chin Quock Wah, has not had a fair and impartial
trial before the said Commissioner of Immigration, at Seattle, 
King County, Washington, that there is no evidence in the records
to sustain the Department's Exclusion and Deportation Order; that 
said Chin Quock Wah, after the Department had illegally ordered 
his exclusion from entry into the United States, and his deportation 
therefrom, without any authority of law, by the illegal act of 
said Solicitor J. B. Densmore, or by who<add>m</add>ever said order was 
issued, was denied a fair and impartial trial, in accordance with 
law, in that the record does not show who signed the Order of
Deportation, and it further appears upon said record, that it
was signed by the Assistant Secretary, without naming who the
Assistant Secretary of the Department of Labor is;And also that
Chin Quock Wah, was denied further, in that at the time of his 
hearing before the Commissioner of Immigration, at Seattle, 
Washington, Henry M. White, or by <add>some</add> person or persons acting by, or
under said Commissioner of Immigration, that said Chin Quock Wah, 
was not allowed to consult counsel, or was he advised of his right
to have counsel, and that he was further denied the right to 
have witnesses, for and in his behalf, and he was nor appraised
of his right to have witnesses appear for and in his behalf; that
said Chin Quock Wah, was denied the right to face his witnesses, 
and that evidence was taken without said Chin Quock Wah, being 
<fw>-4-</fw>
<pb/>
then and there, facing said witnesses, and <add>he</add> was not appraised of 
his right to cross-examine said witnesses, who gave evidence 
against him for and in behalf of the Government.</p>
<p>VI
Your Petitioner further alleges that Chin Quock Wah, 
is the minor son of an American Citizen, and that to deny him
of his right to enter and remain in the United States, is 
depriving him of his liberty, without due process of law, and is 
in violation of the Constitution of the United States.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE, your Petitioner prays that this Court
find that said Chin Quock Wah, has not been accorded the rights
and privileges allowed by the treaty between the United States
and China, and that he be discharged and allowed to join his 
father, who is a merchant in Boston, Massachusetts.</p>
<p>Dated this 8th day of March, 1915.</p>
<ab>Adam Beeler
Attorney for Chin Quock Wah.</ab>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON,
COUNTY OF KING. ) SS</p>

<p>ADAM BEELER, being first duly sworn,
on oath deposes and says: That he is one of the attorneys
for the said Chin Quock Wah; that he has read the foregoing 
Further Amended Petition, knows the contents thereof, and that
the same is true of his own knowledge; that those facts which
he does not know of his own knowledge, he alleges upon
information and belief to be true.</p>
<ab>Adam Beeler</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 9th day of March, 1915.</p>
<ab>James H Doyle
Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</ab>
<pb/>
<p>Original.
No. 2971.</p>

<p>In the United States 
District Court, in and 
for the Western District 
of Washington, Northern 
Division.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the 
Application of CHIN QUOCK WAH, 
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>FURTHER AMENDED PETITION
and 
STIPULATION.</p>

<p>BEELER &amp; SULLIVAN
Attorneys for Petitioner.
510-11 White Bldg.
Seattle, Wash.</p>

<p>2x</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. District Court, 
Western Dist. of Washington, 
NORTHERN DIVISION
MAR131915</p>
<ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk, 
By EML Deputy</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>