<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>Exhibit "C"
Statement of K. Umeda, Made at Oakland Cal.
June 2, 1913</p>
<p>K. Umeda sworn by Thos M. Fisher</p>
<p>My first connection with this case was when I lived upstairs
over Ito's place at 1020 Stockton St., San Francisco. There 
was trouble there, the girl, Hana, wanted to live with Saito and I
was appealed to be Washio to held settle the trouble, I refused at
first but later Saito came to me and I said I would help. Saito
said he wanted to go into the country for the purpose of raising
this money. They money mentioned was money that it was agreed Saito
was to pay Washio for the girl Hana, I don;t recall the exact
amount. Saito asked me to stand good for the money also to stand
good for come bills he owed at some stores. I guaranted that Saito
would pay the money and on the strength of that guarantee Washio and
Ito allowed Hana to go with Saito. Ito was running a house of prostitution
at 1020 Stockton St., Saito and Hana were to go to Sacramento 
and possibly Fresno the understanding being that they were to
return in two weeks, they to try to raise the money in that time.
Instead of returning as agreed they ran away and went up north.</p>
<p>What I did in this matter in the first place was done through
friendship for Saito. When they didn't come back they all came to
me,. I having stook good for Saito, I had nbo interest whatsoever in
the woman or her earnings other then as I have already told you.
Washio sentphotographs of Hana around the country to try to locate
them, Washio was sore at e and also all the places where Saito
owed money. Having gone good for these people I paid a number of the bills
they owed then I went to Seattle to try to locate them, when I arrived
at Seattle I was met by a Japanese, whose name I don't know,
who had a telegram from Washio which he showed me saying I was going
to Seattle, that was soemtime in June or July 1912. I didn't locate
them so I came back to San Francisco, I was looking for them about a
week where she was, but when he started to show me he didn't know
where she was or couldn't find her and then he said she must have
gone to Tacoma. I went to Tacoma but couldn't find her. Washio was
in San Francisco when I returned. While I was in Seattle this Japanese
brought a man to my room and said he was a detective who had
been trying to locate Hana. I was rooming in the Ujine Hotel.</p>
<p>Shortly after I returned to San Francisco Washio went to Seattle
he wired to Ito from Seattle telling him to go to the Burns Agency
and Ito and I and Nakada went there. Washio had written a letter to
Ito telling Ito to have me swear out a warrant for Hana, when we asked
the Burns people about that they said it couldn't be done. Ito got
some other wires from Washio later and told me the party was coming. 
I didn('t go to the boat to meet them but I believe Ito did, also his
wife.


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>