<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-09" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
In the Circuit Court of the United States for the District of
Washington. Northern Division.

No. 776

In the Matter of the application
of Salfest A. Sylvester for a 
writ of habeas corpus.

ORDER DISCHARGING PRISONER under writ of habeas corpus.

This matter coming on regularly to be heard this 3rd day of
July, 1899, upon the writ of habeas corpus issued herein, the
petitioner appearing by his counsel R.B. Albertson, Esq., and the
respondents by their counsel John B. Hart, Esq., and a return to
said writ having been filed by the respondents, and a motion to
quash said return and for the discharge of the prisoner from the
restraint under the warrant set forth by said return <add>having been made and filed by the petitioner</add> And it
appearing to the court that said return does not show sufficient
cause for the restraint of the prisoner in that the requisition
papers in said matter are not made a part thereof, and in that
the warrant under which the petitioner is held is void on its face;
and the court being fully advised in the premises, grants said
motion. Wherefore it is ordered, considered and adjudged that
said return be and the same is hereby quashed and set aside and
that the petitioner be released from the custody under said warrant
and that the respondents and all other persons be and they are hereby
restrained from holding the petitioner further under said warrant;
and that the petitioner recover of and from the respondents
his costs and disbursements herein.

And now at this time counsel for respondents states in open
court that he does not desire to appeal from the foregoing order,
and further states that he is satisfied that the Governor of North
Dakota and the authorities of that States intend to prosecute

-1-

<pb/>

petitioner under the same charge referred to in said warrant and
to make a new demand upon the Governor of the State of Washington
for a writ of extradition under which the petitioner shall be returned 
to North Dakota for trial; and said counsel further moves
the court that pending communication between him and the Governor
of North Dakota petitioner be remanded to the custody of the Sheriff
of King County. Said counsel for the petitioner objects to said
motion on the ground that since the discharge of the petitioner
from custody under said former warrant he is entitled to his liberty
forthwith, and on the ground that there is no process of law
under which he can be held further in that
there are no extradition 
proceedings now pending against the petitoner. Upon argument
the court grants said motion, and does now order the petitioner to
be remanded to the custody of the Sheriff of King County, until
Wednesday, the 5th day of July, 1899, at 3 o'clock p.m., when he 
shall again be brought before the court to obey such order as the
court may then make herein. To this order of the court the
petitioner through his counsel excepts, and said exception is allowed.

done in open court this 3rd day of July, 1899.

C. H. Hanford
Judge

<pb/>

Tx.

(ORIGINAL)

No. 776.

GOB 6-145

In the Circuit Court
OF THE
UNITED STATES
District of Washington Northern Division

In the Matter of the
Application of Salfest
A. Sylvester for writ of
Habeas Corpus

Order discharging 
Prisoner

FILED IN THE
U.S. Circuit Court, 
DIST OF WASHINGTON

JUL 3 1899

A. REEVES AYRES, CLERK

<del>JAS. HAMILTON LEWIS,</del>

H M Matthew
R. B. Albertson
Attorney for petitioner




</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>