<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>In the District Court holding terms at Olympia.</p>

<p><del></del> In the matter of the application of William Jones William H. Doyle, et al. for a writ of habeas corpus</p>

<p>To John B. Allen, U.S. Pros. Att'y and to C. H. Hanford, assistant U.S. Pros. Att'y
for Washington Territory.</p>

<p>You and each of you will please take notice that a Writ of habeas corpus has issued to the U.S. Marshall Jesse W. George in charge of the U.S. Penitentiary McNeils Island, Pierce County, W.T. commanding him to bring the bodies-and eah of them-of the above named parties before the Hon. John P. Hoyt, associate Justice of the Supreme Court and Judge of the 2nd. Judicial district of W.T. that they and each of them may be discharged and restored to their liberty.</p>

<p>And you will please appear and then show cause to the contrary if you can.</p>

<p>Said writ is made returnable at ---o, clcock, on the ----- day of March 1885. at the court room at Olympia, W.T.</p>

<p>Olympia W.T.
March, --- 1885.</p>

<p>Attorneys for petitioner</p>

<p><unclear>Invoice</unclear>by copy admitted this -- day of March 1885</p>

<p>Assistant U.S. Attorney
for Washington Tery</p>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>US District Court Olympia</p>

<p>Inn application of William Jones Et al for writ of habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Notice of <unclear>Agency</unclear> of Writ</p>

<p>Ordered March 10 1885</p>

<p>RG OBrien
Clerk</p>


<p>Territory of Washington}
County of Thurston} SS</p>

<p>D.W. Thurstong being sworn says that he is a citizen of the United States That he <unclear>would</unclear> the within notice on C. H. Hanford on Saturday of March 1885 by <unclear>delivering</unclear> to him personally a true copy hereof at his office in Seattle King County W.T. after first asking the said thonford to acknowledge service of the same and the said <unclear>conferd</unclear> refusing so to do</p>

<p>Dan H Thurston</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 9' day of March 1885</p>

<p>Joseph W Robinson
Notary Public</p>

