<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<note>906</note>

<p>Evidence taken before Daniel Collins, Coroner Pierce Co, WT on an inquisition to examine the cause or manner of death of Seamerch alias "John" an Indian, who died at Elk Plains on 21st day of August 1861</p>

<p>Jury convened at the residence of Mr. Yung at Elk Plains in the County of Pierce, W.T. where the deceased lay dead, examined the body &amp; the following wounds and injuries were found.</p>

<p>First. An incised wound across the bridge of the nose on a line with the eyebrows; but glancing downwards to the nose; not very deep or dangerous.</p>

<p>Second. A stab in the nape of the neck, glancing downwards along the spine; about four inches and a half in depth and made apparently with a knife or some sharp instrument.</p>

<p>Third. A stab on the left shoulder, entering the socket about two and a half inches, made with same instrument as stated above.</p>

<p>Fourth. A stab in the back part of left shoulder striking the shoulder blade bone &amp; glancing downwards, about four and a half inches in depth, same as above.</p>

<p>Fifth. A stab through the left arm, mid-way between the elbow and shoulder: completely severing the muscle, made with same as above.</p>

<p>Sixth. A stab in the right side, under the arm-pit, striking a rib and glancing downwards, four inches in depth.</p>

<p>Seventh. A stab in the left side, between fourth and fifth ribs, penetrating the lungs.</p>

<p>Eighth. A stab in the same side, between the fifth and sixth ribs or there abouts, which penetrated to the lungs.</p>

<p>Ninth. A stab in the same side, between the sixth and seventh ribs, or thereabouts, penetrating to the lungs.</p>

<p>Tenth. A stab in the same side, between the eighth and ninth ribs, or thereabouts, which penetrated to the lungs. The orifice of this wound was larger than any of the others; for through it there

<pb...></pb...>

<note>906</note>

issued a portion of the lobe of the left lung, as large a a man's hand. This must have been accomplished by twisting the knife or instrument around once or twice before withdrawing the same.</p>

<p>Eleventh. Wound in the left hand, the first or small finger being almost severed, and the second finger very badly ut, done probably be deceased taking hold of the knife, or having it <unclear>nomced</unclear> from his hand.</p>

<p>The <del>sixth</del> seventh, eighth, ninth, and tenth wounds were deep and dangerous, all having penetrated the chest and entered the lungs</p>

<p>The sixth wound, tho 'deep, was not dangerous.</p>

<p>Examined Wm Young, on oath, who testifies as follows: The Indian's name is Seamoch alias "John". He was brought to Young's house on Monday morning, the 19th day of August, 1861, and he died about hour of five oclock in the morning of the 21st day of August, 1861, near the residence of Witness.</p>

<p>(The inquisition heard the testimony of several Indian women for the purpose of furthering the ends of Justice, by ascertaining what number and who were the white men that were present at the time the Indian was mortally wounded.)</p>

<p>The inquisition adjourned to meet in Steilacoom on the 23d day of August, 1861, at 10 o'c A.M.</p>

<p>2nd day.</p>

<p>Henry &amp; Bradly sworn, testifies as follows: Several persons were at his house on Sunday, August 18th, were drinking; the following persons were there: James Riley, Tho.s Horn, Aexander McDonald, Michl Eustice, Dominick Corcoran, John MLeod, Mr Colanan &amp; Mrs. <unclear>clunus</unclear> was drunk and does not anything that transpired in the barn that evening. Barn is about 40 yards from the house. Mrs. Bradley was absent on Sunday.</p>