<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0116.003"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Wiley v. Keokuk. Case</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0116.003</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Wiley v. Keokuk. Case</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1870-05">May 1870</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Keokuk, Moses</term>
<term>Kingman, C.F.</term>
<term>Wiley, Albert</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Douglas County</term> 
<term>Indiana</term>
<term>Massachusetts</term>
<term>North Carolina</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Wiley, Albert</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Keokuk, Moses</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Last, First</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Last, First</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Kingman, C.F.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName> 
<placeName>Douglas County, Kansas</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="sab">transcribed, encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0116.003"/> 

<p>Albert Wiley
v
Keokuk
Kingman</p>

<p>The first error alleged occurred in selecting a jury. The person was challenged for cause on the ground that he had once already errored on a <unclear>jury</unclear> on a talesman in the treat of a cause at the same team of the conet, the court overrated the challenge, This was error. Code sec 270, It appears that after the person had served as a talesman he had ben called to seen as a regular juror for te term in place of a juror excused. This made no difference, the law remained the same, the challenge should have been allowed, the beneficent objects of the section could not to frees hated by placing a man on the regular paned who could not serve on a penny if challenged. The object of the law is to get rid of professional jurors, a most pertiferous set as every lawyer knows, and this could not be done away with by a sheriff or court, by <del>mutting could</del> putting such a jurer on the regular <unclear></unclear>. The juror was afterwards challenged peremptoily by plantiff in then and there removed from the jury. The record does not show that the defendant exhausted his persemptory challenges. Then funds bring the case directly within the ruling of thi court in the case of Merton v The State 1st <unclear></unclear> 468, "By the means the defendant seems</p>

<p>2</p>

<p>effectivally to have relived himself from the grievance of which he complains" and the case will not be reserved for an error of the court which the party cured by his own action. </p>
<p>The next serer claimed in that the court used in the chargs to the jury and special attention in called to the 6th intention which is as follows
"That the letter of instruction of communication Mix, does not pistfy the illegal act of Agent Wiley. He is answerable in damages to the plaintiff for any illegal act."</p>
<p>The plaintiff in error claims that by the instruction the court total the jury that Wiley did do some <del>illegal</del> act to Keokuk and that such act was illegal and that the letter of <unclear>communition</unclear> mint did not justify such illegal act. It is apparent from the need that the court did do just what it is claimed that is did. The indication of the court is two plain not to have been understood by the jury. Did the pleadings need evidence authorize such an instruction. The jury are only to pass upon the issues made up in the case. They pass upon the controverted facts, that is the facts controverted vy the proceedings. In this case the petition alleged an assault and battery and false imprisonment. The answer set up two grounds of defense</p>

<p>3</p>

<p>first a general denial and seemed a special defense showing what the defendant had really done and attempting to justify his acts by these facts. It was an <unclear>atminine</unclear> that the defendant was the primary moving cause of the arrest and imprisonment of the plaintiff and an attempt to justify his conduct therein. Now notwithstanding the general denial we suppose that whatever was admitted in the special defense need not have been proved. This special defense so far modified the general denial that whatever was admitted therein was excepted from the general denial. It ought to be so on general principle of pleading, it must be so enamoured as it is a formal confession of the existence of the facts therein set forth. A careful examination of the answer has conrimced us. That had there been no evidence in the case the courts would have had to give nominal damages at least on the pleadings as they stood, and to do so would necessarily have hel that in the answer was an admission of facts that made the defendant guilty of an illegal act in <del>the ane</del> causing the arrest and <del>false</del> imprisonment of Keokuk.</p>
<p>The court there committed no error in <unclear></unclear> the jury as it did that Wiley had been guilty of an illegal act towards the plaintiff and of course these can be no justification in laws</p>

<p>4</p>

<p>for an illegal act. I there if justification in law, there can be no illegallity. As the pleadings had admitted the acts done it was proper for the court to <del>set</del> so say to the jury and it was its duty to say to them that such acts were illegal if such was the law.</p>
<p><unclear>Aor</unclear> we think this ruling is at all in conflict with the case of Carl Home v The State /Kansas 42. to which we have been refused. The plea of not <unclear></unclear> is that case put everything in <del>don</del> issue, and it was necessary for the state to prove every fact essential to make up the crime, and every such fact was to be passed upon by the jury, unbiased by <del>the court</del> anything thte court might say. in this case it was the duty of the court on the pleadings to say that the judgements must be for the plaintiff and it was proper to say/do to the jury, and the court, did no more at most in the instruction under consideration</p>
<p>The seventh and eighth instructions are objected to. They are as follows</p>
<p>7 "That whenever the elements of frand malice gross negligence or oppression mingle in the controversy the law allows the jury to give</p>

<p>5</p>

<p>what is called exemplary or indictive damages" 
8 " That in cases of tors and actions for false imprisonment, the jury are the only proper judges of how much the plaintiff ought to recover,"</p>
<p>These instructions raise the question so much discussed of late by writers upon law as to whether such damages as are called exemplary, indictive or punitive ought ever to be allowed We content ourselves with following to connect of authorities and decide that the instructions go no further than such authorities warrant. If the law is wrong let the law making power correct it. The rule as laid down by the court below has already received the sanctions of this court. Malone v Muphey 2nd Kansas 2150., The whole subject is discussed pro and con, and the authorities refused to in 2 <unclear>Grempleafs</unclear> Ev. sees 253-5 and note, and in <unclear>Seos.</unclear> on measure of damages 4th Ed. 533 and note. And after all this discussion, the Supreme Court of the US decide the law as laid down in these instructions. No Justice given delivering the opinion of the court well says." If repeated pedicial decision for more than a century are to be received at the best experition of what the law is, the question will not admit of argument. By the common as well as by statute laws, men are often punished for aggravated misconduct of lawless acts by means of a civil action, and the damages inflicted by way of penalty or punishment, given to the party</p>

<p>6</p>

<p>injured" We have no doubt that such is the law. Where it be founded in grand reason or not is not so much our promise to say, as to determine if it be law. The writer hereof believes it to be not only good law but founded on sound principles and beneficial in its application. It often fernishes the only restraint upon a bad man who cares little for his neighbors character his person, or his property. The party injured pursues the wrong doer to punishment, when society is too careless to do so.</p>
<p>It is claimed however in this case that the action being for assault and battery, which is punishable by criminal proceedings, if exemplary damages are allowed, then the wrong doer is likable to be punished twice. To this answers may be made each of which is satisfactory, while the action is free assault and battery and false imprisonment. The evidence only showed a false impoverishment and the plaintiff fails to show how that is made a criminal offence again. the great weight of authorities is against such a modification of the doctrine. In Massachusetts, Indiana and North Carolina such a limitation has been engrafted upon the doctrine of exemplary damages. but in most of the states it has been rejected and we think rightfully.</p>

<p>7</p>

<p>These reasons under it unnecessary to consider at length the instructions asked by the defendant and refund, for they are the direct converse of those given, asking the court to say that the jury could only give a verdict for the damages sustained or "actually sustained" The petition contained the usual averments formerly found in actions for assault and battery and false imprisonment and the jury were authorized under it to give exemplary damages as we understand the law, and the instructions asked laid down a much more limited rule and consequently ought not to have been given

on a motion for a new trial it was insisted that the verdict was against the law and the evidence and two reasons are urged in support of the petition. First that the evidence did not show a state of facts that would authorize a recovery against Wiley, Set as see. Wiley was agent for the Sae and <unclear></unclear> enorinns of which tribe Keokuk was chief. Commissioner mix had directed that no delegations from any of the tribes should visit Washington as there was not appropriation to pay their expenses. This letter as was one from <unclear>Superinterduct</unclear> Murphy was read by Wylie to Keokuk and other on the 16th day of November 1868. When Keokuk said he <del>had</del> should go as he had money and would pay his own expenses. That on the 22nd of November Keokuk and four others of the tribe started for Washington without license so to do.</p>

<p>8</p>

<p>That they were overtaken by <unclear>Wylie</unclear> at Lawrence on the next day. That Wylie on that day went <unclear>repere</unclear> a United States Comminioner for the district of Kansas and made a complaint in writing under oath, changing that Keokuk a Sacnus Toy Indian of the Sac and Tory reserve in the county of Srunklin in the district and state of Kansas did on the 23d day of November 1868 leave said resure, and did disobey the order of the United States Communer of Indian Affairs and the order of other agents of the United States to him given and asking that Keokuk be apprehended and dealt with according to law. C.W. their affidavit a warrant was issued and Keokuk <unclear></unclear> by the United States marshal and brought before the Commissioner, Wylie employ. I command and certified in the case and thereupon the commissioner decided that Keokuk should give bad <unclear>fa his</unclear> appearance at the next terrce of the United States Court for the district of Kansas, and directed the marshal to take him into custody. Keokuk refused to give bail and was taken to jail and kept there till he was released upon habeas corpus.</p>
<p>This is a sufficient outlaw of the testimony in the case to understand what is deceased necessary to say on the point under consideration. The complaint made by Wylie changes no offense on the part of Keokuk, neihter did</p>

<p>9</p>

<p>the warrant or mittimus, describe any officers known to the law. The substance of the complaint is stated above, and the warrant and Mittimus generally follow it, though the mittimus is more verbose, as though the Commissioner felt it necessary to say something more, than that Keokuk had left the reserve and was travelling to Washington to justify his act in sending him to jail. Still no offence in charged known to any system of law of which our han any knowledge. The facts are so banen as not to lay the foundation for jurisdiction. The affidavit warrant and Mittimus afford ample evidence that no criminal charge was prefaced or passed upon, nor a sufficient pretense of one to challenge judicial <unclear>deidetion</unclear> and the conclusion sweeps away the ground on which the decisions rested to which the plaintiff in error refuse in his brief.</p>
<p>Another reason urged why the veroich should have been act aside is that the plaintiff below was Moian and as such was subject to the <unclear></unclear> and neglect of the United States to make such regulations for his government as the President of the United States should deem proper, and for the interest of the tribe to which he belonged; or in other war or Keokuk</p>

<!-- bottom of page cut off -->

<p>10</p>

<p>We are not prepared to give our sanctiere to the doctrine abore set forth: but might well do so and not distrub the action of the court below, for we are nowhere shown any law of the United States, or any regulation of the President that <del>preent</del> makes it a punishable offense for are Indian to go to Washington at his own expense, Nor does the letter of the Commissioner, or Superintendent. But we suppose that nothing but a law would wait as a justification for arresting and improving a <unclear></unclear></p>
<p>If it is necessary to <unclear></unclear> to this point, there indeed have we learned little of the principle of a government professedly <unclear></unclear> on law. Nor does it make any difference that the party injured in an Indian, whether he be regarded as "a ward of Government," or as belonging to a "domestic dependent nations" or "a distinct independent political community <unclear></unclear> them original natural rights" <del>in</del> to each of which classes they honor at times been assigned by the language of the Supreme Court of the United States. In any view which keeping the peace and disobeying no law humor or divine. In case not be the subject of arrest and imprisonment by any one except at the peril of the affender. His rights are regulated by law, and when he appeals to the</p>

<!-- bottom of page cut off -->

<p>11</p>

<p>of the court below <del>by</del> for this reason. Having examined the record and all the allegd error and finding no reason to reverse the judgement of the court below the same will be affirmed</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
