<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0492.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Pizzi, Annabella D." xml:id="adp">Annabella D. Pizzi</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>NSF</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0492.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant.</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1915-10-08">October 8, 1915</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Medcraf, Francis Medcraf</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>The State of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Emery, Geo D.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Lundin, Alfred H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Helsell, Frank P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="justice_of_the_peace">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
                  
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#adp">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT FOR THE
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF 
the application of 
FRANCIS STEPHEN MEDCRAF
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus.

Bail and Supersedeas Bond.</p>
<p>KNOW ALL MEN BY THESE PRESENTS, that we, FRANCIS STEPHEN MEDCRAF
as principal and Geo W. Hill ----- and Era Bell Hill -------
his wife, and Michael Marion Null, and Nell Johnson his wife, 
as sureties, are held and firmly bound unto the UNITED STATES OF
AMERICA, for the use of whomsoever is or shall be entitled thereto,
in the penal sum of FIVE HUNDRED DOLLAR ($500.00), to be paid
the said obligee; for the payment of which, well and truly to be
made, we bind ourselves and each of us, our and each of our heirs,
executors, administrators and successors, jointly and severally,
firmly by these presents.</p>
<p>Sealed with out seals and dated this 8th day of October, A.
D. 1915.</p>
<p>WHEREAS, the above bounden FRANCIS STEPHEN MEDCRAF, has prosecuted 
an appeal to the SUPREME COURT OF THE UNITED STATES to reverse
the judgement rendered in the above entitled cause by the District
Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington,
Northern Division, entered in said court on the 30th day of 
September A.D. 1915, denying the petition of the above named petitioner
for a writ of Habeas Corpus and his discharge thereon and remanding
him to the custody of the Sheriff of King County, Washington
and he desires to supersede and stay the said judgement and order appealed
from;</p>
<p>NOW THEREFORE, the condition of this obligation is such, that 
if the said FRANCIS STEPHEN MEDCRAF shall prosecute his said appeal
to effect and abide by and perform the judgement which the said Supreme
Court may render in said cause, or on the mandate of this court by
the court below, and shall be and appeat at all such times and places
as this Supreme Court or the said court below may order and direct,
<pb/>
then this obligation to be void; otherwise, of full force and effect.</p>
<p>Francis Stephen Medcraf
Michael Marion Null
Nell Johnson Null
George W. Hill
Era Bella Hill </p>
<p>WITNESS:
Geo D. Emery</p>
<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON
COUNTY OF KING
SS</p>
<p>BE IT KNOWN that, on this 8th day of October A.D.
1915, before the undersigned, a Notary Public of the State of Washington
duly commissioned and sworn, personall came FRANCIS STEPHEN 
MEDCRAF, Michael Marion Null &amp; Nell Johnson Null his wife and
Geo W. Hill &amp; Era Bell Hill his wife to me known personally 
to be the same persons named in and who executed the foregoing BOND and
they severally acknowledged the execution thereof to be their free and
voluntary act and deed and for the uses and purposes therein free and
voluntary act and deed and for the uses and purposes therein expressed. </p>
<p>Witness my hand and official seal the day and year last above 
written.
Geo D. Emery 
Notary Public for Washington
Residing at Seattle.</p>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON
COUNTY OF KING
SS</p>
<p>Geo W. Hill &amp; Era Bell Hill his wife AND
Michael Marion Null and Nell Johnson Null his wife BEING FIRST DULY
SWORN SEVERALLY DOTH SAY: THAT they are the sureties named in the
foregoing bond; that they are residents and freeholders of the State
of Washington and <add>the communities which they respectively compose are each</add>worth the sum of  ONE THOUSAND ($1,000.00) --- DOLLARS
over and above their debts and liabilites and exclusive of their
property exempt by law from sale on execution.</p>
<p>Michael Marion Null
Nell Johnson Null
George W Hill
Era Bell Hill</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me
this 8th day of October A.D. 1915.
Geo D. Emery
Notary Public for Washington
Residing at Seattle.</p>
<figure></figure>
<p>approved
Jeremiah Neterer 10-9-15
Judge</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>