<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0107.061">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Gus Bendjus et al. v. Territory of Washington. Indictment</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Czapla, Ethan P." xml:id="epc">Ethan P. Czapla</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0107.061</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Gus Bendjus et al. v. Territory of Washington. Indictment</title>
<date when="1887-10-15">September 15, 1887</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archive</repository>
<collection>Grays Harbor Frontier Justice</collection>
<idno>GRH137</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1887-09">September 1887</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Peterson, Pete</term>
<term>Strinberger, Fred</term>
<term>Saxton, John</term>
<term>Agnew, Alex</term>
<term>Burke, Charles</term>
<term>Anderson, Andrew</term>
<term>Blending, John</term>
<term>Allen, C. B.</term>
<term>Harris, A. T.</term>
<term>Colbert, F.</term>
<term>Gilbreath, C. H.</term>
<term>Friedenberg, Walt</term>
<term>Hunter, John</term>
<term>Church, William</term>
<term>Graham, Wilson</term>


</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Montesano, Washington</term>
<term>Chehalis County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Bendjus, Gus</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Strangland, Robert</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Frederiksen, Ben</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Nelson, Frank</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Johnson, Andrew</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Brown, Leander</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Thompson, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Agren, Alex</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Jacobs, Thomas</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Bignold, Lewis B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Robinson, Joseph W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Moody, George J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Allyn, Frank</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Second Judicial District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington Territory</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022" who="lkw">review</change>     
<change when="2021-09" who="#epc">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>No 137</p>

<p>In the District Court of the Second Judicial District of Washington Territory,
       holding terms at Montesano for the County of Chehalis. W T.</p>

<p>
       Indictment</p>

       <p>Territory of Washington<lb/>
                        vs.<lb/>
       Gus Bendjus - Robert Stranglaud<lb/>
       Ben Frederickson - Pete Peterson<lb/>
       Frank Nelson - Fred Stromberger<lb/>
       John Blending - Andrew Johnson<lb/>
       Leander Brown - John Saxton<lb/>
       John Thompson - Alex Agren<lb/>
       Thomas Jacob - E. Emel<lb/>
       Andew Anderson and Charles Burke</p>

<p>The Grand Jury of the County of Chehalis Territory of Washington
       composed of good and lawful persons from the body of the Second
       Judicial District, and for the County aforesaid, duly elected, impanneld
       sworn and charged to inquire of and true presentment make
       to the said Disctrict Court of the regular September term thereof A D 1887 of the 
       said District Court begun and held at Montesano in the said County of Chehalis in
       the said County of Chehalis, in the District aforesaid on the 12th day of September
       A.D. 1887 of all offenses commited

<pb/>

<fw>Page 2</fw>

 in the said County against the Territory of
       Washington on their oaths accuse:</p>
    
<p>Gus Bendjus - Robert Stranglaud - Ben Frederickson - Pete Peterson - Frank Nelson
       Fred Stromberger - John Blending - Andrew Johnson - Leander Brown - John Saxton
       John Thompson - Alex Agren - Thomas Jacobs - E. Emel - Andrew Anderson and
       Charles Burke by this indictment of the crime of Riot commited as follows, to writ the said
       Gus Bendjus - Robert Stranglaud - Ben Frederickson - Pete Peterson - Andrew Johnson
       Leander Brown - John Saxton - John Thompson - Alex Agnew - Thomas Jacobs - E. Emel
       Andrew Anderson and Charles Burke on the 9th day of September A D 1887 and in the
       night time, and within one year next proceeding the date hereof, in the said County of Chehalis, 
       in the said Second Judicial District, in the Territory of Washington then and there being 
       with certain other ill disposed and and evil minded persons to the grand jury 
       unknown of the number of one hundred or upwards, with force and arms, and guns, pistols &amp; knives
       did assemble and gather themselves together, and being so assembled &amp; gathered together, the day
       and year aforesaid and in the night time thereof, at and in the said County of Chehalis &amp; Territory
       of Washington the pound net the property of C.B.

<pb/>

<fw>Page 3</fw>

 Allen and A.T. Harris of the value of 
       six hundred dollars, and the pound net the property of and blonging to F. Colbert and the Aberdeen
       Packing Company of the value of one thousand five hundred dollars and the fish trap the property of and belonging
       to C.H. Gilberth and <gap/> Campbellof the value of six hundred dollars, and the pound net of Walt
       Fridenberg and John Hunlin such parties being the owners thereof, and of the value of six hundred dollars, and
       the pound nets the property of and belonging to Wm Clundy of the value of eight hundred dollars, and the pound 
       nets that value of $600.00 beloning to one Wilson Graham, all of the said property, then and being
       in the said county and territory aforesaid, with knives and other implements to the Grand Jury unknown willfully, 
       unlawfully, feloneously and in a vioent and tumultous manner, cut, tear, savage, <unclear>raige</unclear> and pull down
       and destroy and to the great damage of the said C.B. Allen and A.T. Harris, F Colbert, and the Aberdeen Packing Company,
       C.H. Gilberth and <gap/> Campbell, Walt Fredenborg and John Hunter, Wm Church, and Wilson Graham and to the evil example, and
       great terror of all good citizens of this common wealth. 
       </p>

<pb/>

<fw>Page 4</fw>

<p>Contrary to the statutes in such cases made and provided and against the peace and dignity of the Territory of Washington.</p>

       <p>Dated at Montesano in the district aforesaid this 15th day of Septermber 1887. </p>

<p>George J Moody<lb/>
       Prosecuting Attorney of the Second Judicial District. W. T</p>

<pb/>

<p>Gus Bendjus &amp; al</p>
<p>Indictment for Riot</p>
<p>A True Bill<lb/>
J. W. Milroy<lb/>Foreman</p>

<p>Witnesses Examined<lb/>
J.C. Pearson – A. T. Harris<lb/>
Fred Colbert - C. H. Gilbreath<lb/>
Abel Goss - H. C. Winkler<lb/>
Wm Church - Geo N. Scannon<lb/>
Wm Saunders -
</p>

<p>Bail fixed at #300.00 in each case</p>
<p>Frank Allyn</p>

<p>Filed in open court in presence of the Grand Jury this 15th day of September A. D. 1887.</p>
<p>HM Sutton<lb/>
clerk
</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>