<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0208.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ichitaro Matsutsuyu v. Henry M. White. Supplemental Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0208.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ichitaro Matsutsuyu v. Henry M. White. Supplemental Petition</title>
<date when="1919-12-13">December 13, 1919</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1919-12">December 1919</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Japan</term>
<term>San Francisco, California</term>
<term>Los Angeles, California</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Matsutsuyo, Ichitaro</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Wardell, Ray M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Moore, Ben L.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-01" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>No. 4918</p>

<p>In the United States District Court for the Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Ichitara Matsutsuyu to be Released on Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Supplemental Petition.</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Dec 13 1919</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Lietch Deputy</p>

<p>Roy M. Wardall, <del>Wardell &amp;Martin</del></p>
<p>Atty for Petitioner</p>

<p><del>540-1-2</del> 704 New York Block</p>
<p>Seattle</p>
<p>Main 7465</p>

<pb/>

<p>-U.S.Clerk--File-</p>

<p>Copy of within Supplemental Petition received and due service of the same acknowledged this 12th day of December 1919</p>

<p>Robt C Saunders</p>

<p>Attorney for Govt</p>

<p>By E.D.Dalton</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 4918</p>
<p>Supplemental Petition.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Ichitara Matsutsuyu to be Released on Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Leave of Court having first been had, the petitioner now alleges in his supplemental petition the following:</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That the petitioner has been a resident of the United States continuously for nearly thirteen years, having arrived from the Empire of Japan in San Francisco in 1906; that he has, at no time, been out of the United States for a single day or night and during all of said time has been steadily employed or engaged in business for himself; that he has, at no time, received assistance from any source, nor has he been in indigent circumstances; that during his residence in the United States he married in Los Angeles and is the father of a child two and one-half years of age, his wife having died within the past two years.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>That since the filing of the original petition herein an examination has been made of the files of the Department of Labor and its various orders, the same being with Henry M.White, United States Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, and from the foregoing the petitioner alleges and avers that on or about the 13th day of June, 1917, a warrant was issued from the Department of Labor directing Henry M. White,as Commissioner, to examine and give the petitioner a hearing on the sole charge that he was liable to become a public charge.</p>

<p>III.</p>

<p>That in accordance with said order, Deputy Commissioner Callahan, did make a purported examination at McNeil's Island Penitentiary in the state of Washington, and within the District over which this Court has supervision, and at such time, without warrant or authority, attempted to place an additional charge against the petitioner which said charge petitioner had no opportunity to meet or refute the allegations thereof.</p>

<p>IV.</p>

<p>That at said hearing not one centilla of evidence was introduced by said Commissioner to show that the petitioner was likely to become a public charge. On the contrary the petitioner showed himself to be an expert workman and tailor by trade, always during his residence employed for several years operating a tailor shop of his own, maintaining a home and married in the United States and a child born in the United States, and which said child is now in California.</p>

<p>V.</p>

<p>That at said hearing and subsequent thereto, the petitioner introduced ample testimony and supplied in his brief offers of divers parties to guarantee by bond or otherwise that the petitioner would never become a public charge</p>

<p>VI.</p>

<p>That the purported charge and attempt of the Deputy Commissioner to place a further charge against the petitioner at the time of his hearing, was wholly unwarranted without spurious authority, said charge being, that he was convicted of a crime involving moral turpitude within five years from the last day of entry into the United States.</p>

<p>VII.</p>

<p>That said attempted and purported additional charge is wholly untrue, and in addition to being utterly without foundation and fact, is in violation of the treaty rights existing between the United States and Japan, and in violation of the constitutional rights of all persons to have a fair and impartial hearing when charged with the commission of any offense whatsoever.</p>

<p>VIII.</p>

<p>That on or about November 4, 1919, Henry M. White, United States Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle alleges that he was authorized and directed by the Department of Labor to deport the petitioner, said Deportation Order being based upon the recommendation of Henry M. White, United States Commissioner of Immigration.</p>

<p>IX.</p>

<p>Petitioner states that the findings and conclusions of said Henry M. White as United States Commissioner, and the subsequent findings of the Department of Labor are not in any manner sustained by the evidence taken at the hearing and said findings are not predicated upon the evidence established, but upon the hearing, the only charge preferred upon him, to-wit: that of the petitioner's liability to become a public charge, and said finding is wholly repugnant to the treaty rights of the United States with Japan and the Constitutional rights guaranteeing to every person a fair and impartial trial.</p>

<p>X.</p>

<p>That said order of Deportation, and the restraint which followed, the petitioner now being confined at the Immigration Station in Seattle, was issued solely upon the evidence presented in said record, all of which record is in the hands of Henry M. White, U.S. Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, and which your petitioner desires placed in its entirety to this Court.</p>

<pb/>

<p>XI.</p>

<p>Your petitioner further represents that divers parties are ready, able and willing to post any bond required by this Court to guarantee that petitioner herein will not become a public charge.</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that his original petition be, in all matters, sustained and that your petitioner herein be forthwith restored to his liberty.</p>

<p>Ichitaro Matsutsuyu</p>
<p>Petitioner.</p>

<p><gap></gap></p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner</p>

<p>Western District of Washington, Northern Division</p>
<p>ss</p>

<p>ICHITARA MATSUTSUYU, the Petitioner named in the foregoing petition, being first duly sworn on oath says that he has read the foregoing petition, knows the contents thereof and believes the same to be true.</p>

<p>Ichitaro Matsutsuyu</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 12 day of December, 1919.</p>

<p>RM Wardall</p>

<p>Notary Public in and for King County, Washington</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>