<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0205.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Bartholomeo Massulo v. Henry M. White. Return and Answer of Respondent</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0205.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Bartholomeo Massulo v. Henry M. White. Return and Answer of Respondent</title>
<date when="1919-02-17">February 17, 1919</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1919-02">February 1919</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fisher, Thomas M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Massulo, Bartholomeo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Moore, Ben L.</persName>
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2019-12" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="#hc.case.wa.0205.007"/>

<p>No. 4523</p>

<p>Return and Answer of Respondent, Henry M. White, Commissioner of Immigration</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of Bartolomeo Massulo for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Comes now the respondent, Henry M. White, United States Commissioner of Immigration at Seattle, Washington and as a return to the order to show cause hereforto entered by the court on the third day of February, 1919, and as answer to the complaint or application of the above named petitioner for a writ of Habeas Corpus herein, said respondent denies each and every allegation of petitioner's complain, except as herein admitted.</p>

<p>That respondent admits that the questions and answers set forth in paragraph II of the Comlaint herein were propounded to and answered by the said alien, but alleges that said questions and answers comprise only a portion of the testimony adduced;</p>

<p>And respondent further admits that the petitioner after his arrest was at large for a time under bond;</p>

<p>That this respondent further respectfully shows to the court as follows:</p>

<p>1.</p>

<p>That under and by virtue of a warrant of arrest duly and regularly issued on the 10th day of November, 1917, by the United States Secretary of Labor, the said petitioner, Bartolomeo Massulo, was duly and regularly arrested upon the ground that he had been found advocating or teaching anarchy or the overthrow by force or violence of the government of the United States, or of all forms of law, or the assassination of public officials, or that he was a person likely to become a public charge at the time of his entry into the United States; that the said warrant is hereto attached as a part of the attached record marked Exhibit "A".</p>

<p>II</p>

<p>That thereafter, a hearing of said petitioner and of the matters and facts charged in said warrant of arrest was duly and regularly conducted by Thomas M.Fisher, United States Immigration Inspector at Seattle, Washington, on, to-wit: November 12, 1917, at which said hearing the said petitioner was examined and other testimony adduced in behalf of the Immigration service; that a copy of the said testimony and of the proceedings for the deportation of said petitioner is set forth in Exhibit "A", "B" and "C" hereto attached, and made a part of this return.</p>

<p>III.</p>

<p>That the said Inspector Thomas M. Fisher duly and regularly found that the said petitioner Bartolomeo Massulo was an alien and subject of Italy, who landed at the port of New York on or about November 11, 1913; that the said alien at the time of his entry was a person likely to become a public charge and that he had been found advocating and teaching anarchy and the overthrow by force or violence of the Government of the United States, or of all forms of law, subsequent to his entry into the United States, and that the said Inspector recommended the deportation of said alien to the country whence he came.</p>

<p>IV.</p>

<p>That thereafter and on, to-wit: the 5th day of December, 1918, a warrant was duly and regularly issued by the United States Secretary of Labor reciting and finding that the said Bartolomeo Massulo had been found in the United States in violation of the Immigration Act of February 5, 1917, to-wit: that he had been found advocating or teaching anarchy, or the overthrow by force or violence of the government of the United States, or of all forms of law, or the assassination of public officials, and commanded the deportation of the said Bartolomeo Massulo; that the said warrant is hereto attached and made a part hereof as a portion of the attached Exhibit "C".</p>

<p>V.</p>

<p>That the said petitioner has been and is now detained by this respondent under and by virtue of the said warrant of deportation issued as aforesaid; that the said petitioner has had a full and fair hearing and is subject to deportation under that said warrant.</p>

<p>WHEREFORE this respondent prays that the petitioner's application be denied.</p>

<p>John H Sargent</p>
<p>Acting Commissioner of Immigration</p>

<p>Robt. C. Saunders</p>
<p>United States Attorney.</p>

<p>Ben L. Moore</p>
<p>Assistant United States Attorney.</p>

<p>Attorneys for Respondent.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>