<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.ne.0577.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Flora Ohler v. George and Charles S. Shafer. Return and Answer.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Stapleton-Deno, Zoe L." xml:id="zlsd">Zoe L. Stapleton-Deno</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.ne.0577.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Flora Ohler v. George and Charles S. Shafer.</title>
<date when="1898">1898</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1898-04">April, 1898</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Naomi A. Gielday</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Nebraska</term>
<term>Red Willow County</term>
<term>Lancaster County</term>
<term>Third Judicial District Court of Nebraska</term>
<term>Iowa </term>
<term>Hamburg</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Flora Ohler</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>George Shafer</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Charles S. Shafer</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>W.R. Starr</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>McClure&amp; Anderson</persName></person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Albert J Cornish</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
                  
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Third Judicial District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Nebraska</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-07" who="#zlsd">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the District Court of Lancaster County, Nebraska.
In the Matter of the Application  )
of Flora Ohler for a writ of          )     Return and answer to petition.
Habeas Corpus.                         )
                                                         The respondent, Charles Shafer

386.</p>

<pb/>

<p>23-85 IN RE APPLICATION OF FLORA OHLER FOR WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>

<p>for answer and return to the writ of Habeas Corpus issued in this 
case says:</p>

<p>         1st Admits that A.J. Cornish is one of the Judges of 
the District Court of the Third Judicial District of the state of 
Nebraska, and that the petitioner, Flora Ohler is the mother of 
Naomi Geilday and is now deceased; that the said Naomi Gielday is
a minor, 14 years of age and upwards, to wit the age of fourteen
years and eight months and that the said Charles Shafer is not at 
this time deputy sheriff, coroner, constable of this state or United 
States. 2nd. This respondent, Charles Shafer further answering 
says that Naomi Gielday is a minor over the age of 14 years 
to wit of the age of fourteen years and eight months; Sometime in 
January, 1893, in an action pending in said Lancaster County the 
marriage theretofore existed between the said Flora Ohler and Jospeh S. 
Gielday was annulled, and that thereupon the said Joseph S. 
Gielday in the year of 1893 removed from said Lancaster County to 
Red Willow County and State of Nebraska where he resided and was 
a freeholder and elector of said county from the time of removing 
to said Red Willow County to until the time of his death on the 11th 
day of February, 1898, and the said Flora Ohler removed from said 
Lancaster County to the State of Iowa, where she now resides and 
has for more than a year last past. That since the decree of divorce
and before the death of said Joseph Gielday herein before 
mentioned the said Flora Ohler has been twice married. And each of 
said husbands were living at the time of the death of said Joseph
S. Geilday. That said Naomi Geilday came to said Red Willow County
on the 20th day of Novemeber, 1893, and ever since and up to the 
present time has been and is now a resident pf Red Willow County, 
Nebraska, and ever since the commencement of her residence in said 
Red Willow County has been under the care, charge and custody of 
her father up to the time of his death on the 11th day of February, 
1898. A short time after the death of the said Joseph S. Geilday his daughter the said Naomi
Gailday, being more than fourteen years of age, came to the residence
of this respondent and asked to be permitted to make her
home with the family of this respondent and asked to be permitted to make her 
home with the family of this respondent. The said Naomi Geilday 
having no father, morther, sister, brother or other relatives in 
said Red Willow County and state of Nebraska with whom she could 
make her home; thereupon the said Naomi Geilday, and thereupon on the 21st 
day of April, 1898 in said county Court a hearing was duly had 
before the county judge of said Red Willow County as to the appointment 
of this respondent as guardian of the said Naomi Gailday, 
at which time and place it was then and there adjudged by the said 
court that this respondent be, and this respondent was then and 
there duly appointed guardian of the person and property of the 
said Naomi Geilday. Thereupon this respondent duly qualified
by giving bond and taking the oath of office, and ever since said 
21st day of April, 1898, and up to the present time this respondent
has been and is now the guardian of the person and property of 
the said Naomi Geilday. and the said Naomi Geilday by her own desire </p>

<pb/>

<p>23-85 IN RE APPLICATION FLORA OHLER FOR WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>

<p>and without any restraint at any time whatever has been since 
the 14th day of February, 1898, residing with the family of this 
respondent.</p>

<p>     Prior to the said 21st day of April, 1898,
to-wit: On the 9th day of March, 1898, on notice duly given, a 
hearing was duly had as to the appointment of this respondent as 
administrator of the estate of the said Joseph S. Geilday, and on 
the 9th day of March, 1898, this respondent was duly appointed by
the County Court of said Red Willow County, Nebraska, administrator, 
thereupon this respondent duly qualified by giving bond and taking 
the oath of office, and ever since the said 9th day of March, 1898, 
this respondent has been, and now is the administrator of the estate 
of the said Joseph S. Geilday, deceased.</p>

<p>     This respondent now is and has been for more 
than nine years last past, a resident, elector, freeholder, and 
tax-payer of said Red Willow County, Nebraska. This respondent
is informed and believes that the said Flora Ohler is a non-resident 
of the State of Nebraska, and resides at Hamburg, Iowa. </p>

<p>     Hon. George S. Bishop is the duly elected, qualified 
and acting County Judge of said Red Willow County, and has 
been acting as such county judge for more than three months last
past, and having an office in McCook, Nebraska, the county-seat of 
Red Willow County. During the 3rd day of May, 1898, and ever 
since, up to the present time, the said George S. Bishop has been 
in said county discharging the duties of his said office, and during
office hours in the Court House in the county seat of said Red
Willow County, and is no way disqualified from hearing this application
of the said Flora Ohler for a writ of habeas corpus in this 
matter. Honorable George W. Norris, is the District Judge of the
14th Judicial District of the State of Nebraska, and of said Red
Willow County, resides at Beaver City, not to exceed 25 miles from 
the resident of this respondent and of the said Naomi Geilday, and 
is in no way disqualified from acting in this matter. This respondent
is informed and believes that said George W. Norris, District 
Judge as aforesaid, was at Beaver City on the 3rd day of May, 
1898, and could be easily found at said place and has been continuously
 in said district for more than ten days last past and is 
now in said district. At the time of filing the complaint in 
this matter and at the time of issuing this writ and serving the 
same this respondent and the said Naomi Geilday were at their 
residence in said Red Willow County, and in compliance to said 
writ and against their will this respondent and the said Naomi 
Geilday are now before this honorable Court answering the writ in 
this action.</p>

<p>     Therefore and by reason of the foregoing, this 
court has no jurisdiction over the person of this respondent or the 
said Naomi Geilday. </p>

<p>     3rd. This respondent as such guardian duly appointed
is entitled to the care and custody of the said Naomi Geilday. 
The said Naomi Geilday desires to remain and reside with the family
of this respondent and desires that he shall act as her guardian, 
and the said Naomi Geilday has been in no manner restrained of her 
liberty, and her residing with the family of this respondent, and </p>

<pb/>

<p>23-85 IN RE APPLICATION FLORA OHLER FOR WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.</p>

<p></p>






</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>