<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0117.014"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Lelah-Puc-ka-Chee and Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha v. W.G. Malin and G.N. Nellis. Brief and Argument of Petitioners</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0117.014</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Lelah-Puc-ka-Chee and Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha v. W.G. Malin and G.N. Nellis. Brief and Argument of Petitioners</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1899-12">December 1899</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Bridleman</term>
<term>Campbell</term>
<term>Kagma</term>
<term>Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee</term>
<term>Malin, W.G.</term>
<term>McMillun</term>
<term>Nellis, G.N.</term>
<term>Steward, J.O.</term>
<term>Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Iowa</term>
<term>Kansas City</term>
<term>United States</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Malin, W.G.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Nellis, G.N.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Lamb, Jacob W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Shiras, O.P.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court in Northern District Iowa</orgName> 
<placeName>Toledo, Iowa</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019" who="sab">transcribed, encoded.</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0117.014"/> 

<!-- <p>Copied at the National Archives at Kansas City</p> -->

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES IN AND FOR THE NORTHERN DISTRICT OF IOWA</p>
<p>Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee, and )<lb/>
Ta-Ta-Pi-Cha, Plaintiffs )<lb/>
VS<lb/>
W, G, Malin and G,N,)<lb/>
Nellis Defendants</p>

<p>Brief and Argument of Petitioners</p>

<p>In the case of the United States vs Imoda 4 MONT-Page 38 It is held that the relation of the United States to the Indians (Tribal) is that of Guardian and ward, The United States ( PER DEFT Malin) and the Sac and Fox Tribal Indians ( BOTH ADULTS AND Minors) being the wards, Therefore how can a state court have jurisdiction or power to create Malin guardian by letters&amp;&amp; over some of the children of this same tribe, when he already had a power of the same kind and nature from the Federal Government over this entire Tribe,</p>

<p>It has always been the policy of our Federal Government in dealing with and educating the Indians to proceed by <sic>teaty</sic> and consent of the Tribes and also the consent of the parents of the children of such Tribe <sic>togather</sic> with acts of congress in aid thereof and not in conflict therewith, U,S, VS IMODA,4MONT- 38 above, In this case the policy of the U,S, Government is clearly stated,True, the purpose is to civilize and educate them but General Government does not assume to force upon them (the Indians) an education. The fundamental idea is that whatever is done must be by their consent; Even where a Tribe as a Tribe agrees by treaty to send the children of such tribe to school, yet the Government is powerless to enforce attendance. See same case above, Now couple the policy of the U,S, Government as clearly stated in this Imoda case with the acts of the Supliment of the U,S, Revised Statutes VOL-2 NO,s i to 5 1892 to 1895 Pages 248 &amp;428 as to how consent of Parent or next to kin must be made also Statutes of 1878 page 363 sec- 2071 And we have both the policy and the law that must be followed by the Federal government and the U,S, President including his rural agents the defendants herein.</p>
<p>My Esteemed Friend Mr McMillun made the startling assertion that the United States Government Agent and Superintendent (DEFENDANTS HEREIN) had almost unlimited powers over these Indians, but when he shall have carefully examined powers over these Indians, but when he shall have carefully examined the above authorities he will then begin to realize how far local prejudice is likely to carry one really well meaning, when not guarded and protected by a well-read- better legal judgment.</p>
<p>Local and political prejudice caused letters of guardianship to be issued out of the Tama District Court of Iowa to Defendant Malin Over the Petitioner, Lelah-Puc-Ka-Chee, and without law or reason in support thereof, The Indians owe no allegiance to the States and receive no protection from them and therefore jurisdiction over them has ever been and must remain with and in the Federal Government.</p>
<p>United States VS KAGMA 118 U,S, page 375. The want of State court jurisdiction arrises more the fact, that Indians are wards of the Nation than in the territory.</p>
<p>United States VS Campbell. 55N,W, Rep- 553 same in 53 Minn 354. United States VS Bridleman 7Saw,y 243. Ex Parte Cross 3o, N,W, Rep, page 428 same in 20 Neb- page 417. Another good case on this same subject of want of State jurisdiction is found in 43 N,W Rep 602to 606 same case in 76 Mich- 498. being KOBOGUM VS Jackson Iron Co, Indians owe no allegiance to the States and on account of local prejudice the power of the general Government is necessary for their protection On this subject the following are good cases, U,S, Vs KAGAMA 118 U,S 375 &amp; 119 U,S, page 1 5 Dill U,S, 453.</p>
<p>MARRIAGES OF TRIBAL INDIANS BY THEIR TRIBAL LAWS AND USAGES ARE LEGAL AND BINDING IN OUR STATE AND FEDERAL COURTS</p>
<p>44N,W Rep 254 same in 42 Minn 361 Decided in 1890 Earl vs Godley</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
