<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0182.005">
    
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>K. Gregory et al. Type of document</title>
                <principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
                <respStmt>
                    <resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
                    <name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
                    <name n="Bruha, Ashley S" xml:id="asb">Ashley Bruha</name>
                    
                </respStmt>
                <sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
                <sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
            </titleStmt>
            
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>
                    <date>2022</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Produce the Body</authority>
                <publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
                <distributor>
                    <name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </distributor>
                <idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0182.059</idno>
                
                <availability>
                    <licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
                    <p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title level="m" type="main">K. Gregory et al. Civil</title>
                    <date when="1914-01">January 1914</date>
                    <note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
                </bibl>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
                        <collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
                        <idno>2646KGregoryEtAl</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="original" n="category">
                    <term>Case Papers</term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="original" n="type">
                    <term>Civil</term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
                    <term></term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="original" n="term">
                    <term><date when="1914-01">January 1914</date></term>
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
                    <term>Henry White</term>
                    <term>Frank Crosby</term>
                    <term>Clay Allen</term>
                    <term>G.F. Fishburne</term>
                    <term>Parker</term>
                    <term>Kalina</term>
                    <term>K. Gregory</term>
                    <term>M. Aloshin</term>
                    <term>I. Riaboff</term>
                    <term>P. Neanlin</term>
                    <term>I. Erelin</term>
                    <term>L. Orloff</term>
                    <term>G. Yakimoff</term>
                    <term>P. Yakimoff</term>
                    <term>Jeremiah Neterer</term>
                    
                </keywords>
                
                <keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
                    <term>Seattle, Washington</term>
                </keywords>
                
            </textClass>
            
            <particDesc>   
                <listPerson>            
                    <person role="petitioner">
                        <persName>K. Gregory</persName>
                        <persName>M. Aloshin</persName>
                        <persName>I. Riaboff</persName>
                        <persName>P. Neanlin</persName>
                        <persName>I. Erelin</persName>
                        <persName>L. Orloff</persName>
                        <persName>K. Yakimoff</persName>
                        <persName>P. Yakimoff</persName>
                    </person>
                    <person role="defendant">
                        <persName>Henry White</persName>
                    </person>
                    <person role="attorney_petitioner">
                        <persName>Parker</persName>
                        <persName>Kalina</persName>
                    </person>
                    <person role="attorney_defendant">
                        <persName>Clay Allen</persName>
                        <persName>GF Fishburne</persName>
                    </person>
                    <person role="judge">
                        <persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
                    </person>
                </listPerson>
                
                <listOrg>
                    <org>
                        <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
                        <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
                    </org>
                </listOrg>   
            </particDesc> 
        </profileDesc>
        
        <revisionDesc>         
            <change when="2022-02" who="#asb">transcribed and encoded</change>
        </revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>AND FOR A FURTHER AND SEPERATE ANSWER AND RETURN TO SAID APPLICATION FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS,
AND FOR FURTHER RETURN TO SAID WRIT, SAID HENRY M. WHITE ALLEGES AS FOLLOWS:</p>
<p>I.</p>
<p>That the above named petitioners are aliens and are Russians, and arrived on December 19, 1913,
or a few days prior thereto, on the Steamship "Tamba Maru", at the Port of Seattle, King County,
Washington, and made application for admission to the United States.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>That according to the law, they were held for special inquiry by the Immigrant Inspector, and a
Board of Special Inquiry, consisting of T.W. Lynch, J.E. Wilkes and A.T. White, was appointed in the
manner provided by Section 25 of the Immigration Act of February 20th, 1907, and duly convened and
met in the manner provided by the law, on December 23, 1913.</p>
<p>III.</p>
<p>That on December 23, 1913, after a full hearing, (a duplicate report of which appears in the
Immigration files of this cause and is marked "Exhibit A" and made a part of this Return) the Board
decided to reject the aliens on the grounds that they were persons who were likely to become public
charge, for the following reasons:</p>
<p>first: Because they are common or farm laborers and there is no work for them in the United
States.</p>
<p>second: Because they have a limited amount of money, insufficient to maintain them
<pb></pb>
during the winter.</p>
<p>third: Because there are 800-1000 Russians unemployed in Seattle, and thousands of other
nationalities in the same condition, and reports from the Interior are to the effect that the supply
of common labor is far in excess of demand.</p>
<p>fourth: That any addition to the unemployed should be guarded against, and alien laborers should
not be permitted to enter the United States at this time.</p>
<p>For a fuller statement of the reasons for the exclusion of these aliens and their subsequent
detention on this account until they are returned to their native country, we refer to the findings
of the Board of Special Inquiry, set forth in full on the last pages of Exhibition A, refered to
above.</p>
<p>IV.</p>
<p>That the above petitioners and aliens appealed to the Secretary of Commerce and Labor, and the
said Secretary affirmed the decision of the Board of Special Inquiry by a decision rendered solely
upon the evidence adduced before the said Board. That the decision was adverse to the admission of
the said petitioners and aliens and his action, and that of the Board, as above set forth, are
correct and final on this subject.</p>
<p>WHEREFORE said Henry M. White prays the above entitled court that the said writ be dismissed and
the ap-
<pb></pb>
plication and petition therefor be denied.</p>
<p>THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
NORTHERN DIVISION
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>SS.</p>
<p>HENRY M. WHITE, being first duly sworn, upon his oath deposes and says: That he is the party
named in the foregoing answer; that he has read the same, knows the contents thereof and verily
believes the same to be true.</p>
<p>Henry M White</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 16th day of January, 1914.</p>
<p>Ed. <unclear></unclear>
Deputy Clerk, U.S. Dist. Court, Western Dist. of Washington</p>
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>