<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0222.010">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Francis Stephen Medcraf vs. Frank T. Hodge. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0222.010</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Francis Stephen Medcraf vs. Frank T. Hodge. Criminal.</title>
<date></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Emery, George D.</term>
<term>Field</term>
<term>Lamar</term>
<term>Lincoln, Abraham</term>
<term>Marshall</term>
<term>Matthews</term>
<term>Wo, Yick</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>California</term>
<term>San Francisco, California</term>    
<term>Canada</term>
<term>England</term>
<term>France</term>
<term>Greece</term>
<term>London</term>
<term>Michigan</term>
<term>Minnesota</term>
<term>New York</term>
<term>North Carolina</term>  
<term>North Dakota</term>    
<term>Oregon</term>    
<term>South Carolina</term>
<term>Texas</term>
<term>Washington</term>
<term>Wisconsin</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Francis Stephen Medcraf</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Frank T. Hodge</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>George D. Emery</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-04" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN 
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON NORTHERN 
DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN RE. THE APPLICATION OF 
FRANCIS STEPHEN MEDCRAF
FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS.
3038
BRIEF FOR PETITIONER.</p>

<p>MR GEO. D. EMERY, for the Petitioner <del>.</del></p>

<p>THE PETITIONER was charged and conviced before a Justice of the
Peace with the 'crime' of practicing dentistry without a certificate'
contrary to the provisions of the Dental Code of Washington.</p>
<p>Having been committted to prison under this conviction he brings
this proceeding to enquire into the lawfulness of the imprisonment.</p>
<p>He alleges that the statute under which these proceedings were
had and the conviction was entered is void because in conflict with 
the provisions of Section 1 of the Fourteenth Amendment to the U. S.
Constitution, in that he is deprived of his libert and property
without due process of law and that the Act in question den<del>e</del>ys to him
(a person within the jurisdiction of the State) the 'equal protection
of the laws'.</p>
<p>The amendment in question provides,</p>
    <p>"nor shall any state deprive any person of life, liberty or 
    property, without due process of law, nor deny to any person
    within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws."</p>
<p>Sec. 1977 of the Comp. Laws of the U. S. guarantees equal rights
under the law to all 'persons' within the jurisdiction of the States
and under the laws of every state. Such 'persons' shall have the 
right "in every state and territory - - to the full and equal benefit 
of all laws and proceedings for the security of persons and property"</p>
<p>The citizenship of the 'person' is therefore no consequence.</p>
<p>The pledge of 'equal protection of the laws' is a pledge of the 
protection of 'equal' laws. <add>Yien Wo vs. Hopkins 118 U.S. 356</add></p>
<p>THE FIRST DENTAL CODE of Washington is found in Hills Statutes
&amp; Codes of Wash. Sec. 2854 et seq. being the Act of Jany. 1888.</p>
<fw>1</fw>    
<pb/>
<p>It provides;</p>
    <p>"--it shall be unlawful for any person to engage in the 
    practice of dentistry in the state of Washington, unless said 
    person has graduated and received a diploma from the faculty of a 
    dental college charted under the authority of some one of the United
    States or foreign governments, or shall have obtained a certificate
    from <del>some</del> a board of dentists duly authorized and appointed by the
    provisions of this chapter to issue such certificates."</p>
    <p>A board of 5 dentists is provided for to be appointed by 
    the Governor who are to be "practicing dentists" and take an oath
    of office.</p>
    <p>Persons practicing dentistry in the state at the passage of 
    the Act must enroll their names with the Board within 3 months and
    shall thereupon - without examination - receive a certificate as a 
    practitioner of dentistry.</p>
    <p>Any perosn may present to the Board a certificate or diploma
    from any reputable dental college and satisfy the Board of his right
    to the same, and thereupon such person shall be licensed to practice
    dentistry within the state.</p>
    <p>All others desiring to practice dentistry must submit to an 
    examination before the Board and must show the possession of skill in 
    dental surgery 'satisfactory to said Board' , and shall thereupon
    receive such certificate to practice.</p>
<p>IN 1893 this law was amended; The new act provided for</p>
    <p>A slight change in the system of appointments of the Board.</p>
    <p>Examination of those desiring to practice dentistry in the 
    state, prescribing a standard of qualifications and requiring that 
    "no person shall be eligible for such examination unless he or she
    shall be of good moral character and shall present to said board his 
    or her diploma from some dental college in good standing and shall 
    give satisfactory evidence of his or her rightful possession of the 
    same; PROVIDED, That the said Board may admit to examination such 
    other persons of good moral character as shall give satisfactory 
    evidence of having been engaged in the practice of dentistry ten years
    prior to the date of the application for examination."</p>
    <p>All persons authorized to practice under the fomer law and 
    still engaged in practice are to be enrolled and licensed without 
    further examination.</p>
    <p>Students enrolled in a regular dental college and studying 
    in a licensed dentists office in the state are exempted from the
    penal provisions and might practice under their preceptor.</p>
    <p>(N. B. There was then, as now, no 'dental college' in the State
    so the regular attendance thereon required by the act was of no
    value or effect in fact.</p>
<p>IN 1901 this law was materially amended and all its provisions 
inconsistent with the new act were repealed. This act is Chap 152 of 
the Laws of 1901. Section 4 of this act provides;</p>
<p>"Any person or persons seeking to practice dentistry in the State
of Washington, or to own, operate or cause to be operated or run, 
or manage a dental office or place for the practice of dentistry in 
the State of Washington, after the passage of this Act, shall file
his or her name, together with an application for examination, with
<fw>2</fw>
<pb/>
the Secretary of the State Board of Dental Examiners and at the time 
of making such application, shall pay to the Secretary of such Board
a fee of twenty-five dollars and present him or herself at the first
regular meeting thereafter of said Board to under examination 
before that body.</p>
<p>No person shall be eligible for such examination unless he or 
she shall present to said Board his or her diploma from some Dental 
College in good standing and shall give satisfactory evidence of his 
or her rightful possession of the same ; PROVIDED, this section shall 
not apply to persons engaged in the practice of dentistry at the 
time of the passage of this act who are bons fide citizens of the 
State of Washington."</p>

<p>Provision is made for the issue of license or certificate to the
successful applicant and for recording such certificate and the 
practice without such record of dentistry is made penal under fine of 
$50.00 to $200.00 or imprisonment in the County Jail for not more 
than six months.</p>
<p>It appears by the record that the State Board of Dental 
Examiners employed one Conover to go the office of petitioner and secure 
his professional services ot remove two decayed teeth and paid him
therefor. Thereupon Conover - by direction of the Board - filed a 
complaint with the Justice, secured a warrant thereon and the arrest
of petitioner for 'practicing dentistry without having a certificate
of admission to practice recorded with the County Auditor', contrary
to said Act. <add>(State Board prosecuting Core)</add></p>
<p>Upon the trial, petitioner duly raised all the constitutional
questions herepresented by his objections being overruled, the 
evidence was taken. It thereby appeared that the petitioner had served
five years as an apprentice to a competent and reputable dentist in
London, Eng; had continuously thereafter practiced dentistry in the 
employ of competent dentists in England, France and Greece for 8 
years; thereafter continued such practice for himself in London, 
Canada and the United States for 7 years and thereafter in Seattle for 
7 1/2 years, making a continuous practice of 27 1/2 years -including his 
apprent iceship. That he had, before commencing practice in Seattle, 
duly applied to the said Board of Dental Examiners, tendered the fee 
and requested and appeared for examination but such examination was
refused to the ground that the petitioner had no diploma from a dental
college. Whereupon and for that reason a certificate and license 
were refused. His conviction and sentence followed.</p>
<fw>3</fw>
<pb/>
<p>ARGUMENT.</p>

<p>THE POWER OF POLICE REGULATION of the practice of DENTISTRY by the 
State being conceded, it is contended by the Petitioner that this 
Act far transcends the powers of the State in that particular.</p>
<p>It is unreasonable in its provisions; an unnecessary and improper 
restrictino of and infringment upon the rights of the individual to 
practice his profession for his livelihood; unnecessarily deprives
him of property and restrains his liberty, contrary to the constitutional
provision referred to; and constitutes unlawful discrimination, 
and is therefore VOID.</p>

    <p>"In the exercise of the police power in the regulation of 
    business, the legislature may not arbitrarily impose any vexatious 
    burdens upon the pursuit of any of these avocations."</p>
        <p>People vs Steele 14 L.R.E. (NS) 368.</p>
        <p>Kan. City Gas Co. vs Kan. City 198 Fed. 500</p>
        <p>Harmon vs State 66 Oh. St. Rep. 254</p>
    <p>"The public power to regulate railroads and the private right 
    of ownership of such property co-exist; they do not destroy each one
    the other; and where the power to regulate is so arbitrarily 
    exercised as to infringe upon the rights of ownership, the exertion is 
    void because it is repugnant to the due process and equal protection 
    clauses of the Fourteenth Amendment."</p>
        <p>Atlantic Coast Line RR. vs North Car. 206 U.S. 1</p>
    <p>"There is no easier nor more tempting opportunity for the 
    practice of tyranny than in the police control of occupations. Good and
    bad motives often combine to accomplish this kind of tyranny. The 
    zeal of the reformer as well as <del>the</del> cupidity and self interest must
    alike be guarded against. Both are apt to prompt the employment of 
    means to attain an end desired, which the constitution prohibits."</p>
    <p>- - "if the business is not inherently harmful, the prosecution 
    of it cannot rightfully be prohibited to one who will conduct it in 
    a proper and circumspect manner. Such an one would be 'deprived of 
    his liberty without due process of law'."</p>
        <p>Tiedman on Police Powers Sec. 102.</p>
    <p>"Any prohibition which extends further than to prevent the 
    admission of incompetent men, will be unconstitutional."</p>
        <p>Ib. Sec. 87</p>
    <p>"If under the guise of the police power, the legislature 
    unreasonably and capriciously restrains one's liberty or property, the
    Court may interpose the Constitution and declare the law void."</p>
        <p>State vs Smith 33 L. R. A. (NS) 187. (Mo.)</p>
    <p>"A law which unnecessarily and oppressively restrains a citizen
    from engaging in any trafic or disposing of his property as he may
    see fit, though passed under the specious pretext of a preservative
    of the health of the inhabitants, would be void."</p>
        <p>State vs Fisher 52 Mo. 174.</p>
<p>The right to practice one's profession is 'property' of which he may 
not be unnecessarily or arbitrarily deprived.</p>
<fw>4</fw>
<pb/>
<fw>5</fw>    
        <p>State vs. Sachs 2 Wash 373</p>    
<p>The practice of the profession of Dental Surgery of Dentistry is 
a profitable employment, an honorable profession and an important 
one both to the petitioner and to the public. The sole element 
of danger and the sole point at which the police power approaches it 
is in the admission to practice incompetent persons. The health
of the public demands that due precautions be exercised by the state
in admitting to practice dentistry only those who are qualified and 
possess good moral character and the requisite technical skill.</p>
<p>Beyond this the State has no right or power to go. In prescribing
the standard of qualification it must look to the true purpose which 
it is authorized to conserve. It may not, under the pretext of a 
police regulation, create and protect a select and favored class, to 
the exclusion of others equally well qualified to practice the
profession. Wherein does a diploma entitle a man to undergo an 
examination to test his fitness, any more than long years of active and
arduous practice and practical experience under qualified tutors?</p>
<p>Why may the boy or girl fresh from the halls of some Dental 
college, be admitted to display his or her qualifications by examination
while the actual practitioner of 27 years standing, of wide and 
valuable actual practice and experience, is debarred therefrom?</p>
<p>Is such a requirement 'reasonably necessary' to the health of the
inhabitants? Or is it not rather valuable in that it will restrict 
the number of practitioners that may come in from other states to the
possible detriment of the present local practitioners?</p>
<p>It is said that the legislature is the best judge of the necessity 
for the exercise of the police power and the means of accomplishing
that exercise. This may possess some merit but it must not be
carried too far. The moment that the legislature transcends the limit
of 'reasonable and necessary requirement' it comes in conflict
with the Constitutional provision and must fall.</p>
<p>In Eastman vs State 10 N.E. 97 cited by the respondent here, the 
supreme court of Indiana announced the strange doctrine that the 
question of whether the act was reasonable or not was a legislative
<add>5</add>
<pb/>
<fw>6</fw>    
and not a judicial question. Strange assumption. If this were
true, how could the courts ever determine a law to be unconstitutional</p>
<p>The legislature having adopted it, must be presumed to have found
it necessary <add>and reasonable</add>, therefore it is constitutional!</p>
<p>Again and again the Supreme Court of the United States has 
contradicted this doctrine and held that the reasonableness of the law 
and its necessity are for the Court to pass upon and if found 
unreasonable and unnecessary as an exercise of the police power, <del>they are</del> <add>it is</add>
void.</p>
<p>in LAWTON VS STEELE 152 U. S. <del>187</del> <add>133</add> Justice Brown speaking for that
Court said;</p>
    <p>"To justify the state in thus interposing its authority in behalf 
    of the public, it must appear, first, that the interests of the public
    generally, as distinguished from those of a particular class, 
    require such interferance; and, second, that the means are reasonably 
    necessary for the accomplishment of the purpose and not unduly oppressive
    upon individuals; The legislature may not, under the guise of 
    protecting the public interests, arbitrarily interfere with private 
    business, or impose unusual and unnecessarily restrictions upon lawful
    occupations. In other words, its determination at to what is a proper
    exercise of its police powers is not final or conclusive, but is 
    subject to the supervision of the Courts." After citing numerous case
    the court continues;</p>
    <p>"In all these cases the acts were held to be invalid as involving 
    an unnessary invasion of the rights of property adn a practical 
    inhibition of certain occupations, harmless in themselves, and which 
    might be carried on without detriment to the public interest."</p>
        <p>Sanitary Dist. vs. C. &amp; A.R.Co. 108 N.E. 314</p>
    <p>The exercise of the police power must be necessary and its
    methods reasonable in their provisions and must not unnecessarily nor 
    arbitrarily interfere with the inherent rights of the citizen. When
    they go beyond these limits, the are in conflict with the Constitution
    and have no validity.</p>
        <p>State vs Florida E.C. RR. 67 So. 911</p>
        <p>Atlantic C.Line RR vs North Car. 206 U.S. 1</p>
<p>THE OBJECT OF TEH LAW is the protection of the health of the 
inhabitants. To that end, the qualifications of those who assume to 
practice dentistry are material and of importance. Reasonable tests and
regulations to secure the end are lawful and if such interefere with 
the right of the individual to practice, they are still valid. But 
when they go beyond the line of reason or necessity and are no longer
regulative of the practice of the profession but unduly restrict that 
right in a qualified individual, they are prohibited by the Federal 
Constitution.</p>
<fw>6</fw>
<pb/>
<fw>7</fw>
<p>Every citizen has a right to engage in any lawful pursuit.
This is a natural right. The practice of Dentistery could not lawfully
be prohibited by the State nor could it be materially hampered
without great inconvenience and injury to the public. Like the 
practice of law or medicine it is essential to the health and well
being of the people. When the State has taken reasonable and proper
measures to protect the people from imposition and want of skill on
the part of its practitioners, it has fulfilled its duty and exhausted 
its power. It is fitting that practitioners be required to 
possess good moral character and to be skilled in their profession.
Such skill may be attained, in a perfunctory way, by a course in a 
dental college, but without practical experience, the graduate is 
not thoroughly competent to practice. He is only beginning his 
experience. It is idle to compare the skill of a youthful graduate 
just from his college with the ripened experience of the practitioner
of 27 years actual practice of his profession. Why should the one 
be admitted to the test of an examination as to fitness and not the 
other ?</p>
<p>At common law the field of dental practice was open to all. The 
practitioner was held liable in damages for any act or neglect not 
justified by his profession. A system of apprenticeship was 
recognized and became an established custom. This of course was long
before any Dental College was founded. The custom grew into a law
and the greatest dental practictioners of modern times obtained their 
first professional schooling through the apprenticeship to some
dentist. The custom still prevails in almost every state and is 
recognized in our own.There is not and never was a dental college
in this State. How then can an apprentice or student be enrolled
in and attend lectures in such a college and at the same time gain
anything of knowledge from a dental preceptor in this state?</p>
<p>Such a provision of law is meaningless in view of the conditions.</p>
<p>In almost every state there exists an association of dentists
under various names, constituting a state dental society. This 
ystem of societies is bound together by a National organization.</p>
<p>In pursuit of its own purposes, this society has framed and 
pressed to enactment the laws governing the practice of dentistry <add>7</add> 
<pb/>
<fw>8</fw>    
in many of the states, notably in New York, Minneota, Michigan,
Wisconsin, the Carolinas, North Dakota, Oregon, California, and 
Washington.</p>
<p>In the states where such society has secured legislation, the 
requirement of a diploma is made a pre-requisite to an examinatino,
always expecting those in actual practice when such acts were passed</p>
<p>In some of these states the Courts have been led into sustaining
such laws though it is apparent from examination of the decisions
that the c onstitutional question has rarely been raised and
never upon such a state of facts as here exists. Little authority 
is cited to sustain such decisions. The reasons given in support of 
them are unsatisfactory and in many cases the question decided is 
entirely obiter dictum.</p>
<p>An examination of the statutes of all the states shows;
19 states provide for diploma as pre-requisite to examination.</p>
    <p>Arizona, California, Colorado, Florida, Georgia, Iowa,
    Kentucky, Maryland, Michigan, Minnesota, Missouri, New
    York, North Carolina, North Dakota, Oregon, Pennsylvania, 
    Wisconsin, Washington, and Wyoming.</p>
<p>17 states require either a diploma or an examination</p>    
    <p>Arkansas, Alaska, Connecticut, Delaware, Idaho, Illinois,
    Indiana, Kansas, Massachusetts, Mississippi, Montana, 
    Nevada, Nebraska, New Jersey, Ohio, South Dakota and Utah.</p>
<p>30 prescribe a standard of qualification in specified branches
of learning.</p>
<p>18 require an examination "satisfactory to the Board"</p>
<p>A majority of the states providing for both diploma and examination
make some provision whereby the Board of Examiners must consist of 
members of the State Dental Society.</p>
<p>The same states provide, generally, for the admission without 
examination upon the certificates of Dental Boards of such states
as admit their practitioners on like certificates - in other words
a reciprocal law.</p>
<p>The New York law is noticable as an example of the influence of 
this Society. <add>The applicant must have passed 4 years in
a High School and be a graduate of such</add>
school or its equivalent or must have received as a graduate a dental
degree or have pursued a course of dental study and hold a degree
from some dental college or Foerign Country or must have practiced <add>8</add>
<pb/>
<fw>9</fw>    
dentistry for 25 years in some state other than New York.
The State Dental Society is directly recognized and the Board appointed
from its members.</p>
<p>These conditions give much force to the suggestion that the 
laws in question are framed with the design to protect the Dental
Society from competition rather than the public. They rank with
the legislation influenced and secured by Manufacturers, Plumbers,
and dealers generally which ostensibly protect the public yet in 
truth serve more perfectly to foster monoplies and combinations.</p>
<p>It would be perfectly easy to enact laws that would really 
protect the inhabitants from quacks and unskillful practitioners and 
at the same time give to honest and competent dentists the right to 
live and practice their vocation.</p>
<p>The act of 1901 discriminates against apprentices, no matter
how skilful they may have become by years of subsequent practice, 
and requires them to go through a dental college in order to be
entitled to show they q alifications. In other words, they must 
expatriate themselves and take three years of a dental college
course to learn just what they know already, before they can be even 
examined as to their skill and knowledge. To state the case is to 
point its unreason.</p>
<p>OUR OWN SUPREME COURT, in Brown vs State 37 Wash. 105 held this
very act void in part. The act provides that the owner or manager
of a dental office must be a licensed dentist. This portion was
held in conflict with the state constitution. The court said;</p>
    <p>"We feel that a court should be reluctant to pronounce a statute
    invalid, except where its plain duty impels such action,. 
    Conceiving this to be such a case, we are led to declare that part of 
    the statute requiring an examination and license in order to 'own,
    run or manage' a dental office or department, void."</p>
<p>If this part of th e ac t is void, why not the whole act? Can it 
be presumed that the legislature would have passed the rest of the
act, repealing the 'standard' and confining the license privilege to 
graduates only, if it had believed the portion stricken to be void ?</p>
<p>The mutilated act is much less valuable to the public than the 
act which it supplements. The act of 1893 provided a fixed standard 
to which practitioners must conform - a required amount of skill <add>9</add>
<pb/>
<fw>10</fw>
<add>Wash
42 Due 82</add>
which they must possess. This might be shown either by a diploma fr
from some recognized dental college or by an examination upon certain
fixed subjects, constituting a standard , to which all must attain.</p>
<p>In the same decision the court further says;</p>
    <p>"The police power does not justify the witholding from one 
    individual of a natural privilege or right, in order that a corresponding
    advantage may be added to the rights or privileges of another.</p>
    <p>The restriction is permissible only as a preventive of evil results
    reasonably to be expected without such limitation. Russell on 
    Police Power pp 34,35 says; 'To justify the statute in thus interposing 
    its authority, in behalf of the public, it must appear, first, that
    the interests of the public generally as distinguished from those of
    a particular class, require such interferance, and second, that the 
    means are reasonably necessary for the accomplishment of the 
    purpose, and not unduly oppressive upon individuals.' "</p>
<p>The true te st of those who assume to practice dentistry must
necessarily be, not the mere possession of a diploma from some 
college, but the "possession of the actual technical skill and knowledge
peculiar to the study and practice of dentistry".</p>
<p>It may be proper to provide that the possession of such diploma 
shall be competent evidence of the possession of such skill but it 
is manifestly unfair and oppressive to exclude those who possess 
this skill, gained from experience and practice and without having 
procured a diploma. It is the 'skill and knowledge' which protects 
the public - not the diploma. It is common knowledge that there 
are many competent dentists in this country who have obtained their 
skill and knowledge from long study and practice in some dentists
office and who never passed through a dental collece. The practice
of apprenticeship prevails in this as in most foreign countries.</p>
<p>Shall all such be excluded from practice - nay, even from examination
as to their fitness? Must they go to a dental college to 
learn that which they already know ?</p>
<p>Again in State vs Clausen 65 Wash. 178, the supreme court of 
this state referring to the police power says;</p>
    <p>It is not meant to be asserted that this power is above the 
    Constitution, or that everything done in the name of the Police power is
    lawfully done. It is meant only to be asserted that a law which
    interferes with personal liberty and property rights is valid only
    when it tends reasonably to correct some existing evil or promote
    some interest of the state, and is not in violation of any direct
    and positive mandate of the Constitution. The clause of the 
    Constitution now under consideration was intended to prevent the arbitrary
    exercise of power, or undue, unjust and capricious interferances
    with personal rights; not to prevent those reasonable regulations
    that all must submit to as a condition of remaining a member of <add>10</add>
<pb/>    
<fw>11.</fw>    
    society. In other words, the test of a police regulation, when 
    measured by this <del>case</del> clause of the constitution is reasonableness as 
    constra distinguished from arbitrary or capricious action."</p>
<p>Measured by this test, does not this statute violate the 
constitutional provision ? Why exclude the large class of competent
apprentice-made dentists for the sole benefit of the college 
graduates who are even far less competent in point of fact ?</p>
<p>Is it reasonable to exclude the large class of dentists who gained
their skill and knowledge without the aid of a college education ?</p>
<p>Do petitioners 27 1/2 years of apprenticeship and active practice count 
for nothing ? Is it reasonable to forbid him to demonstrate to the 
Board his competency, to exhibit his knowledge and skill, because 
he did not obtain them at some dental college ? Or because he did
not live in the state at the time of the passage of the act?</p>
<p>In State vs Thompson 48 Wash. 291-3 the supreme court of this
state has declared in favor of the constitutionality of this act.</p>
<p>While this is not binding upon this court it is cited by the 
respondent in support of the conviction. The case is not a persuasive
one. The argument seems to beg the question. It is said;</p>
    <p>" The statute makes the same requirements of all applicants for 
    examination. No favored or preferred classes are created or 
    recognized. The requirement of both diploma and examination as a test of
    knowledge and skill is not such an unreasonable or arbitrary one 
    as to invalidate the statute. The right to determine what requirements
    must be met by an applicant is within the exclusive province
    of the legislature."</p>
<p>The above statements are peculiar in view of the admitted facts 
here. The statute does create and recognize a favored class, viz;
graduates of dental colleges. It discriminates against those who 
are otherwise competent but have no diploma. It ignores or rather
denies the rights of the men who have come up the long hard way of 
practical experience. The requirement of both diploma and examination
is not a reasonable but is an unreasonable and an arbitrary 
requirement. The right'to determine what requirements must be met
by the applicants' is qualified by the Constitutional provision and 
the legislature has no power to overstep its limitations. The 
requirements must be reasonable and necessary to the ends designed.</p>
<p>If the language of the decision is to be taken as its sense it
<add>11</add>
<pb/>
<fw>12</fw>
means that the legislature is the ultimate judge of the reasonableness 
of its requirements. It distinctly overrides the declaration
of the supreme court of the United States in the many cases cited.</p>
<p>If that were true, the constitutional provision would have no 
force. The legislature says it is reasonable - the constitution to 
the contrary and there is no power to overrule that decision ?</p>
<p>Such is not the law. Of what force are constitutions if they 
can be thus ignored or overridden?</p>
    <p>Chief Justice Marshall long ago declared "The powers of the 
    legislature are defined and limited, and that those limites may not
    be mistaken, or forgotten, the Constitution is written. To what
    purpose are powers limited, and to what purpose is that limitation
    committed to writing if those limits may atany time be passed by
    those intended to be restrained? The distinction between government 
    with limited and unlimited powers is abolished if those limits do not 
    confine the persons on whom they are imposed and if acts forbidden
    and acts allowed are of equal obligation."</p>
        <p>Marbury vs Madison 1 Cranch 137. (2 L.D. 60)</p>
<p>The Washington case is based on the decision of the California court
in Ex Parte Whitely 77 Pac. 879, and that in turn upon Dent vs West
Virginia 129 U. S. 124. (32 L.D. 623). Examination of the latter 
case will show that the court was passing upon a very different
statute. The West Virginia Act provided that license should be
issued to three distinct classes of persons;</p>
<p>1.- Those possessing diplomas from some dental college,</p>
<p>2.- Those who had resided and practiced in the state for ten years,</p>
<p>3.- Those who passed a satisfactory examination.</p>
<p>The possession of a diploma was one ground for the issue of a 
license without examination; The fact of having practiced for ten years 
in the state prior to the passage of the act, was a second ground,
and the possession of the requisite skill and knowledge as shown by
a satisfactory examination was a third ground. Under such a law,
no competent person was excluded. Here, no matter how skilled or 
wise the applicant may be, no matter how long he has practiced or 
what wide experience he may possess, it all falls to nothing before 
the right of the college graduate of 21 summers who possesses a 
diploma of graduation from some Dental College.</p>
<p>Not a single case can be found in the books which bases its 
support of such a law as we are here considering upon any stable or 
<add>12</add>
<fw>13</fw>
satisfactory reason. None that cites a well reasonaed and supporting
authority. We have examined with care the many cases cited by 
respondent here and none of them satisfies the reason or appeals to 
competent supporting authority. In fact, many of them are directly
in support of our contentions.</p>
<p>The two cases which support respondents contention most directly
are the Thompson case in this state and the Vandersluis case in
43 Minnesota. The latter case, like the former, simply begs the 
question and substitutes assertion for argument. It cites no 
supporting authority. Gothard vs People 15 pac. is like it in its
want of argument or authority for its support. State Rl.Crandall vs
Mc Intosh 103 S.W. is a Missouri case and the point is entirely
obiter. People vs Griswold, the recent N.Y. case, refers to the 
Smith case recently decided by the U.S. Supreme court but wholly 
ignores its argument and authority. It is exactly contrary to the
Smith case and is entitled to no consideration here.</p>
<p>In short, the only decisions that are at all in support of the
respondents contentions are those of state courts passing upon their
own statutes. The tendency of such courts is to sustain their own
statutes. It was to correct that vice the Supreme Court of the 
United States was given jurisdiction in all cases under the Federal 
constitution and acts.</p>
<p>The clause of the Constitution in question is the most vital
in the whole document. It was the answer of the people to the 
fallacious doctrine of State Rights. It cost hundreds of thousands
of lives and millions of money to write it into the Constitution
and it has received more consideration from the Supreme Court than
any other clause of that important document.</p>
<p>A brief review of <add>some of</add> those decisions may be of value.</p>
<p>Yick Wo vs Hopkins 118 U. S. 356 is a leading case upon this 
phase of the amendment. An ordinance of San Francisco prescribed
certain regulations for the construction of laundries and required
all to conform to them and further to obtain a license from the
board of supervisors, which license might be refused in the discretion
of the board. After complying with the requirements as to 
construction and having been denied a license such as denial being based <add>13</add>
<fw>13</fw>
upon the will or discretion of the Board, Yick Wo was convicted of 
violating the ordinance and in reviewing the matter the Supreme 
Court of the United States, speaking by Mr. Justice Matthews, said;</p>
    <p>"The fourteenth amendment is not confined to citizens. It says,
    'nor shall any state deprive any person of life, liberty of property
    without due process of law; nor deny to any person within its 
    jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws'. These provisions are 
    universal in their application , to all persons within the territorial
    jurisdiction, without regard to any difference of race, or color or
    of nationality; and the equal protection of the laws is a pledge of 
    the protection of EQUAL LAWS.</p>
<p>The ordinance is then held to be unjustly discriminatory and void.
The case is elementary and instructive.</p>
<p>In LOCHNER VS NEW YORK 198 U. S. 52 the question arose upon the 
statute of the state forbidding that any employee should be required
or permitted to work more than 60 hours in one week. It was 
held that this statute conflicted with the fourteenth amendment and
was void, the court saying;</p>
    <p>"The general right of the individual to make a contract in 
    relation to his business is part of the liberty protected by the 14th 
    amendment of the Federal Constitution. Under that provision no 
    state can deprive any person of life, liberty or property without
    due process of law. - - Both property and liberty are held on such
    reasonable <del>terms</del> conditi ons as may be imposed by the governing
    powers, and with such conditions the 14th amendment was designed not 
    fore, where legislation of this character is concerned, and where
    the protection of the Federal constitution is sought, the question
    necesaarily arises; Is this a fair, reasonable and appropriate 
    exercise of the police power of the state, or is it an unreasonable,
    unnecessary and arbitrary interferance with the right of the 
    individual to his personal liberty or to enter into those contracts in
    relation to labor which seem appropriate to him or necessary for the 
    support of himself and family> - - Is it within the police power
    of the state? That question must be answered by the courts.</p>
    <p>The purpose of the statute must be determined from the natural and
    legal effect of the language employed. and whether it is or is not 
    repugnant ot the constitution of the United States must be determined
    from the natural effect of such statutes when put in operation..
    The court looks beyond the mere letter of the law in such cases."</p>
<p>In Toledo W. &amp; W. Ry. vs Jacksonville 67 Ill. 40 , (cited with
approval in the Virginia Supreme Court in State vs Goodwill 6 L. R.
A. 622 it is said;</p>
<p>"It is not within the power of the legislature, under the pretense 
of exercising the police powers of the state, to enact laws not 
necessary to the health and safety of the community, that will be 
oppressive and burdensome upon the citizen."</p>
<p>In State vs Goodwill 6 L.R.A. 622, the court says;</p>
<p>"The rights of every individual must stand or fall by the same
rule of law that governs every other member of the body politic
under similar circumstances; and eveey partial or private law which 
directly proposes to destroy or effect individual rights, or does 
the same thing by restricting the privileges of certain classes of 
citizens and not of others when there is no public necessity for such 
discrimination, is unconstitutional and void."</p>
<p>S;aughter House Cases 16 Wall. 36
<add>14</add></p>
<pb/>
<p>14</p>    
        <p>Butchers Union etc. vs Crescent City 111 U.S. 746</p>
<p>"Generally it is for the legislature to determine what laws and
regulations are proper , in the exercise of the police power, but 
if it passes an act, ostensibly for the public health, and thereby
destroys or takes away the property of a citizen, or interferes with 
his rights or personal liberty, then it is for the courts to determine
whether it is a proper and reasonable exercise of the power and 
if not, to declare it void. - -"</p>
<p>The rule pointing to the true test of such laws is well stated
by Justice Field in Hing vs Crowley 113 U. S. 703. viz;</p>
    <p>"The discriminations which are open to pbjection are those where 
    persons engaged in the same business are subjected to different
    restrictions or are held to different privileges under the same 
    conditions,; it is only then that the discrinination can be said to 
    impair that equal right which all can claim in the enforcement of 
    the laws."</p>
        <p>BARBIER VS CONNOLLY 113 U. S.27 reasserts these principles.</p>
    <p>" The 14th amendment - - undoubtedly intended , not only that
    there should be no arbitrary deprivation of life, liberty or 
    property, but that equal protection and security should be given to all
    under like circumstances in the enjoyment of their personal and civil
    rights; that all persons should be equally entitled to pursue their 
    happiness and acquire and enjoy property; - - that no impediment
    should be imposed to the pursuits of anyone except as applied to 
    the same pursuits by others under like circumstances; that no greater
    burdens should be laid upon ine, than are laid upon others in the 
    same calling and condition."</p>
    <p>HENNINGTON VS STATE OF GEORGIA 163 U.S. 300.</p>
    <p>"The well setted rule is, that if a statute purporting to
    have been enacted to protectthe public health, the public morals or 
    the publicsafety HAS NO REAL OR SUBSTANTIAL RELATION TO THOSE
    OBJECTS or is a palpable invasion of rights secured by fundamental 
    law it is the duty of the court to so adjudge and thereby give effect 
    to the Constitution." Mugler vs Kansas 123 U.S. 623. Minnesota
    vs Barber 136 U.S. 313</p>
    <p>RAICH VS TRUAX et al. 219 Fed. 273 seems to be in point;</p>
    <p>The state act forbade the employer of labor to employ less 
        than 80 % of qualified electors in his work. The requirement also
    extended to native-born citizens as being the 'qualified' ones to be
    selected.</p>
        <p>Judges Morrow, Van Fleet and Sawtelle held;</p>
    <p>"We think the act in question denies to complainant the equal
    protection of the laws, and is therefore in violation of the 14th 
    amendment to the Constitution of the U.S. and is void."</p>
<p>Quoting from the decision of the U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals
in Tiburcio vs. Parrott, the court said,</p>
<p>"In our country hostile and discriminating legislation by a state
against persons of any class - - - in whatever form it may be 
expressed, is forbidden by the 14th amendment of the Constitution."</p>
        <p>In re Ah Chong (C.C.) 2 Fed. 733</p>
<p><add>15</add></p>
<pb/>
<fw>15</fw>
<p>The citation of Federal cases construing this amendment might be 
prolonged indefinitely, but they are all to the same end.</p>
<p>The state courts have often given effect to this amendment.</p>
<p>State vs Smith 33 L. R. A. (NS) 187 thus;</p>
    <p>"If, under the guise of the police power, the legislature
    unreasonably and capriciously restrains one's liberty or property, the
    Court may interpose the Constitution and declare the law void."</p>
<p>State vs Fisher 52 Mo. 174;</p>
    <p>"A law which unnecessarily and oppressively restrains a 
    citizen from engaging in any trafic or disposing of his property 
    as he may see fit, though passed under the specious pretext of a 
    preservative of the health of the inhabitants, would be void."</p>
<p>State vs Harmon 66 Ohio St. Rep. <add>254.</add></p>
    <p>A law which provided for the issue of licenses to 
    engineers upon examination, limiting the right to same to a certain 3
    year class and excluding all others, was held void.</p>
<p>The case of KANSAS CITY GAS CO. VS KANSAS CITY 198 Fed. 500 is 
a most instructive case and a great number of authorities are cited 
and discussed.</p>
<p>STATE OF NEW HAMPSHIRE VS PENNOYER 5 L.R.A. 709 is a case in 
point and frequently cited in other decisions.</p>
<p>The statute there in question provided for the issue of licenses
to practice medicine to those who should;</p>
    <p>(a) Pass a satisfactory examination. or</p>
    <p>(b) present a diploma from some medical school etc.</p>
<p>Those passing an examination to pay a fee of $5.00 while those
presenting a diploma paid a fee of $1.00.?Practice contrary to those
provisions was made penal. BUT</p>
<p>The provisions of the preceeding section (penal) shall not 
apply to persons who have resided and practices their profession in
the town or city of their present residence during all the time
since January 1st 1875." The act was passed in January 1879.</p>
<p>Washington Act.</p>
<p>Persons who are engaged in the 
practise of dentistry at the time
of the passage of this act, wh o 
are bona fide citizens of the
state of Washington, are 
exempt from the penalties of 
this Act.</p>
<p>New Hampshire Act.</p>
<p>All physicians except those who 
practised all the time between
Jan. 1st, 1875 and Jan. 1st 1879
and during that period did not 
remove from one town to another
are subject to the penalty.</p>
<p>The Court said;</p>
<p>"The law cannot discriminate in favor of one citizen to the 
detriment of another. the principle of equality pervades the entire 
Constitution. The Bill of Rights declares expressly that all 
government is instituted for the general good, for the common benefit
protection and security of the whole community, and not for the <add>16</add>
<pb/>
<fw>16</fw>
interests or emolument of any one man, family or class of men; that
every member of the community has a right to be protected by it in
the enjoyment of his life, liberty and property. x x x No one citizen
or class of citizens can by law be charged with the performance of 
duties or be subjected to burdens not by law made incumbent upon all
other citizens in the same circumstances. (Missouri vs Lewis 101 U.
S. 22; Barber vs Connolly 113 U.S. 31; Yick Wo. vs Hopkins 118 U.S.
356? )(The objection is that) 'of those physicians who are declared by 
statute, or under its provisions, are found, qualified to practice,
some are and some are not subjected to the burden of obtaining a 
license. Exemption from that burden is made to depend, not on integrity,
education and medical skill, but upon a continuous dwelling
in one place for (at)a certain time . It is arbitrary discrimination
permitting some and forbidding others to carry on their 
business without regard to their competency or to any material difference 
in their situation. The test is not merit but unchanged 
residence. For the right to continue the pursuit of his profession one 
physician isnot while another,his neighbor, who may be his equal or 
superior in learning, experience and ability, is,required ot pay 
$5.00. This is not the equality of the Constitution. The magnitude
of the unequal burden is immaterial. If any inequality is 
permitted the discrimination might be made prohibitory and a monopoly
of business given to physicians who have resided in a town or city
for a specified time." State vs Express Co. 60 N.H. 219</p>
        <p>State vs Hinman 18 Atl. 194.</p>
<p>CHICAGO M &amp; ST P RV VS WESTBY 47 L.R.A.(NS) 97 is closely in
point. The law of the state imposed certain burdens upon 
commoncarriers, in respect to negligence, not imposed upon other employers
under like circumstances. The U. S. C. C. A. per Judge Sanborn, 
exhaustively reviews the authorities and lays down the rule governing
the right of classification as attempted by the legislature.</p>
<p>""There must be such a difference between the situation and 
circumstances of all members of the class and the situation and
circumstances of all other members of the state in relation to the 
subjects of the discriminatory legislation as presents a just, natural
reason for the difference made in their liabilities and burdens, and
in their rights and privileges.</p>
<p>"All who are in a situation and circumstances relative to the 
subjects of the discriminatory regulation indistinguishable from
those members of the class must be brought under the influence of the
law and treated by it in the same way as are the members of the
class."</p>
<p>"But the members of these classes may not be selected arbitrarily 
without just or sound reason inherent in their respective situations
and circumstances relative to the subject matter of the legislation
for the difference in the burdens imposed and privileges conferred
upon them by such discriminatory law."</p>
<p>"While reasonable classification is permitted, without doing
violence to the equal protection of the law, such classification
must be based upon some real and substantial distinction, bearing a 
reasonable and just relation to the things in respect to which such
classification is imposed; and classification cannot be arbitrarily 
made without any substantial basis. Arbitrary selection cannot be 
made by calling it classification."</p> 
    <p>BONNETT VS VALLIER 17 L.R.A. (NS) 491, a Wisconsin case is 
    ably presented by Justice Marshall, one of the brightest legal minds
    of the present era.</p>
    <p>" There must  be reasonable ground for police interferance and also
    the means adopted must be reasonably necessary for the accomplishment
    of the purposes in view." <add>17</add></p>
<pb/>
<p>WYETH VS THOMAS 23 L.R.A. (NS) 147, is a case where the act 
in question required all persona applying for license as undertaker
to have taken a regular couse of embalming in some recognized 
school etc. the court held the law violative of the constitution as 
unreasonable and an unnecessary interferance with the rights of the 
individual.</p>
<p>"The right to enjoy life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness is 
secured to everyone under the constitution of Massachusetts. This 
includes the right to pursue any proper vocation to obtain a 
livelihood. Substantially the same right is secured also by the 
Constitution of the United States which does not permit any state to 
deprive any person of life, liberty or property without due process 
of law. The nature of this right has been stated and illustrated in
many cases. (Citing) There is not doubt that the refusal to permit 
anyone to engage in the busiess of an undertaker is a violation of
this right, unless there is some good reason for the refusal."</p>
    <p>PEOPLE VS SCHENCK 44 L. R. A. (NS) 48 is also in point.</p>
    <p>CONNOLLY VS UNION SEWER PIPE CO. 184 U. S. 554 likewise sustains 
    the principles we contend for.</p>

<p>But ehe case of SMITH VS TEXAS 233 U. S. 630 is the case which 
we insist is most closely analagous to and controls the case at bar.</p>
<p>The state of Texas had passed a statute requiring that no person
should be appointed Conductor of a freight train unless he had 
previously served two years a brakeman on a freight train. An engineer
who had also served a a passenger conductor, was so appointed and 
on arrest and conviction for violation of this statute, the case was 
reviewed by the Supreme Court of the United States. The case is 
exhaustively briefed and is the very latest pronouncement upon the
question at bar and from a controlling authority. It readily 
appears that the highest court in the land has become more and more
alive to the necessity of opposing the tendency to legislate for the
benefit of particular classes and to circumscribe with the 
constitutional provision the acts of the states in alleged exercise of 
their police power. Justice Lamar says;</p>
<p>Life, liberty and property and the equal protection of the law, 
grouped together in the constitution, are so related that the 
deprivation of any one of those separate and independent rights may lessen
or extinguish the value of the other three. In so far as a man is
deprived of his right to labor, his liberty is restricted, his 
capacity to earn wages and acquire property is lessened and he is denied
the protection of the law afforded to those who are permitted to 
work. Liberty means more than freedom from servitude,and the 
constitutional guaranty is an assurance that the citizen shall be protected
in the right to use his powers of mind and body in any lawful <add>18</add>
<pb/>
<fw>18</fw>
calling. - - If the service is public, the state may prescribe 
qualifications and require an examination to test the fitness of 
any person to engage in or remain in the public service. - - - 
tests and prohibition should be enacted with reference to that 
object , and so as not unduly to interfere with private business or 
impose unusual and unnecessary restrictions upon lawful occupations.
Lawton vs Steele 152 U.S. 137. - - The necessity of avoiding the 
fixing of arbitrary tests by which competent persons would be excluded
from lawful employment, is also recognized in Smith vs Alabama
124 U.S. 465-480 - - The liberty of contract is, of course, not 
unlimited; but there is no reason or authority for the proposition
that conditions may be imposed by statute which will admit some who 
are competent and arbitrarily exclude others who are equally 
competent and arbitrarily exclude others who are equally 
competent to labor on terms mutually satisfactory to employer and 
employee. None of the cases sustains the proposition that under the 
power to secure public safety, a privileged class can be created and
be then given a monopoly of the right to work in a special or 
favored position. Such a statute would shut the door , without a hearing
upon many persons and classes of persons who were competent to serve
and would deprive them of the liberty to work in a calling they were 
qualified to fill with safety to the public and benefit to themselves."</p>
<p>This case se ems to clearly and fully in every principle sustain
our contentions.</p>
<p>Not only is it ably reasoned, but it is considering a law 
enacted in pursuance of the same police power and prescribing equally 
unnecessary tests and excluding equally competent persons by reason
of its provisions from earning their daily bread by their lawful 
calling.</p>
<p>Numerous cases could be added wherein the same principles have 
been enunciated but enough have been cited to show the clear and
established trend of authority in the highest court of the land and 
wherever the same subject has received the consideration of thoughtful
minds.</p>
<p>To say that the boy or girl who is fresh from the dental college
of some otherstate shall have privileges of examination not granted
to well qualified men of long practice and acquired learning in the
profession, is to deny to the latter the protection of equal laws.</p>
<p>It is unjust and unlawful discrimination. It does not tend to 
nor even remotely benefit the public, but is a bane rather than a 
blessing. Who would employ the youthful graduate in preference to 
the dentise of 27 years experience, fully equipped with <add>the</add> learning of 
years and up to the standards of the day?</p>
<p>Petitioner has acquired his skill and knowledge by the way 
recognized for centuries as the proper and only way to the top of his 
<add>19</add>
<pb/>
<fw>19</fw>
profession. By that profession he must maintain himself and his 
family. What public necessity is there which requires that he and
othres of his class must now waste years of time in passing through
a dental college to get a diploma in order to entitle him and them to
show to a competent Board that they know the details and requirements
of their profession? There was no public outcry for such a 
law. It repealed a better law than it presents to the state. If its
design was to regulate the 'owning and managing' of dental offices
it fell wide of the mark.? It repealed the fixed standard to which 
applicants were required to comply and substituted a 'satisfactory' 
and hence an arbitrary examination - the opinion of an arbitrary 
body - as such standard. It was too evidently enacted in the 
interest of the established dentists and not of the general public and
it should be held void.</p>
<p>Of the jurisdiction of this court there can be no question.</p>
    <p>Ex Parte Siebold 100 U. S. 371 404</p>
    <p>Royal vs Royal 117 U.S. 241</p>
    <p>In Re Albert White 43 Fed. 913</p>

<p>We submit that the language of Tiedman on Police Power quoted
early in this argument, is most appropriate to this case</p>
<p>"Any prohibition which extends further than to prevent the 
admission of incompetent persons, will be unconstitutional".</p>
<p>If a college education is to be made the sole test of the right 
to an examination for fitness, in dentistry, why not in law? or in
any of the other professions? Is the college graduate to be placed
upon a pedestal in an exalted class by himself and granted privileges 
denied to the man of years who has attained far greater skill and
knowledge by the arduous pathway of experience?</p>
<p>Abraham Lincoln, by such a test, would have been debarred from 
practice. John Marshall would never have been a justice of the
Supreme Court. Many a man who is or has been a shining light in 
the fields of law, medicine and dentistry would have been excluded
in favor of the adolescent graduate with his diploma.</p>
<p>It is not the diploma but the knowledge and skill which it 
evidences which protects the public. He who has that knowledge and
skill, no matter how or where acquired, is equally entitled to the <add>20</add>
<pb/>
<fw>20</fw>
protection of the law in the pursuit of his chosen avocation.</p>
<p>To deny him is to refuse him that equal and exact justice which 
it was the aim and purpose of the Constitution to secure.</p>
<p>Respectfully sumitted</p>
<ab>Geo. D. Emery
Atty. for Petitioner.
419 Central Build'g
Seattle.</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>