<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0447.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>William Warden v. John H. McGraw. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Ham, Bethany R." xml:id="brh">Bethany R. Ham</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0447.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">William Warden v. John H. McGraw. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1889-05-27">1891</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives</repository>
<collection>King Frontier Justice</collection>
<idno>Case No 6866</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1889-05">May 1889</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Lee, Frank P.</term>
<term>Johnson, W. H.</term>
<term>Thornton, H. J.</term>
<term>Rivers, C. M.</term>
<term>Campbell, Jas.</term>

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Warden, William</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>McGraw, John H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, Cornelius H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>King County</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-06" who="#brh">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0447.001"/>

<p>
FILE
No. 6866
</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>
Territory of Washington
County of King                      ss
    In the District Court of the Third Judicial District holding terms at Seattle.

In the matter of the applicationof, 
William Warden,
    For a writ of Habeas Corpus.

    To the Hon. C. H. Hanford Judge of the District court for the Third Judicial district of Washington Territory. Your petitioner William Warden respectfully shows:
</p>
<p>
That he is unlawfully imprisoned,, detained confined and restrained of his liberty by John McGraw, sheriff of King County and Territory of Washington W H Johnson jailor of the Counry of King and Territory of Washington and H. J. Thornton Constable of Seattle. precinct in the City of Seattle County of King and Territory of Washington in the County Jail of King County Washington Territory:
That the imprisonment, detention, confinement and restraint is illegal and that the illegality thereof consists of this to-wit: 
    That only pretext or cause of such detention and arrest <add>was a warrant</add> issued out of a Justice's Court of said County upon a complaint charging your petitioner with the crime of robbery and <add>that he</add> is a fugitive from Justice, upon the complaint of one Jas. Campbell.
    That therefore said Justice issued out of said Court a warrant requiring the arrest of this petitioner upon said charge. That said warrant was delivered to one H. J. Thornton constable of said County and that he by virtue of the same arrested this petitioner and yet holds him in his custody in the County jail of King County Terr. of Washington:
</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>
Your petitioner would further state, that prior to the issuance of said warrant he was arrested byb the City Authorities of thr City of Seattle County of King and Territory of Washington upon the same charge and that your petitioner petition<add>ed</add> this honorable court for a writ of Habeas Corpus which application was <del>held</del> <add>heard</add> on its merits by this said court and your petitioner herein dischzrged.
    That your petitioner upon said complaint apeared before C. M. Rivers the Justice of the Peace before whom said warrant was issued and upon whom the examinatiin of the crime in the said warrant, w contained was triable and that there and then demanded an examination by virtue of Chapter (79) seventy nine page 187 of the Code of Washington Territory:
    Your petitioner would further state that the warrant upon which thisarrest, imprison<add>m</add>ent, detention and confinement and restraint are based was in the possession of the said office in the petition named whe<add>re</add> te former application and Writ were heard and acted upon and that then and there said ofcicers were present with this said warrant <del>and</del> then in their possession and failed and refused to produce the same and de ied its existence when called upon to produce the same by this court: That the Justice before whom this cause was brought failed and refused to hear this said cause and grant your petitioner herein a speedy and proper investigation herein under section 974 of the C de of Was<add>h</add>inton: That your petitioner is not guilty of the said charge preferred against him in the said warrant and that no additional evidence other than complainant can be produced as to your petitioners guilt.
    Wherefore, your petitioner prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus may be granted, directed to John H McGraw sheriff of King County Wasnington Terr. and W. H. Johnson Jailor of King Co. W. T 
</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>
<add>and H. J. Thornton</add> constable of Seattle precinct of Seattle King Co. Washington Terr., com anding <add>T</add>h<add>e</add>m to have the body of your etitioner before you<add>r Hon Court</add> together with the complaitant in the said warrant of arrest and all other witnesses under the sec ion 974.

    To do and receive What shall then and there be considered by your honor concer ing him and that your petitioner may be restored to his liberty. 
    William Warden
Dated May 27th. 1889.
Territory of Washington
County of King              ss

    William Warden being duly sworn deposes and says, that he isthe petitioner named in the foregoing petition subscribed by him that he has heard the foregoing petition read, and that the statements therein made he beleives to be true. 
    William Warden
Subscribed and sworn to before me this 27th day of May 1889.
    I Frank P. Lee
Notary Public.
in and for Washington Territory
</p>
<pb></pb>

<p>
Let a writ of Habeas Corpus issue as prayed, 
Dated at Seattle W. T.               C. H. Hanford Judge
May 27th 1889.
</p>



</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>