<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0177.002.xml">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">February 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Baljo, Jack</term>
<term>Bajlo, Tonka</term>
<term>Cushman, Edward E.</term>
<term>DeBruler, Ellis</term>

</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Tonka Bajlo</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Edward E. Cushman</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
<del>SOUTHERN</del> <add>Northern</add> Division.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Tonka Bajlo for the Writ of 
Habeas Corpus. ) 2459
No. 1328.</p>

<p>RETURN TO ORDERS TO SHOW CAUSE
AND ANSWER TO PETITION.</p>

<p>To Honorable Edward E. Cushman, Judge of the Above entitled
Court: - </p>
<p>Comes now Ellis DeBruler, Commissioner of Immigration
at Seattle, Washington, adn for return to the Order to Show 
Cause herein filed April 16, 1913, shows to the Court that
he has not at any time failed to safely keep the said Tonka
Bajlo since the date of her original arrest, and that no
order of this court has ever issued requiring him to safely
keep the said Tonka Bajlo a prisoner; and for return to the
Order to Show Cause issued herein on April 17, 1913, and for 
answer to the Petition filed herein, states as follows:</p>
<p>- I -
Said Ellis DeBruler denies that the said Tonka Bajlo
is confined in violation of the Constitution of the United
States; that she was compelled to testify against herself 
upon a criminal charge; also denies that she had no opportunity
to present evidence on her behalf, and denies that
she was ordered deported upon a criminal charge. He further
denies that she did not understand the nature of the proceeding
against her, and that she made any deman for counsel
<pb/>
until after the matter had been closed upon a fair, proper and regular hearing.</p>
<p>- II -
Said Ellis DeBruler further denies teh charges against 
against said Tonka Bajlo are without foundation of law or
fact, and that any order for her deportation was made without
an opportunity for her to have proper legal hearing.</p>
<p>- III -
Said Ellis DeBruler alleges that the said Tonka Baljo
is detained by virtue of the final ruling of a competent 
tribunal, to-wit: The Secretary of Labor of the United 
States, and denies that she is restrained of her liberty by 
reason of any false charges against her. The said Ellis
DeBruler further alleges that he has no knowledge or information
sufficient to for a believe, and therefore denies that
the charges made against her by Jack Bajlo, her husband, 
were for the purpose of wreaking vengeance upon her, the said
Tonka Baljo.</p>
<p>And for a further and separate answer and return to 
said Order to Show Cause, and said Application for a Writ
of Habeas Corpus, said Ellis DeBruler, alleges that on or
about the 7th day of April, 1913, said Tonka Baljo was 
arrested by one Thomas M. Fisher, Inspector of Immigration,
stationed at Seattle, Washington, under authority of the
Department of Labor of the United States in violation of the 
Act of Congress approved February 20, 1907, and amended by
the Act of March 26, 1910, to-wit: That she was an alien
found practicing prostitution after her entry into the 
United States, and as such, liable to deportation in the
<pb/>
<fw>(2)</fw>
</p>









</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>