<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Ibrahim, Meyri" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.1183.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-01" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

 <head> In the United States Circuit Court of the Ninth Circuit
In and for the Western district of Washington
Northern Division.

In the Matter of the Petition of
Earnest Hutchinson
for Writ of Habeas Corpus. </head>

<p> To the Honorable C.H. Hanford, Judge.
The petition of Earnest Hutchinson respectfully represents to your honor. </p>

<p> -I- 
That your petitioner is a citizen of the United States and
of the State of Michigan and a member of the firm doing business
in the state of Washington under the firm name and style of 
"National Stamp Company", having their domicile and principal
place of business in the city of Ypsilanti, in the said state
of Michigan. </p>

<p> -II-
That said company is engaged in business in the cities of
Tacoma, Seattle, Everett and other place in the state of
washington; and that said business consists of general merchadising,
advertising, and manufacturing for, and selling to
the trade in the said state of Washington and in several
states of the United States where said company is carrying on
business, buyers' stamps, otherwise called Trading Stamps. </p>

<p> -III-
That the purposes and obects of said company are:
To buy, sell, and exchange merchandise; to do a general
merchandise and advertising business; to print, issue, and circulate
advertisements; to make and carry out contracts with
corporations and individuals; to advertise their business by
special and useful devices to give merchandise in exchange for

<pb/>

Buyers' Stamps, commonly known as "Trading Stamps" and which
said stamps are due bills, certificates or vouchers to be sold
by said company, and to be redeemed by it in merchandise,
according to its contracts, rules, and regulations. </p>

<p> -IV-
That said buyers' Stamp is issued by and as a due bill of
said National Stamp Company and is redeemed by said company in
exchange for merchandise at the store or place of business of
the said company in the cities of Tacoma, Seattle, and Everett,
or any other city, town or place in the United States where said
company has an office or is doing business aforesaid. </p>

<p> -V-
That said stamps of said company are sold to the trade at
the rate of fifty cents a hundred and are given by the trade or
merchant as a cash discount to each purchaser, one stamp to each
ten cents represented in the purchase, and which said stamps
are redeemed by said stamp company in merchandise at its place
of business in said cities of Tacoma, Seattle and Everett, or
any other city, town, or place in the United States, and that
said stamps are used only as a means of advertising the business
of petitioners and of the merchants using the same, as a medium
of co-operation and exchange for value: </p>

<p> -VI-
Petitioner attaches hereto and makes a part hereof a
stamp book used in the said business of petitioner marked Exhibit
"A", which said Exhibit "A" is for the convenience and
information of the people doing business with said company and
the merchants using said stamps and which said book explains the
method of obtaining, using and redeeming said stamps. </p>

<p> -VII-
That at the ninth bi-ennial session of the legislature of
the State of Washington, the State Legislature passed and enacted

<pb/>

House Bill No. 340, entitled "An Act making it a misdemeanor
to sell or exchange property under the representation, adverttisement,
notice, or inducement that an unidentified, unknown,
unselected, or chance prize, premium or premium gift, or that
a stamp, tradig stamp, coupon, or other like device, entitling 
the holder to recieve such a prize, premium, or premium gift,
or that the redemption of such a stamp, trading stamp, coupon,
or other like device to such said sale or exchange, as aforesaid
<del> , </del> and providing a penalty therefor." And which said act
was approved bythe Governor on or about the 14th day of March,
A.D., 1905, a copy of which said act is hereo attached, and
for greater certainty is made a part hereof and marked Exhibit
"B". </p>

<p> -VIII-
Petitioner attaches hereto and makes part hereof, marked
Exhibit "C", a true and correct copy of the complaint, 
filed against petitioner and upon which he is unlawfully held and deprived
of his liberty and which said complaint is founded upon
said House Bill No. 340.
Wherefore, your petitioner demurs to said complaint and 
for cause of demurrer alleges:
1st. That the information and complaint against petitioner charges no offense or crime,
2nd. The said House Bill No. 340 under wich petitioner is deprived
of his liberty an upon which said compaint is founded is unconstitutional and void <del> </del> </p>

<p> -IX-
That said act, (House Bill No. 340) passed as aforesaid,
by said Legislature and approved by the Governor, is unconstitutional
and void in this to-wit:
1st. That it is destructive of the lawful business of
plaintiffs, and is destructive of their rights as individals
and citizens of the United States.

<pb/>

2nd. That said act is against public policy.
3rd. That said act is in restraint of trade and commerce
between the people of this state.
4th. That said act is in restraint of Inter)State trade
and commerce.
5th. That said act is special and class legislation and
wrongfully, unlawfully and unreasonably discriminates against
the lawful business affairs of petitioner.
6th. That said act unlawfully, wrongfully and unconstitutionally
deprives petitioner of his liberty and right to
fully contract and carry on lawful business, trade, and commerce. 
7th. That said act unlawfully, wrongfully and unconstitutionally
prohibits and restrains petitioner from engaging
in lawful business and takes away and destroys property without
due process of law.
8th. That said act imposes an unreasonable and unjust
burden upon petitioner and upon trade and commerce, and is in
violation of their constitutional rights.
9th. That said act is in violation of and in conflict with
the Constitution of the United States and of the State of
Washington; that said Legislature of the State of Washington
has not the legal power or authority to enact such law as
herein complained of.
10th. That said act impairs and interferes with petitioners
right to engage in lawful business, and is a wrongful and unconstitutional
exercise of the police power of the state of
Washington.
11th. That said act unlawfully interferes with and impairs
the obligations of contract; and said act is an arbitrary
and unconstitutional interference with the right of private
contract.
12th. That said act is oppressive, discriminative, prehibitory

<pb/>

and unresonable and is not <add> a </add> proper and lawful erercise
of the police power of the Legislature of the State of Washington.
13th. That said bill embraces more than one subject, and
14th. That the subject of said bill is not expressed in
the title.

</p>

<p>- X -
That your petitioner is unlawfully restrained of his
liberty by L.C. Smith, Sheriff of King County, State of 
Washington. </p>

<p> -XI-
That said Sheriff pretends to and does hold petitioner

















<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>