<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0162.059">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt> 
<title>Ray Raymond v. Territory of Washington. Attorney Statement</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
<name n="Hidalgo, Emily" xml:id="eh ">Emily Hidalgo</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0162.059</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ray Raymond v. Territory of Washington. Attorney Statement</title>
<date></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Griffitts, Thomas C.</term>
<term>Peel, J.J.L.</term>
<term>Booge, John J.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Spokane County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Raymond, Ray</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Territory of Washington</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Griffitts, Thomas C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>

<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Fourth Judicial District</orgName>
<placeName>Spokane County, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#lkw">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2021-07" who="#eh">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">
        
<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0162.059"/>

<p>Territory of Washington<lb/>
County of Spokane} ss<lb/>
In the District Court of the 4th
Judicial District holding terms
at county seat of Spokane County</p>

<p>Territory of Washington<lb/>
vs. Plaintiff<lb/>
Ray Raymond Defendant</p>

<p>Territory of Washington<lb/>
Spokane County} ss<lb/>
I Thomas C. Griffitts being
first duly sworn state: I am one of the attorneys of the
defendant Ray Raymond in this cause and have
been such attorney since the charge was first made
against Defendant June 26, 1886 and have had
principal charge of the case for her, I believe the defendant 
cannot have a fair trial in this cause in
this county of Spokane on account of and owing
to the prejudice and entitlement of the inhabitant, 
against her. That among other reasons
and sufficient reasons for such belief and as
showing such indictment and prejudice I state
the following facts:</p>

<p>It has been stated throughout the county that
at time of the killing of such defendant was a 
common woman of the town and the keeper of 
brothel known in the "Bay Windows" situated
on Fourth Street in the city of Spokane Falls in this
county, and that she was an unusually bad, dangerous 
and <unclear>horrednous</unclear> woman of her kind
and very handy and wanton in the use

<pb/>

of firearms, all of which last allegations of her very
dangerous and quarrelsome, or affiant, from his
own knowledge believes to be untrue, and that
from such statements, being to him and repeatedly
made a general belief in the truth thereof seems
to exist among the inhabitants of the city
of Spokane Falls and of this county generally,
and these statements and the belief in their truth
have tended greatly to excite the prejudices of the people
of the county against the defendant. That at the
time of the killing <del>known</del> and ever since, it
was and has been repeatedly affirmed, and
stated that theretofore Defendant had
murdered her husband, and has also murdered 
two men and one woman in Montana 
and so positively and repeatedly, have these
statements been made that a general belief in
their truth appears to pervade the people of
the county, and affiant has conversed with 
many people of the county who believe such
charges and repeat them as true, that each and
all of said statements and charges are untrue
as affiant verily believes and affiant has
has a letter from the former husband  of
defendant since that killing and knows
he was there and believes he is now alive,
that the presentation of these statements and
their general belief has tended greatly to prejudice
the people of this county against defendant

<pb/>

and to incite and influence the prejudices of the people
of the county.</p>

<p>At the time immediately following the killing and before
the coroner's inquest, and while the deceased man Finch
lay dead in the hallway of the "Bay Windows" and defendant 
was a close prisoner therin and in a bed
under constant charge of a physician. Crowds of
men gathered on the streets of Spokane Falls and
about said building and heard what purported
to be the facts connected, with the killing often
repeated and discussed among them, and ull
of the accounts of the killing I then heard among
them were untrue, Highly colored and
greatly executed and very unfair to defendant, 
and I also heard many false rumors 
of and concerning defendant circulated
among them greatly to her prejudice and I heard
many expressions of bitter prejudice
against her from among them, such as
"she ought to be hung" and the like pronounced 
with vehemence and propensity
and calling defendant a "whore" and other
offensive names and for many days
thereafter I heard similar expression of
bitter prejudice and intense feeling against
defendant from and among the people of the
city of Spokane Falls and of Spokane
County, and I also heard many bitter complaints
of the office having defendant in charge for

<pb/>

for with taking her from this house in the condition described 
and incarcerating her in te "city-jail"
a nasty, dirty, filthy, unhealthy place totally unfit 
for the confinement of a well man, an
known to be such, and I am inferred and 
believe and upon such information and
belief allege that citizens of this county went to
the offices having her in charge and demanded 
that she be placed in said jail, and
accused the officers for not doing so.</p>

<p>That on the morning following the killing and
coroners inquest the "Morning Review." The city
daily paper then published in Spokane County, and
a paper of general circulation in said
County, published what purported to be the facts
of such killing as disclosed before said coroners 
jury a copy of which said publication is
attached hereto marked B. and made part
of this affidavit. That in said publication 
it was stated that defendant stated the 
facts of the killing as there given before the coroner's
jury, which statement was wholly untrue
for in truth and in fact defendant did not
appear before her make any statement to

<pb/>

the said Coroner's Jury, and the said publication
failed to state the fact, if said killing truly, and yet
they were greatly <unclear/> being given as the
confession of defendant before the Coroner's
Jury, and by reason of the premises such
publication greatly prejudice defendant's
case with the people of the county, that said
Review is also a weekly paper of general circulation 
in this county and the same publication
was again published in its weekly edition
of about the date of July 3d 1886.</p>

<p>That on June 26, 1886, defendant was arrested by
a warrant issued by J.J.L. Peel Esquire of
the Justice of the Peace of Spokane County, charged
with the crime of murder in the first
degree in the killing of said Finch
and on the following week a preliminary examination 
in this charge was had before said
Peel under John J. Booge, another of the Justices
of the Peace of said County, which lasted
about four days and was held in the
city of Spokane Falls with open doors
and attended constantly by a large 
number <del>crowd</del> of the inhabitants and <unclear/>
of Spokane County. That during said
examination the prosecuting attorney
frequently denounced defendant and the
class of women to which it was stated
she belonged vehemently asserted that

<pb/>

the offense she had committed was a crime
wanton, unprovoked and cold-blooded
murder, and tried to and did excite prejudice 
against defendant by repeatedly pointing
to the offense as the <unclear/> of what he termed
the "wide open system" of dealing with
saloons and the serial evil in Spokane Falls
and which he therein to be thoroughly condemned 
and insighted against by many good
people of the county, and further sought to
inflame the passions and excite the
prejudices of the working men of the
county by repeatedly and vehemently charging
during the examination that defendant
shot deceased because he wore <unclear>overalls</unclear>
and that her parlor was occupied by
gentlemen with doe skin pants on, and
that had deceased worn doe-skin
pants he would not have been shot and
so vehemently and insistently was this
urged by the public prosecution though
no evidence whatever supported it
that the working men were greatly
excited and prejudiced against defendant 
thereby and as affiant has recently 
been informed and verily believes
true are greatly excited and prejudiced
against defendant and are watching
this case with a great deal of interest.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>