<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0473.002"> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant</title> <!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Gross, Mikayla" xml:id="mg">Mikayla Gross</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0473.002</idno> <!-- replace with number from spreadsheet -->

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of Document.</title><!-- replace with name of case; type of document -->
<date when="1111-11-11">September 2, 2021</date><!-- replace with date in both sortable and human readable forms -->
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image.</note> <!-- remove or change, if otherwise -->
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository><!-- insert name of repository -->
<collection></collection><!-- insert name of collection -->
<idno></idno><!-- insert name of repository's identifier -->
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term><!-- Civil or Criminal -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1111-11"></date>29 July 1899</term><!-- insert date of court term -->
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Denning, J. Henry
Mason, William
Miller, John F.
Nordstrom, Charles W.
Lewis, James Hamilton
Jacobs, Orange
Spencer, W. C.
McBride, W. P.
Ellanerth, P. C.
Hart, John B.
Calhoun, C. V.
Willard, Rufus S.
Marion, A. B.
Bories, Emil
McElroy, James F.
Ayres, A. Reeves 
Walthew, H. M.
Hanford, C. H.
Ashley, M
Moors, A. N.
Van de Vanter, A. T.
Van de Vanter, A. D.
McKenney, James H.
Owrigher, B.
</term><!-- insert names of other people mentioned in document -->
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County, Washington
Washington D.C.
Seattle, Washington</term> <!-- insert places mentioned -->
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Nordstrom, Charles W.</persName><!-- insert name of petitioner, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>State of Washington</persName><!-- insert name of defendant, if a person -->
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner"><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
<persName>James Hamilton Lewis .</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>John F. Miller</persName><!-- insert name of attorney, if known -->
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jacobs, Orange</persName><!-- insert name of judge, if known -->
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court Northern Division</orgName> <!-- insert court name -->
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName> <!-- insert court location -->
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021" who="mg">transcribed.</change> <!-- change description, initials, and date -->
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.473.002"/> <!-- insert number from spreadhseet -->
<p> IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES FOR THE DISTRICT </p>
<p>OF WASHINGTON, Northern Division</p>

<p>In the matter of the Application of
Charles W. Nordstrom, for the Writ of
Habeas Corpus, Appearing by his next
friend, J. Henry Denning</p>

<p>PETITION FOR WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS</p>
<p>To the Honorable Judge of the Circuit Court of the United States
for the District of Washington, Northern Division:-</p>
<p>Your petitioner for relief by habeas corpus and for writ
therein most respectfully to the court, that,</p>
<p>I</p>
<p>Your petitioner J. Henry Denning avers that he is the friend of 
the said Charles W Nordstrom in whose behafl he petitions for relief
in habeas Corpus and for a writ of habeas corpus herein.</p>
<p>II</p>
<p>That the said Charles W. Nordstrom is a citizen of the United
States and a resident of the State of Washington, and is at present
confined in the county jail of King County, State of Washington, under
an alleged conviction of muder had in the Superior Court of the
State of Washington for King County, on April 2, 1892, and thereafter
various proceedings were had and judgement and final sentence of
death taken had against said Charles W. Nordstrom by the said 
Superior Court of the State of Washington.</p>
<p>III</p>
<p>And that they said Nordstrom was sentenced to death and to be
excecuted by the sheriff of said King County, and that subsequently
to-wit, on the day of 189, the said Charles W.
Nordstrom sued out a writ of habeas corpus before the Circuit Court
of the United States for the District of Washington, Northern Division,
claiming relief thereunder; saild reflief being denied by the said
Circuit Court, whereupon and thereafter said petitioner appealed said
Habeas Corpus proceeding to the Supreme Court of the United States;
said Sureme Court of the United States did on the day of 
189, dismiss the petition upon the ground that the matter was not
complete enough in the details of the pleading, in failing to set out with
proper certainty and preciseness the exact grounds upon which the
petitioner rested his contentions embracing the attempt to deprive
petitioner of his life without due process of law, particularly, in that
he failed to annex a copy of the indictment or information and to set
out the verdct in the case, both of which were subjects of complaint;
that thereafter the said court duly dismissed said petition and con-
firmed the order of the Circuit Court of the United States for the
State of Washington, and sent down to said Circuit Court of the
United States for the State of Washington its mandate on or about the 
8th day of March, 1899.</p>
<p>IV</p>
<p> That said mandate of the Supreme Court of the United States
specifically provided that the said cause of said petitioner was
returned to the said Circuit Court of the United States for further
proceedings therein to be had, to-wit, to be had in the Circuit Court
of the United States for the State of Washington according to the 
laws of the United States and according to justice on the permises. </p>
<p>V</p>
<p>That thereafter, to-wit, on the 15th day of May, 1899, the said
Superior Court of the State of Washington for King County assumed to
take jurisdiction of the petitioner befire any final judgment had been
made by the said Circuit Court of the United States for the State of 
Washington upon said petition and in accordance with the mandate of 
the Supreme Court of the United States, and without any order having
been made by said Circuit Court of the United States, or by any proper
order whatsoever in the premises either transferrng the said cause to 
the said Superior Court of the State of Washington, or releasing and
relieving itself of jurisdiction of said peitioner Charles W. Nordstrom
</p>
<p>VI</p>
<p>That the said petitioner Charles W. Nordstrom by his friend duly 
made objection to the Superior Court of the State of Washington for
King COunty, to-wit, the Hon. Orange Jacobs, Judge, taking jurisdic-
tion therein in anywise whatsoever, for that, to-wit, the said petition-
er had the right to proceed n the said United States Circuit by appro-
priate amendment amendng his petition to conform to the opinion of the
Supreme Court of the United States, in the cause given and rendered in 
that certain case, entitled, Charles W. Nordstrom v. The State of
Washington, based upon the opinion and reasons of that other certain
case of Carner v. State of Washington, both petitions being similar
in letter, words, paragraph and subject matter.</p>
<p>VII</p>
<p>That said Superior Court of the State of Washington for King County 
assumed to take jurisdiction over the objections of said petitioner,
and did proceed, notwithstanding, to exercise said jurisdiction to the 
exlusion of the said Circuit Court of the United States against the
objection and protest of said petitioner and his friend, to which due
exception was taken, which exception was allowed and preserved in the
record of said cause.</p>
<p>VIII</p>
<p>The petitioner informed the court by affidavit and by due presen-
tation of the record that sad question of said petitioner's federal
rights in the Federal Court was still undisposed of, which said 
affidavit was duly filed and duly presented before the said Hon. Orange
Jacobs, Judge of the said Superior Court of the State of Washington for
King County, and the said federal question was therein fully stated,
wholly and completely, as more fully appears by reference to the
record on file in the Superior Court of the State of Washington for 
King County, which said objection to the said jurisdiction to said
jurisdiction were in the words as appears in exhibit "a" to this 
peition, which exhibit is made a part of this petition for reference.</p>
<p>IX</p>
<p>Your petitioner further alleges that notwithstanding said objec-
tion and said question being raised, that said Superior Court of the 
State of Washington for King County proceeded to take jurisdiction of
the person of petutuiner and sentence him to death, to-wit, to die on
the 11th day of August 1899, to be hanged by the sheriff of said King
County; that from said conduct and action of said Judge of the 
Superior Court of the State of Washington for King County said
petitioner did duly appeal to the Supreme Court of the State of Washing-
ton claiming relief and exemption upon his said ground of his federal
rights and previleges as therein set fort; that the Supreme Court of 
the State of Washington did on the 24th day of July, 1899, deny to the
said petitioner relief, and did decide the said federal question and
conention against the interests of said pettioner and adverse to his 
contention, and did refuse the relief prayed for, and did affirm the
condcut and action of the said Superior Court, to-wit, the judgement of
the said Hon. Orange Jacobs in overrulung the obections of said
petitioner to the jurisdiction of his court, and did overrule and deny
petitioner's petition for relief upon the ground that under the 
federak kaw and the Consitution of the united States that said Auperior
Court had no jurisdiction of the cause and of the petitioner, for that, 
to-wit, the said Circuit Court of the United States for the State of
Washington alone and only held and had jurisdiction of the Retitioner
in anywise whatsoever any proceeding whatsoever authoriaing the 
State court to take jurisdiction of the person of the said Charles W.
Nordstrom in anywise whatsoever.</p>
<p>X</p>
<p>The the said Supreme Court of the State of Washington in so de-
ciding against the contention and claim of right of said petitioner
denied him his rights under the Constituion and laws of the United 
States, and decided contrary to petitioner's rights under the con-
stitution of the United States, and against the laws of the United
States, and in violation of the laws of the United States and to the
detriment of petitioner's interests and against the life of petitioner
and contrary to the Constitution of the United Stat es and the laws thereunder.</p>
<p>XI</p>
<p>Your petitioner further showeth that previous to the 15th day of
May, 1899, to-wit, on March the 18th, 1899, prior to and previous to 
the Superior Court taking jurisdiction of said Charles W. Nordstrom,
Your petitioner J. Henry Denning as the friend of the said Charles W.
Nordstrom did duly by affidavit make known to the court a fact which 
has ever since remained, and is now a factm that the said Charles W.
Nordstrom gas subce tge verdict and judgmebt against him, become insane,
that he was of unsound mind, that he was demented and crazy, that he
was unable to present to the court in his own behalf any fact or factsw
which might go to the amelioration of his sentence or the avoidance
of the execution thereupon. That he was in such condiction of mind as
to be unable to prepare himself for the event of death, and was in
such a state of mind as to make the act inhuman that would take his 
life by process of law or otherwise, that the said Chares W. Nordstro m
was wholly irrespnsible in mind, and for a long time prior thereto
has been and was then a subject for the insane asylum, being crazy
and insane.</p>
<p>XII</p>
<p>That the petitioner did ask that a hearig be had for the said
Charles W. Nordstrom, that said hearing be judicial, that said hearing
be legal, that petitioner did pettion that all proceedings against the
said Charles W. Nordstrom be stayed until such legal hearing could be
had, that said Charles W. Nordstrom be permitted such a hearing, and 
particularly, for such a hearing as would enable him to produce witness-
es and those acquainted with his condition by whom it could be demon-
strated annd established that he was of such unsound mind as to exempt 
him from furtherprocess of the law, and to exept him from any other or
further process of the courts looking to his inoaroeration as criminal and of taking his life as such.</p>
<p>XIII</p>
<p>That said court delined and refused to grant to the said Nordstrom
a legal hearing either by jury or by legal comission in open court
whereat and at which time the said Nordstrom would have the opportunity 
through his friend to establish his mental condition. That said peti-
tion was sustained by affidavit and by evidence tendered to the court
from impartial, reliable, trustworthy, and wholly creditable sources
who has knowledge and information absolute as to the condition of the
mind of the said Nordstrom, yet, nevertheless and notwithstanding,
the said court refused to grant the said Nordstrom an opportunity of
presenting witnesses in his behafl through his friend or in anywise
in order to establish at a legal hearing in open court or to a jury
or before the court upon a trial his real mental condition or to
establish his said insanity. </p>
<p>XIV</p>
<p>That subsequently the said court nevertheless proceeded upon the 
statement that the said court was satisfied and did proceed notwith-
standing theinformation of the affidavid informing the said courtof
the insanity of the said Nordstrom; and your petitioner durther showeth 
that said affidavid was in nowise denied denied by the said court or
the Prosecuting Attorney of King County or by any person whomsoever by
any written form of denial from any sourse whatsoever that the said
Nordstrom was insane as claimed by yoru petitioner in behalf of the 
said Nordstrom.</p>
<p>XV</p>
<p>The the said Hon. Orange, Jacobs, Judge of the Superior Court of
the State of Washington for King County did insist upon naming a day 
for the execution of the said Nordstrom, and did, notwithstanding the h 
showing and representations, name the 11th day of August, 1899, as 
the time for taking the life of the said Nordstrom by the 
sheriff of King County, Washington.</p>
<p>XVI</p>
<p>There is no statute in the State of Washington prescribing
offence of murder in the first degree and murder in the second degree.
That the verdict returned against your petitioner is in words follow-
ing, to-wit:
</p>
<p>State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintiff,</p>
<p> -vs-</p>
<p>Charles W. Nordstrom,</p>
<p>Defendant.</p>
<p> "We, the jury in the above entitled cause wherein the State
of Washington is plaintiff and Charles W. Nordstrom is defendant, do 
find the defendant guilty as charged."</p>
<p>That the said verdict in nowise adjudges your petitioner guilty
of murder in the first degree. That said information charged your
petitioner with the crime of murder in the second degree two offences;
first, with the crime of murder in the first degree; second, with the
crime of murder in the second degree. That the said verdict herein
finds your petitioner guilty as charged, and but and only charges him
with the crime of muder and in nowsie specifiying that they find him
guilty of murder in the degree known as first. That under
the law no presumption can prevail, save and except a presumption most
favoring the petitioner. That the Supreme Court of the State of 
Washington construed the statute under which your petitioner was tried
and declared the law of the State of Washington tobe that a killing
proved created the presumption of murder in the second degree. That
there must be an especial finding of murder in the first degree to 
justify the presumption of the existence of such. That the absence of
 any statement or finding of any jury against your petitioner other
then as herein stated no other nor futher nor greater offence has
been adjudged against him than that of murder in the second degree.
That the punishment for murder in the second degree is imprisionment in
the penitenitary of the State of Washington exceeding twenty years,
and in nowise is there law or authority for the taking of the life of
your petitoner, or any other person upon such verdict as herein
reported and returned upon such information as herein stated and
filed against your petitioner.
</p>
<p>XIX</p>
<p>That any attempt to take the life of your petitioner at this 
time is in violation,</p>
<p>First, of the Constitution of the United States providing and pre-
scribing and granting due process of law, to-wit, a full and complete
hearing upon all the issues raised by the petitioner, among which,
your petitioner's condition of mind, that is, to-wit, his insanity,
and his right to be exempt from execution while in such condition.</p>
<p>Second, Is in direct violation of the statutes of the United
States and the law of the United States prescribing that all process
of any State or any State Court shall be null and void while any pro-
ceeding is pending either upon appeal or on Habeas Corpus before a
Federal Court of the United States.</p>
<p>Third, Because the same is contrary to the Constitution of the 
United States, is contrary to the laws of the United States, and is
without any jurisdiction in the State Court of this or any other State,
and in violation of the rights of your petitioner as a citizen of the
United States and entitled to the protection oof the laws of the 
United States and Constitution of the same.</p>
<p>W H E R E F O R E, Petitioner prays that Your Honor will grant
unto your petitioner a Writ of Habeas Corpus commanding your petitioner
to be brought before this court at such time and place as the court
shall deem convenient, whereat the court could inquire of the matters
and things alleged by your petitioner, and that Your Honor would
issue a Writ of Certiorari to the Superior Court of the State 
of Washington for King County ordering to be duly certified to the
court the records of this said cuase for information, that Your Honor
may beinformed of the premises, and that upon such record and upon
such hearing of the cause such further and other order may be made
as in the premises will be right and proper.</p>
<p>And your petitioner will ever pray.</p>
<p>Charles W. Nordstrom</p>
<p>Petitioner</p>
<p>By J Henry Dunning</p>
<p>His Friend.</p>
<p>James Hamilton Lewis</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner</p>
<p>State of Washington, )</p>
<p>:ss.</p>
<p>County of K i n g )</p>
<p>J. HENRY DENNIN, being first duly sworn, on oath d eposes
and says: That he is the friend of the petitioner named herein,
Charles W. Nordstrom, that he knows the matters and things set forth
in the petition, and of the matters of his own knowledge says they
are true, and the other mattres of law he is advised thatthey are 
true and therefore believes the wole of said petition to be true.</p>
<p>J. Henry Denning</p>
<p>Subscribed and swron to before me this 29 day of July, A.D. 1899.</p>
<p>P.C. Ellanerth</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>
<p>INFORMATION.</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON, </p>
<p>FOR KING COUNTY</p>
<p>The State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintiff,</p>
<p>No. 472</p>
<p>Charles W. Nordstrom,</p>
<p>Defendant.</p>
<p>I, John F. Miller, prosecuting attorney for King County, State of
Washington, come now here and give the xourt to understand and be in-
formed and on oath de accuse Charles W. Nordstrom by this information
of the crime of murder in the first degree, as follows:</p>
<p>He, the said Charles W. Nordstrom, in said King County, State of
Washington, on the 27th day of November 1891, purposely, and of his
deliberate and premediatated malice, killed Wiliam Mason, by then
and there purposely, and of his deliberate and premediated malice,
shooting and mortally wounding the said William Mason, with a gun which
he, the said Charles W. Nordstrom, then and there held in his hands.
</p>
<p>Dated at Seattle, in said County of King aforesaid, the 8th day of December 1891.</p>
<p>John F. Miller,</p>
<p>Prosecuting Attorney.</p>
<p>State of Washington, )</p>
<p>: ss.</p>
<p>County of K i n g )</p>
<p>John F. Miller, being first duly sworn, deposes and states 
that he is the prosecuting attorney of King County, State of Washing-
ton, that he has read the foregoing information, and that the allega-
tions and statements made therein are true as alleged.</p>
<p>John F. Miller.</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 8th day of December 1891.</p>
<p>W.b. Spencer,</p>
<p>Clerk of the Superior Court, King
County, Washington,</p>
<p>By W.P. McBride, Deputy Clerk.</p>
<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON FOR KING COUNTY.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION OF
CHARLES W. NORDSTROM FOR RELIEF FROM
CONDITION OF INSANITY</p>
<p> State of Washington,</p>
<p>Plaintiff, No.</p>
<p>-vs- A F F I D A V I T.</p>
<p>Charles W. Nordstrom</p>
<p>Defendant.</p>
<p>State of Washington, )</p>
<p>: ss.</p>
<p>County of King. )</p>
<p> James Hamilton Lewis, being first duly sworn, on
oath deposes and says: That for record of the preceeding in the said
matter above named and for a record of the recitals of all the facts 
connected therewith, the following is a true and absolute statement
is a complete, full and true exemplification, exhibition, and
statement of the whole record of transaction in connection with the
proceeding. That all matter of every nature whatsoever that is now
or has been a part of any record or of any proceeding in so far as 
the same has been made known in anywise whatsoever is 
herin stated, provided, except only such record as the trnacript of 
the Clerk of the Superior Court of this County has disclosed anterior 
to the datte of this affidavit. That on the day of A.D. 1899,
at the City of Seattle, King County, Washington, Charles W. Nordstro,
was duly charged upon affidavit by J. Henry Denning, a legally
qualified dependent, and due suggestion and statement by motion based
upon said affidavit was also propertly made and duly filed, duly
reciting and regularly stated charged the said Nordstrom of being
non compos mentis ; that said Nordstrom was of insane mind and un-
able to appreciate his surroundings, had no knowledge sufficient to
conduct his affairs, or understand or appreciate the extent or
nature or consequence of any proceeding being had or taken against
or for him or in which he was interested. That this deponent, as 
counsel for the said Nordstrom, duly moved the Court for such proper
proceeding looking to the ascertainment of the mental state of the
said Nordstrom, based upon and supported by the said affidavit and
charge of insanity, also that such other course be had and taken by
which judgment appropriate to the proceeding and further proceedings
consistent with the facts elicited to be had. That thereupon the Court,
in the presece of the Counsel for the State, representing the County
of King, and appearing as opposing the motion for inquiry into the
lunacy of the said Nordstrom; and said Court stated that he would
name a Commission to examine into the subject at a future day named,
to-wit: the day of 18999; that thereupon this affiiant 
as counsel for defendant arose and stated to the Court that, in so
far as the selection of a Commission for a preliminary inquiry, the
commissioners being scinentific men, was concerned, affiant favoured 
proceedings to that extent, but must not be understood as consenting 
to the intimation given out that said Commission could take upon
themselves the right to pass upon the question, or to proceed for or 
against the defendant of their own volition as a court or trial
body That affiant felt it his duty to inform the Court then and
there that nothing could be done carrying with it the idea that 
affiant was waiving such rights as defedant would have, or was 
sitting in acquiescence to the course of proceeding without taking
the due course of informing the Court as to what he thought, as
counsel for the defendant and an advuser of the Court, was proper and
just in the premises, either as to the course of proceeding or the 
course of procedure.
</p>
<p>That on the day of , 1899, affiant being present 
as a friend of the defendant, Assistant Prosecuting Attorney, John B. 
Hart, being present representing the State, Hon. Orange Jacobs, the
presiding Judge in the presence of affiant and said Assistant
</p>
<p>Prosecuting Attorney, John B. Hart, stated that he had agreed
upon a Commission of physicians consisting of five gentlemen, being
medical men, to-wit: Drs. C.V. Calhoun, Rufus S. Willard, A.B. 
Marion, Emil Bories, and the phsician attendin in the Insane
Asylum at Steilacom; that he had concluded upon the commission 
without taking the suggestions of either the said Nordstrom or his
friend or any one in his behalf, or of the state or any one in its
behalf. Affiant then publicly state that he presumed that he would be given 
notice when the said commission would be returnable whereupon and at 
which time he assured he would be given opportunity to present what
 he thought and understood under the law were the rights of the
said Nordstrom; That affiant then and there understoof the court
specifically to say to the said Assistant Prosecuting Attorney that he 
should prepare such proper order naming the day of the citation and
serve the same upon affiant, and understood the said Assistant Pros-
ecuting Attorney to assert that he would do such; and this affiant 
then and there relying upon service of notice upon him of some kind
or in some form of the meeting of said commission by which he
would be given due opportunity of presenting the rights of the said
Nordstrom, and such other motion or suggestions as to affiant would 
appear right, just as proper in the premises. That subsequently,
to-wit, on the day of 1899, the said Hon. John B. Hart, 
Assistant Prosecuting Attorney in open court upon this affiant making public statement to the Court that
upon that statement of the Court, he had been led to believe that he 
was to have notice, by reason of said statements of the Court to the
said Assistant Prosecuting Attorney, she said Hon. John B. Hart stated
that he did not so understand the Court or that he did not hear the
Court make such statement, and affiant states that in this opinion of
the said Hon. John B. Hart, and the said Prosecuting Attorney's office
representing the state in opposing the proceeding, were sincere in
their statemet thaht they did not hear the court and did not so under-
stand the court, and affiant begs to state that he under no consider-
ation either directly or indirectly asserts that the said Assistant 
Prosecuting Attorney, Hon? John B. Hart, the Prosecuting Attorney or
any of his assistants or deputies, purpsely violated the order of the 
Court or attempted to evade any duty to the Court that was incum-
bent upon them. That from said date up to and including Saturday
morning 10 o'clock of the 6th day of May, 1899, when this affiant
made his oral protest against the proceedng which he had understoof
had transpired there had been in nowise whatsoever, directly or indi-
rectly, served upon the said Nordstrom, upon this said affiant, or
J. Henry Denning, or any other person whomsoever, any notice of any
proceeding, or the time fo any proceeding, or the occasion of any
action, or the presence, or the citing of any commission, or of any
proceeding whatsoever in anywise whatsoever connected with or con-
cerning or relating to, the commission or alleged inquiry into the
 condition of the said Nordstrom, or as to the proceedings or course of
any alleged commission or body of persons, or of any proceeding of
any nature whatsoever in anywise whatsoever. That affiant as a friend 
of the said Nordstro observed from the public press, the only form
of notice or information of any whatsoever; first appearing in 
the Seattle Daily Times the following article:</p>
<p>THE DOCTOR NAMED.</p>
<p>Judge Jacobs Appoints the Commission to</p>
<p>Examine into the Sanity of Nordstrom.</p>
<p>udge Jacobs to day announced the names of the members of the
medical commission appointed for the purpose of examining into the 
sanity of Charles W. Nordstrom, the condemned murderer of Willie Mason
The commission is composed of Dr. F. L. Godard, Superintendent of the
Western Washington Insane Hospital for the Insane; Dr. C.V. Calhoun,
Dr. A.N. Marion, Dr. Emil Bories and Dr. Rufus Willard.
Court were instructed to resent in </p>
<p> "We have made a very careful examination of the prisoner  and
taken the testimony of the sheriffs and other officers in whose
custody and under whose observation the said Charles W. Nordstrom 
has been since his incarceration, and we are of the unanimous 
opinion that he is now in such a condition of mind as to be able to
distinguish between right and wrong. And as far as we have been 
able to ascertain there has been no material change in his mental
condition since his conviction."</p>
<p>"G.V. Calhoun, Foreman,</p>
<p>F.L. Goddard,</p>
<p>Emil Bories</p>
<p>A.N. Marion</p>
<p>Rufus Willard"</p>
<p>Nordstrom, in charge of a deputy sheriff, sat inside the rail
when the fice commissioners, through their foreman, presented their
report. Through the reading he listened with attention and appeared 
to smile sardonically. Possibly it was only a nevous twitching of
the muscels of his face. He refused to talk to any one in the court
room or later in his cell down in the jail.
</p>
<p> the verdict of the commission was a suprise to many persons,
even those familiar with Nordstrom's case. While most of the latter
were not inclined to believe Nordstrom insane, they were equally
unprepared to announce him thoroughly sane, and it was the general
opinion among them that the commissioners would disagree or report
Nordstrom mentally unballaced. </p>
<p>The commissioner's verdict will be final with Judge Jacobs. as he
publicly stated that he would abide by the result of the examination
and sentence or not sentence the prisoner to death, according to
whether the commission reported him sane or insane.</p>
<p>That intermediate form the publication of one article to the 
other affiant nor the said Nordstrom or this affiant, or any person or
persons whomsoever acting in behalf of the said Nordstrom in any
capacity whatsoever, received any notice whatsoever of any proceeding,
or opportunity given in anywise whatsoever for the protection of the
rights, interest, or cause of the said Nordstrom, or to bebeheard by
witnesses or by counsel or by friend, or to be present to cross-examine
or opporunity to protext the rights of the said Nordstrom against
others whose interests are adverse to the claims of the said
Nordstrom or the clients of his friends. And the said Hon. Orange 
Jacobs, before whom this affiant made oral protest against the 
proceedings and the treatment of the said Nordstrom in the premises,
stated that he had chosen said commission and instructed them ti
investigate the question of the sanity of the said Nordstrom, by look-
ing exclusively and solely to the single standard of whether the 
said Nordstrom was able to distinguish right from wrong, and if so,
to report such fact to him. That he the said Judge prohibited the
commission from being visited or attended by any one representing
said Nordstrom either as counsel or friend, likewise prohibiting the 
attendance on said commission by any one representing the state in 
anywise whatsoever; affiant says that the said commission was authorized to take
such procedure as they thought proper and in such maner as they
chose, no person being allowed to suggest testmony in behalf of the 
said Nordstrom, nor to aypear and cross-examine, or to elicit before
the said commission either the prejudice, bias, competency, incom-
petency, qualification or disqualificatio of any witess or their 
interests who did so testify against the said Nordstrom and his 
claims. Affiant states that it was his opinion and understanding
gathered from the law and the doctrines therein announced that the
office of the commission was to inquire and possess themselves of cert-
tain facts and to qualify themselves as experts and that thereafter
they were to appeard at such proper time and under such proper circum-
stances to give their testimony either before the court in a judicial
inquiry or a jury in a hearing or trial and their opinion, which
opinio together with the testimony upon which it was based being 
also before the court or a jury, and there submitted to the ordinary
test permitted by the law, and ordinary cross-examination and inveti-
gation under the rules and standards justified by the law, and said
court or jury would have seached their conclusions under the ordin-
ary procedure upon an ordinary tried or ordinary hearing in which the
life or interests of a person were involved would have been conducted.
That whatever testimony was had by the commission and the nature of it
or the facts elicited, or the course of their procedure, or the con-
uct of their inquiry being in nowise reported or preserved or know,
it is impossible that the same could be the subject of review, or re-
vision, investgation, or correction by any Judge or of any appellate
court or tribunal, which according to the rights or interests of any
person interested or involved in said proceeding should have been
accessuble and of existence, affiant therefore is unable to state more fully the facts of
any inquiry whatsoever or any proceeding whatsoever conducted by
said commission or any part of the same, of which affiant will only
state his opinion that the said commission understood that their duty
was that, however, insane defendant might have appeared, however unfit
for the excecution or the due discharge of any obligation, however
wanting in moral senses and blunted intellegence, it was enough if
by the inquiry they could ascertain if he knew right from wrong on
any subject, that then and there such ascertain,ent ended their duty,
and that alone became the subject of their recommendation. That the
tests or course which said commission took in discharging their
instructions and duties in order to ascertain whether the defendant
knew right from wron, or what basis they used as a base of right, or 
what basis they used as a base of wrong, whether one recognized by the
law, or any recogized by modern science and the law, or whether one which
would have been permissible had it been submitted to a judicial tri-
bunal, and affiant is unable to state and is unable to inform the 
court because of the utter failture and complete abscence of all
record of the proceedings, and becase of the utter refusal neglect
of the said commission to make any any proceeding of record in anywise
whatsoever accessible to the said Nrdstrom or his friends or coun-
sel. That thereafter, to-wt, on the 5 day of May, 1899, the 
said commission assuing to act as such, returned into court a 
certain alleged finding, commonly called a verdict, of their judgment
as to the said Nordstrom, which is in words and language as follows.
to-wit:
To the Hon. Orange Jacobs, Judge of the Superior Court:
</p>
<p>Your commission, appointed to examine Charles W. Nordstrom, a
prisoner now confined in the county jail under sentence of death, and
report his mental condition to this honorable court, has performed
that duty and beg to report as follows:</p>
<p>We have made a very careful examination of the prisoner and
taken the testimony of the sherrifs and other officers in whose
custody and under whose observation the said Charles W. Nordstrom
has been since his incarceration, and we are of the unanimous
opinion that he is now is such a condition of mind as to be able to
distinhuish between right and wrong. And as far as we have been
able to ascertain there has been no material change in his mental
condition since his conviction.</p>
<p>G.V. Calhoun, Foreman,</p>
<p>F.L. Goddard,</p>
<p>Emil Bories,</p>
<p>A.N. Marion,</p>
<p>Rufus Willard.</p>
<p>That the said alleged verdict and judgment in nowise finds any
fact either of the sanity of insanity of the said Nordstrom, or any
other fact whatsoeverwhich can be recognized or is in conformity to the
law as a legal finding upon any issue which in law could be legally
recognized by any tribunal recognized by the law. That there has never
been at any time any hearing or inquiry upon the charge on non campos
mentis or insanity only made against or in behalf of the said 
Nordstrom in anywise whatsoever, and at this hour and at this time
said charge so duly made remains undisposed of without investigation
conclusion or judgment in anywise whatsoever.</p>
<p>That this affidavit is made in order that some record of the
proceeding while now on the memory of persons interested may be
preserved, to the end that the rights of the said Nordstrom may be 
duly protected by such proper legal course and procedure as under the
Constitution and laws of the United States and the State of Washing-
ton would be just in the premises. That affidavit particularly wishes
to impose upon the court, or any appellate court, that speaking as
the friend of said Nordstrom, he desires to conve unequivocally
the impression and information that the said Hon. Orange Jacobs in
whatsoever course or action he took in the premises was animated and
influenced by what he belives to be the highest sense of his duty and
was a justifyable proceeding, and one which he believed shuld be duly guarded by
the law and proper notice in the premiss as was incumbent upon
The State</p>
<p>That affiant states it to be his opinion and belief that the
mistake and injustices which has arisen to the said Nordstrom and
which has grown out of this proceeding as theu now exist have
been brought about by an unfortunate misunderstanding, in that the 
court presumed that the Prosecuting Attorney would give due notice
to the said Nordstrom and his friend and counsel in order that his
right as understood by him, would be duly urged at the proper time,
and that the said Prosecuting Attorney misunderstood, or not com-
prehending the court in that direction, failed to understand that
such was the desire of the court or that such was the duty of the
Prosecuting Attorney, and no notice whatsoever of any proceeding, what-
soever was given, and no notice of any proceeding whatsoever was
permitted or allowed or in anywise transpitred by which the said 
Nordstrom's interests could have been presented, guarded or protected.
That affiant would have ventured ti appear before the court had he
known at what time the commission itended to sit or have a hearing.
That affiant had lately returned from the East and had great press of 
business affairs upon him and did not have opportunity
or occassion to go at all hours to the cour house and ascertain by
investigation whether any proceedings have been taken or not, particu-
larly, is this true in view of affiant's natural expectation that
due and proper notice would be given the said Nordstrom or his friend
and counsel.</p>
<p>James Hamilton Lewis</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 10th day of May, A.D. 1899.</p>
<p>Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>
<p>Exhibit "A"</p>
<p>IN THE BALANCE.</p>
<p>Murderer Nordstrom Before an Insanity
Commission</p>
<p>"Their Finding will Determine whether he shall Die
or go to the Asylum.</p>
<p>The commission appointed by Judge Jacobs for the purpose of 
determining whether or not Murderer Charles W. Nordstrom is insane
began its itttings this afternoon. The commission is composed of
Dr. F.L. Goddard, superintendent of that Western Washington Hospital
for the insane: Dr. A.N. Marion, Dr. G.V. Calhoun, Dr. Emil
Bories, Dr. Rufus Willard. Dr. Calhoun was appointed Foreman of the
commission.</p>
<p>Before the commission began its session Judge Jacobs delivered an
impressive charge to its members. He recited the authority under
the law by virtue of which the commission was appointed; defined
insanity as contemplated by the law as being a condition of mind un-
able to distinguish between right and wring, and charged the members
of the commission to investigate ever particle obtainable
evidence which would throw light on the question oe whether or not
Nordstrom has become insane since his confinement in the County Jail.</p>
<p>Judge Jacobs laid particular stress upon the responsibility
 that devolved upon the members of the commission, stating that the
destiny of the condemned man rested upon their finding in his case
The law, he saidm did not contemplate the excecution of an idiot or
maniac, but it was the duty of the commission to determine by every
scientific test known to the medical profession whether or not the
prisoner is in a state of mind to recognize his condition and his 
impending doom.</p>
<p>At a late hour this afternoon the commission had not yet bagan
to examine witnesses, the time being occupied in discussing a mode
of procedure. It is likely that one of the first witnesses will be
Ex-county Jailer Munroe, who was in charge of the County Jail at the 
time Nordstrom was first confined. He will testify to Nordstrom's
consition at that time.</p>
<p>The sessions of the commission will be held in Judge Jacobs'
private office in his chambers, and every one is denied admittance to
the room except the members of the commission and the prisoner.
Even the deputy sheriff must remain in the ante-room within call."</p>
<p>United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington.</p>
<p>In the application of
Charles W. Nordstrom for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus by</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>his next friend
J. Henry Denning.</p>
<p>No. 784</p>
<p>Appearance.</p>
<p>To the Clerk of the above Entitled Court:</p>
<p>You will please enter my appearance as attorney
for pettioned
in the above entitled cause</p>
<p>James Hamilton Lewis</p>
<p>Notice--Attorneys will please endorse their own Filings. Rule 47.</p>
<p>10.00 paid</p>
<p>GoB 6-163</p>
<p>no. 784</p>
<p>United States Circuit Court</p>
<p>District of Washington.</p>
<p>In the application of
Charles W. Nordstrom</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>for Habeas Corpus
etc.,</p>
<p>Appearance.</p>
<p>Filed JUL 20 1899 189
A. Reeves Ayres </p>
<p>Clerk.</p>
<p>HM Walthew</p>
<p>Deputy Clerk.</p>
<p>James Hamtilton Lewis</p>
<p>For Petitioner</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,</p>
<p>Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application of
Charles W. Nordstrom for a Writ of
Habeas Corpus, Appearing by his next,
Friend, J. Henry Denning.</p>
<p>No. 784</p>
<p>O R D E R.</p>
<p>This cause coming on for hearing upon the petition of petitioners
for a Writ of Habeas Corpus, the court, being advised upon the petition
and upon hearing counsel for the peitioner, denies and refuses to grant
the said Writ; to which ruling of the court petitioner excepts.
Exeption allowed.</p>
<p>Petitioner thereupon gives notice that he appeals from the said
ruling of the court and from the whole and every part thereof and
appeals his said petition and his said cause and the whole and each
and every part thereof to the Supreme Court of the United States,
holding terms at the City of Washington, District of Columbia, and to
the next regulat term thereof, and particularly appeals from the said
ruling of the said court denying and refusing to grant the said Writ of 
Habeas Courpus.</p>
<p>Which said appeal is here and now allowed.
Done in open court this 29th of July, 1899.</p>
<p>C.H. Hanford
District Judge</p>
<p>GoB 6-162</p>
<p>(ORIGINAL)</p>
<p>No. 784</p>
<p>In the Circuit Court
of the 
UNITED STATES</p>
<p>District of Washington, Northern Division</p>
<p>In the application of 
Charles W. Nordstrom
for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus by
his next friend,
J. Henry Denning,</p>
<p>Order</p>
<p>Filed this 29th day
of July 1899
A Reeves Ayres Clerk.
By HM Walthew Deputy</p>
<p>JAS. HAMILTON LEWIS</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner</p>
<p>Office--FIFTH FLOOR, PIONEER BLOCK</p>
<p>Corner First Ave. and James St. SEATTLE, WASH.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,</p>
<p>Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application of
Charles W. Nordstrom for a Writ of
Habeas Corpus, Appearing by his next,
Friend, J. Henry Denning.</p>
<p>No. 784</p>
<p>NOTICE OF APPEAL.</p>
<p>To the State of Washington, and to A.T. Van de Vanter, Sheriff
of King County, State of Washington, and to Hon James F. McElroy,</p>
<p>Comes, now the petitioner, Charles W. Nordstrom, by his next
friend, J. Henry Denning, and appeals the above entitled cause and the
whole thereof to the Supreme Court of the United States, holding terms
at the City of Washington, District of Columbio, and to the next
regular term thereof, and more especially appeals from that certain
order made and entered in the above entitled cause on the 29 day of
July, 1899, by the Honorable C. H. Hanford, Judge, sitting 
as the Circuit Court, denying the petition of petitioner for a Writ 
of Habeas Corpus and refusing to grant the said Writ of Habeas Corpus
as in his said petition prayed.</p>
<p>And you will take notice that the record and proceedings upon
the said petition will be duly certified through the said above
entitled court to the said Supreme Court of the United States at the
next regular term thereof upon said named appeal.</p>
<p>James Hamilton Lewis</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner.</p>
<p>United States of America, )
District of Washington, :ss
C o u n t y of K i n g. )</p>
<p>M. ASHLEY, being first duly sworn, on oath deposes and
says: That at all the times herein and hereafter mentioned, I was,
and am now, a citizen of the United States of America, and of the
District of Washington, and a resident of King County, in said District
of Washington, above the age of twenty-one (21) years.</p>
<p>That at Seattle, King County, State of Washington, on the 31st
day of July, A.D. 1899, I duly served the within Notice of Appeal together with
a duly certified copy f the order allowing the affiant foreing
M.A. J.H.D. upon A. T. Van de Vanter, sheriff of King County, State of Washington,
he being the respondent and appellee in said within Notice of Appeal
named, by delivering to and leaving with the said A.T. Van de Vanter,
sheriff of King County, State if Washington, a true copy of said
within Notice of Appeal and a duly certified copy of said order allowing
M.A. J.H.D. said appeal.</p>
<p>That at Seattle, King County, State of Washington, on the 31stt
day of July, A.D. 1899, I duly served the within Notice of Appeal, together with 
a duly certfied copy of the order allowing the appeal herein,
M.A.J.H.D upon James F. McElroy, Prosecuting Attorney for King County, State of
Washington, on behafl of the said State of Washington, the State of 
Washington beng the respondent and appellee insaid within Notice of
Appeal named, by delivering to and leaving with said James F. McElroy,
Esq., Prosecuting Attorney for King County, State of Washington, a true
copy of said within Notice of Appeal and a duly certified copy of said order
M.A.J.H.D allowing said appeal.</p>
<p>M Ashley</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 31st day of July, A.D. 1899.</p>
<p>J Henry Dening
Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>
<p>(ORIGINAL)</p>
<p>No. 784</p>
<p>In the Circuit Court
of the 
UNITED STATES</p>
<p>District of Washington, Northern Division</p>
<p>In the application of 
Charles W. Nordstrom
for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus by
his next friend,
J. Henry Denning,</p>
<p>Notice of Appeal</p>
<p>Filed this 31st day
of July 1899
A Reeves Ayeres Clerk.
By A.N. Moors Deputy.</p>
<p>JAS. HAMILTON LEWIS</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner</p>
<p>Office--FIFTH FLOOR, PIONEER BLOCK</p>
<p>Corner First Ave. and James St. SEATTLE, WASH.</p>
<p>United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington.</p>
<p>In the application of
Charles W. Nordstrom for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus etc.,</p>
<p>No. 784</p>
<p>Praecipe</p>
<p>To the Clerk of the above Entitled Court:</p>
<p>You will please issue citation, returnable pursuant
to the rules in such cases; also prepare appeal and make
transcript on appeal to the Supreme Court of the United States,
to include petition for Habeas Corpus writ, order denying the
issuance of writ and allowing the appeal; opinion filed in the
cause, notice of appeal to the Supreme Court and notice to sherrif and assignment
of errors and duly certify the same within the time and in the manner
prescribed by law
Jas. Hamilton Lewis
Atty for Petitioner</p>
<p>Notice--Attorneys will please endorse their own Filings. Rule 47.</p>
<p>no. 784</p>
<p>United States Circuit Court
District of Washington.</p>
<p>In the application of
Charles W. Nordstrom
for Habeas Corpus 
etc.,</p>
<p>Prcaecipe</p>
<p>Filed July 29 1899
A. Reeves Ayeres Clerk
A. N. Moors Deputy Clerk
Jas. Hamilton Lewis
For Petitioner.</p>
<p>United States Circuit Court for the District of Washington.</p>
<p>In the application of
Charles W. Nordstrom for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus etc.,</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>No. 784</p>
<p>Praecipe</p>
<p>To the Clerk of the above Entitled Court:</p>
<p>You will please issue Four certified copies of the 
order refusing to grant the writ herein and
allowing an appeal; and, also, Four certified
copies of the citation issued herein</p>
<p>James Hamilton Lewis</p>
<p>Notice--Attorneys will please endorse their own Filings. Rule 47.</p>
<p>no. 784</p>
<p>United States Circuit Court
District of Washington.</p>
<p>In the application of
Charles W. Nordstrom
for Habeas Corpus 
etc.,</p>
<p>Prcaecipe</p>
<p>Filed July 29 1899 189 </p>
<p>A. Reeves Ayres </p>
<p>Clerk</p>
<p>H.M. Walthew</p>
<p>Deputy Clerk</p>
<p>Jas. Hamilton Lewis,
For Petitioner.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,</p>
<p>Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application of
Charles W. Nordstrom for a Writ of
Habeas Corpus, Appearing by his next,
Friend, J. Henry Denning.</p>
<p>No. 784</p>
<p>N O T I C E.</p>
<p>To the Hon. A. T. Van de Vanter, sherif of King County, State of 
Washington:</p>
<p>You will please take notice hereby that Charles W. Nordstrom,
now in your custody, duly petitioned the Circuit Court of the United
States for a Writ of Habeas Corpus seeking relief thereunder, and,</p>
<p>Whereas, the said writ and relief was denied, and</p>
<p>Whereas, said petitioner duly moved for the right of appeal and
for the transfer of his whole cause to the Supreme Court of the United
States, and</p>
<p>Whereas, the said cause came on for argument as to the granting
of the said appeal and the transfer of the whole cause to the appellate
Court, and was heard upon the 29th day of Juy 1899, by the Hon.
C. H. Hanford, Circuit Judge, and,</p>
<p>Whereas, after hearing said application, an order of appeal was 
duly granted, and the said cause was so ordered transferred to the
Supreme Court of the United States, a full copy of said proceedings
ad the order allowing said appeal, being duly certified, is hereunto
annexed for your information and advice.</p>
<p>And, whereas, under the Revised Statutes of the United States,
being the law of the United States, particularly, Section 766 of the 
said Revised Statutes of the United States, reads as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>Sec. 766 "Pending the proceedings on appeal in the 
cases mentioned in the three preceding section, and until final judg-
ment therein, and after final judgment of discharge, any proceedings
against the person so imprisioned or confined or restrained of his 
liberty, in any State Court, or by or under the authority of any
State, for any matter so heard and determined, under such writ of
Habeas Corpus, shall be deemed null and void."</p>
<p>And whereas, the Supreme Court of the United States In Re Jugiro
140 U. S. 295, construing the said section, defined the same to mean
"in cases where the applicant was held in custody under the authority
of a state court or by the authority of a State to stay the hands of 
such court or State while the question as to whether his detention was
in violation of the Constitution, laws or treaties of the United 
States was being examined by the courts of the United States having
jurisdiction in the premises;" which sad decision is more fully
referred to in the case on In Re M'Kane, 61 Fed. 205, where it was
held to mean that until final decision in the Supreme Court f the 
United States no disturbance of the condition of the prisoner as he
was at the time of the denying of the writ can be in anywise had: </p>
<p>Therefore youa re hereby notified that you are to hold posession
or custody of the said petitioner, Charles W. Nordstrom, now in your 
keeping at the City of Seattle, County of King, State of Washington,
in such manner as to your discretion shall seem meet and proper, in
nowise assuming for any cause to execute any sentence of death
whatsoever upon the said petitioner, Charles W. Nordstrom, and you
will be duly notified of any other proceedings in the premises.</p>
<p>You will please govern yourself accordingly.</p>
<p>Respectfully,</p>
<p>Jas. Hamilton Lewis
Attorney for Petitioner.</p>
<p>United States of America, )
District of Washington, :ss
C o u n t y of K i n g. )</p>
<p>M. ASHLEY, being first duly sworn, on oath deposes and
says: That at all the times herein and hereafter mentioned, I was,
and am now, a citizen of the United States of America, and of the
District of Washington, and a resident of King County, in said District
of Washington, above the age of twenty-one (21) years.</p>
<p>That at Seattle, King County, State of Washington, on the 31st
day of July, A.D. 1899, I duly served the within Notice upon A. T.
Van de Vater, Sheriff of King County, State of Washington, he being
the respondent and appellee in said within Notice named, by delivering
to and leaving with said A. D. Van de Vater, Sheriff of King County,
State of Washington, a true copy of said within Notice.</p>
<p>That at Seattle, King County, State of Washington, on the 31st
day of July, A. D. 1899, I duly served the within Notice upon James F.
McElroy, Es., Prosecuting Attorney for King County, State of Washing-
ton, on behalf of the State of Washington, said State of Washington
being the respondent and appellee in said within Notice named, by
Prosecuting Attorney for King County, State of Washington, a true copy
of said within notice. </p>
<p>M Ashley</p>
<p>Subscried and sworn to before me this 32st dau of July, A.D. 1899.</p>
<p>J Henry Denning
Notary Public in and for the State
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</p>
<p>IN THE CIRCUIT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES, DISTRICT OF </p>
<p>WASHINGTON,Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application of
Charles W. Nordstrom for a Writ of
Habeas Corpus, Appearing by his next,
Friend, J. Henry Denning.</p>
<p>No. 784</p>
<p>ASSIGNMENT OF ERRORS</p>
<p>Comes now the petitioner and assigns as error committed by
the Court in the above entitled cause at the time of the hearing of
the same, as follows:</p>
<p>I</p>
<p>That the Court erred in declining and refusing to issue the
Writ of Habeas Corpus upon the record of the above named cause.</p>
<p>II</p>
<p>That the Court erred in refusing to issue an order to show
cause why the Writ should not issue in the above named cause.</p>
<p>III</p>
<p>That the Court erred ub refusing to make an order restraining
proceedings pending the hearing of the Petition for the Writ of Habeas
Corpus in the above named cause.</p>
<p>James Hamilton Lewis
Attorney for the Petitioner.</p>
<p>No. 784</p>
<p>In the Circuit Court</p>
<p>OF THE</p>
<p>UNITED STATES</p>
<p>District of Washington, Northern Division</p>
<p>In The matter of the application
of Charles W. Nordstrom for a 
Writ of Habeas Corpus,
appearing by his next
friend J Henry Denning</p>
<p>Assignment of Errors</p>
<p>Filed this 31st day
of July 1899
A Reeves Ayers Clerk.
By A.N. Moors Deputy.</p>
<p>JAS. HAMILTON LEWIS</p>
<p>Attorney for Petitioner</p>
<p>Office--FIFTH FLOOR, PIONEER BLOCK</p>
<p>Corner First Ave. and James St. SEATTLE, WASH.</p>
<p>Received copy of the within
and service of the same admitted this
day of 189
Attorney for</p>
<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, ss:</p>
<p>The President of the United States of America,</p>
<p>To the Honorable the Judges of the Circuit
Court of the United States for the
District of Washington</p>
<p>GREETING:</p>
<p>Whereas, lately in the Circuit Court of the United States
for the District of Washington, before you
or some of you, in a cause entitled In the matter 
of the application of Charles W. Nordstrom
for a writ of habeas corpus, appearing
by his next friend, J Henry Denning, No.
784, wherein the order of the said Circuit 
Court, entered in said cause on the 29th
day of July, A.D. 1899, is in the following
words, viz;</p>
<p>"In the Circuit Court of the United States, District of Wash-
ington, Northern Division.</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application of CHARLES W. NORDSTROM for a
Writ of Habeas Corpus, Appearing by His Next Friend, J. Henry 
Denning. No. 784. Order.</p>
<p>This cause coming on for hearing upon the petition of petitioner
for a writ of habeas corpus, the court, being advised upon the peti-
tion and upon hearing counsel for petitioner, deies and refuses to
grant the said writ; to which ruling of the court petitioner excepts.
Exception allowed.</p>
<p>Petitioner thereupon gives notice that he appeals from the said
ruling of the court and from the whole and every part thereof and
appeals his said petition and his said cause and the whole and each
and every part thereof to the Supreme Court of the United States,
holding terms at the city of Washington, District of Columbia, and
to the next regular term thereof, and particularly appeals from the
said ruling of the said court denying and refusing to grant the said
writ of habeas corpus.</p>
<p>Which said appeal is here and now allowed.
Done in open court this 29th day of July, 1899.</p>
<p>C. H. HANFORD.</p>
<p>District Judge.</p>
<p>as by the inspection of the trancript of the record
of the said Circuit
Court, which was brought into the SUPREME COURT OF THE UNITED STATES
by the virtue of an appeal taken by Charles W. Nordstrom (by his next
friend J. Henry Denning), whereon A. T. Van de Vanter, Sheriff
of King County, Washington, and the State of Washington
were made the parties appellees
agreeably to the act of Congress,
in such case made and provided, fully and at large appears.</p>
<p>And whereas, in the present term of October, in the year of our Lord
one thousand nine hundred the said cause came on to be heard
before the said SUPREME COURT, on the said transcript of record, and
o motions to dismiss or affirm which were argued bu counsel;
</p>
<p>On consideration whereof, It is now here ordered, adjudged,
and decreed by this Court that the order, of the 
said Circuit Court in this cause be, and the same is hereby, affirmed,
with costs; And that the said A. T. Van de Vanter,
Sheriff, and The State of Washington recover
against the said Charles W. Nordstrom,
(by his next friend J. Henry Denning), Eighty
four dollars and fifty cents for their
costs herein expended and have exceution
therefor. May 13, 1901.</p>
<p>You, therefore, are hereby commanded that such execution and
proceedings be had in said cause,
as according to right and justice, and the laws
of the United States, ought to be had, the said appeal
notwithstanding.</p>
<p>Witness the Honorable Melville W. Fuller, Chief of Justice of the
United States, the 31st day of May, in the year
of our Lord one thousand nine hundred and one
COSTS of Van de Vanter, Sheriff, et al.</p>
<p>Clerkj $35.00
Printing Record $29.50
Attorney $20.00
$84.50</p>
<p>James H. Mckenny</p>
<p>Clerk of the Supreme Court of the United States.</p>
<p>#784</p>
<p>GoB 7-3</p>
<p>SUPREME COURT OF THE UNITED STATES</p>
<p>No. 388, October Term, 1900</p>
<p>Charles W. Nordstrom (by
his next friend J. Henry Denning),</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>A. T. Van de Vanter,
Sheriff re., et al.</p>
<p>MANDATE</p>
<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. Circuit Court,
DIST. OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>JUN 10 1901</p>
<p>A. REEVES AYRES, Clerk</p>
<p>HM Matthew Dep.</p>
<p>SUPREME COURT OF THE UNITED STATES OCTOBER TERM 1900</p>
<p>Costs of A.T. Van de Vanter, Sheriff re., et al.,</p>
<p>in No. 388,</p>
<p>1900 October Form appearance, .25,
filing precipie and receipt, .50; filing papers, $2.25; filing motion,
.25; filing briefs, $5.00; submission, .20;
judgment, $1.00; filing
same, .25; recording, .40; mandate, $5.00; preparing record for printer, etc.,
$19.50; cost of printing record, $29.50; attorney's docket fee,
$20.00; costs and copy, .40 
</p>
<p>$84.50</p>
<p>$84.50</p>
<p>Fee Book , paage 17.873</p>
<p>Fees: James H. McKenney</p>
<p>Clerk Supreme Court U. S. </p>
<p> CERTIFICATE</p>
<p>United States of America }</p>
<p>ss.</p>
<p>Western District of Washington }</p>
<p>I, JAMES C. DRAKE, Clerk of the Circuit Court of the United States, for the Western
District of Washington, do hereby certify that the foregoing attached papers constitute the
JUDGMENT ROLL in the foregoing entitled cause, No. 784
wherein In re: Application of
Charles W. Nordstrom for
Writ of Habeas Corpus Plaintiff
and 
Defendant</p>
<p> In Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto set my hand and
offixed the Seal of said Circuit Court, this the 
30 day of DEC A. D. 1911</p>
<p>JAMES C. DRAKE</p>
<p>Clerk.</p>
<p>By B Owigher</p>
<p>Deputy Clerk.</p>
<fw type="footer"> &amp;</fw>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>