<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0216.036">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chin Hing v. United States of America. Interrogatory</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Russell, Ellie" xml:id="edr">Ellie Russell</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Petitioning for Freedom</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0216.036</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Chin Hing v. United States of America. Interrogatory</title>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US District Court Western Division of Washington, Seattle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hing, Chin</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Sullivan, John J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, John J.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#edr">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the United States District Court, for the Western District 
of Washington Norther Division</p>
<p>In The Matter of
Chin Hing</p>
<p><add>#2857</add>
Interrogatories to be propounded
to Louis D. Post, Assistant
Secretary of the Department
of Labor., Washington, D. C.</p>
<pb/>

<p>1. Are you the Assistant Secretary of Labor, and if so,
when were you appointed to such office?</p>
<p>2. Were you on duty at the Department of Labor on each
of the following dated: September 24th, 1914, September 25th, 1914
and September 26th, 1914?</p>
<p>3. What office does Mr. J. B. Densmore hold in your 
Department, if any?</p>
<p>4.State whether it is or is not the custom for Mr. J.
B. Densmore, the Solicitor for the Department of Labor, to consider
and decide appeals in Chinese and immigration cases, as "Acting
Secretary" of Labor, notwithstanding the fact that you or Secretary 
Wilson, or both of you, may be on duty at the time when Mr. Densmore
asumes to act as Secretary?</p>
<p>5. Did you formerly excercise the functions of "Acting
Secretary" in considering and deciding Chinese appeal cases, at
any time when Mr. Densmore was on duty in the Department? If so,
why or upon what authority were Chinese appeal cases taken from you
and given to Mr. Densmore to decide, and when?</p>
<p>6. Have you been advised, officially or otherwise, of
any ruling made by a Federal Court of the United States, that Mr. 
Densmore cannot lawfully decide Chinese appeal cases, as "Acting
Secretary" if either the Secretary or Assistant Secretary of Labor
or either of them shal be on duty in the Department of Labor at 
the time when Mr. Densmore assumes to so act?</p>

<p>7. If so, do you know whether Mr. Densmore had decided
or continues to decide any Chinese appeal cases since such ruling?</p>
<p>8.Do you know whether or not Secretary Wilson has been
absent from the Department for any lengthy period since this case
or any other case in which the same question is involved, has
been pending in court, and if so, when?</p>
<p>9. Were you or were you not the Acting Secretary during
his abence, if he was absent?</p>
<p>10. Did you decide any Chinese appeal cases as Acting
Secretary during Secretary Wilson's abseence, and if not, why not,
and who did assume to act as Acting Secretary in his absence
while you were present in the Department of Labor?</p>
<p>11. Did J. B. Densmore, in giving his ruling in any of
the Chinese appeal cases which he either affirmed or reviewed
while either you or Secretary Wilson were present in the Department
of Labor, sign his name as "J. B. Densmore, Acting Secretary
of Labor."?</p>
<p>12. Will you state on what date the ruling of "Acting
Secretary" Densmore was made in the case of Ching Hing, in affirming
the Order of Deportation, and whether or not on said date
either you of Secretary Wilson, or both of you, were present in
the Department of Labor?</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>