<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0000.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1891">1891</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-09" who="#lkw">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

"In the Superior Court of the State of Washington, for King
County.

The State of Washington, Plaintiff.
vs
Adolph Krug and Henry Fihrman, Defendants.

Number 864.
Indictment.

Adolph Krug and Henry Fuhrman are accused by the Grand
Jury of the State of Washington, in and for King County, said state, 
by this indictment of the crime of using public money in order to
make a profit out of the same, and for purposes not then and there 
authorized by law, committed as follows:

That on the 2nd day of July, 1892, the said Adolph Krug
then and there being and at said time was a city officer, to-wit:
the duly elected, qualified and acting city treasurer of the City
of Seattle, in the County of King, State of Washington, and being
then and there charged under the provisions of the charter and the
amendments thereto of the said city of Seattle, the said charter
being commonly known as the Freeholder' charter, with the receiving
and safe keeping of all moneys belonging to and the property of
the said city of Seattle; the said city of Seattle then and there
being a municipal corporation duly organized and existing under and
by virtue of the laws of the Territory (now state) of Washington,
and as such officer and city treasurer as aforesaid, the said
Adolph Krug was then and there by virtue of his said city office
entrusted with the sum and amount of $10,000.00 in lawful money,
for safe keeping, the same being public money belonging to and the 
property of the said city of Seattle, and which said money was under
the care, custody and control of the said Adolph Krug as such officer
and city treasurer as aforesaid, and the said Adolph Krug, officer
and city treasurer as aforesaid on the 2nd day of July, 1892 in said
King County, State of Washington, unlawfully, feloniously and in a 
manner not authorized by law, did use the said $10,000.00 public
money as aforesaid, of the value of $10,000.00 in lawful money,
in order to make a profit out of the same and for a purpose then
and there not authorized by law; and the said Henry Fuhrman then
and there at the time aforesaid, the said Adolph Krug in the manner
and form as aforesaid unlawfully and feloniously did aid, counsel,
abet and assist,

Contrary to the form of the statute in such cases made
and provided and against the peace and dignity of the state of
Washington.

Dated at Seattle in the county and state aforesaid, this
the 23rd day of October, 1893.

John F. Miller.

Prosecuting Attorney. "

(3)

<pb/>

which indictment is alleged to be framed and founded under
Section 57 of the Code of Washington, known as the Second
Volumbe of Hill's Code.

That upon the said indictment there was a trial had before
jury of the County of King, and the jury in that said cause,
Number 864 rendered a verdict of guilty.

That upon the said verdict an alleged judgment was rendered
against the defendant by one of the Judges of the Superior 
Court of King County, in words and figures following, to-wit:

IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON FOR THE COUNTY OF
KING.

Monday March 26, 1894.

The State of Washington,
864
vs
Adolph Krug, impleaded with
Henry Furhman,

Motion denied,
Sentence, etc.

And now this cause comes on for further hearing on defendant's 
motion to set aside verdict and for a new trial, pursuant to continuance,
thereof, the State appearing by the Prosecuting Attorney,
John F.Miller, and defendant appearing in person and by his Counsel,
Messrs. Lewis, Gilman &amp; Fishback. And now upon due consideration 
thereof said defendant's motion for a new trial is denied, to
which ruling defendant excepts and the exception is allowed, defendant
thereupon moves the court for arrest of judgment; which motion
on consideration thereof is denied. Exception taken by defendant
is allowed.

And now upon motion of the Prosecuting Attorney the said defendant,
Adolph Krug, is brought before the bar of the court to be 
sentenced.

And no legal cause being shwon or appearing to the court why
judgment should not be pronounced upon the defendant, the court
sentences the said defendant, Adolph Krug, to be punished by confinement 
at hard labor in the Penitentiary of the State of Washington
for a term of Seven (7) years and to pay all costs of this action
Defendant's counsel therupon give notice in open court 
of their appeal from the verdict and the judgment of this court to
the Supreme Court of the State of Washington. And the Court fixes
and determines the amount of defendant's Appeal Bond in the sum of
$5.000.00

<pb/>

which judgment was rendered on the 26th day of March
1894.

V1.

That the said alleged judment is still in existence.
That the same has been appealed from to the Supreme Court of
the State of Washington, and the said judgment affirmed, and is
now in existence and in force and full effect. That under said
judgment the said Moyer assumes to imprison and to keep imprisoned
and to have imprisoned in the penitentiary of the State of
Washington this petitioner, and now threatens and continues to
threaten to seize the body of this petitioner from his present
imprisonment and convey him to further imprisonment, to-wit:
to the penitentiary of the state of Washington, where he is
to be held for the petiod of Seven years.

V11.

That the imprisonment of this petitioner by the said
Moyer, or any other person, under the said alleged judgment
and proceeding would wholly be contrary to petitioner's right
as a citizen of the United States, and particularly in violation
of your petitioner's rights as a citizen of the United States,
contrary to the laws of the United States, in violation of the
Constitution of the United States and directly against the
special right and immunity and exemption from imprisonment
without due process of law, as provided by the Constitution of
the United States, in behalf of this petitioner as a citizen of
the United States; all of which more particularly appears in
the following, detailed, manifested and exhibited to the Court,
viz:

V111.

That the Constitution of the United States prescribes
in Article VI., that "No person shall be held, etc., to answer

(5)

<pb/>

the charge of an infamous crime without due process of law
###". And the further provision that "Such person when held
or attempted to be held shall by indictment be informed of the
nature and cause of the accusation". That this provision was in
pursuit of the Common Law and meant that the facts and circumstances 
of the charge shall be presented to the defendant in
complete detail, that he may understand the same and prepare to
defend himself with the same detail essential to meet the charge
against him.

1X.

That the State of Washington when admitted into the
Union was admitted by express contract in the Enabling Act
that the Constitution of the State of Washington should not be
repugnant to or inconsistent with the Federal Constitution.
That in view and in pursuit of this provision and mandate, 
the Constitution of the state of Washington did provide and 
does now provide and at all times hereinafter state it was
provided that "In Criminal prosecutions the accused shall have
the right ### to demand the nature and cause of the accusation 
against him; to have a copy thereof, etc.", being Section
22 of the Constitution.

X.

That notwithstanding such provisions, this petitioner was
arraigned upon the form of alleged indictment hereinbefore stated
and immediately in the Superior Court demurred to the same upon
the ground that it did not state the facts nor inform him of the 
nature and cause of his accusation; that the Code of Washington
provided that in all criminal offenses, being the laws of
Washington, and in all informations or indictments, the information
or the indictment must contain ### a statement of the acts
constituting the offense, in ordinary and concise language,
without repetitions, and in such a manner as to enable a person of

(6)

<pb/>

common understanding to know what is intended", being section
5944 of the Code of '96.

That the demurrer of petitioner to the alleged indictment
for the reason that it did not inform him of the nature and
cause of the accusation was overruled on the ground and for
the reason that in the particular case in which your petitioner
was indicted and arraigned, such was not necessary; that it
was only necessary in such case to charge him in a "general way",
as provided by the Act of the Legislature of the State of
Washington, of December 20th, 1889 and contained in Hill's
Code, Dec. 58, Vol. 2, prescribing and providing that in the
particular offenses provided for in Sec. 57 of the Code of
Washington, the special rule shall obtain, and that notwithstanding
the Constitution and the general laws of the state
and the Constitution of the United States, in all provided
and guaranteed that in all offenses the special acts and the
nature and cause specifically of the accusation was to be
presented to the defendant, that in the present instance and
instances where the defendant was charged, and in his case,
and in the indictment with which he was charged, and as to the
offense with which he was charged, it was only necessary "to
allege generally the general fact," without "specifying any 
further particulars," and that notwithstanding such, "on the
trial thereof, all other facts of every nature could be proven
against the defendant, though the same had been in no wise
specifically set up or plead, or the nature or the cause of
the same at any time set forth by presentment, information or
indictment."

X1.

That upon the overruling of the demurrer your petitioner
was put to trial upon the said indictment, and testimony ofered
upon the said indictment, which was in no wise a part of the
same or could be a part of the same, and which, from the

(7)

<pb/>

manner of the indictment it was impossible for your petitioner
to know could have been intended or expected. Your petitioner
duly objected to the same because the same was not plead and
because the same was not set forth, all of which objections
were overruled and exceptions duly preserved. Your petitioner
moved in due time for Bill of Particulars of the said indictment,
asking that the Bill of Particulars should set forth
what was intended to be charged specifically against the
defendant under the general allegation of the alleged indictment,
which petition and a request and motion for Bill of
Particulars was denied to your petitioner, to which there was
exception duly preserved by your petitioner. That the cause
proceeded to trial, and upon the said indictment, your petitioner
being in no wise informed as to the manner of the cause
to be submitted against him, was unable to prepare for his
defense, and was surprised at the nature of the testimony;
had prepared his defense along the line of what he believed
was the nature of the cause and charge as he had gathered it
from common rumor and common report, but the evidence introduced
under the said alleged indictment was of such a nature so foreigh
to what he believed and understood that he was wholly 
misled as to his defense, and at the close of the case of the
State, so informed the Judge of the Court, and made his showing
of such surprise, and objected to the consideration of the
testimoy because of such surpise and injustice,which objection
was overruled; duly made motion for time in which to prepare
his defense, submitting himself to any reasonable time the
Court would give, even the short period of 12 hours, which was
denied your petitioner, to which your petitioner excepted.
Your petitioner being unable to proceed further, having no
witnesses, his preparation having been along the lines
different from that of the evidence introduced against him,

(8)

<pb/>

and having no opportunity to prepare his defense in view of
the manner of the prosecution, was compeled and thus forced
to submit himself as a citizen of the United States to the
prosecution against him without opportunity to meet the same
and to defend the same, and a jury under the instruction of the
Judge and acting under the authority of the Court, rendered
a verdict upon the said testimony against your petitioner,
upon the testimony offered against him and because and forsooth 
your petitioner could offer no testimony in his behalf
for want of time or opportunity to prepare his defense; your
petitioner having full and complete defense, and your petitioner
being then as he now alleges, not guilty of the charge
against him.

X11.

That thereafter your petitioner was by the Superior 
Court of King County sentenced to imprisonment upon the said
unjust verdict, and from the said judgment did duly appeal to
the Supreme Court of the State of Washington, and therein
his said appeal presented his alleged wrongs, and particularly
that as a citizen of the United States he had been proceeded
against by the state of Washington and his liberty taken without
due pocess of law, in that to-wit: that the alleged
indictment in no wise conformed to the Constitution of the
State of Washington or of the Constitution of the United States
in apprising him of the nature and cause of his accusation,
but constituted a trap to seize and allure and subsequently
to destroy his liberty as such citizen of the United States,
contrary to his protest and against the Constitution of the
United States and the laws therein.

X111.

That the cause came on duly for hearing before the
Supreme Court of the State of Washington: that the said

(9)

<pb/>

Supreme Cout of the State of Washington sustained the contention
of Appellant, admitting that the said alleged indictment 
against him did not conform to the Code of Washington in that
particular portion and part commanding that it shall state the
acts and facts constituting the offense. That the aleged
indictment did not conform to the constitutional provision
both of the state of Washington and of the United States,
requiring that the defendant, your petitioner, be informed of
the nature and cause of his accusation. That the
Supreme Court admitted, adjudicated and adjudged that under the
law generally any person would have a right to have the nature
and cause of the accusation set out and presented, and
particularly if he were a citizen of the United States; that
his rights as such citizen were to demand and to have the
nature and cause of the accusation specifically set out,
that he may be able to prepare and meet the same and defend
against the same; but the Supreme Court of the State of
Washington further decided and held that as it was true, and
your petitioner alleges it so to be, that as to your petitioner
and the cause with which he was charged and the offense which
was alleged against him and the crime with which he was
charged, the Legislature of the State of Washington in
behalf of the state of Washington, had by the Act of its
Legislature of December 29th, 1889, paragraph 2, as shown in
the 2nd Volume of Hill's Code, Sec. 58, that it was only
necessary to set forth generally that your petitioner had
committed the crime alleged against him, and that no other
details or specifications of any other or further particulars

(10).

<pb/>

concerning either the manner, the mode, the method of the
commission or the acts which constituted, or the facts of 
which it was a part or which made it up, be set up or given to
the defendant, either in the alleged indictment or by a 
Bill of Particulars, and that such legislation justified a
departure from the Constitution and fundamental rights
guaranteed all persons and all citizens of the of the State
of Washington, <add>and the United States</add> to the extent that the defendant be made an
exception and that he would have to suffer his prosecution
in the form it was presented, notwithstanding the surprise 
and the wrong and injustice it did him in preventing him from
making his defense in not apprising him of the nature and 
cause of the accusation; that the Legislature of the state of
Washington had said that in this particular case the right to be
apprised of the nature and cause of the accusation was not the 
defendant's, and that in this particular prosecution the right
to demand the nature and cause of the accusation by either
Bill of Particulars or specific indictment had not been
accorded to this defendant, but as to him and his kind it had 
been legislated that they were not to have the rights and the
privileges accorded to every other citizen charged with any
other offense under the laws of the state of Washington or as
such citizen of the United States and as such citizen of the
United States would have under the laws of the state of Washington
or the laws of the United States; and further, that the
Legislature had prescribed that what rights and immunities 
and privileges had been accorded other citizens of the
State of Washington in other prosecutions by the constitution
of the United States, was suspended and denied and not intended
to be accorded to the defendant as a citizen of the United 
States charged as he was with the offense hereinbefore set
out, forsooth and because the legislature had so provided:

(11)

<pb/>

and for this reason, and this reason alone, the Supreme
Court sustained the validity of the prosecution against your
petitioner, upon which ruling the sentence against your 
petitioner was affirmed.

X1V.

Your petitioner asserts that in his brief and presentation 
to the Supreme Court of the State of Washington, he
could not have assumed and did not assume that the Supreme
Court would admit that the said indictment was illegal as against
the Constitution and the laws of the United States and the
State of Washington, and espouse it wholly under this provision
of the right to make a special exception and to deny the
general rights and general immunities to your petitioner
which were accorded to every other citizen under the constitution
and laws of the United States and the State of Washington.
Your petitioner duly made petition for re-hearing, seeking to
show that such statute and law under which the said indictment
was now being upheld, was contrary to the constitution of the
state of Washington and particularly contrary to the constitution
of the United States and to the rights of your petitioner
as a citizen of the United States, but the said Supreme
Court refused the said petition upon the ground that as "that
"question was not originally raided in the original brief, it
" would not be considered, and that therefore they were not
"called on to pass upon the question further."

XV.

That from the said judgment your petitioner, contending
that the said manner of prosecution was contrary to his rights
as a citizen of the United States, under the laws of the United 
States, did duly appeal to the Supreme Court of the United
States, and the cause was there heard, and the Supreme Court of
the United States decided that it did not have jurisdiction

(12)

<pb/>

of the question, for that the principal Federal question; that
is the denial to the defendant, your petitioner, of equal
rights, immunities and privileges under the law, by reason of
the particular legislation which was offered to justify the
form of the indictment, had not been raised in the Supreme 
Court of the State, or if raised, had not been passed upon,
and therefore was not a subject for appeal; reserving, however,
to your petitioner, along with what was then and is now known
as the "Chapman case", the right to prosecute his remedy in an 
original proceeding in the United States Court in the jurisdiction
where the state Court had been held which had adjudged
your petitioner's rights against him. 

XV1. 

That the time has elapsed in which appeal could be
made again to the Supreme Court of the State of Washington.
That the time has elappsed in which appeal could be made from
the Supreme Court of the State of Washington to the Supreme
Court of the United States, and your petitioner is put to
his remedy, the only one left him, but which is reserved by
the law, of appeal to the United States Court by a Writ of
Habeas Corpus that his rights may be inquired into, as shown by
his petition, and which are particularly:

XV11.

That the State of Washington in assuming to pass that
certain Act of its Legislature, of the session of 1889, being
Section 58 of Hill's Code, wholly violated Section 1 of the
14th Amendment of the Constitution prescribing: "No state
shall make or enforce any law which shall abridge the privileges 
or immunities of citizens of the United States; nor
shall any state deprive any person of life, liberty or property
without due process of law, nor deny to any person within
its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws".

(13).

<pb/>

Your petitioner asserts that when the Legislature of the
State of Washington enacted and the Courts enforced the
enactment saying that your petitioner should not have the
equal privilege as a citizen of the United States of any
other citizen charged with an offense, of being informed of
the nature and cause of the accusation against him, it was a 
denial to him of the privilege guaranteed to all other citizens
of the United States and the state of Washington.
That when the State of Washington enacted <add>the</add> by legislation
and the Courts enforced it, provided in Section 58 of the
Code of Washington, Acts of 1889, as hereinbefore referred to,
it denied and refused to your petitioner as a citizen of the
United States, the immunity under the law guaranteed to
every other citizen, of being exempt from criminal prosecution
except upon and information or an indictment that shall
inform him of the nature and cause of the accusation, and of
that other immunity found in the legislation of the state of
Washington saying that in all criminal prosecutions the facts
and acts constituting the offense must be set up in the
information or indictment. And your petitioner further states 
that such privileges were accorded to all other citizens
of the United States and the State of Washington, and such
immunities, but denied unto your petitioner by such legislation
and by such specific Act of the legislature, and such
ruling of the Courts, and particularly the decision of the
Supreme Court of the State of Washington in that particular
cause hereinbefore referred to and herein now referred to,
and more particularly set out in "Krug vs The State",
reported in 12<unclear/> Volume of Washington State
Reports, page 288

(14)

<pb/>

And your petitioner further asserts that the State of 
Washington by such provision and the enforcement of the same
is depriving your petitioner of his liberty without due process
of law.

And your petitioner further asserts that by such provision
your petitioner is being denied and has been denied by the
Courts equal protection of the laws of the State of Washington
within the jurisdiction of the State of Washington, contrary
to the rights accorded other citizens of the United States
within the state of Washington, and that in so doing the state
of Washington is violating the Constitution of the United 
States and the laws of the United States guaranteeing to your
petitioner as a citizen of the United States equal rights and 
immunities under the law in prosecution for an infamous offense
by due process of law, and particularly abridging the privilege
and immunity of your petitioner as a citizen of the
United States as distinguished and particularly as compared 
to the privileges and immunities other citizens of the
United States have under the general laws of the State of
Washington, who may be charged in the State of Washington
with offenses against the laws.

XV111.

That should the State of Washington through its officers
be permited to continue its restraint and imprisonment of
your petitioner, your petitioner will have been denied his constitutional
rights as a citizen of the United States, and as a 
citizen of the United States be denied his liberty and have the
same taken from him without due process of law, and his privileges
and immunities denied him by the State of Washingtion,
which privileges and immunities are assured him as a citizen 
of the United States.

(15)

<pb/>

X1X.

And your petitioner represents that the record herein
stated in this petition is true and states the truth; and that
for further information, should the Court desire the same,
a Writ of Certiorari addressed to the Clerk of the Superior
Court of King County for any other or further record in this 
cause Number 864, would produce under certificate the said
record for other or further information of the Court, should
the same be necessary.

And your petitioner by this petition seeks to have the state
give him a fair trial and the benefit of the processes of the
law guaranteed to any other citizen of the United States within
the State of Washington, and nothing more; and here and now
seeks from the Court that this petition be heard by the Court, 
and that a decree be rendered by the Court, and an order made
by the Judge that petitioner's prosecution, judgment and imprisonment
was in violation of his rights as a citizen of the
United States, and particularly under the 14th Amendment of
the Constitution of the United States, and that upon such
hearing your petitioner may be accorded such judgment as to the
Court would seem just in the premises, whether the same be
absolute discharge or conditional order that the state submit
him to trial upon a presentment of some form which shall disclose
the nature and cause of his accusation and provide and
insure him the due protection under the laws and preservation
of privileges and immunities of other citizens of the United
States, and particularly the due process of law by which the
nature and cause of his accusation may be manifested, <del>in him</del>
that he may know the same and prepare to meet the same; and
that shall the state refuse so to do within a certain length
of time, he shall receive at the hands of the Court his
absolute discharge from such unjust imprisonment and unjust

(16)

<pb/>

retention, and for which purpose he seeks the gracious Writ of
Habeas Corpus, that he may be brought before the Court for
inquiry upon the matters and things herein alleged, and for 
which and
WHEREFORE, Your Petitioner prays:

That the Court will issue its Writ of Habeas Corpus,
addressed to William H. Moyer, the sheriff of King County,
State of Washington, commanding him to produce the body of your
petitioner before your Honor as one of the Judges of the
Circuit Court, as such time and place as shall be convenient
and meet to the Court. That the cause herein stated and
the matters herein plead may be duly inquired into, and due
order made, as under the law and the circumstances of the cause
shall seem just, meet and proper, and that your Honor may
issue your Writ of Certorari on the Superior Court of the
County of King, to the Clerk thereof, for any other information
or record which may be deemed by the Court essential for further
knowledge or information in the said cause than the record
here exhibited and contained shall disclose. And that your
Honor shall make any other order and orders in the premises
that shall be meet and just and in the distribution of the 
justice due to any other citizen of the United States, as to
your Petitioner.

And your Petitioner will ever pray, etc.

Adolph Krug

<unclear>J.M. Hamilton Lewis-
Attorney for Petitioner

Occidental Block Seattle.

J. A. Statton

L. C. Lilman

J Henry Denning
O.F. Counsel</unclear>

(17)

<pb/>

UNITED STATES OF AMERICA,
STATE OF WASHINGTON,
COUNTY OF KING.

ss.

Adolph Krug being by me first duly sworn, on oath
deposes and says: That he is the Petitioner
named inthe foregoing petition; that he has heard the same read,
knows the contents thereof, and <add>that</add> <del>believes</del> the same is <del>to be</del>true.

Adolph Krug.

Subscribed and sworn to before me this 11th day of February A.D. 1897

J Henry Denning.
Notary Public within and for the State of WAshingotn,
Residing at Seattle, King County

<del>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA,
STATE OF WASHINGTON,
COUNTY OF KING. 

ss.

I HEREBY CERTIFY, That I have compared the foregoing copy with the original complaint
on file with the Clerk of the within entitled Court, in the foregoing-named action, and that the
same is a true, correct and exact copy thereof.</del>

Attorney ofr Plaintiff.

<pb/>

No. 599

In the Circuit Court
OF THE UNITED STATES,
FOR THE
DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
NORTHERN DIVISION.

In the matter of the
Petition of
Adolph Krug
for Writ of Habeas Corpus

FILED Feby 15 1897
IN THE
U.S. CIRCUIT COURT
A. Reeves Ayres.
CLERK

A.N. Moore

Jas Hammilton Lewis <add>,</add> S L C
<del>Stratton, Lewis &amp; Gilman.</del>

for petitioner

101-106 Occidental Block, Seattle.

Copy of within
received and due service of the same
acknowledged this day of 
1896.

Attorney for










</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>