<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1000-01">Month YYYY</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-12" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>1227</p>

<p>In the Circuit Court of the United States Ninth Circuit</p>

<p>Affidavits in Support of Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Filed in the U.S. Circuit Court. District of Washington</p>

<p>OCT 7 1904</p>

<p>A. Reeves Ayres, Clerk</p>

<p>A. N. Moore, Deputy</p>

<pb/>

<p>United States of America, District of Montana</p>

<p>In the matter of the petition of Ham Hung Wah, for a writ of habeas corpus</p>

<p>And now come Lester S. William, Merchant, Charles W. Jackson, Merchant, Robert W. Stualdson, Pastor
Presby. Church, Joseph H. Baker <unclear>job</unclear>, E. M. Garemey, Real Estate and being severally
duly sworn, upon their corporal oath, doth depose and say, each for himself, and not one for another, that
he is and has been for more than ten years last past a resident of Bozeman, Gallatin County, Montana. That
he knows the Chinaman Tom Sing and  his wife Na Lay, who, during a large portion of said period of time have
resided in said Bozeman; that when they first came to Bozeman, they were reputed to be husband and wife, and
lived and cohabited together as such. That after residing in said City some time, they adopted the habits of
western civilization as to dress, abandoned the religion generally believed and practised by their countrymen,
and became members in good standing of the Presbyterian Church, which membership they now maintain. That they
are persons of exceptional intelligence and propriety of demeanor, the Mother speaking the English language with
a fluency and propriety equal to that of almost any native born American. That when they joined said church, in
confirmation of thier status of husband and wife, they were married according to the forms of Presbyterian Church,
having, as it was reputed, been theretofore married in the Empire of China. That the said Tom Sing is a credible witness,
whose reputation for truth and veracity entitles him to be believed.</p>

<pb/>

<p>That his statement, with that of his said wife, as to the place and circumstances of the birth of said Ham
Hung Wah comports with what we know of it by reputation, and we believe the same to be true, and that if the
opportunity shall be aforded to take the testimony of producable witnesses, and hav it examined judicially, it will
be made to appear that the said Ham Hung Wah was born in Montana, subject to the jurisdiction of, and a citizen of the
United States, and that in the matter of the attempted entry of him the said Ham Hung Wah, no attempt is being made
to impose upon the authorities or to obtain an unlawful entry of a Chinese person within the United States.</p>

<p>And further affiants say not.</p>

<p>Lester S. William, Merchant</p>
<p>Charles W. Jackson, Merchant</p>
<p>Robert W. Stualdson, Paster Presbytarian Church since Oct 1st 1902</p>
<p>Joesph H. Baker, <unclear></unclear></p>
<p>E. M. Garemey, Real Estate</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to beforeme this third day of October, 1904.</p>

<p>A. T. McPhurston
   U. S. Commissioner</p>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>