<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0212.006">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Taka Shibata v. Henry M. White. Memorandum of Points and Authorities</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0212.006</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Taka Shibata v. Henry M. White. Memorandum of Points and Authorities</title>
<date when="1920-07-16">July 16, 1920</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1920-07">July 1920</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Nebraska</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Shibata, Taka</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Davis, P.V.</persName>
<persName>Kiefer, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
<persName>Capers, R.E</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
<persName>Rudkin, Frank H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-02" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>No. <supplied>5449</supplied></p>

<p>In the United States District Court for the Western District of Washington</p>

<p>Filed in the United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>Tx</p>

<p>Jul 16 1920</p>

<p>F.M. Harshberger, Clerk</p>
<p>By S.E. Leitch Deputy</p>

<p>James Kiefer</p>
<p>for</p>
<p>Suite 327 Colman Bldg.</p>
<p>Seattle</p>

<p>Copy of within Memorandum received and service of same acknowledged this 16 day of July, 1920</p>

<p>Robt. C. Saunders</p>
<p>For Plaintiff</p>
<p>ED Dalton</p>

<p>The office of the undersigned, Suite 327 Colman Building, Seattle, Washington, is designated as the place at which service of all subsequent papers in this cause, except writs and process, may be made, and the undersigned hereby consents that service may be made at the said place of all subsequent papers. except writs and process.</p>

<pb/>

<p>No.5449.</p>
<p>Memorandum of Points and Authorities.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Petition of Taka Shibata for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>A reading of the record before the Board of Special Inquiry cannot fail to convince the court that the Board acted upon its suspicions and wishes rather than upon the evidence before it.</p>

<p>The first inquiry before the court is did the petitioner have a fair hearing before the Board? In the first place, the Board was not legally constituted. The stenographer is not an Immigration Officer and could not properly be a member of the Board.</p>

<p>U.S.vs. Redfern, 180 Fed. 500, establishes the rule that the Board of Special Inquiry must be composed of Immigration Officers. Such is the language of the Statute and it cannot be dispensed with.</p>

<p>When the evidence is read and reviewed by the court it is difficult to avoid the conclusion that the Board acted wholly upon its suspicions and ignored all the evidence.</p>

<p>It is undisputed that the petitioner was regularly married to her husband who came here from Nebraska to join her. It is not disputed that the petitioner left the Immigration station and went with her husband and lived with him for several days and that thereafter difficulties arose. It is submitted that the Immigrations authorities having landed the petitioner and admitted her to the country the burden now rests upon the prosecution to sustain their charge of entering the country through a conspiracy and not in good faith. There is absolutely nothing in the record except the conclusion of a disappointed husband to sustain the theory that the petitioner did not act in good faith throughout. He does not testify, it will be observed, to any declaration or act of the petitioner which is in anywise inconsistent with the best of faith. He simply states his own inference or conclusion, and the court should keep in mind that he is a disappointed husband, who has paid for the transportation for the petitioner, as well as his own expenses from Nebraska to Seattle, and add to that the natural pique of humiliation of a bridegroom apparently deserted at the altar. This accounts for his construction of petitioner's actions. The testimony shows nothing but ordinary domestic difficulties. The reasons for it are plainly apparent on the record. There seems to be a substantial difference in the educations and social stations of the parties. But more than that, the petitioner came to Seattle, found several relatives here and what is more natural than that she should refuse to go away from where she has relatives to Nebraska on a lonely farm. Her course is not to be commended, but is easily understood. There is nothing whatsoever shown by the record to indicate anything but the ordinary difficulties of a newly married couple to adjust themselves. It appears too that these relatives have in god faith endeavored to effect a reconciliation, but without result.</p>

<p>Now as to the likelihood of becoming a public charge. It is undisputed that the full-blood brother of petitioner is amply able to provide for her and thoroughly willing to do so. The Board of Special Inquiry seems to have proceeded on the theory that inasmuch as they questioned the right of petitioner to remain in the country therefore she must be in danger of becoming a public charge.</p>

<p>The court will review the arbitary and unreasonable acts of the Board of Special Inquiry.</p>

<p>Gegow vs. Uhl, 239 U.S. 3, 60 L. ed. 44;</p>
<p>U.S. vs. Suekichi, 199 Fed. 751;</p>
<p>U.S. vs. Redfern, 180 Fed. 500,</p>
<p>U.S. vs.Martin, 193 Fe. 795.</p>

<p></p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>