<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0368.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Matoba Watari v. T. W. Lynch. Brief of Respondent</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Silva, Salma J." xml:id="sjs">Salma J. Silva</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0368.005</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Matoba Watari v. T. W. Lynch. Brief of Respondent</title>
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date/></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Watari, Matoba</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Lynch, T.W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Allen</persName>
<persName>Martin</persName>
<persName>Wardall</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Faulkner, Judson</persName>
<persName>Revelle, Thomas P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>The District Court of the United States, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>Western District of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2020-07" who="#sjs">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>United States District Court</p>
<p>Western District of Washington</p>
<p>Northern Division</p>

<p>No. 6361</p>

<p>Brief of Respondent:</p>

<p>No. 6360</p>

<p>Dec 4918</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of TERAMOTO SADASHIGE for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>TERAMOTO SADASHIGE, Petitioner,</p>

<p>vs</p>

<p>T. W. Lynch, Acting Commissioner of Immigration, Respondent.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of MATOBA WATARI for a Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>MATOBA WATARI, Petitioner</p>

<p>vs</p>

<p>T. W. LYNCH, Acting Commissioner of Immigration, Respondent.</p>

<p>After a concededly impartial hearing before a board of special inquiry, the petitioner, TERAMOTO SADASHIGE, was excluded and ordered deported on the grounds that he was a Japanese laborer attempting to enter in violation of the President's proclamation of February 24, 1913; that he was without a passport; and that he was a stowaway.</p>

<p>It has been admitted that he has never been in possession of a Japanese passport, and that he had no document bearing the </p>

<pb/>

<p>vise of <del>the</del> an American Consul. It is also admitted that when the vessel arrived at the port he was not included in the crew list of the same and that he had been dropped from its articles as a deserter, and further, that whatever residence or domicile he had or claims to have had previously in the United States was acquired as a result of his original unlawful entry therein.</p>

<p>As to petitioner MATOBA WATARI, he was rejected on the same grounds as TERAMOTO SADASHIGE, and also on the further ground that he was afflicted with a loathsome, contagious disease. WATARI claims a lawful domicile in the United States of some twenty years prior to his departure therefrom on the vessel in question. As to him, it is admitted that upon the arrival of the vessel here, he was not included upon the ship's crew list, that he had been dropped as a deserter, and that he was afflicted with gonorrhea.</p>

<p>Both petitioners came as stowaways and both are Japanese alien laborers.</p>

<p>Upon appeal to the Secretary of Labor, the excluding decisions as to both were affirmed.</p>

<p>If it is true that both petitioners are stowaways and attempted to enter as such, the following, we believe, necessarily follows:</p>

<p>1. They are subject to the Immigration laws and regulations in the same manner as though it were an original entry.</p>

<p>The petitioners argue that because of the seventh proviso of Section 3, of the Act of February 5, 1917, to-wit:</p>

<p>-2-</p>

<pb/>

<p>"Provided further, that aliens returning after a temporary absence to an unrelinquished United States domicile of seven consecutive years may be admitted in the discretion of the Secretary of Labor and under such conditions as he may prescribe,"</p>

<p>that they, as a matter of course and as of right, if we gather their argument correctly, are entitled to re-enter, notwithstanding each one of them falls within several excluded classes as described in the Act.</p>

<p>The statement of the proposition and a fair reading of the proviso itself, we believe, demonstrates the fallacy of this position. The proviso clearly leaves the right to re-enter to the discretion of the Secretary, thus contemplating the usual inspection and hearing by the officers of the Department.</p>

<p>To say that they are entitled as a matter of right to re-enter is to do violence to the clear language of the Act leaving the matter to the discretion of the Secretary. The Act further provides for the promulgation of <del>the</del> regulations by the Secretary in regard thereto and by Hule 16, convincing proof of such domicile and intention of returning thereto is required. The Secretary's decision as to the presence or absence of such convincing testimony is final beyond any question under the Chin Yow case, 208 U.S. 8, where it was said that- </p>

<p>"Jurisdiction cannot be established simply by proving that the Commissioner and Department of Labor did not accept certain sworn statements as true even though no contrary or impeaching testimony was adduced."</p>

<p>It is needless to add that there is nothing in the regulations indicating any intention on the part of the Secretary to forego the discretion vested in him. It merely regulates the procedure to be followed in the presentation of the case to the Secretary of Labor.</p>

<p>-3-</p>

<pb/>

<p>That the re-entering of an alien having a former residence subjects him to all the provisions of the Immigration Act was held by your Honor in re Ichitara Matsutsuya No. 4918, where in a decision filed December 18, 1918, your Honor said:</p>

<p>"Did the <del>rehearing</del> into the United States constitute an entry within the purview of the Immigration Act? The solution depends upon the legislative intent of the Congress. The power of Congress over the alien is unlimited. It may admit without limitation, or exclusde without reason; or prescribe rules for admission, or rules of conduct after admission.</p>

<p>The decision of the Federal Courts are not in harmony. The trend of the decisions, however, hold that a re-entering after a temporary absence, is within the purview of the Act, While not deciding, the Supreme Court in Lapina v. Williams 232 U.S. 78, I think, supports that view. The Circuit Court of the 6th Circuit in Frick v. Lewis, 195 Fed. 693, discusses the issue, and holds a re-entry under the Act, In that case, the petitioner had been a resident of the United States for some time; had declared his intention to become a citizen; went into Canada for an hour, and returned, and was, thereafter, ordered deported. The court declined to release him. The same issue was presented to the same court in Sinincalchi v. Thomas, 195 Fed. 701, where it adhered to this view.</p>

<p>In the Lapina case, cited supra, it was said:</p>

<p>"Upon a review of the whole matter, we are satisfied that Congress in the Act of 1903 sufficiently expressed and in the Act of 1907 reiterated, the purpose of applying its prohibition against the admission of aliens, and its mandate for their deportation, to all aliens whose history, condition, or characteristics brought them within the descriptive clauses, irrespective of any qualification arising out of a previous residence or domicile in this country."</p>

<p>See also Frick v. Lewis, 58 L. Ed. p. 967; U.S. v. Nakao (9th C.C.A. 217 Fed. 49) ex parte, Callow, 240 Fed. 212.</p>

<p>2. Being subject to the Immigration Act and to the Act of May 22, 1918, and to the proclamations and executive orders, rules and regulations issued pursuant to both of said acts, these aliens are squarely within several <del>disticnt</del> definitely excluded classes as follows:</p>

<p>-4-</p>

<pb/>

<p>(a) Stowaways (who can only be admitted in the discretion of the Secretary if they are otherwise admissable).</p>

<p>(b) Japanese laborers attempting to enter in violation of the Proclamation of the President of February 24, 1913.</p>

<p>(c) Teramoto, without any passport whatever issued by the Japanese government and without any documents bearing the vise of <del>the</del> an American Consul.</p>

<p>(d) Watari, with no passport bearing such vise within the next preceding year and with only a passport admittedly obtained and used for a prior voyage.</p>

<p>(e) Watari being afflicted with a loathsome contagious disease.</p>

<p>To say, under the circumstances, that petitioners have been denied a fair hearing or that there is no evidence to support the decision of the Secretary is, we believe, to make a statement not borne out by the facts And the inquiry of your Honor should be directed under the decisions to determine only whether such a fair hearing had been had.</p>

<p>Under the provisions of the Immigration Act and the regulations of the Department, these aliens were not "seamen" nor where they members of the crew of the vessel at the timeof its arrival here.</p>

<p>It is provided in Section I of the Act that:</p>

<p>"The term 'seamen' as used in this Act shall include every person signed on the ship's articles and employed in any capacity on board any vessel arriving in the United States from any foreign port or place."</p>

<p>At the time of arrival both had been dropped as deserters and were not employed on the vessel, nor were they</p>

<p>-5-</p>

<pb/>

<p>included in the ship's manifest and crew list, and, therefore, it follows that they entered or attempted to enter as "stowaways."</p>

<p>The Department and the Court should be guided solely by the provisions of the Act. It appears that they were not seamen within the language of the Act and they, therefore, must be treated as stowaways. Neither the Court not the Department should be required, nor should they undertake, toinquire into the collateral question which the petitioners attempt to inject into the issues namely: Did the master wrongfully list them as deserters?</p>

<p>However, considering for the sake of argument, that such inquiry is proper, we submit the record contains abundant evidence of such desertion, and if there is any such evidence, the decision of the Secretary is of course final.</p>

<p>As to WATARI, he testified:</p>

<p>"A. When I arrived at Yokohama I asked the steward to let me go back to my home and see my folks, and he said if you put up your substitute, so I found my substitute and went up to my home. Previously to that I promised the steward to go back to Kobe when the steamer arrived there. After I went home my folks wanted me to stay longer so I went to Kobe to meet the purser to prolong my leave by letting this substitute stay longer, but I could not see them. The officers of the steamer were all out. I asked the substitute to tell them that I would be back on the steamer when she came back to Kobe after going though Hongkong, and other places in Japan. When she returned to Yokohama I went to the boat and saw the purser and he told me that he had finished with me. I could not do anything else so I just stayed on the boat without having any understanding with the purser."</p>

<p>It thus appears that the only permission he had (and that not from a ship's officer) was to re-join the ship when she had arrived at Kobe from Yokohama. Without any further permission, he definitely admitted his intention not to return to the ship</p>

<p>-6-</p>

<p>at Kobe, as he had promised. The fact that he may have intended to re-board the vessel at some future time is immaterial. He did not intend to return according to his promise and the permission granted him. It is submitted that there is plenty of evidence of his animus non revertendi referred to by counsel, and to say that there is no evidence to support the finding of desertion, or to say that the master acted wrongfully or arbitrarily is stating an absurdity. The master took the only course open to him and his action was legitimately based on petitioners' own conduct.</p>

<p>As said in "The Grace Littleton, 50 Fed. 285:</p>

<p>"But the master was pressed for time. He was compelled to fill up his crew at once. He did so. It would be unreasonable to compel him to wait on the recovery of the sailor from the condition in which he put himself. When the place was filled, no subsequent application of the libelant could help him. His own conduct forced the master to go with someone else and if he lost his place libelant can only blame himself.</p>

<p>See also the Ida G. Farren, 127 FEd. 766, and the Strathearn, 239 Fed. 583.</p>

<p>The steward testified that the captain is the proper person to grant the permission, but that "when he is absent I can let them go ashore just so they come back before the ship sails."</p>

<p>As to TERAMOTO, it appears that:</p>

<p>"A. I left here on the 17th of June and arrived there there on the 23rd, and the steward told me if I wanted to leave I could hire my substitute, and I could go if I did. As my home is in Kobe I worked until the steamer arrived in Kobe and asked him for one day leave to visit my folks. It was granted provided I came back five o'clock the sailing date. I returned to the boat about four o'clock as I promised, and found the steamer had sailed at twelve o'clock that day. I missed the boat in Kobe, then I stayed in my home and went to Yokohama with Mr. Matoba and stowawayed on the boat at Yokohama."</p>

<p>-7-</p>

<pb/>

<p>and the steward testified:</p>

<p>"That at this time affiant told him she would leave at five o'clock in the morning, on the 15th, and that Teramoto should be on board before she left, not naming however any hour or particular time."</p>

<p>It thus appears, as to TERAMOTO also, he was instructed by the steward to "be on board before she left." This he failed to do. It is <del>admitted</del> submitted that there is abundant evidence to sustain the decision as to the question of desertion.</p>

<p>Finally, the respondent contends that even though these Japanese were lawful members of the crew upon the return and were wrongfully classed as deserters, and that the Immigration Department is bound to inquire into this collateral matter, nevertheless, they, being aliens, would be subject to the Immigration Act upon their return in the same manner <del>and</del> as any other entering aliens.</p>

<p>The Immigration Act makes no distinction between an alien seaman returning to the United States upon an American boat and any other alien upon his original entry. Of course, for certain purposes, an American vessel will be treated as part of abd as territory of the United States. But that general proposition cannot override the Act itself. As indicated above, the Act makes no such distinction as contended for by counsel, and it is, therefore, submitted that these aliens, admitting for the time being that they were members of the crew, are subject to the same conditions and the same regulations as other entering aliens. We desire particularly in this regard to call to the attention of your Honor the case pf Castner Curran &amp; Bullitt, Inc., v. Hamilton 275 Fed. 703. were it appeared that: (Eastern District of Virginia)</p>

<p>-8-</p>

<pb/>

<p>"The "Winding Guld"', an American steamship on arrival at the port of Norfolk from a European port in January, 1921, was boarded by the immigration official, who removed to the hospital several members of the crew found to be suffering from one or another of the diseases mentioned in Section 35 of the Act of Congress of February 5, 1917, entitled "An Act to regulate the Immigrationof Aliens to and the residence of aliens in the United States." Subsequently, upon the discharge of the seamen from the hospital a claim for the cost of hospital treatment was made against the owners of the vessel, payment was refused the ship was denied clearance and this petitionwas filed praying for a mandamus against the Collector of the Port.</p>

<p>"No further statement is necessary unless it be to mention the fact that the diseased member of the crew for whose hospital expenses the vessel is denied clearance were shipped from the Port of New York, and were completing a voyage from this country to Europe abd return when their diseased condition was discovered."</p>

<p>In that case, the Court said:</p>

<p>"It cannot of course, be contended that this section is inoperative as applied to aliens who were of the crew of American vessels or that their employment on such vessels entitled them by virtue of that fact to entry into the United States on any other or different footing than an alien otherwise employed, Reference to other sections of the former act but fix this conclusion more definitely and confirm the view that the words "Alien" and "alien seamen" as used there are synonymous terms and that though the alien may become, for many purposes, by virtue of his signing on an American vessel, and American seamen, he nevertheless continues so far as the laws relating to immigration are concerned both an alien and alien seaman."</p>

<p>Respectfully submitted,</p>

<p>Thomas P. Revelle</p>
<p>United States Attorney</p>

<p><unclear>Judson F. Faulknor</unclear></p>
<p>Assistant United States Attorney</p>

<pb/>

<p>No. 6360 and 6361</p>

<p>(Consolidated)</p>

<p>In the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington.</p>
<p>Northern Division.</p>

<p>In Matter of applications for Writs of Habeas Corpus: MATOBA WATARI and TERAMOTO SADASHIGE Petitioners, vs T.W. LYNCH, Acting Commsr' of Immigration, Respondent</p>

<p>Brief of Respondent</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>