<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0000.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title></title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Yu, Jingming" xml:id="jy">Jingming Yu</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Fletcher Decker v. State of Washington</title>
<date when="2022-06-20">June 20, 2022</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District Of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division, 1899-1906, vol2.</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-08">August 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Fletcher Decker</term>
<term>Thomas Waters</term>
<term>Robert W. McClelland</term>
<term>Charlotte Kolmitz</term>
<term>Adam Beeler</term>
<term>George H. L. Murray</term>
<term>Claude H. Ficklin</term>
<term>Thomas Walter Chard</term>
<term>Ivan L. Hyland</term>
<term>A. J. MacEchen</term>
<term>Frederick McEwan</term>
<term>William James Henry Vigors</term>
<term>Cassius M. Clay Robinson</term>
<term>Charles Burdette Robinson</term>
<term>Jeremiah Neterer</term>
<term>Edward B. Cushman</term>
<term>Sydney Brown Woods</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Saskatchewan , Canada</term>
<term>Ontario, Canada</term>
<term>Seattle, King County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Fletcher Decker</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Charlotte Kolmitz</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Adam Beeler</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
                  
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-06" who="#jy">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0000.000"/>

<p>In the Matter of the Extradition of FLETCHER DECKER.</p>
<p>__________</p>

<p>TRANSCRIPT OF PROCEEDINGS Before Robert W. McClelland, U. S. Commissioner, at Room No. 316 Marion Building, Seattle, Washington, August 24th and 25th, 1921.</p>

<p>_____</p>

<p>APPEARANCES: Miss CHARLOTTE KOLMITZ, Asst. U. S. Attorney, and IVAN L. HYLAND, Esq., (Of Messrs. Tucker &amp; Hyland) For the Petitioner; ADAM BEELER, Esq., (of Messrs. Beeler &amp; Sullivan) appearing for Defendant.</p>

<p>----------</p>


<p>G. H. L. MURRAY,    Being first duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>DIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>By Miss KOLMITZ:</p>

<p>Q    What is your name?</p>
<p>A    George H. L. Murray</p>
<p>Q    Your residence?</p>
<p>A    Seattle.</p>
<p>Q    What is your business or occupation?</p>
<p>A    British <add>Vice</add> Consul at Seattle.</p>
<p>Q    On whose behalf, and under whose authority do you appear here?</p>
<p>A    The Government, at Saskatchewan, Canada.</p>
<p>Q    Where is the Province of Saskatchewan?</p>
<p>A    In Canada.</p>
<p>    Miss. KOLMITZ: That is all. Any questions, Mr. Beeler:</p>
<p>    Mr. BELLER: No.</p>

<p>G. H. L. Murray<!--signed--></p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 26th day of August, 1921.</p>

<p>R. W. McClelland</p>
<p>U. S. Commissioner</p>

<p>Seal<!--written and circled--></p>


<p>CLAUDE H. FICKLIN,  Being first duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>DIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>By Miss KOLMITZ:</p>

<p>Q    What is your name?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Now at this time, if it please the Court, I desire to object to this proceeding, and object to the introduction of any further testimony herein on these grounds; First, that the warrant of arrest issued by the United States Commissioner fails to show upon its face that the Commissioner was authorized to issue, as required in a proceeding of this kind, any extradition, expressly under the treaty of 1842 between Great Britain and the United States, and I have a case directly in point on that objection, and that therefore the warrant of arrest is illegal and void. And, second, object to the introduction of any testimony in this proceeding on the ground that the information and complaint made by F. W. Chard, and which is the basis for this whole proceeding, does not allege facts sufficient to constitute the crime of theft or stealing, as defined by the laws of Canada, and I have the Statute of Canada here to establish that fact. There are a few other objections which I have, but which I do not think should be raised at this time, but which I will raise at the proper time, but I do raise those two at this time.</p>
<p>    (Argument.)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The only question that struck me at the time the warrant was issued, was on the affidavit of Thomas Waters, Deputy Marshal. The question came to my mind; I hadnt much time to look it up, as to whether the affidavit should not have been made by some representative of the British Government of Canada. However, the original complaint was afterwards amended, and that complaint was sworn to by George H. L. Murray, a representative of the British Government; I dont know that it would be necessary to issue a new warrant, an alias warrant, to conform to the ammended complain. I rather take it that the process follows all the pleadings in the case, the original and amended; what do you have to say about that, Mr. Hyland:</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: It seems to me that we have to prove, as a matter of fact in this proceeding, that the extradition is sought by a foreign country, and the original complaint does not show that, as a matter of fact, but the amended complaint does; and I doubt very much whether it is necessary for the complaint to show that, if the proof is shown at the time of th ehearing, that the complaint is sought by a foreign government, and that is the reason for Mr. Murray's testimony here, to supplement and show why the proceeding is brought; it does tno seem to me it makes any difference, whethe rin the original complaint or not, as long as showing is made upon the hearing it was done at the request of the foreign government.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I dont exactly catch your argument in regard to the insufficiency of the warrant; do you contend that the warrant should show on its face, or allege onits fact the authority of the Commissioner for issuing the warrant?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Exactly so, and this decision is absolutely in point. (Reads decision)</p>
<p>    (Argument)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The question arises, have I a right to amend this, or issue an alias warrant; I don't see the logic of it, but if it is necessary I am willing to do it; I can certify that I am authorized to, but that is a very funny sort of proceeding.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: This is a summary proceeding; it seems to me you would have a right to amend that any way you like; of course, I think that the hearing ought to go ahead just the same.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I have the right, or the Government has the right, or the Government of Canada has the right to amend its complaint; I dont know any reason why the process cannot be amended, or an alias warrant issued and served on the amended complaint; this original warrant was issued on the first complaint. I declare I dont see the logic of those decisions at all. I can put a self serving declaration in here that I am duly authorized to act; that does not establish the fact at all.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: You can say on your warrant you are authorized to do this.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Yes; the very fact I have done it is tantamount to that sort of a statement. I believe I will think about it until after lunch; look up my appointment; I dont want to get anybody into trouble.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I have another point I want to present when we convene, before we proceed with the introduction of evidence.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: It dont have reference to jurisdiction?</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: You content there is no complaint under the laws of Canada?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: That is one of my contentions, yes.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: It seems to me that ought to be a matter of proof; it is established by the complaint and affidavit; whether that is sufficient or not. We will adjourn until 2 o'clock.</p>
<p>    (At this time an adjournment was taken until 2 p. m.)</p>

<p>--------</p>


<p>AFTERNOON SESSION, 2 p. m.</p>
<p>Hearing resumed:</p>

<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I thought I was right, Mr. Beeler; I dont think it is necessary for me to certify that fact, but I have certified it on the bottom of the warrant.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Then shall we read the authorization into the record, so that it will be complete, as well as on the warrant; this transcript of the record will go up, and it may as well be in there.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The warrant goes up with the transcript.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: The authorization of the Commissioner will go up as part of the record. We will read that into the record when the time comes.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Does the record show in what capacity you are appearing for the government?</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: The British Vice Consul.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: For the purpose of the record, I want to object to the changing or amending of the warrant at this time.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Very well.</p>
<p>C. H. FICKLIN,   Recalled, testified as follows:</p>
<p>Q   (By Miss Kolmitz) Please state your name again, please.</p>
<p>A    I gave him my initials, not the full name.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: If the Court please, at this time I desire, in view of the fact that the Court has overruled my motion on that warrant, to interpose a demurrer to the sufficiency of the information and complaint, and I will ask the Court, if you have the original of that information and complaint to get it, while I present that matter to the Court.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Is your argument directed to the original or amended complaint?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: To the information and complaint; I think this is the original, is it not?</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: We will put it in for that purpose, if you want to argue it; it is not in evidence yet.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: This is the information and complaint upon which the complaint is based?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: No, the petition.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: There is a complaint filed, and original and amended?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: No, the petition.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I am making my objection to the information and complaint executed by T. W> Chard, dated the 14th day of June 1921, and executed before A. J. G. McCohen; that is the information and complaint I am objecting to, because it is upon the information that this proceeding must ultimately rest; it must stand or fall upon the information and complaint, because that is the information that was issued in Canada, and there isnt another basis upon this subsequent information that was issued here. I presume that Your Honor has the record of which this is a copy.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: No, I dont think I have; I have nothing of that kind before me here. Well, there is in evidence here a certified copy of that proceeding.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: It is just an ordinary copy, if Your Honor please; I havent as yet offered the record.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: This is not a certified copy, this is a true copy.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: I haven't offered the record yet.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Read the charged, and I think you will find it sufficient.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Here is the information and complaint upon which this proceeding is based; it would ultimately rest upon some information and complaint made by some one in Canada for the application of the extradition; and that information and complaint is exactly the same as the one here. (Reading) "I, Thomas Walter Chard, of Regina, in the Province of Saskatchewan, taken this 14th day of June in the year 1921, before the undersigned, A. J. MacEchen, one of His Majesty's Justices of the Peace in and for the said Province, who saith that Fletcher Decker formerly of new Wiwa Hill Post Office, in the said Province, on or about the 15th day of November A. D. 1915, near Wiwa Hill Post Office, aforesaid, in the said Province, did steal about Three Hundred (300) bushes of flax the property of Claude Ficklin and was thereby guilty of theft. (Signed) T. W. Chard. Sworn before me the day and year first above mentioned at Regina, in the said Province. (Signed) A. J. G. MacEchen, a Justice of the Peace in and for the Province of Saskatchewan." Now that is the information and complaint upon which this entire proceeding rests; it cant rest upon anything else, because it is upon that that the warrant to apprehend was issued, and it was upon that that the petition was subsequently issued. Now this information does not allege facts sufficient to constitute a crime under the Canadian statute; the only thing that it alleges is that Fletcher Decker on or about November 15, 1915, did stea; no allegation that the stealing was with intent to comfort it to himself, or that he did appropriate it; merely alleges the conclusion; Might just as well allege tha tthe man murdered a man--did commit murder at such and such a time, and by reason thereof he is guilty of murder.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: In other words, I take it you are raising th epont now there is no allegation of aspertation; is that the idea?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: It is lacking that, and lacking a more material element, it is lacking in the allegation of intent. I will call Your Honor's attention to the statute  upon which this is based; the statute is set out in the papers, that the intent must be shown. Now Section 347 of the Canadian Statutes defines theft. (Reads definition)</p>
<p>    (Argument)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: This is the complaint that was filed before me: "Affiant further says taht at the time aforesaid, to-wit, on the 15th day of November, 1915, it was, and now is, provided by the said Criminal Code of Canada, in and by Section 347 of said Criminal Code of Canada, the same then, and now being in force in said Province of Saskatchewan. in the Dominion of Canada, aforesaid, as follows, to-wit: and it sets out the statute which you have read, together, and in particular the four conditions constituting stealing, and alleging that that is the statute he violated. Of course that is an allegation, as I said this morning, which it seems to me would have to be established differently from establishing a question of law in this county, which the Courts are bound to take judicial notice of; that being a foreign statute would have to be established, as a matter of fact, by the proof. Now as to whethe rth ecomplaint in Canada, as filed in Canada, was sufficient in Canada, and before the Courts of Canada, it seems to me to be a question or an issue to bedetermined up there; I am only acting on the complaint as filed before me under the statute of the United States. Now that complaint does set out in particularity the offense, taking and carrying away, and the intent to steal, and sets out the statute in particularity which he violated.</p>
<p>    (Further argument)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I will overrule the objection; note an exception.</p>

<p>Q    Where do you live, Mr. Ficklin?</p>
<p>A    I live in Eastern Oregon.</p>
<p>Q    Where were you living on or about the 15th day of November, 1915?</p>
<p>A    I was living in Saskatchewan, Canada.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know the defendant, Fletcher Decker?</p>
<p>A    Yes, mam.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know this man seated opposite you?</p>
<p>A    I know Mr. Decker.</p>
<p>Q    Is that the same Mr. Decker you knew then?</p>
<p>A    Yes, mam.</p>
<p>Q    Did you have any difficulties up there with Mr. Decker about that time?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to that.</p>
<p>Q    Have any transactions at all with Mr. Decker about that time?</p>
<p>A    Not in 1915, but a little later we had some dealings.</p>
<p>Q    Was any flax belongign to you taken from you?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to that, Your Honor.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: That is proper, I think.</p>
<p>A    I lost some flax out of one of my graineries in the fall of 1915.</p>
<p>Q    Just state the circumstances and all the facts you know regarding that.</p>
<p>A    Well, in the fall of 1915, I had two farms, and I was living on one, and the farm where the flax was located I was not living on; I threshed some flax early in the fall, some in October, and I was living on the other farm, I was not at this farm where the flax was for a period of time, several weeks, and I wen tou there one afternoon and found some of the flax gone; the window had been broken out, and about half of the flax was missing. I went in town and notified the Mounted Police, and secured around the country for several days to see what I could do to locate it, and the police did not come out at that time, and there was nothing more done; I didnt find any one; I got someof the neighbors to helpme, and looked around, and could not locate anything; there was nothing more done about it for a couple of years; and I kind of had an idea that may be Mr. Decker had taken my flax from different reports, and different ones that told me that seemed to know more about it than I did; tales going around the country that he had taken my flax, and was kind of making fun of it, and different ones came to me and told me if I would go to him and ask him about it that he would--that I could get it out of him; and neighbors came to me and told me they could prove and swear he had taken it; he had told then he had taken it away; I reported it to the police several times, and the police officers had been out there at numerous times, and different officers from Regina, and special men came out there and could not get any evidence; they claimed to me that they were practically sure Mr. Decker had taken it, bu tthey could not get the evidence. So after Mr. Decker had thrashed one fall, when I though he would have some money I went out and broached the subject to him, and asked him about it, and we had an understanding, and he told me that he had taken the flax, or a portion of the flax, and would pay me for it. At first, when I went over there and he didnt know anything about the flax at all, and I told him I had waited long enough, I was tired of fooling with him, and if he did not come through, I had evidence I could prove he did take it, and he better come and settle with me for somethin gnear what I lost in the flax.</p>
<p>Q    Just what did he say to you about taking the flax?</p>
<p>A    Well, I cant remember just exactly as to the very words he used; when I asked him about it he said he didnt know anything at all in regard to it, first, and I told him that I thought he did, and he finally admitted that he had taken a portion of the flax, and claimed that he had been lead into it by different aprties, older ment--I htink that he said older men, or some such statement as that, and he wanted a little time to straighten it--to see other parties and straighten it up, and I told him taht time was no advantage with me, I would give him until a certain time the next day, to straighten up with me for taking that flax, and he came the next day and gave me some money and some grain.</p>
<p>Q    How much did he say he had taken?</p>
<p>A    Well, he told me at that time that he had taken--I cant just remember; he told me at that time that he had taken something--I dont know, I think he claimed at that time that he had taken a load of flax; and at the time when he came to settle with the grain, I had a talk with him; I asked him--I was personally acquainted with him, I said "Fletcher, why are you in this kind of business for; you are a young man?" Well, he told me that he was in debt, and I think that he told me at that time he took all the flax; now I wont say for sure, but I will say that at first he told me that he had only taken a potion of it, and it seems as thought there was others connected with it, any way, he didnt want to--it seems he wanted to settle for it all, and did not want to implicate the other parties.</p>
<p>Q    How many bushels in a load?</p> 
<p>A    I could not say; anywhere from sixty to a hundred, I suppose.</p>
<p>Q    How much did he settle for?</p>
<p>A    Well, he settled for--</p>
<p>Q    What was the money value?</p>
<p>A    He gave me something around between four hundred and fifty and five hundred dollars in money and grain; probably be four hundred and seventy-five or eighty dollars cash--equivalent to that.</p>
<p>Q    And near what post office was your place there?</p>
<p>A    Near the Wiwa Hill Post Office.</p>
<p>Q    And this was the transaction and the crime which complaint was made to the authorities there at Saskatchewan, was it?</p>
<p>A    Yes, mam.</p>

<p>         Cross Examination:</p>

<p>By Mr. BEELER:</p>
<p>Q    Do you swear that Mr. Decker took your flax, did you see him?</p>
<p>A    I didnt see him take it.</p>
<p>Q    Would you say that he took your flax?</p>
<p>A    I will say that he told me he took it.</p>
<p>Q    A part of it, you mean?</p>
<p>A    A portion of it, and I will say further, that when we had the last settlement, as near as I can remember, I asked him--I told him, "Now"--I aske dhim what he was doing; why he was in this business for; he said he had been lead into it by older men; I advised him to go straight, and get out of that kind of business, and I think, as far as I can remember, we had quite a little talk, and we sit down; he brought this load of wheat, and we sat down by the side of the grainery, after we unloaded this wheat, and I talke dto him like I would my brother or anybody, and I advised him to get out of that kind of business and go straight; and I advised him further, if he had trouble with the police in settling this up, they might still want to get any evidence, I was going ahead and settle it up, to get it squared up, and he need not be feared of me, I would not put in any evidence against him; and I think tha the told me at that time that he took it all; now I wont swear to it.</p>
<p>Q    But you told him at the time that you would put in no evidence gainst him if he would pay up the money?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir; I told him if I was called as a witness I would tell the truth; as far as I was concerned I would put in no evidence against him; if I was called against him as a witness in the case I would tell what I knew.</p>
<p>Q    You would not urge prosecution?</p>
<p>A    No; I had urged it for two years.</p>
<p>Q    Before anything was done?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    After you were paid--</p>
<p>A    I was practically through with it.</p>
<p>Q    In other words, the way you felt then, and the way you feel now, you would not go to Canada voluntarily and testify aginst him, would you?</p>
<p>A    No sir.</p>
<p>Q    You are living in Oregon now, are you not?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Been living there for how long?</p>
<p>A    A year ago in February.</p>
<p>Q    A year ago last February?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Man of family?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    If I may ask, what occupation are you engaged int here?</p>
<p>A    At the present time?</p>
<p>Q    Yes.</p>
<p>A    I am running a transfer business</p>
<p>Q    And you propose to reside in Oregon continuously?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir, as far as I know.</p>
<p>Q    Don't intent to go back to Canada?</p>
<p>A    On business.</p>
<p>Q    You intend to go back?</p>
<p>A    I intent to go back on business.</p>
<p>Q    That will be only for a short while?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Was there any statement made as to who this other party was that was implicated in this theft of flax?</p>
<p>A    Not from Mr. Decker; no.</p>
<p>Q    By anybody else?</p>
<p>A    Different rumors around the country.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Objected to as immaterial.</p>
<p>A    Several implicated.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Yes, I think it is probably immaterial.</p>
<p>Q    Was Mr. Robinson?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: I object to that as immaterial.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: The witness testified that there was only one load he accused this man of taking; if there was other flax, we should be permitted to interrogate this witness--</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: There may be some other parties that are guilty, but we are not trying them here.</p>
<p>Q    Robinson was living up there?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Objected to as immaterial.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Sustained.</p>
<p>Q   You know of disputes between the Robinson's and Mr. Decker, dont you?</p>
<p>A    No sir.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Objected to as immaterial.</p>
<p>Q    I mean the Robinson's who have made affidavits here.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: There are lots of Robinson's/</p>
<p>Q    Do you know Cassius M. Clay Robinson?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: I object to that as immaterial.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: This is preliminary.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I will let him answer that.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know Cassius M. Clay Robinson?</p>
<p>A    Not personally acquainted with him; I know him when I see him.</p>
<p>Q    He is a farmer up there?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Been up there in that vicinity near you for severl years?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know Charles Burdette Robinson?</p>
<p>A    I don't know him by the name of Charles; I know a man by the name of Bob Robinson.</p>
<p>Q    Are Bob Robinson and Cassius M. Clay Robinson brothers?</p>
<p>A    Bob and Charley and Cassius--the two I know they are called Bob and Cash.</p>
<p>Q    They are brothers?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Did you ever talkt o these two men during the year from November 1915, up to the time you were settle dfor this flax in 1917?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    Did these two men ever tell you that Decker had admitted to them that he had taken this flax?</p>
<p>A    One of the brothers, I cant call the name of which one, told me that he could prove that Mr. Decker had taken the flax; that was my authority for going to Mr. Decker in regard to the flax.</p>
<p>Q    Both of these Robinsons have been in a good many scrapes up there, havent they?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Objected to as immaterial.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Sustained.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I presume I will be allowed an exception to all these rulings?</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Yes.</p>
<p>Q    What time, Mr. Ficklin, in 1917 was it when you had this alleged conversation with Mr. Decker?</p>
<p>A    What time in 1917?</p>
<p>Q    Yes.</p>
<p>A    It was in the fall at harvest time, probably around October; I would not say for sure, but around October.</p>
<p>Q    Of 1917?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    That was three years ago; it will be four years this coming October?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    At the time you learned of this did you make any complaint to any of the authorities up there?</p>
<p>A    At the time the flax was taken?</p>
<p>Q    No, at the time you had this conversation with him?</p>
<p>A    Did I make a complaint to the authorities?</p>
<p>Q    Yes.</p>
<p>A    In regard to the flax?</p>
<p>Q    Yes.</p>
<p>A    No sir.</p>
<p>Q    Had he ever been arrested after this discussion of yours?</p>
<p>A    Not that I know of.</p>
<p>    Miss KOMITZ: Objected to as immaterial.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know when he was arrested?</p>
<p>A    For this?</p>
<p>    Miss KOMITZ: Objected to as immaterial anad not proper cross-examination.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Well, may be it has something to do with this proceeding, I dont know.</p>
<p>A    What was the question?</p>
<p>Q    Do you know when he was arrested?</p>
<p>A    I cant tell you the date, or when it was; he was taken into Gravelbourg and arrested, and I believe he was leet out on bail sometime; taht would be after 1917; I cant just figure when it was.</p>
<p>Q    At any rate, you are sure it was after your conversation with him?</p>
<p>A    Oh, yes.</p>
<p>Q    But it was on no complaint of your's?</p>
<p>A    No sir.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know whether any of these Robinson's made this complaint?</p>
<p>A    I don't know.</p>
<p>Q    Did you ever have anything to do with bringing about these proceeding here?</p>
<p>A    No sir.</p>

<p>         RE-DIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>By Miss KOLMITZ:</p>
<p>Q    Where is Gravelbourg you jsut mentioned?</p>
<p>A    Gravelbourg, Saskatchewan, just southwest of Moose Jaw of the C. &amp; R.</p>
<p>Q    In Canada?</p>
<p>A    Yes, mam.</p>
<p>Q    And he was arrested there and admitted to bail?</p>
<p>A    Yes, mam.</p>
<p>Q    As far as you know, do you know what happened after that?</p>
<p>A    No, mam.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know how he happened to be down there at that time?</p>
<p>A    No, mam.</p>

<p>Claude N. Frelleu<!--signed--></p>

<p>Subscribed and sword to before me this 26th day of August, 1921.</p>

<p>R. W. McClelland<!--signed--></p>
<p>U. S. Commissioner</p>
<p><!--Seal, written and circled--></p>


<p>THOMAS WATERS,   Being first duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>         DIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>By Miss KOLMITZ:</p>
<p>Q    What is your full name?</p>
<p>A    Thomas Waters.</p>
<p>Q    What is your occupation?</p>
<p>A    Deputy United States Marshal.</p>
<p>Q    And did you arrest this defendant?</p>
<p>A    I did.</p>
<p>Q    About when?</p>
<p>A    3rd day of August.</p>
<p>Q    1921?</p>
<p>A    1921.</p>
<p>Q    And state what conversation you had with the defendant after seeing him?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Objected to on the ground that the question is entirely too broad.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Conversation he had with the defendant at the time he was arrested?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Yes.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: You mean on this charge?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: On this charge, yes sir.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: If it was on this charge--</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Objection overruled.</p>
<p>A    We went to Ronald Station, Mr. Burke of the Department of Justice, and I, and we had a telegram from the Department of Justice at Portland, directing us to arrest this party; we went out there and asked him if he was Mr. Decker, he sai dhe was, and we told him we had a telegram advising us to arrest him; he at first--</p>
<p>Q    (By The Commissioner) Was that before or after he was put under arrest that he made the statement to you?</p>
<p>A    Why, I havenet said he made any statement yet; I was telling how we came out there to arrest him.</p>
<p>Q    Had you arrested him before you talked with him?</p>
<p>A    As soon as he admitted his identity we tol dhim we had a telegram from Portland advising us to arrest him.</p>
<p>Q    And pu thim under arrest?</p>
<p>A    Put him under arrest, yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    (By Mr. Beeler) This conversation was had after?</p>
<p>A    After.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: We object to all this.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Let him say a little further how it came up.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: He already testified this conversation came up after he arrested him.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: What is the difference.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Question of identity.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: He admitted his identity, and then was informed he was put under arrest, after admitting his identity, after being put under arrest; as I understand him, he had a certain conversation with the officer; I believe that would be improper.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: I will ask him this question. If you will let the witness proceed I think you will fin dit is not objectionable.</p>
<p>Q    Did he ask you on what charge he was being arrested?</p>
<p>A    He did.</p>
<p>Q    What did you say to him?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to that, Your Honor.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Nothing objectionable about that.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The officer just testified that the told him he had a warrant for his arrest, and put him under arrest.</p>
<p>Q    (By The Commissioner) Did you inform him at that time that any statement he made to you might be used against him?</p>
<p>A    I did not.</p>
<p>Q    (By Miss Kolmitz) I will ask you this: Did you ask him any questions, or were you confined to answering his questions?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to that, Your Honor, as immaterial.</p>
<p>Q    Were you answering the defendant's question, or were you trying to get information from  him?</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: My understanding of the rule is--</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: We will show this information that the defendant gave to the marshal was volunteered information; was a voluntary statement which the Marshal was not the least bit interested in, and it was forced on him. He went out there, as he said, to arrest the man; he aske dhim his name, put him under arrest; the man volunteered the information, and tried to get some information from the Marshal; there is nothing improper about it; if there was any duress, of course, it would be objectionable.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The very fact he was under arrest was duress.</p>
<p>    Mr.<!--error in document?--> KOLMITZ: Not when the Marshall<!--error in document?--> was not asking for information.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: As I understand the rule, it is the duty of the officer to inform the defendant if he makes any admissions the statements may be used against him, then if with that information he makes statements they are voluntary admissions against his interests.</p>
<p>    Mr. Beeler: There is no question but what that is the law; we object to this character of questions.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: Just a question of identity, if Your Honor please.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Well, it is admitted that was made before he was put under arrest.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: The name Decker, but there may be a million Decker's.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The witness testified that he defendant told him that he was the man named in this warrant, which he had for his arrest, and thereupon he arrested him.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: I did not so gather it.</p>
<p>Q    (By The Commissioner) That was the testimony, Mr. Waters?</p>
<p>A    Yes sir.</p>
<p>Q    (By Miss Kolmitz) Did you tell him you had a warrant for his arrest?</p>
<p>A    I told him I had a telegram from Portland advising us to arrest him.</p>
<p>Q    (By Mr. Hyland) Giving his full name?</p>
<p>A    Fletcher Decker; the first thing I asked him when I went up to him, if he was Fletcher Decker.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to any voluntary statement of the witness; <del>in</del>not responsive to any question.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: He stated very fully, he went and aske dhim if his name was Fletcher Decker, he asid it was; he tol dhim he had a warrant for his arrest, told him what for; and he admitted that he was--</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: No, that is what I want to ask him.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Already testified; ask it over again; that was what I understood him to say.</p>
<p>Q    Did the defendant ask you why he was being arrested?</p>
<p>A    He did.</p>
<p>Q    What did you answer?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to that, what the officer might have told him.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: That is all right; it was the duty of the office either to read the warrant or tel him what the content of it was.</p>
<p>Q    What did you tell him?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: He alrady testified he didn't have any warrant, merely had a telegram.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: He has a right to advise a man what he is being arrested for.</p>
<p>Q    What did you tel him?</p>
<p>A    I told him I did not know what the charge was, merely a telegram from Portland; I presumed it was some offense he had committed in Oregon.</p>
<p>Q    What did the defendant answer to that?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to that, what the defendant may have answered to that; certainly it would not be proper; no showing he had been advised that any statement he might make might be used against him.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: He had a right to tell him he was not the man.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: That was after the arrest then?</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: No, he told him he had a telegraphic warrant for his arrest; the defendan twanted to know what for, and the officer told him he though it was for some offense in Oregon; it was the duty of the officer when he arrests a man under a warrant, either to read the warrant or tell him the contents of it, then make the arrest; if the defendant wants to make a statment, it is teh duty of the officer to tel him whatever statment he makes may be used against him, and with that information, if the defendant then makes a statement if is a voluntary statement against his interests; but up to that time it is the duty of the officer to tell him he has a warrant, and what the warrant charges--what he is being arrested for; all that part of the conversation is admissible evidence. Now we have gotten that far; is there anything else?</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: He said he thought it was a crime in Oregon; that was what the officer said.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Yes.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: The question was, waht, if anything, did the defendant say at that time he answered any questions the officer asked him.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: That was what I was objecting to, because he had been put under arrest, but he had not been tol dby th eofficer that anything he might say would be used against him, jsut as Your Honor ruled.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: He had not been put under arrest yet; he asid before he was arrested that he told him he thought it was for an offense committed in Oregon.</p>
<p>    THE WITNESS: He was under arrest at that time.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: He told him he was under arrest; the witness has tol dus that.</p>
<p>    THE WITNESS: As soon as he admitted his identity I read the telegram to him.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I think that is all there is to it.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: That is all we cared about, was the question of identity--the other statements corroborating his identity, that was all. If Mr. Beeler can find anything objectionable about that matter he shold satisfy the Court, and, furthermore, satisfy himself.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: His identity has already been proven by the witness Ficklin.</p>
<p>    Miss. KOLMITZ. That is all we care to ask this witness.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: No Questions.</p>

<p>Thomas Waters<!--signed--></p>

<p>Subscribed and sword to before me this 27th day of August, 1921.</p>

<p>R. W. McClelland<!--signed--></p>
<p>U. S. Commissioner</p>
<p><!--Seal, written and circled--></p>

<p>--------------</p>


<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: We offer in evidence the original record from Canada certified to by the proper authorities.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Probably it had better be marked for identification.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Mark it Exhibit "A".</p>
<p>    (Original record marked "Exhibit "A" offered by the Government)</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: That has merely been offered. I want to object to certain documents. First, I want to object to the warrant dated August 5, 1921; Your Honor will observe there were two warrants issued, one dated June 14th and one August 5, 1921. The record show she was arrested, as Mr. Waters, the last witness, that he arrested him on August 3rd. I apprehend that the purpose and the reason of this warrant to apprehend dated August 5, 1921, was executed--</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: You mean August 4th?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: August 5th here, was executed after this amended petition or complaint, whatever it is called, was executed, but this warrant of August 5th, which is there, and which they are now offering--here is the warrant dated August 5th; there is one warrant dated August 5th, and another warrant dated June 14th, 1921. The defendant was arrested by reason of the warrant of June 14th, because Mr. Waters has just testified that he was arrested on August 3rd, and the record shows that therefore he was arrested two days prior to the issuance of this warrant.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: My warrant reads August 4th, which would be the day after the telegraphic warrant.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: There was a warrant issued here in June; the complaint was made five years ago; this warrant you are talking abou thas never been executed. The warrant of August 5th, there is no official return on it at all, merely a warrant that was issued, and he was arrested under the warrant of the 4th of August.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: He could not have been, Your Honor, because he was arrested on the 3rd day of August, the Marshall has so testified.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The Marshal may have taken him under arrest on the telegraphic warrant, but the formal warrant issued by me was issued on the 4th day of August, and served by the Marshal on the 4th day of August, signed by Thomas Waters, Deputy. Go ahead and make your objection.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to this warrant dated August 5, 1921, on the ground that the record shows he had already been arrested two days prior to the issuence of this warrant. I object to the introduction of the affidavits of the following named witnesses: Frederick A. McEwan, dated the 28th day of July, 1921; the affidavit of William James Henry Vigors, dated July 25, 1921; the affidavit of Cassius M. Clay Robinson, dated July 25, 1921; the affidavit of Charles Burdette Robinson, dated teh 25th of July, 1921; on the ground and for the reason that these affidavits were taken without any opportunity on the part of the defendant to be present at the time of their taking; that he was unable to cross-examine the witnesses, unable to be represented in person or by counsel, and was given no opportunity of any kind or character whatsoever to cross-examine them, and therefore it would be prejudicial to permit those to be offered in evidence. I further object to the balance of this so-called Exhibit "A", which consists of certifications, that the law with relation to theft is as set forth in the exhibit, on the ground and for the reason that the law is not properly authenticated; nothing to show that the officials certifying to it were justified or authorized to certify to it; and, furthermore, on the ground that there was no showing that the English Parliament ever authorized the Dominion of Canada to pass a law with relation to theft, as is purpoted in this Exhibit "A", and on that last point I have a case directly in point as to that.</p>
<p>    (Argument)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: As I stated this morning, it seems to me that the law of Canada, which it is claimed the defendant has violated, is a matter of fact to be proven by competent evidence; it does not occur to me that the mere affidavit, which is ex parte--the affidavits filed here, or even the certificate of the officer, is sufficient proof that that is the law of Canada. I have got to find that Canada had the law that is alleged to be violated, as well as to find that the defendant, as a fact, did violate it. Now as I understand it, I cant take as proof the certification of an officer as to what the law is in a foreign country. Have you anything to say about that?</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: That is the only way to prove it, by some person who is familiar with the law of that country, and practices there.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER. I have to have the proof.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: That is what he states in his affidavit.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Being an affidavit without chance of cross-examination.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: We don't have to prove it beyond a reasonable doubt; we are not trying thtis man for the crime; all we are trying to do at this time is to show evidence of criminality, and that this man is the person who--the question of identity is made, then we are done with the case; if we have shown evidence of criminality; we are not trying him for the crime; we are not convicting him now, all we are showing is he is the man, and there is an evidence of criminality, and that is what our statute says, Your Honor; we ahve set forth what the evidence is in this complaint, if Your Honor please, which is certified to by the United States Commissioner at Regina, and he certifies to all of these instruments that we have filed here. (Reads certificate of Commissioner at Regina. Argument.)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The only difference is this, as to whether a fact as to what the law is can be proven by a certificate, and whether it has to be proven in court as another fact, by a witness in pereson, appearing before the court, so that he may be cross-examined by the other party. All lawyers undersatnd that an affidavit is not evidence in a court, a deposition is evidence because of the very fact that the opposing party has a chance to cross-examine.</p>
<p>    (Further argument)</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: We will offer in evidence the same sections referred to by Mr. Beeler. This is the Criminal Code of Canada and the Canada Evidence Act, published by James Crankshaw, B. C. L., K. C.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I object to that, reading from this book.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Let him present his offer.</p>
<p>    Mr. Hyland: Being the Third Edition of the Author's Annotated Works on the Criminal Law of Canada, Toronto. The Carswell Co. Limited, Law Publishers, etc. 19 Duncan Street. 1910. We will offer this book in evidence, and ask to withdraw it and substitute only the sections that are referred to under Mr. Dingwall's three affidavits.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Are you objecting to it?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Yes sir, I am objecting to the introduction of this, because there is nothing to show it is the Statute of Canada; nothing to show that this book was over authorized by the Dominion of Canada, or proving that it contains the law with relation to theft, or any of the criminal laws of Canada. Nothing to show this law was in effect in 1915--November 15, 1915, the date on which this alleged theft was committed, or it is the sam enow as it was then, or was the same in 1915, as it is purpoted to be here in this volume, and, further that it is not the proper way to establish the existence of a law of a foreign country; not properly proven; not properly authenticated; not properly established, and this evidence here is incompetent for the establishment of that fact.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I will let this matter go over until to-morrow at eleven o'clock.</p>
<p>    (The following is the order of appointment and authorization of the United States Commissioner)</p>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPOINTMENT OF ROBERT W. McCLELLAND, UNITED STATES COMMISSIONER.</p>

<p>__________</p>

<p>By an order duly made and entered of record on the 13th day of October, 1915, pursuant to the Nineteenth Section of Chapter 252 of the Act of Congress passed at the first session of the Fifty-fourth Congress of the United States, has appointed Robert W. McClelland, Esq., to be United States Commissioner at Seattle, Washington, for the term of four years commencing on the 14th day of October, 1915, unless sooner removed by an order of the Court; and by virtue of the Act of Congress and the Order of the Court aforesaid, the said Robert W. McClelland, Esq. is duly authorized to exercise the powers pertaining to the office of United States Commissioner, and to receive the fees and compensation provided by law, during the said term of four years.</p>
<p>WITNESS the Hon. Jeremiah Neterer, District Judge, and the seal of the said District Court, this 14th day of October, 1915.</p>

<p>FRANK L. CROSBY</p>
<p>Clerk.</p>

<p>---------</p>

<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT, WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPOINTMENT OF ROBERT W. McCLELLAND UNITED STATES COMMISSIONER TO ACT IN EXTRADITION CASES.</p>
<p>NOTICE OF APPOINTMENT.</p>

<p>__________</p>

<p>To Robert W. McClelland, United States Commissioner:</p>
<p>You are hereby authorized, commissioned and appointed United States Commissioner in and for the Western District of Washington, to hear and determine all matters of extradition, and to act in the matter of the prosecution of fugitives from justice from foreign countries, in all matters and proceedings therein, which may be brought before you as United States Commissioner.</p>
<p>This appointment and authority is supplemental to your order of appointment dated October 15, 1915, for the purpose of extending your jurisdiction generally to all extradiciton matters which may be brought before you.</p>
<p>Done in open Court this 14th day of October, 1915.</p>

<p>JEREMIAH NETERER</p>
<p>United States District Judge.</p>
<p>------------</p>

<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON. NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE DESIGNATION OF UNITED STATES COMMISSIONS TO HEAR EXTRADITION PROCEEDINGS.</p>
<p>__________</p>

<p>By an order duly made and entered of record on the 1st day of October, 1919, pursuant to the Nineteenth Section of Chapter 252 of an Act of Congress passed at the First Session of the Fifty-fourth Congress of the United States, have appointed Robert W. McClelland, Esq. to be United States Commissioner, at Seattle, Washington, for the term of four years, commencing on the 14th day of October, 1919, unless sooner removed by an order of the court. And by virtue of the Act of Congress and the Order of the court aforesaid, the said Robert W. McClelland, Esq. is duly authorized to exercise the powers pertaining to the office of the United States Commissioner, and receive all fees and compensation provided by law during the said term of four years.</p>
<p>WITNESS the Hon. Jeremiah Neterer, District Judge, and the seal of said District Court, this, the 5th day of October, 1919.</p>
<p>R. M. HARSHBERGER,</p>
<p>Clerk.</p>
<p>-----------</p>

<p>    Mr. BEELER: All this is going in over my objection, because it is my contention you cannot cure the defective warrant of arrest, and it having been so issued, it was defective. I further object to the introduction of the alleged authority showing that the Commissioner was authorized to issue warrants for the apprehension of persons sought to be extradicted, on the ground and for the reason that the authority was not alleged and stated in the warrant at the time it was issued in the first instance.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Objection overruled; exception allowed.</p>
<p>(At this time an adjournment was taken until 11 a. m. August 25th, 1921/)</p>
<p>--------</p>

<p>SYDNEY BROWN WOODS,</p>
<p>AUGUST 25, 1921, 11 a. m.</p>
<p>Hearing resumed:</p>
<p>Being first duly sworn,</p>
<p>testified as follows:</p>

<p>DIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>By Mr. HYLAND:</p>
<p>Q    You may state your name to the Commissioner, please.</p>
<p>A    Sydney Brown Woods.</p>
<p>Q    Of what country, Mr. Woods, are you a resident and citizen?</p>
<p>A    Canada; Edminton, in the Province of Alberta.</p>
<p>Q    Your age?</p>
<p>A    Forty-nine.</p>
<p>Q    Your profession?</p>
<p>A    Barrister and solicitor.</p>
<p>Q    Are you a barrister and solicitor admitted in the Dominion of Canada?</p>
<p>A    I am a barrister and solicitor admitted in the Province of Ontario, and also in the Province of Alberta. The Provinces have the jurisdiction regarding admission.</p>
<p>Q    The Province of Alberta is one of the former Northwest Territories of Canada?</p>
<p>A    Yes.</p>
<p>Q    Of which the others are what?</p>
<p>A    Saskatchewan.</p>
<p>Q    How long have you practiced your profession in Alberta?</p>
<p>A    Since it became a Province, in 1906, I went there as the Deputy Attorney General of the Province.</p>
<p>Q    And prior to that time you were admitted to the bar?</p>
<p>A    Of the Province of Ontario; I practiced in the Province of Ontario for nearly ten years.</p>
<p>Q    You are what is known as a King's Counsel, Mr. Woods, appointed by the Governor General of Canada?</p>
<p>A    No, the Governor General has not the appointing of King's counsel, it is the Province that has that; I was appointed the King's counsel by the Province of Ontario along, I cant remember whether in 1906 or 1907, and also by the Province of Alberta a few years later.</p>
<p>Q    You were admitted to the bar in Ontario in what year?</p>
<p>A    1897.</p>
<p>Q    And was at that time a graduate of a law school, were you not?</p>
<p>A    Of the Ontarior Law School.</p>
<p>Q    Ordinarily known as Osgood Hall?</p>
<p>A    Osgood Hall, yes.</p>
<p>Q    And since that time you have practiced your profession in the Province of Ontario?</p>
<p>A    And Alberta.</p>
<p>Q    Under the laws of Canada who has the jurisdiction over criminal offenses?</p>
<p>A    It is the British North America Act, divides the jurisdiction between the Province and the Dominion, in which two sections, known as Section 91 and Section 92 of the British North America Act, under Section 91, the exclusive jurisdiction regarding criminal law; that is, the cirminal law of the country is under exclusive jurisdiction of the Dominion or Federal Parliament; it is the same, in other words, all over Canada.</p>
<p>Q    Now Canada has a criminal code, has it not?</p>
<p>A    Yes, that is what it is called, the criminal code, and it is contained in the Revised Statutes.</p>
<p>Q    I hand you Volume 3 of the Revised Statutes of Canada, 1906, and I will ask you to identitfy the volume, if you can, Mr. Woods, and tell the Court what it is.</p>
<p>A    That is the third Volume of the revision of the Statutes of Canada, mad ein 1906.</p>
<p>Q    Printed under the authority of som eperson?</p>
<p>A    Yes, under the authority of the Govenrment at Ottowa; printed by the King's printer at Ottowa; there is a revision ever ten years ordinarily, and this is the last revision.</p>
<p>Q    This is the last revision?</p>
<p>A    The last revision; they have not yet got out another one.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: I will offer this volume in evidence, if Your Honor please, and then I will ask to withdraw it and substitute copies of the provisions that I wish to use in this hearing.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Very well.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: I will offer this volume in evidence.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Any objection, Mr. Beeler?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I certainly object tot he volume going in evidence, because there is no showing that the matters that are before the Court are in the volume, the particular statutes in question here, or that the particular statutes in question were in effect in November, 1915.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: The testimony is, this is the Criminal Code of Canada, and there is a revision every ten years, and this is the last revision, and it bears date 1906.</p>
<p>THE WITNESS: The law was in force then.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: Surely this has been identified.</p>
<p>Q    Was this in force and effect in 1915, Mr. Woods?</p>
<p>A    Yes.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: There is no showing that the laws have not been amended; we know that laws are frequently amended.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: Until you show it has been amended, Mr. Beeler, it sems to me my offer ought to be accepted.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I think the volume may be accepted as identified; of course, that is with the understanding it will be followed up with proof that the act, or the specific statute under which this case is being prosecuted will be identified also in the volume.</p>
<p>Q    Refer to Section 347, if you will, please, Mr. Woods.</p>
<p>A    347 of the Code?</p>
<p>Q    347 of the Code.</p>
<p>A    Yes; 347 of the code is the definition of theft. All the criminal law--the whole of the criminal law is contained in the Criminal Code, plus the Criminal Evidence Act of Canada, you understand, different sections of the same, that is a codified law in Canada, there are no separate statutes, it has all been codified, that is the Criminal Code containing it, and Section 347 is the definition of theft.</p>
<p>Q    Was that in effect during all of the year 1915?</p>
<p>A    Yes.</p>
<p>Q    Now refer to sub-section 13 of Section 2 of the Criminal Code.</p>
<p>A    That is the interpretation of every one person and owner.</p>
<p>Q    Was that in effect in all of the year 1915?</p>
<p>A    Yes.</p>
<p>Q    Refer now to Section 69 of the Criminal Code.</p>
<p>A    That is the definition of parties to offenses.</p>
<p>Q    Was that in effect during all of the year 1915?</p>
<p>A    Yes.</p>
<p>Q    And refer now to Section 386.</p>
<p>A    Yes.</p>
<p>Q    Was that in effect then?</p>
<p>A    Yes, that is the punishment for theft, or things not otherwise specially provided for; yes, that was in effect then.</p>
<p>Q    Do you know of any provision for the stealing of flax, specific provision. Mr. Woods?</p>
<p>A    Specific punishment provision?</p>
<p>Q    Yes.</p>
<p>A    No; I think it is contained in the general provision 386.</p>
<p>Q    Section 344?</p>
<p>A    That is the statement of things capable of being stolen.</p>
<p>Q    That was in effect at that time?</p>
<p>A    Yes.</p>
<p>Q    All of those particular secitons were in effect--were they in effect in 1915, and are still in effect, Mr. Woods?</p>
<p>A    Yes.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: Now those are the secitons, if Your Honor please, I am particularly calling Your Honor's attention to, and I will ask to substitute copies for this volume, so that it can be retained in the library where it belongs; I have the copies here.</p>
<p>Q    Now under the law in force in the Province of Saskatchewan, what jurisdiction in 1915, had a Justice of the Peace in regard to charging a person with a crime of theft, if any?</p>
<p>A    It is not merely in the province of Saskatchewan, but all over Canada, the same law.</p>
<p>Q    He had what power?</p>
<p>A    With regard to what?</p>
<p>Q    Charging any person with a crime; had he the powe to do it?</p>
<p>A    He has power to take an information in th eusual way from anybody complaining there has been a crime charged, anad issue a warrant or summons, according to his discretion, apparehend<!--spelling error in document--> the individual, and upon the individual being tried before him, he has power to hear what we call the preliminary investigation in regard to indictable offenses,  and to commit th eperson for trial at a higher tribunal; an din regard to offenses that are not indictable offenses, but are punishable by summary conviction, he has in certain cases power to summarily convinct; that depends upon the particular offense with which the person is charged; in case of an indictable offense he has the power only to hear what we call the preliminary investigation, and commit the person for trial.</p>
<p>Q    But he has the right, as you say, to take the preliminary evidence, and to issue the complaint, and charge teh person with the crime?</p>
<p>A    The complaint is the complaint of the person; for instance, if it is a matter of theft, that is the complaint of the person whose property has been stolen,a nd he lays an information and complaint, the form of it is in the Code, before a Justice of the Peace, and that Justice of the Peace takes that information, and upon that information issues his complaint and warrant for an indictable offense, and then there is a summons charging him, that is issued by the Justice of the Peace, you see. "The facts were sworn before me on so and so, J. P." that means Justice of the Peace; in each case there is a summons, or he can issue a warrant, you see.</p>

<p>CROSS EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>By Mr. BEELER:</p>
<p>Q    What is you rname, please?</p>
<p>A    Sydney Brown Woods.</p>
<p>Q    Mr. Woods, you say you have practiced your profession in the Province of Ontario and Alberta?</p>
<p>A    Yes; I practiced in Ontario fro, 1897 until the Province of Alberta and the Province of Saskatchewan were formed from what was previously the Northwest Territories of Canada.</p>
<p>Q    When was the Province of Saskatchewan formed?</p>
<p>A    In the year 1906, it will be in here (indicating book).</p>
<p>Q    In 1906?</p>
<p>A    And Alberta, also.</p>
<p>Q    You never practiced your profession in the Province of Saskatchewan?</p>
<p>A    No, but at the time--you see, I went to Alberta as the Deputy Attorney Ceneral<!--spelling error in doc--> of Alberta, and at that time the Court to which one was called in those Provinces was still the Supreme Court of the Northwest Territories, you see; it was not until after that that the two different courts in the two different Provinces were created, and I was called to the bar of the Supreme Court of the Northwest Territory.</p>
<p>Q    But you never practiced your profession in Saskatcheawn after it was created into a Province?</p>
<p>A    Not personally; my firm practices in Saskatchewan.</p>
<p>Q    But you personally never did?</p>
<p>A    I never happened to be in Saskatchewan in particular.</p>
<p>Q    Your office is not in Saskatchewan?</p>
<p>A    My office is in the City of Edmonton; members of my firm go to Saskatchewan.</p>
<p>Q    But Section 347 of the Criminal Code was that, or was it not the law in the Province of Saskatchewan in 1915?</p>
<p>A    Yes, it is all the same all over Canada in connection with criminal laws; there is no difference in the Provinces, it is a federal matter. Have you the First Volume of this, the British North America Act would show it.</p>
<p>Q    In other words, the criminal law then in the Provinces is dissimilar to the criminal laws in our states?</p>
<p>A    Oh, quite, You see here you have your state laws.</p>
<p>Q    There you have the same as our federal law here?</p>
<p>A    Exactly.</p>
<p>Q    In your practice do you practice criminal law or civil law, in the main?</p>
<p>A    Mainly, you mean my personal practice?</p>
<p>Q    Yes.</p>
<p>A    Mainly at present my practice is civil law, but I do a considerable amount of criminal work.</p>
<p>Q    Have you done any criminal work since 1915?</p>
<p>A    A considerable amount.</p>
<p>Q    Have you ever handled any cases of theft?</p>
<p>A    Oh, yes.</p>
<p>Q    How many cases of theft have you handled?</p>
<p>A    I could not tell you, off-hand, but several; you see the Attorney General of Alberta, whenever he has any--he very very often calls on me to prosecute.</p>
<p>Q    What I am getting at, do you swear here that the criminal law in Canada in realtion to theft has not been amended or changed since 1915?</p>
<p>A    Oh, it doubtless has, but my memory would be that the definition of theft has not been changed.</p>
<p>Q    That is what I am interrogatin gyou about; you say it doubtless has been amended?</p>
<p>A    You mean criminal law with relation to theft? There are a number of different sections relating to theft.</p>
<p>Q    I am confining my inquiry with refernce to--</p>
<p>A    Section 347?</p>
<p>Q    No, in relation to the sections you have testified to in chief here, Sections 347 and 386, and the various sections Mr. Hyland has interrogated you about?</p>
<p>A    347 is the definition of theft, and my memory would be fairly distinct, that that has not been altered since 1906, and indeed before 1906; that is my memory.</p>
<p>Q    Do you swear--</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: The witness is under oath; I dont think the question is proper; he has asked him "Do you swear"; he is under oath.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: That is one way of asking a question.</p>
<p>Q    You are not sensitive about that question?</p>
<p>A    Not a bit; to be absolutely certain--you quite understand to be absolutely certain there has not been some amendment in some particular word or otherwise, one would have to take each of the statutes and go through them all, as any other lawyer would do; but if you ask me just as a barrister, having had a good deal to do with the prosecution of criminals, whether the definition of theft has been altered since 1906, I would say with just as much reasonable certainty as one lawyer can say to another, it has not; you understand what I mean?</p>
<p>Q    You would not say on oath positively that the law has not been changed, the definition of theft, since 1906?</p>
<p>A    Now you have my answer; I thought it would be satisfactory; I have given it to you in full.</p>
<p>Q    Your answer was that, if I may understand you, the best of your opinion, it has not been changed?</p>
<p>A    I have told you just exactly all I have to say on the subject as to the question of whether Section 347 has or has not been altered since then.</p>
<p>Q    I ask you whether it is the best of your opinion it has not been changed?</p>
<p>A    It certainly is.</p>
<p>Q    But you would not asy positively it has not been changed?</p>
<p>A    Well, you have my answer, sir; I think you are entrenching a little bit.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I think the question has been answered.</p>
<p>Q    You are not in what we call here, practicing in the capacity of a prosecuting attorney?</p>
<p>A    Oh, very often I prosecute; I must have a dozen cases for the Attorney General last year.</p>
<p>Q    Do you happen to know who swore to the information upon which the initial warrant was issued in this case?</p>
<p>A    I dont know anything about this case any more than a man on the street; I happened to be in Seattle, and Mr. Hyland called me up and asked me to come.</p>
<p>Q    Let me ask you this: Under the criminal laws o the Dominion of Canada is it imperative taht the party fromn whom the goods or article is stolen, execute the complaint?</p>
<p>A    No, any policeman or anybody can execute the complaint; yes, anybody who has knowledge of the case; I suppose two thirds of the crimes, theft as well as any other crime, police officers, upon the information that they get, swear to the complaints of persona arrested in the ordinary prosecution; it is their duty.</p>

<p>Sydney Brown Woods<!--signed--></p>

<p>Subscrbied and sworn to before me this 26th day of August, 1921.</p>

<p>R. W. McClelland<!--signed--></p>
<p>Seal<!--written and circled--></p>

<p>    Mr. HYLAND: We will renew the offer; I have some authorities on what question; I just wanted to put Mr. Woods' testimony in here, because I was able to get him here; just a circumstance. I renew my offer to introduce the whole file, i introduced yesterday. (Reads authorities. Argument).</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I dont think I will need any more authority on that point, Mr. Hyland.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: Then we will rest, your Honor.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: You have admitted the document?</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Yes. Have you anything further?</p>
<p>(Document heretofore identified as Governmet's Exhibit "A", received in evidence).</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: The document so offered, for the purpose of the record, it is referred to as Exhibit "A". The whole document is offered as one piece of evidence. Certainly the Court couldnot accept the depositions of the four witnesses named therein, that is Frederick A. McEwan, William James Henry Vigors, Cassius M. Clay Robinson and Charles Burdette Robinson--</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: They are the charges against him; they are part of the charge.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I am confining my objection, for the moment to those four affidavits, and that is all there are. They are improper, and they contain a lot of matters that are highly hearsay; any one reading those affidavits of those four witnesses can see it is nothing but hearsay. I do not think any one of the four witnesses makes any one statement of his own personal knowledge; one of the witnesses purports to make some statement with relation to some alleged confession of Fletcher Decker. Frederick A. McEwan, in reference to the admissions of Decker, the very first witness; no showing at all that he knows the handwriting of Decker, or familiar with it.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: Look at the certificate.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: It is incompetent. I dont care about the certificate. I am talking abou the substance of his statement.</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: I am talking abou the certificate of the United States Consul.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Certainly it could not be said that kind of evidence could be used before Your honor if the witnesses were here and attempted to testify to that against the defendant, without any representation of counsel, Your Honor would not permit a witness to ramble around in the maze of hearsay and speculation.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The testimony of the witness Frederick A. McEwan is purpoted to be an admission or statement made by the defendant Deceker to him in August 1918, 3rd day of August, a written statement made by Fletcher Decker to him, signed by Fletcher Decker.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: But he has not a signed statement.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: They set it out here as being the signed statement of Fletcher Decker, with the name signed to it, "Fletcher Decker'.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: No showing he knows Fletcher Decker's signature.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: He said Fletcher Decker made that statement to him in writing as follows:</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Could that be introduced in evidence, some man testifying he had a copy; suppose this witness was here now and be sworn, and he have a copy of a paper, I mean a typewritten copy as he has here, and have the name "Fletcher Decker" typewritten, as it is here, and say "Yes, this man made a statement before me, and here it is, it in typewritten" and Fletcher Decker's name is typewritten on this statement.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: What would be the difference between that and supposing the witness is calle dto testify as to an admission made by the defendant; suppose it was a verbal and oral admission, wouldnt he be allowed to testify what the defendant admitted against his interests, without having that admission put in writing, and signed by the defendant.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: That may be true where they attempt to show an admission or a confession, Your Honor; the very least they can have is the confession, otherwise it would open up the doors for all sorts of collusion, all sorts of fraud.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I think that would be a question for your cross-examination, or rathe rfor your introducing evidence to the contrary, that he did not make that statement. I dont think it could be objected to as evidence, simply because it is not in the signature of the defendant. The witness is testifying that the defendant on such and such a date made the following statement.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: He could testify that that is true, bu the could not testify and then in addition fortify his testimony by saying "Here is a copy of it typewritten, with the typewritten signature of this man on it."</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I think I will overrule the objection. Was that the only objection you had to it?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: The objection to the last three--you, of course, had my objection yesterday in the record to the fact that these statements, and none of them, are properly certified, and, in addition to that, in the fact, especially the affidavits of the two Robinson's, Cassius M. Clay Robinson and his brother, it is nothing but hearsay and absolutely incompetent.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I cant agree to that, Both of the brothers say that Decker stated to them that he took the flax; in other words, they are testifying that the defendant admitted the taking of th eflax; that is not hearsay.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: He said "I heard about some flax being stolent from Claude Ficklin.<!--end quotation wasn't typewritten?--></p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: Of course, that part of it is hearsay; it is in the history leading up to the matter, but the principal portion of the testimony is the admission or statement of the defendant himself,--admitting the act.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: "The next morning after I had a conversation with my brother about some horses", all that is certainly incompetent.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONERS<!--commissioners? plural? maybe a typo-->: Those matters may be immaterial.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: And he says, "I was at my brother Charles place when Fletcher Decker came to my place".</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: That is a matter for the Court to pass on at the trial.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: He said "Come on now, fess up, I am not going to squeal on you". Very well, I have my objection there.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I will overrule the objection, and let the document as presented be admitted.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: I want to put in one additional objection. Do you rest, Mr. Hyland?</p>
<p>    Mr. HYLAND: Yes.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: Are you through, Miss Kolmitz?</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: Yes.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: On behalf of the defendant, at this time I want to challenge the legal sufficiency of the evidence to bind the defendant over. In my opinion, the evidence that is now before the Court is legally insufficient. In the first place, the information and complaint executed before the Justice of the Peace in the Province of Saskatchewan, one A. J. G. MacEchan, does not state facts sufficien to constitute a crime. The warrant issued by the Commissioner dated August 4, 1921, upon which apparently this man is supposed to have been arrested, did not show its face at that time that the Commissioner had the authority to issue a warrant. It is true that at sometime during the course of the hearing there was attached to this document the statement by the Commissioner that he did have the authority to issue the warrant, and that he was duly authorized to issue it, but that was after the defendant had been arrested, so that, in the first instance, the warrant on which he was arrested did not comply withthe statute, and hence any additions that might be pat on the warrant thereafter coul dnot cure the initial defect of the warrant. The same observation can be made of this so-called amended complaint, which was filed on August 18th. There was no steps taken to re-arrest the defendant on anothe rwarrant, but merely to add other matters, and the defect that existed in the initial information and complaint could not be supplemented by this amended complaint. There are other matters I might go into, but I do not care to at this time. I do not see how this warrant, which apparently is admitted was defective, could be subsequently cured by adding the notation that is now ont here.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: There isnt any doubt but what the Commissioner has to have special authority from the Court to issue warrants, and hear matters on extradition, and when that quesiton was raised yesterday I submitted a special authority, as issued by the Federal Court, signed by Judge Neterer, and also Judge Cushman, authorizing me, as Commissioner and examining magistrate, to issue warrants and hear extradition matters. I do not think the statutory provision requires the Commissioner to certify that fact on the warrant itself in order to make the warrant effective. I have, however, certified on the warrant my authority and referred to the date when it was issued and given, merely that the papers may show on their face what auhtority I have, and when it was given. Now as to the original complaint and the amendment, I know of no rule in extradition matters that differs in the proceedings in other matters brought before an examining magistrate, or before me as a Commissioner as an examining magistrate. I understand the rule to be in those extradition matters, that the hearing here and proceedings is as other hearings and proceedings in this district, and that is what I have attempted to following. Now under the practice and proceeding here the Government has a right to amend its complaint after the evidence is in, to make it conform to the evidence. In this case, however, the complaint was amended prior to the beginning of this hearing, or the taking of any evidence. I dont think the objection of counsel in eithe rone of these two instances is well taken, and I will overrule it, and grant an exception. Do you want to put any evidence in?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: No.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: We will ask that the defendant be remanded to the King County jail to await the hearing on this matter by the Secretary of State.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: That will be the order.</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: What bond will be required, Your Honor.</p>
<p>    Miss KOLMITZ: No bond; we have an authority on that point.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: That was the question I had in mind; I dont know whether any bond can be taken, or not.</p>
<p>    (Argument and citation of authorities)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The statute does not make any provision about bail. This is an extradition matter, and he is charged with having violated the laws of a foreign country, and this proceedin gis merely to determine whether the facts justify holding him on extradition. Now extradition matters, or course, are determined by statutory provisions, and I will have to find in the statute itself some authority as to the bond, otherwise I would not feel taht I would have authority to admit him to bail. Do you have any authority?</p>
<p>    Mr. BEELER: No; I know that in removal cases--</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: That is different in removal cases, that is between the states, from one state to another; the matter depends on the general law.</p>
<p>    (Argument)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: As I understand, the only thing I can do, if I hold the evidence sufficient, is to hold the defendant to the Secretary of State for further proceeding, for extradition, I cant find any authority anywhere authorizing me to admit him to bail.</p>
<p>    (Further argument)</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: The evidence shows he was admitted to bail, and jumped the bail.</p>
<p>    FLETCHER DECKER: There was nobody put any bail up for me, that is the reason I didnt jump no bail, there was none put up.</p>
<p>    THE COMMISSIONER: I cant find any authority anywhere; I havent been able to find anything that authorizes me to admit him to bail; I would like to do it lawfully, but I dont know of any authority.</p>
<p>---------</p>


<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION. BEFORE Hon. ROBERT W. McCLELLAND, Esq., COMMISSIONER OF THE UNITED STATES.</p>
<p> IN re THE EXTRADITION OF FLETCHER DECKER.</p>
<p>JUDGEMENT.</p>
<p>__________</p>

<p>This cause coming on for hearing upon the 24th day of August, 1921, upon the complaint of Thomas Waters, and the amended complaint of G. H. L. Murray, British Vice Consul, for the extradition of Fletcher Decker, the said Fletcher Decker appearing at this hearing, having been theretofore admitted to bail, thereupon the evidence of G. H. L. Murray, Claude Ficklin, Thomas Waters and Sydney Brown Woods was taken in shorthand, and documentary evidence was introduced in evidence as Exhibit "A", and from such evidence so introduced I find, that Fletcher Decker, in the Province of Saskatchewan, in the Dominion of Canada, on or about the 15th day of November, 1915, near Wiwa Hill Post Office, he, the said Fletcher Decker then and there being, did then and there take, steal and carry away about three hundred bushels of flax, the property of Claude Ficklin, and was thereby guilty of theft.</p>
<p>I further find, that said offense is an extradictable offense under Section 5270 of the Revised Statutes of the United States as amended by an act of Congress approved June 6, 1900, entitled "An Act amending Section 5270 of the Revised Statutes of the United States", and the extradition convention between the United States of America and the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, proclaimed by the President of the United States the 25th day of March 1890, supplementary to the Tenth Article of the Treaty concluded between the same high contracting parties on the 9th day of August, 1842.</p>
<p>And I further find, that the said Fletcher Decker, produced in this proceeding, is the same identical person who is charged with having committed the offense hereinbeforementioned; anad I, the undersigned, Robert W. McClelland, United States Commissioner, residing at Seattle, King County, Washingotn, in the Western District of Washignton, Northern Division, and fully authorized by Judges Jeremiah Neterer and Edward B. Cushman to act in all extradiiton proceedings, by my written appointmenet a copy of which is offered in evidence in the above entitled cause. And I have attached hereto a copy of the complaint issued herein, and of the amended complaint, with the testimony taken before me in the above entitled proceeding, and a copy of my warrant of arrest, which testimony was taken down in shorthand and transcribed, and the same as transcribed is true an dcorrect, and the witnesses have signed the same. I also certify Exhibit "A" hereto attached is the identical introduced in evidence, and is all the exhibits that have been introduced as evidene in the hearing in this matter. And I make this certificate in order that the same may be forwarded to the Secretary of State of the United States, so that a warrant may issue upon the requisition of the proper authorities of the Province of Saskatchewan, in the Dominion of Canada, for the surrender of Fletcher Decker, according to the said treaty or convention hereinbefore mentioned.</p>
<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hadn and affixed the seal of my office this 27th dayof August, 1921.</p>

<p>R. W. McClelland<!--signed--></p>
<p>United States Commissioner.</p>
<p>Seal<!--written and circled--></p>


<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION. BEFORE Hon. ROBERT W. McCLELLAND, Esq., COMMISSIONER OF THE UNITED STATES.</p>
<p>IN RE: THE EXTRADITION OF FLETCHER DECKER.</p>
<p>COMMITMENT:</p>
<p>__________</p>

<p>This Cause having come on for hearing on the 24th and 25th day of August, 1921, upon the application of George H. L. Murray, for the extradition from the Northern Division of the Western District of Washington, to the Province of Saskatchewan, in the Dominion of Canada, on eof the Dominions of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, rules by His Majesty, George the V, its King, of one Fletcher Decker, and it appearing to the Court from the tesitmony introduced in said hearing that the said Fletcher Decker did, in teh Province of Saskatchewan, in the Dominion of Canada aforesaid, on or about the 15th day of November, 1915, near Wiwa Post Office, the said Fletcher Decker then and there being, did then and there steal abou three hundred bushes of flax, the property of Claude Ficklin, and was thereby guilty of theft, contrary to the Criminal Code of Canda, and that said crime is oneof the crimes covered by the extradition convention between the United States of America and the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland, and proclaimed by the President of the United States of America on the 25th day of March 1890, supplementary to the Tenth Article of the Treaty concluded between the same high contracting parties on the 9th day of August, 1842.</p>
<p>That heretofore I have certified the foregoing facts, together with a copy of all the tesitmony taken before me to the Secretary of State that a warrant may issue upon the requisition of the proper authorities of the said Province of Saskatchewan in the Dominion of Canada.</p>
<p>NOW THEREFORE, the United States Marshal for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division, is hereby directed, and this is his warrant to commit the said Fletcher Decker to the King County Jail, there to remain until such surrender shall be made to the Province of Saskatcehwan of the said Fletcher Decker.</p>
<p>Done in open Court this 25th day of August, 1921.</p>

<p>R. W. McClelland<!--signed--></p>
<p>U. S. Commissioner.</p>
<p>Seal<!--written and circled--></p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>