<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0155.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Charles W. Nordstrom v. Edward Cudihee. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Czapla, Ethan P." xml:id="epc">Ethan P. Czapla</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0155.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Charles W. Nordstrom v. Edward Cudihee. Petition</title>
<date when="1901-07-25">July 25, 1901</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21 US Circuit Courts, Western District of Washington, Seattle; Law Register Northern Division 1899-1906, vol 2</collection>
<idno>951CharlesNordstrom</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1901-07">July 1901</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Nichols, Sam. H</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Nordstrom, Charles W.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Cudihee, Edward</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Lewis, James Hamilton</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Soderberg, Nils</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Palmer, Edward</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Hanford, Cornelius H.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States Circuit Court For Ninth Judicial Circuit</orgName>
<placeName>Washington Territory</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-10" who="#epc">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>In the United States Circuit Court for the State of Washington Ninth Judicial Circuit, Holding Terms at Seattle</p>

<p>In the matter of the Petition of Charles W. Nordstrom for Writ of Habeas Corpus and relief thereon
       vs.
       Edward Cudihee, a citizen of the State of Washington and Sheriff of King County</p>

<p>To the Honorable Judges of the above named Circuit Court:</p>

<p>Your petitioner Charles W. Nordstrom by his attorney James Hamilton Lewis respectfully showeth: That I petitioner
       Charles W. Nordstrom is a forced resident of the United States and is a man over the age of twenty-one years and
       petitioner is a subject of the Kingdom of Sweden and a citizen of Sweden and an alien. That he is incarcerated in
       prison in King County, State of Washington at the City of Seattle. That he is being wrongfully detained in prison by
       the sheriff of King County Edward Cudahee, respondent. That respondent is a resident and citizen of the State of
       Washington, County of King and a citizen of the United States. That said imprisonment is illegal and the restraint
       is contrary to the Constitution of the United States and in violation of the laws of the United States.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>That the said petitioner is held as he is informed and believes by the respondent with the intent that he shall be further 
       held for the purpose of taking his life; to-wit, to execute him, or having this petitioner executed and for the purpose of 
       having some Judge in the County of King name a day and sing a paper known as a Death Warrant for the purpose of 
       naming and setting a day upon which this petitioner shall be executed and the said person named in the said paper
       to be orded to execute this petitioner; whereas, as your petitioner alleges there is no law for such action and no law
       for such action and now law in the State of Washington or in the</p>

<pb/>

<p>United States under which such action can be had or conducted on the part of any Judge or person in the County of
       of King for the State of Washington looking to the execution of this petitioner and there is no law of the State of Washington
       or of the United States by which this petitioner should be held longer in restraint or imprisonment by any person whomsover
       pending or waiting, naming or fixing any day for his execution or of any other disposition of this petitioner in anywise whatsover
       and respondent should be restrained and prohibited from longer detaining this peteioner.</p>

<p>III.</p>

<p>Your petitioner futher informs the Court that he is not guilty of murer or of any other crime; but that notwithstanding certain conviction
       was had of this defendant for the offense of murder previous to the first day of January 1900 from which this petitioner duly complained
       to the State courts for relief; all of which denied him. And respondent the Seriff of King County threatens to execute this petitioner by
       hanging him by the neck until dead August 23, 1901.</p>

<p>That at the time the said judgment against the said defendant was affiremd and became final, the said petitioner was and on the 2nd day
       of Apil A.D. 1900 sentenced to die by being hung by the sheriff of King County, State of Washington; the said hanging to be on the 23
       day of August 1901. That at the time this petitioner was so sentenced and at the time this petitioner was tried for the alleged offense, which
       was the killing of one John Doe Mason and at the time this petitioner was informed against for the said killing and at the time this petitoner
       was informed against for the said killing and at the time the petitoner was tried and at the time the final judgment was rendered against the
       petitioner, the only law authorizing capital punishment and execution in the State of Washington was that certain provision of the laws of the 
       State of Washington and more particularly contained in sections 6993, 6994, and 6995 of the Code known as "Balinger's Code, being a
       certification of the laws of the State of Washignton; which prescribed and only prescribed that the person duly sentenced to death should be
       hung in the County where the said sentence</p>

<pb/>

<p>was passed and the trial had and by the sheriff of the said County wherin the said trial was had and the said sentence was passed.
</p>
<p>That at the time this petitioner was informed against and was tried and was sentenced and judgment became final in the State courts,
       the only law in existence respecting and concerning and relating to the execution of this petitioner, or of any other person, was that 
       herein referred to , which alone vested and invested the sheriff of King County with the right and authority to execute the prisoner or
       the person so condemned and limited and wholly limited the said execution to the venue, jurisdiction and place in the County of trial
       and place of sentence.</p>

<p>VI.</p>

<p>That subsequent to the trial of this petitioner, the conviction of this peteitioner, the return of the verdict and subsequent to the final judgment
       and before execution of the judgment, while the same was pending, the Legislature of the State of Washington did duly repeal all law upon
       the subject of hanging and executions, did wholly repeal then the law existing upon the subject, particularly repealing all law authorizing the
       sheriff of King County, or any sheriff, or any officer which had heretofore been authorized to execute the judgment against this petitioner and did
       repeal and put an end to all law in the State of Washignton authorizing any person whomsover to execute this petitioner adn in the State did enact
       an covering the whole subject matter and as being the only law upon the subject, to-wit, that certain Act of Legislature of the State of Washington,
       approved March 8,1901, as appears on page 100 of the Laws of Washington of 1901, prescribing a new and absoute form of procedure, a new and
       absolute authority in a new and heretofore unnamed person respecting executions and did paticularly provide, which had not heretofore been provided
       nor a part of the law; that, the person condemed to death should be delivered to</p>

<pb/>

<p>the Warden of the Penitentiary; that the said Warden shall take the prisoner so condemned and keep him in solitary confinement until the day appointed in
       the warrant for his execution; and that upon the day so appointed the Warden should, within the walls of the penitentiary execute the prisoner or the person
       so ordered to be executed.</p>

<p>VII.</p>

<p>That the said law repealed all other laws existing upon the subject and that there is no other law or process whatsover other than that neamed in the said Act
       of March 8, 1901. </p>

<p>VIII.</p>

<p>Your petitioner further represents that notwithstanding there is no law for the further detention and holding of him, the said petitioner, and not withstanding as he
       alleges that there is no law justifying or authorizing the form of judgment to be executed against him, either of imprisonment or of execution, the said sheriff of King
       County still holds your petitioner in custody and restraint without authority of the law and against the law.</p>

<p>IX.</p>

<p>That your petitioner under the Constitution is entitled to be held only by due process of law and that as an indictment of the United States, as your petitioner is, he 
       is entitled to be relieved from an unjust and improper restraint and from any law that seeks to hold him contrary to the Constitution for the purpose of execution
       or otherwise.</p>

<p>X.</p>

<p>That the excuse or reason given by the said State of Washignton and the sheriff of King County, particularly for the restraint and holding of the said petitioner is that 
       under the law of the State of Washington heretofore named, to-wit, the Act of Marh 8, 1901, said State of Washington and the said Sheriff has a right to hold said prisoner,
       your petitioner herein, and that under the law it is their purpose to</p>

<pb/>

<p>return the said petitioner to the warden of the State Peitentiary for the purpose of having this petitioner executed, as provided by said law, by the said warden of said
       State Penitentiary. That the said law so far as it concerns this prisoner, your petitioner herein, and so far as it relates to him, is invalid and otherwise ex post facto; that
       is to say, the said law has been passed subsequent to the alleged commission by this petitioner of any crime subsequent to the trial of this petitioner and subsequent to
       the final udgement and subsequent to the judgment which was rendered against him, but before the said final judgment was affirmed in the Supreme Court of the United
       States, and the said law adds burdens to this petitioner which were not to be borne by him, nor a part of the law at the time he was tried, nor a part of the law, which law
       was a part of the procedure under which he was to be tried; nor a part of the law under which any form of judgment against him could be executed, and the said law as to
       him, your petitioner herin, is void as violating the provisions of the Federal Constitution in this, to-wit:</p>

<p>First, in that it does not provide due process against him, and Second, that the same is invalid being ex post facto law as against your petitioner, and your petitioner asserts
       that any attempt to take any steps against him in the way of execution or further imprisonment or restraint under the said law is wholly void, unconstitutional; contrary to the 
       law and against the law; particularly of the Constitution of the United States and of the statutes thereunder.</p>

<p>XI.</p>

<p>That the said law designated as the "Rand" law heretofore referred to and which had previously repealed all laws upon the subject ot which it the said Rand law related, leaving
       no other law upon the subject thatn the said "Rand law".</p>

<pb/>

<p>XII.</p>

<p>The said Rand law thereafter, to-wit, on the 12th day of June 1901 by the legislature of the state of Washington was repealed by the following Repealing Act:</p>

<p>Chapter I.
       Repealing An Act Relative to the Death Warrant.</p>

<p>An Act repealing an act entiled "An Act relating to the death warrant, the contents therof, the return fo the same, and fixing place of execution and amending sections 6993 and 6995
       of Ballinger's Annotated Codes and Statutes of Washington", approved March 8th, 1901, and declaring an emergency.</p>

<p>Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Washington:
       
       Section 1. The act of the legislature of the State of Washington entitled "An Act relating to the death warrant, the contents thereof, the return of same, and fixing place of execution, and 
       amending sections 6993 and 695 of Ballinger's Annotated Codes and Statutes of Washington, "approved March 8th, 1901, is hereby repealed.

       Sec. 2. For the purpose of preventing the act hereby repealed from ever becoming operative for any purpose an emergency is hereby declared to exist and this act shall take effect immediately.

       Passed the Senate June 11th, 1901.
       Passed the House June 12th 1901.
       Approved by the Governor June 12th 1901.</p>

<p>XIII.</p>

<p>That after the said repeal of the said Rand law as herinbefore referred to the said Legislature fo the State of Washington duly then and there enacted a law, having for its purpose the creation 
       and establishment of a complete of procedure, complete in itself, sepeate and apart from any other law upon the subject and for the purpose of being wholly the law adn the only law upon
       executions; which law is as follows:</p>

<pb/>

<p>Chapter 9

       (S.B.No.4)

       Relating to the Death Warrant.

       An Act relating to the issuance of the death warrant, the contetns thereof, the return of same, fixing the place of executions, providng for the safe custody fo the condemned, defining the duties
       of the superintentdent of the State Penitentiary, the seriff and the clerk in relation to said warrant, repealing all acts or parts of acts inconsistent herewith, excepting as to acts done and crimes
       commiteed prior to the taking effect of this act.

       Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Washington:

       Section 1. When judgment of death is rendered following conviction adn no appeal is taken, or the judgment has been affirmed on appeal, a death warrant shall be issued by the clerk of the trial
       court, which said warrant shall be signed by a judge of said court and attested by the clerk under the seal of the court. Said warrant shall be directed ot the superintendent of the State Penitentiary
       of the State of Washington and shall state the conviction of the person named therein and the judgement of the court, and appoint a day in which the judgement  shall be executed by the Superintendent
       of the State Pernitentiary, which shall not be less than thirty nore more than ninety days from the date of final judgment.</p>

<p>Sec. 2. At the time of the issuance of said death warrant an order shall be issued by the clerk of the court, which shall be signed by the judge and attested by the clerk under the seal of the court. Said order
       shall direct the sheriff to hold the person condemned to death, who shall be name therein, in safe custody and forthwith deliver said person together with the death warrant into the hands of the superintendent
       of the State Penitentiary.</p>

<p>Sec. 3. Upon delivery to him of said death warrant and of the person therein named, the Superintendent of the State Penitentiary shall take the person condemned to be executed and keep said person in 
       safe custody within said State Penitentiary until the day appointed in the wararnt for the exectution upon which appointed day he shall carry out the mandate contained in said warrant by executing said
       condemned person within the walls of the State Penitentiary in the manner provided by law. And between the date of receiving such condemend person and the date fixed in such warrant for his execution,
       and such superintendent shall not suffer or permit any person to visit, converse, or communicate with such condemend person excepting the attendants in the State Penitentiary, Legal, spiritual and medical
       advisers, and the members of the immediate family of the condemned person, which visits and communication shall be under and subject to the rules and regulations of the State Penitentiary.</p>

<p>Sec. 4. The superintendent of the State Penitentiary shall keep in his office as part of the public records a book in which shall be entered a copy of the death warrant and his reutnr made theron together with a
       complete statement of his acts in pursuance of said warrant.</p>

<p>Sec. 5. Within twenty days after said execution the superintendent of the sate penitentiary shall return said death warrant to the clerk of the court form which same was issued with his return</p>

<pb/>

<p>thereon showing all proceedings had by him thereunder.</p>

<p>Sec. 6 The sheriff to whom the above named order is issued and delivered shall immediately execute such orer and return the same into court within twenty days after he has delivered the death warrant
       and the person named therein into the hands of the superintendent of the state penitentiary, with his return thereon showing all proceedings had by him thereunder.</p>

<p>Sec. 7. The clerk of the court from which the death warrant and the order to the sheriff were issued shall upon receipt of the returns from the superintendent of the state penitentiary and from the sheriff, 
       hereinbefore directed, file same ith the records in the case and subjoin to the record of conviction and sentence a brief abstact of such returns.</p>

<p>Sec. 8. Pending the issuance of the death warrant the sheriff shall hold the condemned person in safe custody.</p>

<p>Sec. 9. All acts or parts of acts in conflict with this act are hereby repealed, except as herinafter provided.</p>

<p>Sec. 10. The provisions of this act shall not apply to any act done or crime heretofore committed shall be prosecuted under the laws existing at the time of the commission of said acts or crimes in the same
       manner as if enacted, and all such existing laws and especially sections 6993 and 6995 of Ballinger's Annotated Codes and Statutes of Washington are herby continued in force as to all such acts and crimes
       committed prior to the taking effect of this act.
       Passed the Senate June 12, 1901.
       Passed the House June 12, 1901.

       Note by the Secretary of State.

       The above act was recieved by the Governor on the 12th day of June, 1901 and not being filled wihtin the time required by law with his objections thereto, becomes a law under the provisions of the Constituion
       of the State of Washignton, the same being filed on June 24th 1901, without the signature of the Governor.

       Sam H. Nichols,
       Secretary of State.</p>

<p>XIV.</p>

<p>The said enactment being the only one upon the subject now existing in the State of Washington and for the State of Washington. The said enactment, however, under the Constitution of the State of Washington
       is not to be in effect, cannot go into effect and is of no effect or operation until ninety (90) days after the 12th day of June 1901. That therefore and whereas, by reason of the permises, there is no law, of any nature
       whatsoever now in existence concerning or</p>

<pb/>

<p>appying to executions of persons for the offense of murder other than that of the said Act known as Senate Bill No.4 above stated, which said Act has no effect of operation in anywise whatsover upon this petitioner
       and in nowise upon any person or persons whomsoever until after the 12th day of September 1901.</p>

<p>XV.</p>

<p>That unless your Honors, the judges of the Circuit Court of the United States, shall rescue your by its due process of habeas corpus, your petitioner fears and now charges that the State of Washington, through the
       sheriff of King County, will continue to longer imprison him and will without the intervention on the part fo your Honors unlawfully and wrongfully and without any authority proceed to his execution, the taking of his
       life without due process of law and in violation of the Constitution of the United States, and by virtue and only by authority of an invalid, repealed or ex post facto law of the Legislature of the State of Washington.</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that your Honors will issue to him, your petitioner herein, a writ of habeas corpus to produce his body before the Court upon investigation and inquiry as to the matters herein stated
       and grant the relief as herin prayed for; or that your Honors will grant an order to show cause why the said writ should not issue and relief upon the said writ, at the time of the issuance of the same, be granted as herein
       prayed, and your petitioner prays that upon the hearing of the said writ it shall be ordered by the Court that there is no law or authority in the State of Washington for the execution of the prisoner, your petitioner herein, or
       for the carrying out of any udgment against this petitioner and that the restraint of this petitioner and his imprisonment be declared to be illegal and ordering this petitoner to be at once discharge and go hence without day.</p>

<p>James Hamilton Lewis</p>
<p>Attorneys for Petitioner</p>








</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>