<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0088.021">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Testimony</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0088.021</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Testimony</title>
<date when="1887">1887</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1887">1887</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Welch</term>
<term>McKay, William</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McKay, Alice</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, Della</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Ronald, J. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Gilman, L. C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020-05" who="#lkw">encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#nl">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Capt. Welch, a witness called on behalf of the respondent, after being duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>Q. [Gilman] You reside in Seattle? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. What has been your occupation during the past six or eight years? A. Policeman.</p>

<p>Q. Of the City of Seattle? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Have you during that period known the petitioner in this case Alice McKay.</p>

<p>A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. What has she been doing during that period. A. Well, I never knew her to do anything here. She has been off and on here between here and Tacoma.</p>

<p>Q. Has she ever lived here during that period A. She lived a short time here.</p>

<p>Q. Where? A. Well, she lived down on the beach at the foot of Pike street. Lived there a while.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know, Captain Welch, what her reputation at the present time is as a law abiding <del/> woman and as a woman of sober and temparate habits?</p>

<p>A. Well, I could not really say as to her character, I cannot <sic>saw</sic> anything against her except what I heard.</p>

<p>Q. What was her reputation? A. It was not good.</p>

<p>Q. Did she have the reputation of being a drunken woman?</p>

<p>Ronald: We object.</p>

<p>The COURT: Objection overruled and exception allowed.</p>

<p>A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Was she not one of those persons that you police were watching?</p>

<p>RONALD: We object.</p>

<p>The COURT: You may answer. Exception noted.</p>

<p>A. I dont know that we watched her very close, we could have got her if we had wanted her, at any time.</p>

<p>Q. Was her husband <sic>McKan</sic> with her at that time? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Did you know McKay? A. <sic>Ys</sic> sir.</p>

<p>Q. What kind of a looking man is he? A. He is rather a good looking man.</p>

<p>Q. Is he a white man? A. Yes sir.</p>

<fw>[Jones, D-EX. <gap/> 17. <gap/> 76--110.</fw>

<pb/>

<p>CROSS-EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>Q. [Ronald] You say she was a bad woman and is a bad woman at the present time?</p>

<p>Mr. GILMAN: One more question. Do you know where McKay is? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know the cause or reason for his leaving the Territory? A. I heard that there was a warrant for him.</p>

<p>The COURT: Do you know what he left for? A. No sir.</p>

<p>RONALD: Do you know what that woman has been doing for the lst two or three years, since she left her husband? A. I dont know what she has been doing the last year.</p>

<p>Q. Dont you know as a fact that this woman has worked hard and been an industrious woman, trying to earn an honest living? A. I dont know.</p>

<p>Q. What are you doing now, loafing around the streets since you left the police force? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>GILMAN: You have means to support yourself? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>The COURT: That is not material.</p>

<p>------0------</p>

<fw>[Jones, C-EX. <gap/> 18. <gap/> t76--112.</fw>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
