<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0365.016">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>John Matthews v. Henry M. White. Testimony</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Leon-Flores, Jacky" xml:id="jlf">Jacky Leon-Flores</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0365.016</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">John Matthews v. Henry M. White. Testimony</title>
<date when="1921-08">August 1921</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1921-08">August 1921</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Matfeo, Antonio</term>
<term>Lozarok, Annie</term>
<term>Fisher, Thomas M.</term>
<term>Bourland, Lilian Held</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Matthews, James</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>White, Henry M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Vanderveer, George F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Pierce, Ralph S.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Saunders, Robert C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Kolmitz, Charlotte</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Neterer, Jeremiah</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court of the United States for the Western District of Washington</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-07" who="#jlf">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  

<p>37012/600                  NcNeil Island.</p>

<p>
Re-opening case of         T.M Fisher, Examining Inspector
JOHN MATTHEWS.             Lilian Held Bourland, Reporter.</p>

<p>Alien Sworn.</p>

<p>Q   (Inspector Fisher) I want to get a little more detailed information
    from you. What was your name in the Old Country?
    A. My name in the Old Country was Yan Matveyeff.
Q   And you changed it yourself to John Matthews? A. Yes.
Q   You told me you were born in Ukrania? What is the name of the place
    in Ukrania. What is the country, provice, district, state, town?
    A. State of Chartkoof (?) Town of Noshkofsky (?)
Q   Ukrania is now a part under the Russian flag and part under the
    Austrian flag. A. Yes.
Q   What do you call your nationality? A. Ukranian.
Q   At that time were you an Austrian subject? A. Yes, sir, yes.
Q   What was the last place in that country that you lived. Did you live
    in any other place? A. No, my mother and father were born in that
    Chortkoof.
Q   What was the date of your birth there? A. I cannot tell you.
Q   How old are you now? A. I am 29 years old.
Q   How do you know that? A. I had my book made out by the priest
    when I left that country?
Q   A passport?  Yes, I lost it in the Porkupine fire in Ontario.
Q   Never got another one? Never applied for one with the Consul or any
    one else?  A. How could I, I have not been back, No, sir.
Q   Do you know whether there is any baptismal or birth record?
    A. That was all in my book given by the priest but I have lost it.
Q   Do you know whether it was recorded there? A. It is all changed
    there now.
Q   What was the nearest place where your Government had a recording office
    or something of that kind? A. That was Chortkoff.
Q   What was your fathers name? A. Antonio Matfeo (Matveyeff)
Q   Your father was born there? A. Yes.
Q   Do you knows your mother's maiden name - her name before she was married?
    A. Annie Lozarok.
Q   Are your parents living? A. No, sir.
Q   Have you any relatives in the Old Country that you know of?
    A. I have no written to the Old Country since I was - 15 years ago,
Q   Do you know whether your parents are living? A. My mother died
    when i was 7 and my father when I was 14.
Q   Are you married? A. No, sir.
Q   When did you leave the country? A. I left Ukrania when I was,
    I think about 15 years old.
Q   Now, you have lived in Canada for a number of years?  A. I lived
    in Canada ever since- all my life since I came over.</p>

<pb></pb>

<p>37012/600</p>

<p>
Q   How did you get that mining claim that you told me about your have over
    in Canada, if you had never became a citizen of Canada?
    A. In Canada if you came from England, France, or Germany, or - you
    could, if you were prospecting, you could go mining and prospecting.
    They never asked if you are a citizen or not.
Q   Did you ever become a citizen of Canada or not? A. No, sir, I did not.
Q   Wheen you entered the United States at Victoria the record shows that
    you stated you were a citizen of Canada, You claimed to be a Canadia
    citizen? A. Yes, yes, All very well. When you live in Canada, in
    a country 12 years, you are a Citizen, you think-
Q   You claimed it by reason of the length of time you lived there and not
    because of any papers? A. Yes, sir.
Q   Did you buy any property? A. Yes, I have a claim.
Q   Did you buy it?  A. No, sir. It is a mineral claim.
Q   You had partners in it? A. Yes sir, Four of us.
Q   Have you heard from them lately? A. No, sir, and I don't want
    to either from this place.
Q   What do they call you, John Matthews or Jack Matthews?
    A. Just call me Jack Matthews around Canada wherever I was, with the
    people I was working with.
Q   You got that name from your name from the Old Country- Yan?
    A. In the Old Country I was called Yanich Matevyeff. In my passport
    which has been wrote by the Austrian priest- Yan Matevyeff
Q   The English of that would be John Matthews or Jack Matthews?
    A. I have always, all my life had only one name since I came to Canada,
    The prient said, you take this name- Jack Matthews- Priest Wooley,
    in Cobalt. Write to the priest and he tell you all about it.
Q   You never declared your intention to become a citizen of the United
    States? A. No, sir. You fellows could write to Cobalt Police
    Station and they will give you my record because I never have been in - I
    have been in Cobald for 9 years and I never was one in trouble, but in
    the registration there they have my name, where I reported once a
    money. They could tell you who I am. Or write a Pichartin (?)
    I was working or to my mines where I was working, and you find out who
    I am, and if I was arrested for even about 24 hours or ever in trouble,
    I never arrested for an hour for 13 years. That in Alaska was my first
    trouble.</p>

<p>    Description: Age 28; Height 5'61/4in; weight 189 lbs; forehead, medium,
    face round; build heavey; hair, dark brown; nose, regular; eyes, hazel green,
    complexion, ruddy; marks, scar left side head, 2" over ear 1/2n long;
    Scar, right index finger 1 3/4" long; portion right ring finger removed,</p>

<p>Attest:
Lilian Held Bourland,
Book 1066 Transcribed February 4, 1921</p>

<pb></pb>
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>


</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>