<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0181.043">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Seventy-six Hindus v. Seattle Department of Immigration. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>

</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0000.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Petitioner v. Defendant. Type of document</title>
<date when="1000">1000</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>National Archives and Records Administration, Seattle Branch, Washington</repository>
<collection>RG 21: US District Court, Western Division of Washington, Seatle</collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-10">October 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<pb></pb>
<p>IN THE UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT FOR THE WESTERN DISTRICT
OF WASHINGTON, NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>
<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE 
UNLAWFUL DETENTION OF 
SEVENTY-THREE HINDOOS.) ) )
No. 2532. 
MEMORANDUM BRIEF OF 
PETITIONERS. 
REPLY BRIEF.</p>
<p>PRACTICE OF DEPARTMENT.
It will be noted that the respondent states
that it has been the practice of the department to issue
warrants where the aliens were likely to become public
charges, and not to wait until the aliens had become
public charges. This clearly shows that the practice
of the department has not been in accordance with law,
and in accordance with Section 20. The respondent urges
that he knows of no decisions in which more than a
liklihood to become public charges is necessary.</p>
<p>The language of Section 20 is to plain and
the government's rules are so clear that it was intended
that the alien should actually become a public charge
before a warrant should be issued, that a decision could
hardly be founded on a matter that is plain on its face
as to the intent of Section 20</p>
<p>The practice of the department in the past is
<pb></pb>
not law for this court, but the construction of Section
20 can be but one way, if the court is strictly construes
that section, as petitioners believe it should be construed.</p>
<p>RESPONDENT'S CITATION PROVES PETITIONERS' CASE.</p>
<p>By reference to United States vs. Williams, 
175 Federal, 274, it will be noted that this case decides
the very points contended for and by the petitioners.
The holding there was that if the Secretary violated the
statute, that the courts would interfer, also that the
courts would see that there was some evidence upon which
the decision of the secretary was based. In that case, 
the Court further decided that it was not only necessary
to find that the alien had become a pauper, but that it
might be shown that alien had become a prisoner as well,
showing clearly that if would be neccessary for him to
become something, either a pauper or a prisoner.</p>
<p>The United States attorney contends that the
warrant was not issued as a result of a clandestine entry, 
but on a liability to become a public charge, showing
clearly that these cases could not come within the purview
or the intent of Section 20.</p>
<p>FRANK GREEN'S STATEMENT.</p>
<p>That respondent states that he had a talk with
Mr. Frank Green, and the attorney for petitioners 
likewise had a talk with the said party. Mr. Green states
that he was a soldier in the Philippine Islands and that
it was customary to demand a registration certificate 
before permitting aliens in the Philippine Islands to 
<pb></pb>
testify in court or to do any act concerning governmental 
or city or state business, but on reading the affidavit 
of the interpretor which petitioners furnished, Mr.
Green states that doubtless that is a fact today, and
that such rules are doubtless followed. That what he 
was referring to was that during the time of the insurrection
when he was a soldier was issuing some of these
certificates himself. That he really did not know as
to the law or as to what the immigration or governmental
requirement was, but he believes that perhaps some
such rule as that mentioned by the interpretor was
probabaly correct.</p>
<p>GOVERNMENT ADMITS OUR CONTENTION. 
It will be noted by referring to the memorandum
brief of respondent on the first page thereof, the 
second from the last line, this language used by the attorney
for the government, "and whether at said hearing
some evidence has been secured". It has been our contention
that no evidence has ever been presented. At 
the bottom of page 3 of respondent's brief, it will be
noted the government contends that the language used
in Section 20 quoted by petitioners as to those who do
become public charges is contended by the government to
have meant to meet cases where it could not be said
that there was a liklihood to become a public charge
at the time of entry. There is nothing in the law
justifiying this assertion and Section 20 is so plain that
it would be hard to read this contention into it.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>At the bottom of page 4 of respondent's brief, 
counsel states that Section 20 explicitely authorizes 
deportation for unlawful entry. This is quite correct, 
but he goes on and parenthetically states (including
original liability to become a public charge within three
years). There is nothing in the law to justify this 
parenthetic statememt and the section is so plain as to
make it obvious to the court that this is not intended.</p>
<p>On page 5 of respondent's brief, the sixth line
thereof, counsel states that the official warrants upon
authority of which the aliens are held has no bearing
on the original entry into the Philippines and that the
original entry is not questioned by the secretary's
warrant, but that the only ground on which the aliens are
held is of their liability to become public charges, which
is plainly not in accordance with Section 20, and here
again the government practically admits our contention.</p>
<p>Again, in the middle of page 6, the government
admits our contention as to the method of issuing the
informal certificate prior to the issuance of the cedula
or head tax. Thus it will be seen that the United States
attorney has in his bried admitted every contention made
be counsel for the aliens, his only contention now being
that Section 20 does not mean what it plainly and un-
equivocally states, and if it is to be strictly construed
the government's contentions cannot stand a moment.</p>
<p>The only other contention made by the government
is an attempt to read into Section 20 certain practices
<pb></pb> of the department which the petitioners claim is no
ground by reason of the unauthorized and unlawful 
authority exercised by the secretary and immigration 
officials in the past, due largely to the fact that the
courts have not had these matters brought to their 
attention in the past.</p>
<p>At the top of page 7 of respondent's brief,
respondent states that the same exhibits attached to
the brief of petitioners were sent to Washington,
this is not true. There were documents sent to Wash-
ington, but none so conclusive of a proper examination
at Manila and a lawful entry, as the ones attached to
petitioners' brief. It seems to petitioners that
these documents cannot be answered and that a lawful 
entry is shown thereby, the government admitting again
that these documents show more or less clearly that the
aliens were before the immigration authorities at Manila.</p>
<p>Again, at the end of the first paragraph of
Paragraph 7 it will be noted that the government admits
that there was no clandestine entry, but it is here con-
tended that the unlawful entry is not the basis for the
secretary's warrant on authority of which the aliens are
now being held, again admitting that an unlawful entry
is not shown in any way and practically admitting a
lawful entry.This does away with the only ground upon
which the government has to stand, which throws the
argument back upon the liability to become a public
charge, and in view of the specific terms of Section 20,
this contention must fall.</p>
<pb></pb>
<p>SECTION 20, NOT SECTION 3.</p>
<p>The government in the respondent's brief,
endeavors to inject Section 3 into the argument. The court
will have little difficulty in determining that Section
3 has nothing to do with this case and Section 20 is the
only section upon which the secretary can issue the
warrants.</p>
<p>NO EVIDENCE INTRODUCED.</p>
<p>On the last page of respondent's brief, this
language is found,"some evidence, however slight, having
been introduced in support of the ruling of the secretary".
No matter how carefully the court scans the testimony,
he will find that there has not been a word of testimony
and there has been no evidence introduced and there has
never ever been any evidence before any of the government
officials on the point involved in this petition,
on the fact of aliens having already become public
charges.</p>
<p>In the case cited by the government, it will be
noted that the courts held there must be some evidence and
that the decision was only final where it complied with
the law, in the one case where there had been no appeal
taken when that was the requisite, and in the other that
there had been an unlawful entry shown by the evidence, which
is not true in the case before this Honorable Court.
Respectfully submitted,</p>
<p>Herbert W. Meyers
Attorney for Petitioners.</p>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>