<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<title>DISTRICT COURT PROCEEDINGS</title>

<p>Julia D. Tolmie is suing for divorce from Alexander T. Tolmie, who, if the charges set fortha re true, has failed ot treat the lady as a wife should be: His most particular and keenly felt amissions being his frequent and prolonged absence from his castle and, to add insult to injury, he has failed in any way to provide the necessaries of life during his sojourn in other climes, such as bread, meat, milk, butter and the other little necessary accessories required to keep the soul from shuffling off this mortal coil, and so on the strength of this statement, or words to that effect, Judges Greene this morning referred the matter to M. W. W. Newtin, who will hear both sides of the oft told tale of domestic infelicity, deduce his own conclusions, and in good time report to his superior.</p>
<p>The greater portion of the day has been occupied--and still is--in the trial of Mr. J.F. Kelly, charged with the not uncommon crime of grand lardeny, for which the law fires penalties in case of guilt at various periods, all of them too long, however, in the minds of those who have to pay the fiddler at Seatco. Mr. Kelly's case consists in the fact that there was a check for $100 issued on the Tacoma bank. It was signed by, or rather it parported to be signed by Mr. Nelson Bennett, a gentleman not unknown in this section of the country in connection with great engineering and railroad work. On the presentation of the check to Mr. Bennett for payment by the bank, that gentleman most emphatically denied that he had ever signed such check, and, apparently for good and occult reasons, Mr. Kelly was supposed to have done so. In consequence of this Mr. K. was tried on March 4th, but the case was dismissed on the ground of legal technicalities. Mr. Kelly, however, was reindicted the smae day, and nearly all day long twelve men, good and true, have been listening to both sides of the story of the forged check, and they will hardly reach a conclusion before tomorrow.</p>
<p>Genuine New England maple syrup at Nelson Chilburg's.</p>
