<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<title>THE OLD AND NEW CHIEF JUSTICE
Impressive Scene at Court.</title>

<p>Immediately upon the convening of Court at 11o'clock this morning, the commission of Judge Richard A. Jones, as Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of Washington Territory and as Judge of the Court of the Third Judicial District, was presented by Hon. Eben Smith, President of the Bar Association, to his honor Judge Roger S. Greene, the retiring Chief Justice, Judge Greene immediately after the formal presentation to him of the new Chief Justice, administered the oath of office to that gentleman in a most remarkably impressive manner, every spectator of the large and interested audience rising en masse as if actuated by magnetic impulse and remained standing until the ceremony was completed. Judge Jones at its conclusion made a short address, in which he complimented his predecessor in fitting and deserved terms and entered upon the discharge of his official duties. At this stage of the proceedings Hon. Eben Smith arose, and in fitting remarks, introduced to the attention of the Court the action of the Bar of the Third Judicial Distrit of Washington Territory and presented the resolutions which appear in the following, and moved that the same be spread upon the records of the Court. We now quote the records of the Court:</p>
<p>Now, on this 12th day of March, A.D., 1887, came Eben Smith, President of the Bar Association of King County, Washington Territory, and touching the retirement of Roger S. Greene, of the Third Judicial District, and Chief Justice of Washington Territory, in behalf of the members of the Bar of the Third Judicial District, moves the Court that the resolutions following be received and spread upon the records of this Court, which motion was by the Court, Hon. Chief Justice Jones presidng, granted.</p>
<p>At a meeting of the members of the Bar of the Third Judicial District of Washington Territory, held at the Court room of the District Court for the Third Judicial District, at Seattle, King County, on the 11th day of March, 1887, the following resolutions were adopted without a dissenting vote.</p>
<p>Dated this 11th day of March, A.D., 1887. EBEN SMITH, President of the Bar Association of King County, W.T.</p>
<p>Roger S. Greene has filled the position of Justice and Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of Washington Territory for the past seventeen years and is now about to retire from the bench; therefore.</p>
<p>Resolved, That we, the members of the Bar of the Third Judicial District of Washington Territory, do cordially unite in testifying our high appreciation of the eminent Christain virtues, unflagging industry, uniform patience, profound and varied learning, sincere anxiety to do justice and absolute independence which have distinguished this upright magistrate through his judicial career, as well as our grateful recollection of the kindly courtesies he has constantly exhibited and our sincere wish for his continued health, happiness and prosperity; and</p>
<p>Resolved, That the President of the Bar Association of King County be requested to present these resolutions to the Court and ask that they be entered on the minutes and that a copy be engraved and presented ot the retiring Chief Justice.</p>
<p>Judge Greene then arose and amid profound silence and evidently affected by the surroundings, in his calm, dignified, clear concise and withal eloquent manner and elegant style, made on of the most impressive responses and farewell addresses that was ever listened to in any hall of justice, like unto the eloquence of the speech of Baker--and his farewell too--when he left the United States Senate and went forth to the tented field to meet his death for the principles upheld by him. Judge Green in his remarks reviewed the history of the Territory as it had passed before his eyes in the last seventeen years. He spoke in graphic terms of the birth of towns and cities; of the vast resources of our country and of its penetration and further development by the iron horse. Alluding to changes that have occurred in the administration of justice in this Territory and to the service of women in our jury system, always beneficial in its results and complimented the members of the Seattle Bar, as one of the strongest, ans ablest of the county, remarking that no higher talent was contained in any Bar. That it would have been impossible for any man to have maintained the character and virtues which were ascribed to him by these gentlemen without the able support and assistance which had been by them rendered to him, and Judge Greene bespoke for his successor the cordial assistance and aid in the discharge of the duties upon which he had entered. The speech of Judge Greene at times was permeated with a keen sense of humor all the more enhanced by the gravity which presaged the climax.</p>
<p>After Judge Greene's address, Hon. E.P. Ferry made a formal motion that Hon. Roger S. Greene be admitted ot practice as an attorney and counselor in the courts of Washington Territory, and then Judge Greene stepped forward, the entire bar and people assembled the roll of attorneys and took the usual oath.</p>
<p>Judge Jones then ordered an adjournment of his Court until April 11th.</p>
