<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>WASHINGTON VOTERS Tuesday will choose among others one U.S. Senator plus the seven person to represent them in the federal House of Representatives. Regardless of who is elected this time, it is highly unlikely that nay will turn out to be as flamboyant as J. Hamilton Lewis. Or as chagrined as John Beard Allen. Or as crazy as poor Marion Zioncheck.</p>
<p>It's been a mighty long time -- 78 years, in fact -- since the voters of Washington have sent a real dude to Congress. But J. Hamilton Lewis qualified for that distinction when he was elected in 1896 to one of the state's two at-large seats in the U.S. House.</p>
<p>Lewis moved to Seattle from Savannah, Georia, in 1885. He was a lawyer by trade but he found little demand for his services</p>

<title>Politicos of the Past
The Flamboyant, the Crazy And the Chagrined
by Eldon Barrett</title>

<p>at the bar so he turned to teaching rhetoric at the University of Washington and moonlighting as a stevedore on the waterfront. He also was a private in the Seattle Rifles during the anti-Chinese riots.</p>
<p>These were the days when Champ Clark and Tom Reed held sway in the House, Alongside these two political powers, the ordinary lawmakers faded into the woodwork -- except Lewis. He would show the Eastern city slickers that not all the folks from the far Northwest were blockheads dad in holey old mackinaws the shod in corked boots.</p>
<p>In fact, his initial entrance into the House chamber to receive the oath of office was a sensation, duly noted by the staid New York Times in a n article headlined "A Thing Of Beauty."</p>
<p>"...As he came down the center aisle," said the Times article, "he was a vision of loveliness, so to speak, for he was spotlessly and exquisitely arrayed. From pointed patent leather shoes to carefully parted auburn hair, he was a thing of beauty and, let us hope, a joy forever."</p>
<p>The Times reporter said Lewis' light trousers were "carefully cresed until they would cut paper." He wore a Prince Albert coat "smoothly pressed" and a white martingale about his neck.</p>
<p>"And underneath his waistcoat," the article continued, "his shirtfront was hidden beneath a puff tie of rich and shiny blue silk. His dainty hands were encased in a pair of brigh yellow gloves, and his face was covered with whiskers of the same color."</p>
<p>Champ Clark described Lewis as "the greatest dude in the United States."</p>
<p>Speaker Reed said he was a "thing of beauty and jaw forever."</p>
<p>Regardless of -- or possibly because of </p>

<fw type="footer">ELDON BARRETT is a reporter in the Seattle bureau of United Press international.</fw>

<p>-- his flamboyant debut, the folks back home declined to send Lewis back for another term, but he went on to a brilliant law career in Chicago where he was elected in 1912 as a senator from Illinois. Lewis diedd in 1939 while serving as the Democratic whip in the Senate.</p>
<p>Before the 17th Amendment was enacted in 1913, U.S. senators were chosen by their respective state legislatures. John Beard Allen, a Walla Walla lawyer, served one term but when he sought re-election, he found himself embroiled in a bitter political battle in Olympia. That was in 1893. </p>
<p>The parties were split over his selection and his supporters were unable to muster a majority. On the other hand, Allen backers were able to keep the other candidates from making the grade.</p>
<p>For three months the state lawmakers


debated the issue, but finally they gave up and went home without acting on the appointment. Consequently, Gov. John Hart McGraw, a friend and political ally of Alen, stepped in and reappointed him to the post.</p>
<p>This was satisfactory to the U.S. Senate Committee on Elections, but the tuff Senate, after five months of indecision, voted down Allen's nomination, 32-39, and refused to seat him. The majority held that to let the governor appoint a senator would establish a precedent that would be intolerable.</p>
<p>The embarrassed Allen went home and the state functioned with only one member in the upper chamber until the legislature met again in 1895 and named U.S. Rep. John L. Wilson to the Senate. Wilson had been the tax collector under President James Arthur at Spokane Falls and Colfax.</p>
<p>Rep. Marion Zioncheck was the most tragic of the lawmakers representing this state in the nation's capital. A brilliant, tough young Pole who had been brought to the United States at the age of three, he gew up on Ski Road and was poor most of his life. He worked as a logger, cowboy, dishwasher, fish peddler and rat catcher. He wanted to be a lawyer and finally got his diploma from the University of Washington and was admitted to the bar in 1929.</p>
<p>During his last year of college, he was elected president of hte student body and organized the independents on campus into an anti-Freek coalition opposing the fraternity boys. He applied the tactics he learned on campus when he led a movement to recall Seattle Mayor Frank Edwards, whom Ziocheck charged was playing wiht private power against the people. The voters did recall Edwards and Zioncheck found he had political muscle. In 1932 at the age of 32 he ran for Congress, declaring he was a radical, and won. He won again in 1934.</p>

<p>Then on New Year's morning in 1936, he began a downhill sleighride that ended with his suicide. He staggered into the lobby of a Washingotn apartment house, plugged in all the numbers on the switchboard and wished everyone on the exchange a "Happy New Year."</p>
<p>He sobered up in jail.</p>
<p>A few days later he was arrested for speeding. When told he was doing 70 miles an hour, he said: "It couldn't have been me, I'd have been doing 80."</p>
<p>Rubey Louise Nix, a WPA typist form Texarkana, read about him in the newspapers, looked him up and shortly thereafter they were married. On their honeymoon, Zioncheck had several automobile wrecks, sideswiped a truck, was challenged</p>


