<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<note>906</note>

<p>The Territory vs James Riley</p>

<p>Be in <unclear>rembrued</unclear> that on the 4th judicial day of the Sept. Term 1861 of the District Court of the 2d jud District W.T. the Defenden was brought into Open Court in custody of an officer and that the Grand Jury emannelled sworn and charged on the first days of the Term come into Court <sic>and and</sic> won by order of the Court discharged in <del>podence</del> of the Defendant and the Court then ordered a Grand Jury to be summoned by the Sheriff of Thurston County which writ down orally by the Sheriff and that the times <unclear>secispicial</unclear> in orally summonings and <unclear>puttings</unclear> said Jurys into the Box did not exceed five minutes, and that the Defendant was then called upon at once to make his challenged to the <unclear>painist</unclear> if any be taken</p>

<p>That the Defendant thereupon orally challenged the pannel of Grand Jurors then &amp; there <unclear>protseiteds</unclear> to him at the Grand Jury about to be sworn &amp; charged to <unclear>enquire</unclear> of official against the laws of the Territory, and thereupon requested the Court to grant him sufficient <unclear>time</unclear> to prepare his said challenges in writing verified by affidavit as required by law. to the eaid that the Court might pass upon and determine the sufficiency thereof and in case said challenges to the persons should not be allowed that them the Defendant <unclear>nright to</unclear>

<pb...></pb...>

<unclear>excscribe</unclear> his right to challenge the indictment <unclear>annnlgent</unclear> of said Jury before being sworn which request of the Defendant was refused by the Court and did said challenge to the personal <unclear>disadured</unclear> by the Courtw without granting any time to propose said challenges in writing at <unclear>afidavit</unclear> and without says hearing at to the sufficing thereof. and said Grand Jury was thereupon immediately sworn and charged.</p>

<p>To all which the Defendant excepted and prays the Court to award this his Bill of <unclear>Excepttent</unclear> and to seige and seal the <unclear>same</unclear></p>

<p>Clarke Landon &amp; Dminken &amp; Garfield</p>

<p>Attys for Deft</p>


<p>Refused as not being in accordance with the facts</p>

<p>C C Hewitt C J and presiding Judge of 2nd Judicial District</p>