<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>In the District Court of the Second Judicial District of Washington Territory holding Terms at <unclear>Montesano</unclear> for Chehalis County, W.T.</p>

<p>Territory of Washington vs. Gus Beudjus Robert Shauglund Ben Frederickson, Pete Peterson, Frank Nelson, Fred Strougburger, John Bleadery Andrew Johnson, Leander Broun John Saxon, John Tompson Alex Agreu Thomas Jacobs. E Emal. Andrew Anderson and Charles Burka Defendants } #135 Indictment</p>

<p>Gus Beudjus, Robert Shauglund, Ben Frederickson, Pete Peterson, Frank Nelson, Fred Strougburger, John Bleuding, Andrew Johnson, Leander Brown, John Saxon, John Tompson, Alex Agreu, Thomas Jacoms, E Emil Andrew Anderson and Charles Burke are accused by the grand jury of Chehalis County Washington Territory by this indictment of the crime of Malicious Mischief committed as follows, to wit:</p>

<p>the said, Gus Beudjus, Robert Shangluud, Ben Frederickson, Pete Peterson, Frank Nelson, Fred Strongburger, John Bleuding, Andrew Johnson, Leander Brown, John Saxen, John Thompson, Alex Agree

<note>II II</note>

<pb...></pb...>

Thomas Jacobs, E Emel, Andrew Anderson and Charles Burke on the 9th day of September A.D. 1889, and is the right term, in the said County of Chehalis in the said Second Judicial District, in the Territory of Washington, then and there being <unclear>one Pound rich</unclear> of the value of $600.00, the property of one Wilson Graham, then &amp; there being and sitate in the said County and Territory, thereby maliciously intending to injure and destroy such <unclear>Poundrich</unclear> did willfully, maliciously, unlawfully, feloneously and with malace towards and against said Wilson Graham cut, tear, pull down injure and destroy to the great damage of the said Wilson Graham</p>

<p>Contrary to the statute in suce case made and provided and against the peace &amp; dignity of the Territory of Washington</p>

<p>George Jo Moody</p>

<p>Prosecuting Attorney</p>

<p>Second Judicial District.</p>

<p>Washington Territory</p>