<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>C. H. HANFORD, a witness called on behalf of the Respondent, after being duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>Q. [Gilman] Mr. Hanford, do you know the petitioner in this case, Alice McKay? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. How long have you known her? A. Something like six or seven years.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know what her character is as a law abiding woman and as a temparate woman?</p>

<p>RONALD: We object to that.</p>

<p>The COURT: Do you mean her public reputation?</p>

<p>GILMAN: I intended to prove both.. I do not know that I can prove any specific acts by Mr. Hanford.</p>

<p>The COURT: You ask then simply if he knows her general reputation as a law abiding citizen.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know what her general reputation is as a law abiding woman and as a temperate woman?</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: At the present time?</p>

<p>The COURT: It is in the present tense that the question is asked.</p>

<p>A. Well, jus tat the present time I do not think I know much about her reputation, within the last year I have not known much about her or her reputation.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know what it was prior to that time?</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: We object.</p>

<p>A. Yes.</p>

<p>Q. What was it?</p>

<p>Mr. Ronald: We except.</p>

<p>A. I cannot say I know as to temperance, but as to her being a law breaker I know her reputation.</p>

<p>Q. What was it? A. It is bad. Persistent, troublesome violater of the law.</p>

<p>Q. In 1883-4 you were assistant district attorney were you not? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Did you ever have occasion to prosecute this woman? A. I did.</p>

<p>Q. When? A. It was in the fall of 1883 at Tacoma.</p>

<p>Q. For what offense?</p>

<p>RONALD: We object it is immaterial.</p>

<p>The COURT: Objection overruled and exception noted.</p>

<p>A. For selling spiritous liquors to Indians.</p>

<p>Q. With what result?</p>

<p>RONALD: We object.</p>

<fw>[Hanford, D-EX. <gap></gap> 15. <gap></gap> 76--100.</fw>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>The COURT: I presume there is better evidence.</p>

<p>Gilman: In the short time I have had I have not had time to get the record in Tacoma to introduce that. We will offer to prove the conviction of the defendant.</p>

<p>CROSS-EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>Q. [RONALD] How many times do you know of her being arrested for assault and battery? A. I dont remember any specific acts of being arrested for assault and battery.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know of her being arrested except that one time? that you prosecuted her Mr. Hanford, of your own personal knowledge? A. Not of my own personal knowledge.</p>

<p>Q. That is the only time that you knew of her violating any law? A. Yes, of my own knowledge.</p>

<p>Q. The fact is the jury hung in that case? A. no sir.</p>

<p>REDIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>Q. [Gilman] What is the fact? [I think I am entitled to it as he has gone into the question]</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: We object I would not have been allowed to ask that question.</p>

<p>The COURT: I will hear the answer, but I will strike it out myself if I change my mind about it.</p>

<p>Q. What was the verdict? A. She plead guilty, there was no jury called.</p>

<p>RONALD: It is not a fact that you suspended sentence because she was under duress and force to do so by her husband? A. No sir, that was not the case. There has <sic>naver</sic> been a judgement in the case, the Court suspended sentence.</p>

<p>GILMAN: For what cause?</p>

<p>RONALD: We object.</p>

<p>The COURT: Objection overruled, exception allowed.</p>

<p>A. Because she appeared in Court with <sic>twi</sic> small children and made an appeal to the court that it would be a great hardship to send her to the Penitentiary on McNeal's island, where there was no provision made for the keeping of a</p>

<fw>[Hanford, RD-EX. <gap></gap> 16. <gap></gap> 76--105.</fw>

