<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In the District Court of the Third Judicial District of Washington 
Territory, holding terms at Seattle</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of 
Lee Kee 
for a writ of habeas corpus
Petition</p>

<p>To the Honorable Roger S Greene sole presiding Judge of said Court</p>

<p>The petition of <unknown>No Liv</unknown> respectfully represents</p>

<p>I. That Lee Kee is unlawfully imprisoned confined and restrained of 
his liberty by James H Woolery chief of police and leeping the jail 
of the city of Seattle at the city jail of said City in King 
County Washington Territory</p>

<p>II. That the cause or pretense of his aforesaid confinement and 
restraint according to your petitioners best knowledge and belief 
is by virtue of an alleged committment, a copy of which is 
hereto <unknown>annexed worded</unknown> Exhibit "A" and made part hereof.</p>

<p>III. That your petitioner is advised and verily believes that the 
imprisonment of the said Lee Kee is illegal and that said 
illegality consists in</p>

<p>First
That the offense charged in the said alleged commitment of 
itself constitutes no crime for which the said Lee Kee should 
be restrained of his liberty</p>

<p>Second
That the court from which said alleged commutment 
issued had no jurisdiction of said pretended offense</p>

<p>Third
That the Court from which said alleged commitment
(NEW PAGE)
issued had no authority to issue the same.</p>

<p>Fourth:
That the said pretended commitment is void upon <unknown>itsface</unknown></p>

<p>Fifth
That the ordinance of the city of Seattle, for a violation of which 
is <strike></strike> named in said commitment as cause therefor
is without authority of law and is void.</p>

<p>Sixth
And that by reason of for each of said causes the prisoner is deprived of his liberty without due process of law.</p>

<p>Wherefor your petitioner prays that a writ of Habeas
Corpus may be granted directed to the said James H Woolery 
Chief of Police and Jailer of said city of Seattle commanding
him to have the body of the said Lee Kee before your
Honor at a time and place therein to be specified, to do 
and receive what shall then and there be considered before your 
honor together with the time and cause of the said Lee Kee's 
detention and said writ. and that the said Lee Kee 
may be restored to his liberty.</p>

<p>Dated at Seattle May 25th 1885</p>

<p>his 
<unknown>Wo</unknown> <unknown>Lin</unknown>
On behalf of Lee Kee <unknown></unknown></p>

<p>Territory of Washington
County of King ss.</p>

<p>Wo Lin being duly sworn on oath 
says that he is the subscriber to the <unknown>alm</unknown> <ampersand></ampersand> foregoing <unknown>heletion</unknown>,
that he <unknown></unknown> the <unknown></unknown> on behalf of the said Lee Kee : that he has heard read the <strike></strike> said petition, and believes the statements and allegations <unknown></unknown> <unknown></unknown> to be true 
Wo Lin his name
Subscribed and sworn to before me this 29 day of May 1885
Harold Preston Notary Public  </p>
