<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>In the District Court of the Second Judicial District</p>

<p>OF THE TERRITORY OF WASHINGTON,</p>

<p>Holding Terms at Kalama, for the Counties of Cowlitz and Wahkiakum and Pacific.</p>

<p>John Seibert Plff vs. Sarah E. Seibert Deft} Action brought in the District Court of the Second Judicial District of the Territory of Washington holding terms at Kalama, for the counties of Cowlitz Wahkiakum <del>and Pacific</del>, and Complaint filed in the County of Cowlitz, in the office of the Clerk of said District Court, May 27h 1878</p>

<p>To Sarah E. Seibert Defendant</p>

<p>In the name of the UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, you and each of you are hereby required to appear in an action brought against you by the above named Plaintiff in the District Court of the Second Judicial District of the Territory of Washington, holding terms at Kalama, in Cowlitz County, for the counties of Cowlitz Wahkiakum <del>and Pacific</del> <gap></gap> and to answer the complaint filed therein (a copy of which accompanies this summons) within twenty days (exclusive of the day of services) after the service on you of this summons- if served within the county; or, if served out of the county, but within the Second Judicial District, within thirty days or if served out of said District then within <del>sixty</del> forty days- or judgment by default will be taken against you according to the prayer of said complaint.</p>

<p>The said <unclear>notion in tinnight to</unclear> dissolved the bonds of matrimony <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear> between the plaintiff and defendant and that plaintiff have such <unclear></unclear> and further <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear> be equitable and just. and you are hereby notified, that if you fail to appear and answer said complaint as above required, the Plaintiff will thke judgment against you by default as prayed for in complaint</p>

<p>Witness Roger S. Greene, Esquire, Judge of the said District Court, and the Seal of the said Court, this 28h day of May A.D. 1878</p>

<p>RU OBrien Clerk</p>

<p>By H H Holt Deputy</p>