<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>In the District Court holding terms at Seattle, King County
Washington Territory.</p>

<p>Territory of Washingtonm
County of King. ss.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application 
of AH SAM and AH WHO for a writ of 
Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>To the Honorable Roger S! Greene, Judge of the above entitled
Court and Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of Washington Ter-
ritory:</p>

<p>The petition of Ah Sam and Ah Who respectfully shows, that 
they and each of them are unlawfully imprisoned, detained and con-
fined and restrained from <strike>his</strike> their liberty by John H. McGraw, sheriff
of said King county, Washington Territory. That said imprison-
ment, detention, confinement and restraint, <strike>are</strike> is illegal and that 
the illegality thereof consists in this, to wit:</p>

<p>That on the 19th day of February I885 at the city of Seattle
in said King county, before G. A. Hill, Esq., a justice of the 
peace in and for Seattle precinct in said county, a sworn complaint
was made by one Wm. Murphey, wherein your petitioners were, and 
each were, charged with the alleged pretended crime as follows:
That at Seattle in said King county, on the I9th day of February
I885, Ah Sam and Ah Who did commit the crime of carrying on as 
proprietors thereof a gambling game as follows; By then and there
being the said Ah Sam and Ah Who unlawfuly and wilfully did as 
proprietors thereof carry on a gambling game then and there played 
with cards and other gambling devices, for money and for gain,
(NEW PAGE)
of said grand jury or for theur commitment to the custody of said
sheriff. That there is no evidence against the said petitioners 
or either of them sufficient to constitute any probable cause for 
holding said petitioners or either of them to await the action 
of said grand jury or for their commitment to the custody of said 
sheriff.</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioners and each of them pray that a 
writ of Habeas Corpus may be granted, directed to the sheriff
John H. McGraw, sheriff of said King County aforesaid, commanding 
him to have the body of said Ah Sam and Ah Who and each of them 
before Your Honor at a time and place therein to be specified, to 
do and receive what shall then and there be considered by Your 
Honor concerning them or either of them, together with the time 
and cause of their detention and said writ, that they may be re-
stored to their liberty.</p>

<p><unknown>Weoraught Terry Mcorught
+ Wtolieu</unknown> Attorneys 
for Petitioners</p>

<p><chinese></chinese> (Ah Sam)
<chinese></chinese> (Ah Who)</p>

<p>Territory of Washington,
County of King. ss.</p>

<p>Ah Sam and Ah Who being 
each first severally duly sworn, each for himself doth depose and 
say that he is one of the Petitioners named in the above and fore-
going petition, that he has h ard the same read, knows the con-
tents thereof and believes the same to be true. 
<chinese></chinese> (Ah Sam)
<chinese></chinese> (Ah Who)</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before 
me this 2Ist day of February I885.
<unknown>Jolene H Witchell</unknown>
Notary Public in and for King County Washington Territory.</p>