<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>Territory of Washington County of Thurston }Ss</p>

<p>In the Justice Court Before W.T. Keady Justice of the Peace</p>

<p>Territory of Washington
vs
Sam Hung }ss</p>

<p>To any constable or sheriff and the keeper of the County jail of said county whereas at <unclear>Committee</unclear> of Magistrates court held in my office in said <uncleaar>cit</uncleaar> for the examination of Sam

<pb...></pb...>

Hung for the offense hereinafter stated the said Sam Hung was by me found to having on the 20th day of April 1885 in said city and court committed the offense of embezzlement in this tha said Sam Hung did on said day at the County and Territory aforesaid fraudulently and unlawfully <del>exhibit</del> embezzle, convert to this concurse and commit larceny of the sum of 60 05 cents the property of one Kong Mck then and thereentrusted to said Sam Hung for <unclear/> <unclear/> purpose for him by Sam Hung and upon conviction the said laws did adjudge and determine that said Sam Hung should enter into recognizance in the sum of $500 to be and appear before

<pb...></pb...>

the grand jury at the June 1885 term of the District Court at Olympia and to stand committed to the county jail until a good and sufficient bond should be <unclear>furnished</unclear> such appear and therefore you the said constable or sheriff are commanded in the name of the Territory of Washington for the <unclear/> to convey and deliver the said Sam Hung to the said Keeper and you the Keeper are hereby commanded the said Sam Hung in to your custody into said jail and him safely keep until the terms of said judgmenet are complied with or until he shall there be discharged by due course of law as provided by the statutes of said Territory.</p>

<p>Dated this 23d day of April 1885</p>

<p><unclear/>W. T. Keddy</p>
<p>Committing Magistrate</p>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus may be issued directed to said William Billings commanding him to have the body of your petitioner before your honor at the time and place to be therein specified to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by your honor concerning said charge together with the time and cause of his detention and said writ and that petitioner may be restored to his liberty</p>

<p>Dated</p>

<p>Territory of Washington, County of Thurston}SS</p>

<p>Sam Hung of said county being duly sworn in his oath says that he is the petitioner named in the foregoing petition that

<pb...></pb...>

he has heard the said petition read and knows the contents thereof and that he believes that said petition is true</p>

<p>Sam Pong</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 23rd day of April 1885</p>

<p>Notary Public</p>

<p>Received &amp; Filed
APR 23 1885</p>

<p>R. L O'Brien Clerk.</p>
<p>By W H Nobus Deputy</p>