<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<note>718</note>

<p>Catharine L Martin
v
Jesse Martin Jr } Application for writ of habeas corpus</p>

<p>To the <unclear>Honble</unclear> <unclear>Judge</unclear> Wyche Judge of the 2d Judicial District</p>

<p>The complaint of your petitioner respectfully shows that Catharine L Martin the complainent is the wife of the defendant and the Mother of two Children named martha M Martin and George O. Martin <del>cause</del> <unclear>agrees</unclear> respectively three years and the other 18 months <del>years</del> the issue of the marriage with him</p>

<p>That said defendant by his failure to make provision for his family, and his <unclear>utten wattecaler</unclear> to the in <unclear>recepetres</unclear> and <unclear>wants</unclear> has made it impossible <del></del> for the complainant to live and cohabit with the defendant. That complainant is residing with her father in the county of Thurston in this Territory and has had the care and custody of the said minor children</p>

<p>That the defendant is floating from place to place and claiming to reside in the State of Oregon, from whence he came recently, that on 

<pb...></pb...>

this <unclear></unclear> in this Territory the close destinly sought an opportunity in the temporary absence of complainant and obtained the possession of Mary M. Martin one of the said minor children, complainant avers that the defendant is not a fit  or competent person to have the care, custody and control of said minor child. She therefore prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus may issue directed to the said Jesse Martin Jr the defendant, commanding him to produce before your Honor the said Minor child, forthwith, or at such time as given Now may direct <unclear>Exther</unclear> at Chambers or at the Ensuing term of the U States <unclear>Duc</unclear> Court to be held in Olympia, that the right to the care &amp; custody of the said minor child, as well as the care and custody of the minor child now in possession of the complainant may be determined <unclear>Aull</unclear> as Lerious apprehensions are entertained that the defendant may remove the minor child in his possession as well as the one which she now has beyond the Jurisdiction of

<pb...></pb...>

of your Honor and outside of the limits of the Territory of Washington. She therefore prays that the defendant may be restrained from carrying beyond the jurisdiction of the Court either of the said minor children untill the right to the care of them can be determined.</p>

<p>AS Manter for Catharine L Martin</p>