<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<note>#6958</note>

<p>Territory of Washington}</p>
<p>County of King} Ss.</p>

<p>In the District Court of the Third Judicial District, holding terms at Seattle, In Chambers.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of George Kai for a writ of Habeas Corpus}</p>

<p>To the Hon. C. H. Hanford, Judge of the District Court of the 3rd Judicial District of the Territory of Washington.</p>

<p>Your petitioner George Kai respectfully shows that he is unlawfully imprisoned, detained confined, and restrained of his liberty by John H. McGraw Sheriff of the County of King and the Territory of Washington and Stewart Seckie Jailer of the County of King and Territory of Washington.</p>

<p>That said imprisonment detention, confinement and restraint is illegal; and that the illegality thereof consists in this, to-wit: that the only

<pb...></pb...>

pretenxt or cause of such arrest and detention is and has been by virtue of a commitment issued out of Justice Jno T Millers Court a Justice of the Peace for Seattle W.T. on the 27th or 28th day of March AD 1889. committing said George Kai to the King County W.T. Jail, to await the action of the next ensuing grand jury of King County Washington Territory; that said George Kai has since said March 27th or 28th 1889, been confined in the County Jail of the County of King in the Territory of Washington; that that said Grand Jury then next ensuing after the said 27th or 28th of March 1889 has met, been in session and is now adjourned by proper process of law, and duly, by this Court discharged; and that no true bill of indictment was or has been returned into this this Court against said defendant George Kai charging him with this or any crime against the laws of this Territory</p>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>That your petitioner is not guilty of the charge as <unclear>prefind</unclear> against him in the said warrant of commitment or otherwise.</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus may be granted, directed to John H McGraw Sheriff of King County Washington Territory and Stewart Sackie Jailor of King County Washington Territory commanding them to have the body of your petitioner before this Hon Court forthwith to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by this Hon. Court concerning this cause and that your petitioner may be restored to his liberty.</p>

<p>Dated at Seattle W.T. July 3rd 1889</p>

<p>X George Kai</p>