<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p> At a regular <unclear> </unclear> of the district Court of the State of Oregon for the County of Union began and held at the Court House in Lelpaude Oregon on the first day of November AD 1869 there was present here J G Wilson Judge A C Craij Sheriff and E S <unclear> </unclear> County Clerk. </p>

<p> Due proclamation of the <unclear> Openecey </unclear>of Court having been made. The following among other business was <unclear> trousaited </unclear> on the fifth Judicial day of said term</p>

<p> Martha J. Craven </p>
<p> vs </p>
<p> W H Craven</p>

<p> <unclear> </unclear> this cause coming on to be heard Plaintiff applaud by R A Prince her attorney and the Defendant althought duly saved with proceed appeared not, but made default, and the prosecutisy Attorney appearing in behalf of the State. Now therefore due consideration of the allegations in the complaint and the evidence submitted to the Court and on Motion of Said Plaintiffs attorney it is ordered and adjudged that the marriage contract existing between the plaintiff and defendant be dissolved on account of habitual gross drunkeness on the part of the defendant contracted since the marriage contract existing between the plaintiff and defendant, and continuing for two years next prior to the commencement of this suit , and on account further of cruel and inhumane treatment and personal indignities making life <unclear> burthensome </unclear> by the Defendant to the Plaintiff and it appearing further by the allegations and proof that these parties have one child by the name of Effa Dora Craven of the age of three years. Therefore on motion of said plaintiff's attorney it is further ordered and decreed that the said plaintiff Martha have the custody and education of said Effy Dora and that the defendant William Harry Craven pay the costs and disbursements herein to be <unclear> reservered</unclear> made and expected to be herin taxed and that execution issue thereafter.</p>

<p> Signed Joseph G. Wilson</p>
<p> Judge </p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>