<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>To the Hon. O. Jacobs, Judge of the District Court of the Third Judicial District of Washington Territory:</p>

<p>The petition of Han Lee respectfully shows: That Seo Kim, a Chinese woman of the age of twenty and years, is restrained of her liberty by one Ah Chow, of the city of Seattle in said Territory, who claims to own the said Seo Kim as his slave, and that the said Seo Kim was confined restrained by him in the said city of Seattle until within the past three days, and is now so confined and restrained by him in said City of Seattle unless he <unclear></unclear> have taken or caused her to be taken to Port Madison in Kitsap County for the purpose of preventing her escape or rescue when, if no <unclear></unclear> he still causes her to be restrained of her liberty that the pretense of the restraint so <unclear></unclear> by him, according to the best knowledge and belief of your petitioner, is as follows, that he bought her in China and therefore he claims that she belongs to him, and is fearful that she will leave him. and your petitioner further states that the said Ah Chow, in whose custody and under whose control the said Seo Kim is

against her will, threatens to carry the said Seo Kim out of this Territory and has told her that such was his intention, as your petitioner has been informed by the said Seo Kim, and so believes. That your petitioner believes that he will take the said Seo Kim to Victoria and there sell her to other Chinaman as is a custom among them when their women slaves are displeased to serve them or one <unclear></unclear> and that he would have done so on Monday the 19h <unclear></unclear> had <unclear></unclear> your petitioner <unclear></unclear> <unclear>served</unclear> other Chinese been on the wharf to prevent him when the steamer left for Victoria on that day. Your petitioner further shows taht one Ah Ying, of the said City of Seattle, has procured a license to marry the said SEo Kim, that Seo Kim is <unclear></unclear> to marry Ah Ying, and for that reason Ah Chow restrains her of her liberty and will remove her from this territory to Victoria where he can and will sell her to some other Chinisemen</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner in be

half of the said Seo Kim prays that a writ of habeas corpus may be granted, directed to the said Ah Chow commanding him to have the body of the said Seo Kim before your Honor at a time and place to be <unclear></unclear> specified to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by your Honor concerning her, together with the time and cause of her detention, and said writ <unclear></unclear> at she may be restored her liberty; and that a warrant may also be issued forthwith to the Sheriff or any constable of this county, commanding him to <unclear>take</unclear> the said Seo Kim wherever she may be <unclear></unclear> within the Judicial District and forthwith bring her before your Honor to be dealt with according to law</p>
<p><unclear></unclear><unclear></unclear></p>

<p>Seattle, January 21, 1874</p>