<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>In the District Court <del>in and for</del> of the 3rd Judicial District in and for the County of King Territory of Washington.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of Frank OBrien for a writ of Habeas Cropus}</p>

<p>The petitioner by his Attorney John E. Costello respectfully shows that Frank OBrien is unlawfully imprisoned confined and restrained of his liberty by William Cochran sheriff of said King County in said Territory.</p>

<p>That said imprisonment confinement and restraint are illegal and that the illegality thereof consists in this to wit:-</p>

<p>That said OBrien was committed <sic>by by</sic> Justice of the Peace H. F. Jones on or about the 1st day of January 1889 to await the action of the Grand Jury next to <unclear>crurme</unclear> <del></del> the 1st Monday of February 1889 that said grand Jury has so <unclear>crurmed</unclear> her that the said OBrien has not been indicted that the papers and drawings in said case have not

<pb...></pb...>

been transmitted by said Justice to said District Court, that nothing in the <unclear>vends</unclear> of said Court appears whereby said Court has or can have jurisdiction of <del>said</del> or over the body of the said OBrien</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that a Writ of Habeas Corpus may be granted directed to the said Cochrane commanding him to have the body of Frank OBrien before you Honor at a time and place therein to be specified to do and receive what shall then and there by considered by your Honor concerning him together with the time and  cause of his detention and said writ and that he may be restored to his libety</p>

<p>Dated on the 28th day of February 1889</p>

<p>Frank OBrien</p>
<p>by his Atty</p>
<p>John E. Costello</p>

<p>And now comes the said John E Costello on oath and says that the above statements subscribed to by him are trueof his best knowledge and

<pb...></pb...>

belief. The said Costello for then says that he makes said petition for the reason that said defendant is confined in the County Jail in said King County and therefore unable to make personal <unclear></unclear></p>

<p>Subscribed &amp; sworn to before me this 28th day of Feby 1889</p>

<p>WE Ledgerwood Clerk</p>