<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>1236</p>

<p>Territory of Washington}</p>
<p>County of Pierce}SS</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of Sam Sock and Jim for writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>To Hon John P Hoyt Judge of the second Judicial District of Washington Territory.</p>

<p>County of Pierce ss.</p>

<p>Your petitioners Sam Sock and Jim respectfully show unto your honor that they are residents of said County and Territory That they are illegally restrained of their liberty by one Henry <unclear>Wicror</unclear> Sheriff of said County of Pierce at the City of Tacoma in said County of Pierce</p>

<p>That the cause or pretense of the restraint of their liberty of your <del></del> petitioners is as your petitioners are informed and believe a certain commitment or commitments under pretended sentence issued and executed by one W.H. Harris a Justice of the Peace of said County of Pierce</p>

<p>That said restraint of the liberty of your petitioners and said pretended commitmend under said

<pb...></pb...>

<sic>pretendended</sic> sentence and all proceedings in the cause hereinafter specified to and including the issuences of siad pretended commitment or commitments are and were wholly illegal, null and void for reasons hereinafter stated</p>

<p>Your petitioners further show that they were arrested without any process of law whatever and were afterwards to wit on the 16th day of August AD 1884 taken before one W. H. Harris a Justice of the Peace of said County of Pierce where a complaint was made against them and a warrant issued thereon charging them with being on the 15th day of August AD 1884 guilty of the offense created by section 2073 of the Code of Washingotn of the yyear 1881 as amended by Act <del>No</del> of the laws of 1883.</p>

<p>That on the 18th day of August 1884 your petitioners appeared before said Justice of the Peace for examination of the matters alleged against them in said complaint and warrant.</p>

<p>The said Justice of the Peace then and there refused to examine your petitioners in accordance with law he the said Justice stating that he was in

<pb...></pb...>

1236 

doubt as to whether he should examine your petitioners or proceed to a trial of the cause</p>

<p>Your petitioners by their counsel therefore requested the said Justice of the Peace to elect then and there whether he could examine or by the cause that your petitioners and their counsel might be informed whether they were bieng held for said offense or merely examined as to the probable cause to believe them guilty of said offense which request the said Justice of the Peace did then and there refuse to grant but on the contrary decided that he would hear the evidence and determine then whether he should call it an examination or trial. Said Justice thereupon asked your petitioners if they desired a Jury and your petitioners and their counsel not knowing and being wholly unable to <unclear>acertain</unclear> whether your petitioners were to be tried for said offense then and there or be merely examined as to whether there was probable cause to believe them guilty of said offence were unable to decide whether or not a jury were desired or needed and so

<pb...></pb...>

did not determine and did neither demand or waive a Jury Whereupon said Justice of the Peace proceeded to examine witnesses and hear evidence against your petitioners After hearing all the evidence produced by himself the said Justice was informed by counsel for your petitioners that he had no jurisdiction to try said offense and was again requested to elect whether the proceeding was a trial or an examination and was further requested <del>to</del> in cause he thought there was probable cause to believe the defendants your petitioners guilty to <unclear>bind</unclear> them over for trial to the District Court <del></del>. The said Justice of the Peace then and there asked your petitioners if they had any evidence to offer your petitioners by their counsel replied that not knowing whether the proceeding was a trial or an examination no evidence would be offered/authorized your petitioners have as they are informed by their counsel after fully and fairly stating their case to them a good defense to said offense on the marks thereof</p>

<p>Whereupon the said . Justice of the Peace stated

<pb...></pb...>

1236

</p>


STOPPED AT PG 7 OF 21 DOC PRC 1255