<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<note>6673</note>

<p>In the District Court of the 3rd Judicial district in and for the County of King Territory of Washington</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of Jimmy Jardine alias Russell for a writ of Habeas Corpus}</p>

<p>The petitioner by his Atty John E. Costello respectfully shows that said Jimmy Jardine alias Russell is unlawfully imprisoned confined and restrained of his liberty by William Cochran Sheriff of King County in said Territory</p>

<p>That said imprisonment confinement and restraint are illegal and that the illegality thereof consists in this to wit:-</p>

<p>That said prisoner was committed on or about the 1st day of December 1888 by a Justice of the Peace in and for the Precinct of <unclear>Surgudine</unclear> to await the action of the Grand Jury next to <unclear>connne</unclear> on the 1st Monday of February 1889 that said prisoner has not been indicted for the crime of attempt to commit Rape that the papers and

<pb...></pb...>

documents in said case have now been transmitted by said Justice to said District Court that nothing in the records of said Court appears whereby said Court appears whereby said Court has a <unclear>centare</unclear> jursidiction of or over the body of the said Prisoner.</p>

<p>Wherefore your said petitioner prays that a Writ of Habeas Corpus may be granted directed to the said Cochrane commanding him to have the body of Frank OBrien before your Honor at a time and place therein to be specified to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by your Honor concerning him together with the time and cause of his detention and said writ and that he may be restored to his liberty.</p>

<p>Dated on the 2nd day of March 1889</p>

<p>Jimmy Jardin alias Russell</p>
<p>by his atty John E. Costello</p>

<p>And now comes the said John E. Costello on oath and says that the above statements subscribed to by him are true of

<pb...></pb...>

his best knowledge and belief.</p>

<p>The said John E. Costello further says that he sent us said petition for the reason that said defendant is confined in the County Jail in said King County and therefore unable to make personal <unclear>requests</unclear></p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 2nd day of March 1889</p>