<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<note>"Exhibit A"</note>

<p>Copy of Writ of Deportation</p>

<p>In the District Court of the Third Judicial District of Washington Territory, holding Terms at Seattle, for the County of King. W. T.</p>

<p>United States of America -vs- Ah Ding, Ah Sing, Ah Sam No.2, Ah Lam, Wa Kim, Lee Pin, Gin Cheong, Wong Fong, Wong Boy, Ah Ching No. 1, Ah Ching No. 2, Han Goon, Ah Jim No.1, Ah Jim No. 2, Ah Gong, Wou Ga, and Suey Wee} Writ of Deportation</p>

<p>Now on this 12th day of June, 1889, William H White, United States Attorney being present in Court, and the defendants being also present in <del>Court</del> person and accompanied by their counsel J. A. Stratton, and it appearing to the Court by the statement of facts now made in open court by said United States Attoreny, that sufficient evidence cannot be produced to justify a conviction of the defendants upon the charge in the indictment against them; it is now by the Court on its own motion considered and adjudged that said cause be and the same is hereby dismissed and the indictment herein be and the same is hereby set aside and upon the evidence before the court, it is further considered and adjudged by the court that the defendants are Chinese laboreres who came into the United States from British Columbia in the Dominion of Canada, in violation of law, and that they are not lawfully entitled to be or remain in the United States and that

<pb...></pb...>

they be by the United States Marshal for Washington Territory deported from the United States and returned to British Columbia, the Country from whence they come.</p>

<p>Now, therefore, this is to command you, the said United States Marshal, to take the said defendants On Ding, Ah Sing, Ah Sam No. 2, Ah Sam, Wa Kim, Lee Pin, Gin Cheong, Wong Fong, Wong Boy, Ah Ching No. 1, Ah Ching No. 2, Han Goon, Ah Gim No. 1, Ah Jim No. 2, Ah Gong, Won Ga, and Sing Nee, into your custody and deal with him as herein instructed todo: and these presents shall be your authority for the same, Herein fail not.</p>

<p>Witness the Hon C. H. Hanford, Judge of the said District Court, and the seal thereof this 13th day of June A.D. 1889</p>

<p>R. H. Hopkins, Clerk</p>

<p>District Court Seal</p>