<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>Territory of Washington}</p>
<p>County of King} ss</p>

<p>In the District Court holding terms at Seattle</p>

<p>In Re Application of Thomas Gilbert and Catherine Gilbert for a Writ of Habeas Corpus}</p>

<p>To the Honorable Richard A Jones Judge of said Court:</p>

<p>The Petitioiners Thomas Gilbert and Catharine Gilbert made most respectfully allege and show unto your Honor that they are each imprisoned confined and disposed of their liberty by William Cochoran, Sheriff of the said County of King at Seattle in said county in this Territory</p>

<p>That said imprisonment is illegal and that the illegality thereof consists in the following facts: On May 27 1888, these petitioners were arrested and brought before one W. Soderberg a Justice of the Peace in and for the Seattle Precinct in said King County on a charge of disposing of beer to

<pb...></pb...>

an Indian that on said day a hearing or pretended trial was had before said W. Soderberg and that these petitioners were on said day ordered to pay a fine of $100- by said Justice and in default of the payment of the same were by him committed in said day, to the Jail of said County for the period of fifty days.</p>

<p>That these petitioners have been so confined in said Jail for the full period of said fifty days and four days in excess therof and are now entitled to be set at liberty</p>

<p>That these petitioners have had but one trial before said W. Soderberg and have suffered the full term of punishment by imprisonment ordered in said cause, but that said Soderberg has issued duplicate warrants of commitments is said cause as these petitioners believe.</p>

<p>That the Judgements upon which said warrants of commitments now issued are null and void and that said warrants of commitments are each null and void all of which will appear by an 

<pb...></pb...>

inspection thereof.</p>

<p>That true and correct copies of the said commitments by which said William Cochoran claims to hold these petitioners are herto attached and marked respectfully "Exhibit A" and "Exhibit B" respectively and are hereby made a part of this petition</p>

<p>Wherefore these petitioners pray that a writ of Habeas Corpus issue directed to the said William Cochoran commanding him to prodcue the bodies of petitioners before your Honor at a time and place therein to be stated and then and three do and receive what the Court may order concerning petitioners, and that he the said Cochoran have then and there the said writ and make due return of the date and time of the imprisonments of petitioners and then and there produce the warrant of commitments by which he now holds petitioners</p>

<p>Thomas Gilbert</p>
<p>Catharine her X mark Gilbert</p>

<p>Richard Osborn Atty for Petitioners</p>