<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Copy of Agreement 
This Endenture? made this twenty sixth
day of June, AD 1875, by and between 
Josephine Sheffler of the City and County 
of Walla Walla, Territory of Washington
the party of the first part, and John B. 
Montague of the same place, the 
party of the second part; Witnesseth:
That the said Josephine Sheffler in consideration 
of the covenants on the part of the party 
of the second part herein after contained 
doth? covenant and agree to and with 
the said John B. Montague to forever 
relinquish all right and control of 
Edna Elenor Edwards, a minor of the
age of six years, who is a daughter of 
the said Josephine Sheffler, and the 
issue of a former marriage with 
Charles A. Edwards, the custody pf 
which was given to the said Josephine 
Sheffler by a decree of divorce granted 
to her by the District Court at Missoula
Montana, dissolving the bonds of 
matrimony then existing the said 
Charles A. Edwards, and the said 
Josephine Sheffler, and that the said 
Josephine Sheffler in consideration 
of the covenants herin afore mentioned 
(new page) 
on part of the party of the second part 
will never interfere with the custody, 
Education, or moral or religious 
training of said Edna Elenor Edwards,
or to ever claim relationship, and 
hereby releasing custody of said child 
unto the said John B. Montague, the 
party of the second part, in consideration 
of the covenants on the part of the 
party of the first part, doth covenant 
and agree to and with the said Josephine 
Scheffler, that he will adopt as his 
daughter the said Edna Elenor Edwards 
promising to rear her as a member 
of his family, and to educate her 
and morally and religiously train 
her with due parental care and 
regard hereby giving to the said minor 
the name of Edna Elenor Montague,
In witness whereof the said parties have
hereunto set their hands? the day and 
year in this agreement first above 
written.
Josephine Scheffler
J. B. Montague 
Territory of Washington 
County of Walla Walla 
Be it remembered that on this 28th?
(new page)
day of June, AD 1875, before me the 
Honorable? Judge in the said County and 
Territory personally appeared Josephine Scheffler 
and John B. Montague whose name? are 
subscribed to the foregoing unknown! 
as the parties thereto, personally Known 
to me to be the individuals described 
in and who existed the said foregoing 
unknown! and who cash? acknowledged 
to me that their cash expected the same 
freely and voluntarily and for the uses 
and purposes therein mentioned. 
In Witness whereof I have hereunto 
set my hand and affixed the seal of the 
Probate Court of said County the day and 
year in this certificate first above 
written.
Seal R. Guishard? 
Probate Court 