<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

Alexis Amelin, to whom the writ of Habeas 
Corpus, hereto attached, was directed, commanding 
him to have the bodies of Catherine, Julia, Joseph
and Helen, persons of colour, before this hon
orable court, to gether with the cause of their 
caption and detainer , for return to said writ 
unknown! to the court him? that the said Catherine 
Julia and Helen, were committed to the custody 
amd care of him the said amelin, at Her 
unknown! in the county of Jefferson, same time 
in the month of April - last bu Alexander Scott 
Martin of the Steam boat General Brown as the 
agent of said Scott, for the purpose of bring 
ing the said Catherine Julia and Helen to S Louis 
and to make return of their bodies before the 
Honorable Robert Wash am of the Judges 
of the Supreme Court of the state of Missou
ri in unknown! to a writ of Habeas Cor
pus, issued by said Judge directs to said 
Scott, that said Amelin brought the said 
Catherine Julia and Helen to S Louis as agent 
of said Scott, and on his return found that 
the said Judge had gone to unknown! to att
est a session of the Supreme Court; that 
said Amelin committed the said Catherine 
Julia <&amp;> Helen to the custody of John K 
Walker Esqr Jailor of S Louis County for sage 
keeping, until the said Judge should re
turn to his chambers, the said Catherine
Julia <&amp;> Helen were not taken out of the 
cusotdy of said Amelin, by order of said
Judge, but were left with him as before 
the return by said Judge. That said 
(new page) 
Catherine Julia and Helen are now in the 
actual custody of the said John K Walker 
and are detained by him at my unknown! until 
they shall be claimed and taken away from me 
by my principal or his authorities agent 
that I the said Amelin hold the said Julia Helen 
and Catherine in my custody in no other char 
unknown!then as the agent of said Scott <&amp;> that 
they are not detained by me for any criminal 
or supposed criminal metter, <&amp;> that they are 
now in the custody of said Walker, ready to 
be produced to this honorable Court by him 
on? said writ. And the said Ameline unknown!
that Joseph, mentioned in said writ never 
was, nor is he now in my custody or 
constraint?, or detained by me in any manner 
whatsoeverm but is informed and believes that 
Pierre Chouteau Senior, who claims siad Josph 
as his slave, has sent him up the Missouri
river. ----------------------------------
Sworn to in open Court A Amelin 
May 26th 1826 
A Gambb Clerk  