<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<note>1916</note>

<p>Territory of Washington}
County of Thurston} ss</p>

<p>In the District Court of the 2nd Judicial District of Washington Territory holding terms at Olympia for the Counties of Mason, Chehalis and Thurston.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of 
John Heo
for a writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>To the Honorable J.P. Hoyt Judge of the 2nd Judicial District of Washington Territory</p>

<p>The petition of John Heo respectfully shows.</p>

<p>That he the said John Heo is unlawfully imprisoned, detained, confined and restrained of his liberty by R. H. <unclear>Milroy</unclear> in Olympia Thurston County Washington Territory.</p>

<p>That he the said John Heo is an Indian born in the United States about thirty five years of age.</p>

<p>That his father and mother died twenty five years ago and that since their death he has continuously lived with the whites. That he has at no time lived with any tribe of Indians since the death of his father and mother. That he has lived on no reservation since said time, and that he has at no

<pb...></pb...>

time received or accepted any amenities from the Government of the United States.</p>

<p>That for the past twenty five years severed all tribal relation with the Indians and that for said period oftime he has adopted the habits of the white, tilling the soil for a livelihood.</p>

<p>That said R.H. <unclear>Milroy</unclear> is an Indian Agent of the United States, and that the cause <del>of his</del> or pretense of his arrest and imprisonment is his refusal to cohabit with an Indian woman when so requested to do by said R. H. <unclear>Milroy</unclear>.</p>

<p>That he has committed no crime and that no other cause has been assigned or <unclear>exists</unclear> for his arrest save and except the cause above stated.</p>

<p>That the illegality of the arrest and imprisonment consists in this. That he has committed no crime and that no process has been issued by any Court or officer for his arrest and that no information or complaint has been filed against him.</p>

<p>Wherefore he prays that he may be forthwith discharged from said imprisonment</p>

<p>John P. Judson
Attorney for Petitioner</p>