<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>DEFENSE.</p>

<p>Mrs. ALICE McKAY, Petitioner, . after being duly sworn, testified in her own behalf as follows:</p>

<p>Q. [Ronald] Where do you live? A. In Tacoma, at present.</p>

<p>Q. How long have you lived there? A. I have lived about eighteen years there.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know this little girl, Mary McKay? A. That is my child.</p>

<p>Q. Did you leave her on the door step of the Hospital or any other place? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Did you put her in the hospital? A. I took her and left her in the hospital, as I was recovering very slowly myself.</p>

<p>Q. When was that. A. Perhaps a year before this other law suit was had.</p>

<p>Q. About four years ago? A. About that time.</p>

<p>Q. State the circumstances of your taking her to the hospital and leaving her there? A. Me and that young lady there and Mary and Georgie was down with scarelt feaver.</p>

<p>Q. Who do you mean by Georgie? A. A little boy that was carried in there and taken to Vancouver, and I never seen any trace of since.</p>

<p>Q. Who carried him to Vancouver, the sisters? A. Went to their school there.</p>

<p>Q. You were all down with fever? A. I was recovering, they found it out and came down and looked after me. I laid on the floor in Mr. Brown's old building.</p>

<p>Q. Tell what you did? A. <unclear>hen</unclear> I was getting well they put me in the hospital and that little girl.</p>

<p>Q. Little Mary? A. Yes <sic>ssir</sic></p>

<p>Q. What did you do then? A. I left Mary in the hospital.</p>

<p>Q. Why did you not <sic>stany</sic> in the hospital? A. They would not let me any more. With these other children.</p>

<p>Q. They would not let these other children be in with you? A. No sir. This girl was a little bigger than Mary is now.</p>

<p>Q. What did you do then? A. I went back into thes old building and lived there.</p>

<p>Q. Did you take any steps --- was Mary still with you? A. Mary was there after that.</p>

<p>Q. What did you do toward doctoring her? A. They were furnished with medicine while she was bad. Dr. Weed waited on her and Dr. Smith too.</p>

<p>Q. Did you visit Mary frequently at the hospital? A. Every two or three days.</p>

<fw>[Mrs. McKay, D-EX <gap></gap> 76--139.</fw>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>Q. Did you any talk with the sisters about her? A. Yes, I visited her The sisters sat up with her night and day.</p>

<p>Q. She was sick there? A. Yes very bad.</p>

<p>Q. How long did you leave her in the hospital? A. In about two weeks after Mary went to the hospital my husband wrote to me from Port Townsend and wanted me to come to Townsend. That was about six or eight days, and the little girl had gone to this lady's in Belltown.</p>

<p>Q. To Mrs. Keevin's? A. Yes</p>

<p>Q. What did they say? A. The Sister told her she sent her there to get country air to get strong.</p>

<p>Q. What did you do then? A. I went to see Mary on the next day.</p>

<p>Q. Dd you see her? A. I did sir.</p>

<p>Q. What happened then? A. I stood outside of the door and talked to the child and Mrs. Keevin showed me a hat she had got.</p>

<p>Q. What did you say then? A. She said she took a fancy for the child and she said she would liek to get the papers.</p>

<p>Q. What did you say? A. I said no, I could not give any papers on that child.</p>

<p>Q. Did you promise to bring papers in a week or any time? A. No sir. The sisters have frequently asked for papers, I never promised to give papers on my child.</p>

<p>Q. They frequently asked for papers? A. Yes, the Sisters any time I went to see them they wanted <sic>fpapers</sic> on my child. Up to the time that girls leg was broken and I never went near that sister again.</p>

<p>Q. Mrs. Keevin asked if she could have papers? A. Yes, she asked me for papers.</p>

<p>Q. What did you tell her? A. I told her no.</p>

<p>Q. How frequently have you been back there? A. I have gone frequently to see the child, made several trips. I would be generally left outside of the door and the child would be brought in, I might just see her, I was never allowed to kiss the child, they would give her a crack in the back of the head and send her back in the room.</p>

<p>Q. Who done that? A. Mrs. Keevin, she said she did not want me to come, that she did not want Mary to know I was her mother.</p>

<p>Q. Do you like Mary? A. I <sic>lowe</sic> that child, I love her in my heart, that is my child and I want her.</p>

<p>Q. How often have you tried to get her, asked for her. A. At the time her leg was broken I had a suit about her, and then I took out a writ of habeas corpus, Judge

<fw>[Mrs. McKay, D-EX. <gap></gap> 76--147.</fw>

<pb...></pb...>

Greene denied the writ on account of my extreme poverty, at that time.</p>

<p>Q. Never mind about that. Are you able to support and take care of the child?</p>

<p>A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Are you able to cloathe her warmly A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. School her? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Did you ever go to Mrs. Keevens house drunk? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Never went there drunk? A. No sir</p>

<p>Q. Now Mrs. McKay, do you live in the house at Tacoma with Antoine anybody?</p>

<p>A. I dont live w ith any man sir, never lived with any man outside of my husband.</p>

<p>Q. Are you living in a state of adultery with anybody? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. How long <del></del> since you and your husband separated? A. Two years ago since we separated for good. He has been back awhile last February.</p>

<p>Q. Where has he gone? A. Scotland at present.</p>

<p>Q. You refused to live with himx? A. I told him I would not live with him any more.</p>

<p>Q. What are you doing for a living? A. Washing sometimes, sometimes sewing, Sometimes sells chickens and hogs, sometimes ducks.</p>

<p>Q. Are you keeping a low saloon, any saloon? A. No saloon, I have had no kind of beer or liquor in the house since the day my husband left me.</p>

<p>Q. Have you been drinking any the last year or two. A. I am not drunk sir.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know these <unclear>ta</unclear> policemen here? A. Yes sir. I know these two gentlemen well.</p>

<p>Q. Did they arrest you? A. They arrested <unclear>co</unclear> one afternoon in the summer, on grea.t excitement, two or three little orphan children that came to me in the absence of their father.</p>

<p>Q. Did they arrest you for drunkenness? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Was you drunk? A. No sir, they put me down I suppose for that, they took <sic>gme</sic> there and let me out again?</p>

<p>Q. Do you know any Italian named Antoine? A. I do sir.</p>

<p>Q. Does he live in the house with you? A. No sir, he lives next door. In his own house.</p>

<p>Q. How close is his own house to yours. A. Alongside.</p>

<p>Q. Is there any room from his house into yours? A. No sir, I have my rooms he has his.</p>

<p>Q. His house is alongside? A. Yes sir.</p>

<fw>[Mrs. McKay, D-EX. <gap></gap> 76--153.</fw>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>Q. Did he ever occupy your house or your room or your bed room at all with you?</p>

<p>A. No sir never.</p>

<p>Q. Or anybody else? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. How many children have you with you now? A. Two.</p>

<p>Q. You have been schooling them have you? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. When old enough? A. One has been going to school.</p>

<p>Q. Who supports them? A. I do sir.</p>

<p>Q. You live in your own house in Tacoma? A. I live in my own house.</p>

<p>CROSS-EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>Q. [Gilman] Antoine was with you at the time you were arrested on the beachg by Marshall Hopkins? A. Antoine came with fishermen, he happened to drop in where I was.</p>

<p>Q. Anybody else with you there? A. My children was there.</p>

<p>Q. You had a lot of beer and whisky there? A. I had neither one nor the other If it was there I know nothing about it, it was not mine, if it was there.</p>

<p>Q. You were arrested and taken to Tacoma? A. I gave myself up.</p>

<p>Q. Well, the marshal took you to Tacoma? did he not? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. You went down there and plead guilty to charge of selling whisky to Indians?</p>

<p>A. My husband abused me.</p> 

<p>Q. Was your husband there at the time you were arrested? A. No sir, he had left.</p>

<p>Q. Have you drank any during the last two or three years? A. Sometimes I had a glass of beer.</p>

<p>Q. Dont you sometimes take a glass of whisky? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Dont you sometimes take several glasses of beer? A. No, I do not.</p>

<p>Q. You have not been drunk as the policemen testified? A. No sir, that policeman testified lies, I was going to put him off the force when he came to me and said the afidavits that were going against him.</p>

<p>Q. Were you ever drunk in Seattle? A. Never, sir.</p>

<p>Q. Sheriff McGraw never saw you drunk? A. Not that I know of.</p>

<p>Q. Were you ever drunk so that he could see you? A. Not to my knowledge.</p>

<p>Q. You would know it if you were drunk? A. I think I would.</p>

<p>Q. Will you swear you never were drunk in Seattle? A. I can, I deny all charges of drunkenness in Seattle.</p>

<fw>[Mrs. McKay, C-EX. <gap></gap> 76--159.</fw>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>Q. Have you contributed anything to that child's support since it was left at the Sisters? A. I did not have anything, and anything I had they got.</p>

<p>Q. You did not have anything and anything you had they got? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. You never gave them anything at all? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You were compelled on account of your poverty to leave that child to the care of others? A. I left her in the hosptial at that time.</p>

<p>Q. And you did not up to the time you applied for this writ of habeas corpus you were not able to support her were you? A. I could have taken care of her the same as I did the rest, but they would not giver her to me.</p>

<p>Q. You were not able to support her in a proper manner were you? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Was not that the reason why Judge Greene would not give the child to you because you would not support her? A. At that time.</p>

<p>Q. Now, at the time Mrs. Keevin took this child from the sisters you were not able to support her were you? A. I was sick at that time.</p>

<p>Q. You were unable to support her? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. After you went to see Mrs. Keevin's you did not go back again to where your child was for nine months? A. I have been there every two or three weeks, generally every couple of months.</p>

<p>Q. Will you swear that you went to see Mrs. Keevin, that you went back before nine months? A. Yes, I can swear to that.</p>

<p>Q. Now, how long was it after you saw Mrs. Keevin that you went back there?</p>

<p>A. I cannot say how often because every time I would go he would accuse me of being drunk. I used to generally go to see this <del></del> gentlemen my counsel and then I would go and see the child.</p>

<p>Q. You have been accused pretty generally <sic>oof</sic> being drunk have you?</p>

<p>A. I could not help that</p>

<p>Q. Q. All these people who say that they have seen you drunk are mistaked are they? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. They are mistaken. You think Mr. McGraw and these policemen are mistaken about your being drunk? A. I think McGraw is mistaken.</p>

<p>Q. YOu had a pretty bad reputation with the officers in Setattle did you not?</p>

<p>RONALD: We object it is not cross-examination and it is not a fair and proper question.</p>

<p>The COURT: I think it is. You asked her if she was in the habit of drinking and she said no.</p>

<p>Q> You had rather a bad reputation among the officers in Seattle? A. I dont

<fw>[Mrs. McKay, <gap></gap> 76--135.</fw>

<pb...></pb...>

know.</p>

<p>RONALD: We object, it was not cross examination. It is not proper.</p>

<p>The COURT: If she said so-- she said she did not know.</p>

<p>RONALD: I suppose it is something like my position, Judge, I suppose I have got a bad reputation with the Court from the Court's remarks.</p>

<p>The COURT: It is a fine thing you found it out.</p>

<p>Q. At the time you were arrested you were arrested at Tacoma for being drunk were you not? A. That is the charge, there was no other way they could get at that.</p>

<p>Q. That was the charge you were taken before the police justice were you not?</p>

<p>A. They came to the house the nex day.</p>

<p>Q. And took you? A. The next day.</p>

<p>Q. And you were tried were you not by the police <del></del> justice?</p>

<p>RONALD: We object, it is not the best evidence.</p>

<p>The COURT: She knows whether she was, that is the best kind of evidence.</p>

<p>A. I was not tried at all, he says give me eight dollars and something.</p>

PAGE 46 KNG 5662