<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<note>4598</note>

<note>1832</note>

<p>To the United States District Court for the Second Judicial District of Washington Territory:</p>

<p>Your petitioner <unclear>Prospero Deffilippes and Felip Perell</unclear>of the Territory of Washington, complaining shows that they are unjustly and unlawfully detained and imprisoned by Lewis Byrd in the County Jail, at Tacoma in the Territory of Washington by virtue of a pretended Warrant of Commitment under a <unclear>officer</unclear> of the United States issued under the following circumstances:</p>

<p>Your petitioner is a common seaman over twenty-one years of age and prior to the time of the grievances herein complained of had been a seaman on the Bark Eldorado, a merchant vessel of the United States under a shipping contract for a voyage on said vessel from the port of San Francisco, in the state of California, to the port of Tacoma in Washington Territory and return; and that on the <del>30th</del> 29th day of June 1886, which said vessel was loading at the port of Tacoma, the master thereof L.S. Humphreys, assaulted your petitioners and on June 27h 1886 caused petitioners names to be entered in the log bark as deserters forciably drove them off of said vessel, and discharged them from the further obligation under their shipping contract on said vessel, and then and there ordered your petitioners to leave said vessel, which your petitioners did then thereafter and on the same day said

<pb...></pb...>

L. S. Humphreys made complaint against your petitioner to Alexander Campbell, a Justice of the Peace in and for the County of Pierce in said Territory, upon the charge that your petitioners had deserted said vessel a certified copy of which petition is hereto attached and marked A and made a part hereof and thereupon said Justice of the Peace issued his warrant for the apprehension and arrest of your petitioners a certified copy of which warrant is hereto attached mareks B and made a part hereof and on said 30th day of June 1886 they were arrested on such warrant and taken into custody and they have ever since been kept and remained in custody, and on the 1st day of July 1886, they were taken before said Justice of the Peace for examination upon said charge of desertion from said vessel. Your petitioners objected to the authority of said Justice to try them on said charge, but their objection was overruled, and said Justice proceeded to try them, and found them guilty of the charge, and sentenced them to jail to await the departion of said vessel from the said Port of Tacoma, and to be given over to the master of said vessel upon its sailing from said Port of Tacoma, and under said sentence said petitioners are now confined in said County Jail.</p>

<p>And your petitioners claim that said Justice of the Peace had no jurisdiction or authority legally to try and sentence him in the manner and form above stated. And

<pb...></pb...>

the complaint filed and made before said Justice does not state an offense under </p>


PAGE 8 OF 11 PRC 1854