<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>In the District Court holding Terms at Seattle, King County Washington Territory.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of Alice McKay for a Writ of Habeas Corpus to obtain the person of her infant child, Mary McKay}</p>

<p>Comes now Alice McKay, Petitioner for said Writ, and for amended traverse to the return of John Kevan and Della Kevan, respondents to said Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Denies 1 That the said child Mary McKay is otherwise known as Mary Kevan or that she is named otherwise known as Mary McKay</p>

<p>Denies that in August 1882, or at any other time, petitioner abandoned or deserted said child, when at the tender age of three years, or at any other age, and denies that she ever abandoned or deserted said child.</p>

<p>Denies that she left said child on the door step of the Sisters of Charity or abandoned her there or at any other place at the time alleged or at any other time whatever.</p>

<p>Denies that said child has ever been adopted by said respondents. denies upon information and being that said respondets have educated and reared said child. Denies that <del></del> she <del>respondents have</del> has any information as to the financial <unclear></unclear> to rear and educate said child sufficient to form a belief and cannot therefore admit or deny the same.</p>

<p>Denies one of the paragraphs of said answer in which it is alleged to be an unfit person and each and
<pb...></pb...>
every allegation in said paragraph continued.</p>

<p>Denies the whole of paragraph as to the intermperate and criminal habits of the Father and Mother of said child, and each and every allegation therein contained denies that the Father is a Fugitive from Justice. denies that she is now living in a <unclear>dwelling</unclear> with any person denies that she is addicted to the use of liquor or in the habit of getting intoxicated. Denies that she is the proprietor of a saloon. Denies that she is unfit <del></del> to rear said child but avers that she is in every way competent financially and morally to make a good home for said child and giver her a proper education and support.</p>

<p>Denies the last paragraph which alleges that respondents are legally entitled or in any other way entitled to the custody of said child.</p>

<p>And for further traverse and answers to said Return to said writ.</p>

<p>Petitioner alleges that she is the mother of said child and that at present, her husband William McKay, who is a Sea-faring man is absent in Scotland and that she is making an honest livelihood by labor and earns sufficient to make a good home for herself and children. that she is a fit, competent and proper person to have charge of the said child, her control, maintenance and education, and that she is an affectionate mother
<pb...></pb...>
and is a Protestant and believes in the Protestant Christian religion and desires to have her daughter educated and instructed in said Faith, instead of in the Catholic religion in which respondents are now seeking to have her instructed and educated. Wherefore petitioner prays that she be awarded the custody of her said child.</p>

<p>Ronald &amp; Piles &amp; Elwood Evans</p>
<p>Attys for Petitioner</p>