<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
 
<p> To the Hon John W Colvin Law Commissioner Court of Saint Louis County ~ </p>

<p> The petition of <stike> William Blackburn </stike> Sarah Broadwater showeth, that William blackburn <strike> he </strike> is now a prisioned restrained of his liberty in the custody of the County Jailor of the County of Saint Louis in the State of Missouri, upon the charge or accusation of being a run away slave or fugitive from service and that such imprisonment and restraint is within the common Jail of the said County of Saint Louis and the name of the said Jailor is James A Felks as your petitioner is informed and verily believes. </p>

<p> Your petitioner further showeth that said Blackburn <strike> he </strike> is not imprisioned or restrained of his liberty, upon any charge, for any reason, or upon any account which prevents him from applying for and obtaining the benefit of the writ of Habeas Corpus, as she is informed &amp; verily believes, in or for any cause or reason specified in the sixth section of the said article of chapter seventy five of the statutes of the State of Missouri of 1845, Entitned an act regulating proceedings on writs of Habeas Corpus. </p>

<p> Your petitioner further showeth that the annexed paper marked A, is a true copy of the Process  by which <strike> he </strike> said Blackburn is claimed to be held in such restraint &amp; confinement as she is informed &amp; verily believes. </p>

<p> Your petitioner further showeth, that said Blackburn <strike> he </strike> was merely arrested &amp; imprisoned upon suspicion of being a run away slave, and that no person can or does, to his knowwledge or belief claim service from him, or claim him as a slave, and that he is not a Slave, but is a free man and entitled as such to his freedom as she verily believes and that such restraint &amp; imprisionment is illegal, and that such 

illegality consists in imprisioning him as a run away Slave, where in such &amp; in fact he is not a Slave or a run away Slave but is a free man and she makes this Petition for and on the behalf of said William Blackburn who is a son in law of petitioner </p>

<p> Therfore your petitioner prays <strike> to </strike> that said William Blackburn be discharged from such imprisionment, on your honor being satisfied of the fact that he is not a run away Slave &amp; is entitled to his freedom, and for the purpose of determining that question that a writ of Habeas Corpus may issue to bring him before your Honor and she prays for such Habeas Corpus accordingly. </p>

<p> Sarah her X mark Broadwater </p>