<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>In the United States District Court holding terms at Olympia.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of William Jones, William H. Doyle, Fred Williams and Alfred Woods.</p>

<p>Writ of Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>The President of the United States: To Jesse W. George U.S. Marshall, Greeting:</p>

<p>In the name of the United States we hereby command you hat you have the body of William Jones, William H. Doyle, Fred Williams and Alfred Woods by you imprisoned and detained as it is said together with the time and cause of such imprisonment and detention, by whatsoever names said William Jones, William H. Doyle, Fred Williams and Alfred Woods shall be called or charged, before John P. Hoyt, Esquire, Associate Justice of the Supreme Court and Judge of the Second Judicial District of Washington Territory, holding terms at Olympia, at the Court room at Olympia on the 10th day of March 1885

<pb...></pb...>

at the hour of One O'clock in the afternoon of said day to do and receive what shall then and there be considered concerning the said William Jones, William H. Doyle, Fred Williams and Alfred Woods, And have you then and there this writ.</p>

<p>Witness the Honorable John P. Hoyt Associate Justice of the Supreme Court of said Territory and Judge of said District Court and the seal of said Court at Olympia this 6th day of March A.D. 1885.</p>

<p>R.G. O'Brien
Clerk</p>

<note>court seal</note>

<p>Office of the Sheriff}
of King County W.T.} ss</p>

<p>I J.H. McGraw Sheriff of King County W.T. do hereby certify that a writ of Habeas Corpus of which the foregoing is a true and correct copy, was placed in my hands for service on the 7th day of March 1885 and thtat I personally served the same on the same day on Jesse W. Geroge U.S. Marshal for Washington Territory, by delivering said writ to him, said

<pb...></pb...>

Marshal, personally, in King County in said Territory.</p>

<p>Dated at Seattle this 7th day of March 1885.</p>

<p>J W McGraw
Sheriff</p>

<p>Sheriffs Fees.</p>
<p>Service $1.00</p>
<p>Copy .60</p>
<p>Travel 20 Certificate 50 70</p>
<p>$2.30</p>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>Writ of Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Received &amp; Filed 
Mar 10 1885
R.G. O'Brien Clerk.</p>