<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>In the District Court of the Second Judicial District of Washington Territory holding terms at Olympia
Thurston County Ss.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of Edward B Fuller for a writ of Habeas Corpus to discharge him from the illegal restraint by William Billings at the Jail of said County.</p>

<p>To Honorable Roger S. Greene Judge of said Court.</p>

<p>Edward B Fuller hereby makes application for a writ of Habeas Corpus and for grounds of said application alleges the following:</p>

<p>1st Applicant is now restrained of his liberty by William Billings at the Jail of said County at Olympia therein</p>

<p>2 The cause of said restraint is the follwoign to the best of affiants

<pb...></pb...>

knowledge and belief towit.</p>

<p>Said Billings so as aforesaid detains affiant by virtue of a certain pretended warrant of committment hearing date June 13th 1877 executed by one Galen F James a Justice of the Peace for said county and commanding said Billings to keep affiant in said Jail until discharged by due process of law <del></del></p>

<p>3 Said restraint is illegal in this towit, It does not appear by said pretended committment that affiant has committed any offense or that there exists any <unclear>warrants</unclear> suppose that affiant is guilty of any offense whatever, and it appears thereby that said Justice was &amp; is wholly without jurisdiction to order said committment and that the same is wholly said.</p>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>Wherefore affiant prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus in this behalf be issued to said Billings to the end that affiant be discharged from said illegal restraints.</p>

<p>Washington Territory
Thurston County ss.</p>

<p>Edward B. Fuller being duly sworn says he is the person of that name, named in &amp; who makes the foregoing complaint and application. That he has heard read said complaint, and that the same is true except as to matters therein stated on information and belief and as to these matters that he believes it to be true.</p>

<p>E B Fuller</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 22 day of August 1877</p>

<p>Joseph S. Allem
Notary Public</p>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>Washington Territory
Thurston County
2d Dist Ct
terms at Olympia</p>

<p>Application of Edward B. Fuller for Habeas Corpus</p>

<p>Filed Aug 27-72</p>

<p>RG OBrien
Clerk</p>

<p>JB &amp; JS Allen
Attorneys for Applicant</p>