<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p> Territory of Washington </p>
<p> Walla Walla County </p>

<p> In District Court for the First Judicial District of Washington Territory Before the Hon J.R. Lewis Judge At Chambers </p>

<p>Charles Gahres &amp; Martha J Gahres Guardian of Ella Dora Cravens, a Minor- Plaintiffs</p>
<p> vs </p>
<p>W.H. Barret and Isabella Barret - Defendants</p>

<p> Plaintiffs complaining of Defendants for cause of action alleges: </p>
<p> 1. That the above named Plaintiff Martha J Gahres (formally Martha J Carvens) is the mother of the said minor child Ella Dora Cravens by a previous marriage with on W.H. Cravens and that she is the natural and lawful guardian of the said minor child and entitled to the custody and control of the <unclear></unclear> </p>
<p> 2. That the said Martha J. Ghares formally Martha J. Cravens as aforesaid. <unclear> Married </unclear> a Judgement of divorce <unclear> from </unclear> her former husband W. H. Cravens to <unclear></unclear> torn of the circuit court of the State of Oregon on the County of Union <unclear> began </unclear> and held on the first day of November AD <unclear> 1806 </unclear> in which <unclear> his </unclear> the said court further ordered and decreed that the <unclear></unclear> Martha J Gahres then Martha J Cravens <unclear> had </unclear> the custody and education of the girl Ella Dora Cravens </p>
<p> 3. That <unclear> with </unclear> said Divorce such the members <unclear> thereby</unclear> and the said Ella Dora Cravens <unclear></unclear> within the Jurisdiction of the said court. </p>
<p> 4. That since the said decree of divorce the Plaintiffs herein have been lawfully married and are now living together as husband and wife</p>
<p> 5. <unclear></unclear> Plaintiffs here are <unclear> <unclear> </unclear> for the Education of the said Ella Dora Cravens and that the Plaintiff Martha J Gahres the mother of the said minor child has ample means for that purpose in her <unclear> own wealth</unclear>. </p>
<p> 6. That the said Ella Dora Cranens is now seven years of age and <unclear></unclear> in the Plaintiff <unclear></unclear> the <unclear> Education </unclear> has been wholly neglected. </p>
<p> 7. That the said Ella Dora Cranens is wrongfully and unlawfully withheld from the custody of Plaintiff at Wallada in the County of Walla Walla and Teritory of Washington by Defendants W.H. Barret and Isabella Barret. </p>
<p> 8. That the cause of the said alleged restraint and detention of the said minor child is the best of the knowledge and belief of Plaintiff is an alleged <unclear> gift </unclear> of the said Ella Dora Cravens to Defendants Isabella Barret by the said Martha J Cravens now Martha J Gahres before the decree of divorce aforesaid from her former husband W.H. Cravens and this the illegality of the said restraint and detention <unclear></unclear> in <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear> said alleged <unclear> gift </unclear> <unclear></unclear> without foundation and <unclear></unclear> a <unclear></unclear> of judgement. </p>

<p> Therefore Plaintiffs pray then a Writ of Habeas Corpus may issue <unclear> directed </unclear> to the Defendants W.H. Barret and Isabella Barret commanding them to have the body of the said Ella Dora Cravens before the Hon Judge of this court at a time and place designated by said judge and then and there <unclear></unclear> and <unclear> </unclear> what the said Hon Judge shall consider in the <unclear> premises concerning </unclear> said minor child and that the <unclear> </unclear> cause <unclear> </unclear> the said  minor child is withheld from the care and custody of Plaintiff and for Court in this preceedings. </p>
<p> J. R. Lussunter and T.J. Anden Attorneys for Plaintiffs </p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>


