<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<note>6908</note>

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE THIRD JUDICIAL DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON TERRITORY, HOLDING TERMS AT SEATTLE.</p>

<p>IN THE MATTER OF THE APPLICATION OF LEO SUN, FOR A WRIT OF HABEAS CORPUS | PETITION FOR WRIT.</p>

<p>To the Hon. C. H. Hanford, Judge of the District Court of the County of King, Territory of Washington.</p>

<p>The petition of Leo Sun respectfully shows:</p>

<p>That he, the said Leo Sun, is unlawfully imprisoned, detained, confined, and restrianed of his liberty by T. J. Hamilton, United States Marshal for the Territory of Washington, at the County Jail, in the County of King, in the Territory of Washington.</p>

<p>The cause or pretense of the restraint according to the best of the knowledge and belief of the applicant <del>is</del> is upon a committment issued from United States Commissioners Court, S. D. Davidson Commissioner, at Ellensburg, Washington Territory.</p>

<p>That the said imprisonment, detention, confinement, and restraint are illegal; and that the illegality thereof consists in this, towit:</p>

<p>That the said Leo Sun, was arrested at Ellensburgh, Washington Territory, for having in his possession thirty five-tael tin cans of prepared opium, whereas, in truth and in fact, said opium consisted of twenty-five five-tael tin cans of domestic prepared opium, manufactured in the United States of America, and five five-tael tin cans of perpared opium sold by the United States Marshal of Washington Territory, at a Marshals sale of forfeited goods at Port Townsend.</p>

<p>Wherefore, your petitioner prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus may be granted, directed to the said T. J. Hamilton, United States Marshal as aforesaid, commanding him to have the body of said Leo Sun before your Honor at a time and place therein to be specified, to do and receive what shall then and there by considered by your Honor, concerning said Leo Sun, together with the time and cause of his detention, and said writ; and that he, said Leo Sun, may be restored of his liberty.</p>

<p>Leo Sun</p>

<p>Dated June 3rd, 1889.</p>