<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0010.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>H. J. Mann v. Cynthia Mann. Defendant Motions the Court to Dismiss Writ of Habeas Corpus.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie R." xml:id="nrl">Natalie R. Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0010.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">H. J. Mann v. Cynthia Mann. Defendant Motions the Court to Dismiss Writ of Habeas Corpus.</title>
<date></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Mann, H. J.</term>
<term>Mann, Bessie</term>
<term>Mann, Cynthia</term>
<term>Allen</term>
<term>Crowley</term>
<term>Rhea, G. A.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Walla Walla (Wash)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Mann, H. J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Mann, Cynthia</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Allen</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Crowley</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>First Judicial District</orgName>
<placeName>Territory of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2017-06" who="#djr">transcribed</change>
<change when="2018-06" who="#nrl">encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0010.003.001"/>

<p>In the District Court of the Territory of Washington, and for the first Judicial District thereof, holding terms at Walla Walla, for the Counties of Walla Walla and Franklin, in said Territory.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application of H.J. Mann in behalf of his Daughter, Bessie Mann, for a writ of habeas corpus. </p>

<p>Comes now Cynthia Mann by her attorneys Allen &amp; Crowley, and moves the court to dismiss the writ herein issued, and dismiss said proceedings for the reason that the court has not jurisdiction to issue the same, or to inquire into and determine the question of the care, custody or control of said minor child, Bessie Mann, in a habeas corpus proceeding</p>

<p>And said Cynthia Mann, not waiving said motion, but insisting on her right therto, shows as cause why said writ should be denied and dismissed as follows:

Said Cynthia Mann denies that said Bessie Mann has been or is wrongfully detained or restrained of her liberty, or from her house or from the possession, care, custody, or control of anyone, either against the will of the said Bessie Mann, or otherwise, or at all.</p>

<p>Denies that slues the marriage alleged in the petition, until about the 12th day of May, 1887, the said H.J. Mann and Cynthia Mann lived and co-habited together as husband and wife, but avers that on March 5th, 1887 the said H.J. Mann, without cause, deserted and abandoned said wife Cynthia Mann, and has ever since remained separate and apart from her</p>

<p>Denies that said Cynthia Mann is not a fit or proper person to have the care, custody, control, and education of said Bessie mann.</p>

<note>1</note>

<pb facs="hc.case.0010.003.002"/>

<p>Denies that said Cynthia Mann is a lewd, unchaste, unvirtuous immoral or immodest woman.</p>

<p>Denies that on or about the first day of April, 1885, or at any time, or at all, the said Cynthia Mann committed the set, or crime of adultery with one G.A. Rhea, or with anyone, either at the residence of H.J. Mann and Cynthia Mann, or at any other time or place, or at all.</p>

<p>Denies that she ever, at any time, or at all, had criminal or adulterous intercourse with said G.A. Rhea, or with anyone, or that she at any time disregarded her marriage vows, or failed to observe her duties as a wife and mother.</p>

<p>Denies that petitioner ever, at any time, became aware of any lewd, criminal, or adulterous conduct of said wife, Cynthia Mann, or that she at any time, or at all, was guilty of say lewd, criminal, or adulterous conduct with anyone, or at all.</p>

<p>Denies that hoping to reclaim her therefrom, or to avoid further or any disgrace upon herself or family, or anyone, that said petitioner removed the said wife and children to the State of Indiana, but on the contrary, avers that said petitioner, and his wife and family went voluntarily to the Sate of Indiana because <sic>shey</sic> deemed it best so to do.</p>

<p>Denies that on or about: the 12th day of May, 1887, or at any time the said Cynthia Mann, without the knowledge or consent of petitioner, or against his will, or the will of their said children, or at all, or that in pursuance of any agreement, or understanding between herself and the said G.A. Rhea, the said Cynthia Mann took said children forcibly or otherwise, or against their will, away</p>

<note>2</note>

<pb facs="hc.case.0010.003.003"/>

<p>from their father, or their home, or carried them to the City of St Paul, or elsewhere, or that she either met according to, or in pursuance of said or any agreement, the said G.A. Rhea, or that she then or there, or at any time or place, or at all, permitted said G.A. Rhea to have criminal or adulterous connection, or intercourse with her, or that she at any time, or at all, eloped with the said G.A. Rhea, or that she at any time, either while journeying on the cars, or elsewhere, permitted the said G.A. Rhea to occupy the same bed with her, or that he did at any time occupy the same bed with her.</p>

<p>Denies that for the purpose of secreting said children from their father the said Cynthia Mann took said children to the <sic>Dalls</sic> or that she lived with said children at the <sic>Dalls</sic> for the purpose of secreting them, or that she was there supported, or received support from G.A. Rhea, or that the money used by said Cynthia Mann for traveling, or other expenses, at or from the time she left the State of Indiana, as aforsaid, was furnished, or sent to her, or that any portion thereof was furnished or sent to her, or received by her from the said G.A. Rhea in consideration of criminal or adulterous intercourse had, or agreed to be had by her with the said G.A. Rhea, or with anyone. </p>

<p>Denies that said petitioner has spent much money in seach of said children, or any of them.</p>

<p>Denies that she has at any time refused to deliver said Bessie Mann to her home, but on the contrary, avers that the home of said Bessie Mann has been and is with affiant answering herein</p>

<note>3</note>

<pb facs="hc.case.0010.003.004"/>

<p>Denies that she is living, or at any time has been living in criminal or adulterous intercourse with various or any men, at any place, or at all.</p>

<p>Denies that petitioner is able, or competent to have the care of custody of said Bessie Mann, or that the interests of said Bessie Mann, or the communnity at large, demand or require that said Bessie Mann be taken from the possession of said Cynthia Mann or away from her.</p>

<p>Denies that her influences are lewd, immoral, or licentious, and denies that said Bessie Mann is wanting the watchful care of a kind and virtuous parent: denies that affiant at any time has threatened to, or that she will carry said Bessie Mann out of the jurisdiction of this court.</p>

<p>And further answering herein affiant alleges that she is the wife of said petitioner, and the mother of the child Bessie Mann.</p>

<p>That she, at all times, has had the care, custody and control of said child, and that she is much attached to said child, and the said child is to her, and that she has at all times taken good and watchful care of her, and taught her properly.</p>

<p>That on or about March 5th, 1887, the said petitioner desserted affiant in the State of Indiana, and left her without means, except about $70,000, and wrote from the State of Kansas and told that affiant that if she came there she would have to support herself and children.</p>

<p>That affiant thereupon came went, and for a time remained at the Dalles in the State of Oregon where two of said children were taken from her against he consent, by petitioner.</p>

<note>4</note>

<pb facs="hc.case.0010.003.005"/>

<p>That affiant in June last, moved to Walla Walla County, and has since resided there, and has during said time, been engaged in work, having no means of support, except the labor of her hands and receiving no offer of assisstance from petititioner.</p>

<p>That by her own labor and industry she has taken care of said minor child, Bessie Mann, and has assisted in the support of the two children now in possession of petitioner.</p>

<p>That petitioner is a man of violent and angry temper, and that during their marriage life he treated affiant in a harsh and cruel manner. That in 1885, while he and affiant were living together as husband and wife, he endeavored by solicitations and threats to induce affiant to have criminal intercourse with said G.A. Rhea for the purpose, as he then and there said, of obtaining from said Rhea a large sum of money by way of black-mail. That affiant refused to enter into such conspiracy, but that petitioner, by threats and promises, obtained from her a statement incriminating the said G.A. Rhea, and that he obtained letters written by Rhea to affiant and read and examined them for the purpose of carrying into effect his said scheme of black-mail. That Rhea was a man of large means, and petitioner alleged that if affiant would obey his wishes they could make a fortune out of him the said Rhea. And affiant is informed, and believes that said Mann did obtain a large sum of money from said Rhea by threats and other means, and affiant alleges that never, at any time, has there been any adulterous or other criminal intercourse between herself and the said Rhea, and that petitioner well knows that such is the case.</p>

<note>5</note>

<pb facs="hc.case.0010.003.006"/>

<p>That petitioner has been harrassing, and annoying this affiant from time to time, theatening her that if she did not return and live with him he would take from her the child Bessie Mann, and affiant alleges that she is a fit and proper person to have the care, custody and control of said minor, and that she always has cared for her as a mother ought and should, and alleges that petitioner is not a fit person to have the care, custody and control of said minor child. </p>

<p>Wherefore affiant asks that said writ and the prayer thereof be denied, and that said Bessie Mann be restored to her custody.</p>

<p>Cynthia Mann</p>

<p>Allen &amp; Crowley</p>
<p>Attorneys for Cynthia Mann</p>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>




















