<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p> Ter of Washington </p>
<p> Walla Walla County</p>
<p> In District Court <unclear></unclear> First Judicial District of Washington Ter. Before the Hon. J. R. <unclear> Leuris </unclear> Judge <unclear></unclear> chambers</p>

<p> Charles Gahres &amp; Martha J Gahres Guardians of Etta Dora Cravens, a minor Plffts </p>
<p> vs. </p>
<p> W. H. Barret and Isabella Baret Defts</p>

<p> Plaintiffs complaining of Defendants for <unclear> course </unclear> of action alleges</p>

<p> That the above named Plaintiff, Martha J. Gahres (formaly Martha J. Cravens) as <unclear></unclear> of the said minor child, Etta Dora Cravens by a former marriage with one W.H. Cravens and that she is the natural and lawful guardian of the said minor child, and entitled to the custody and <unclear> corstial </unclear> of the same</p>

<p> Then the said Martha J. Ghares formally Martha J. Cravens as aforesaid retained a judgement of service from her former husband W.H. Cravens of a regular term of the circuit court of the state of Oregon for the county of Union began andheld on the first day of November AD 1869 <unclear></unclear> suit the said Court Justice ordered and decreed that the said Martha J. Gahres then Martha J. Cravens have the custody and education of the said Etta Dora Cravens.</p>

<p> Year of said Divorce suit the parties <unclear></unclear> and the said Etta Dora Cravens <unclear></unclear> written the jurisdiction of the said court. </p>

<p> That since the said <unclear> decree </unclear> of divorce the Plaintiffs herein have lawfully married and are now living together as husband and wife. </p>

<p> That plaintiffs have ample means for the education of the said Etta Dora Cravens and that the Plaintiff Martha J. Gahres the mother of the said minor child, has ample means for <unclear> this </unclear> purpose in her own rights. </p>

<p> That the said Etta Dora Cravens is now seven years of age and that as the plaintiff <unclear></unclear> her education has been <unclear> wholly neglected </unclear></p>

<p>That the said Etta Dora Cravens is wrongfully and unlawfully withheld from the custody of Plaintiff, on Wallula in the County of Walla Walla and Territory of Washington by Defendants, WH Barret &amp; Isabella Barret.</p>

<p> What the course of the said illegal restraint and detention of the said minor child, tothe best of the knowledge and belief of Plaintiffs is an alleged gift of the said Etta Dora Cravens to defendants, Isabella Barret by the said Martha J Cravens, now Martha J. Gahres, before the the decree of divorce aforesaid from her former husband W. H. Cravens0 and that the illigality of the said restraint and detention <unclear></unclear> in this <unclear></unclear> the said alleged gift is totally without foundation and <unclear></unclear> a <unclear> burden </unclear> of Defendants.</p>

<p> Therefore Plaintiffs pray that a writ of Habeas Corpus may <unclear></unclear> divided to the Defendants W.H. Baret &amp; Isabella Baret commanding them to have the body of the said Etta Dora Cravens before the Hon. Judge of this Court, at a time and place designated by said Judge and then and there to <unclear></unclear> inform what the said Hon. Judge shall consider in the <unclear> premise </unclear> concerning said minor child and that <unclear> they </unclear> show cause why the said minor child is whitheld from the care and custody of Plaintiff and for <unclear> courts</unclear> in this proceeding.</p>

<p> A. H. Gosalen &amp; T.J Audens, Atty for Pltffs.</p>


<p> Territory of Washington </p>
<p> County of Walla Walla </p>

<p>Martha J. Gahres being first duly sworn says that she is one of the plaitiffs in the above <unclear></unclear> action that she has heard the foregoing complaint and and believes the same to be true. </p>
<p> Martha J Gahres </p>

<p> Subscribed and sworn to before me this 29 day of August A.D. 1873</p>
<p> W.N. <unclear></unclear></p>
<p> Clerk</p>

<p> In Dist. Court 1st Distr. Chs Gahres &amp; Martha J. Gahres, Plfts </p>
<p> vs </p>
<p> W.H. Barret &amp; Isabella Barret, Defts </p>

<p> Petition for Habeas Corpus </p>

<p> Filed Aug <unclear></unclear> 1873 </p>
<p> Wm U. <unclear></unclear> </p>
<p> Clerk </p>

<p> Sheriff fees $4.00 </p>

<p> J. G. <unclear></unclear> &amp; S. J. <unclear></unclear> Attns for Deft </p>

<p> In reading and due consideration of the writting complaint it is ordered said the writ of Habeas Corpus issue in accordance <unclear></unclear> returnable on the 1st day of Sept 1873. on 1 oclock pm. </p>

<p> J.R. Suirs </p>
<p> Judge </p>
