<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p> In the Dist Court of the 3d Jud Dist of Washington Territory held at Seattle in and for the counties of King Kistap and Snohomish </p>

<p> In the matter of the appliccation of Peter Nelson W Smith H Elsner C Whaley G Matson Charles Lundblad Dennis Coffy &amp; Jacob Anner for a writ of Habeas Corpus </p>

<p> To the Hon JR Lewis Judge &amp;c and now come the aforesaid <sic>applisants</sic> on <unclear>5</unclear>th May of <unclear></unclear> to the <unclear>suffising</unclear> and <unclear>contvanty</unclear> the statue of the said Lewis V Wyshoff Dpty Marshal &amp;c to the said <unclear></unclear> <unclear>Sg</unclear>.</p>

<p>1st that said return does not show upon what charge or for what offense said <sic>applisants</sic> are held, or before what court they are held to answer</p>

<p>2 And said <sic>applisants</sic> aver the truth and <unclear>first</unclear> to be as follows by: that on or about the 8th day of April AD 1875 they <sic>shiped</sic> on board the Bark Bern

of the <sic>osean</sic> SE <unclear>Seg</unclear>  Master for a voyage from San Fransisco to Seattle Puget Sound, <strike></strike> And that afterwards on or about the 11th day of the same month the said master <sic>proseeded</sic> to <sic>sen</sic> with said Bark and with these <sic>applisants</sic> on board without them signing any shipping contracts or agreement in writing or in print <unclear>whatever</unclear> that on or about the 23d day of April aforesaid, the said Bark arrived at the Port of Seattle King County Washington Territory at <sic>whish</sic> time &amp; place said <sic>applisants</sic> are entitled to then <sic>dischge</sic> for said vessel, and then and there demanded to be so <sic>disshaged</sic> and paid off and that in <sic>consequense</sic> of <sic>sush</sic> demand to be <sic>disshaged</sic> and paid off, and for no other cause, the said Master S.E. <unclear>Seg</unclear> <sic>prosured</sic> the arrest and imprisonment of these applicants of after the arrest of said

vessel at said port of Seattle as aforesaid for alleged disobedience of orders and lawful commons of said Master and Officers of said Bark. </p>

<p>Also <unclear>lisense</unclear> said return is in the <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear> and <sic>insuffisient</sic></p>

<p><unclear>WH White</unclear> &amp; <unclear>JJMBitald</unclear></p>
<p>Attys for <sic>applisants</sic></p>
