<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>Territory of Washington }
Second Judicial District} ss</p>

<p>In the District Court Holding Terms at Olympia.</p>

<p>In the matter of the Application of William Jones, William H. Doyle, Fred Williams and Alfred Woods for Writ of Habeas Corpus } Marshal's Return and Answer</p>

<p>To Honorable John P. Hoyt, Judge of the above entitled District Courts.</p>

<p>Comes now Jesse W. George United States Marshal for Washington Territory to whom the annexed writ of Habeas Corpus, is directed, and makes return of the said writ and in obedience to the command thereof brings before your Honor the bodies of the said William James, William H. Doyle, Fred Williams, and Alfred Woods, to do and receive whatsoever shall now here be considered concerning

<pb...></pb...>

them, and the said Respondents respectfully showeth unto your Honor as to the time and cause of the imprisonment of said William Jones, William H. Doyle Fred Williams, and Alfred Woods, That this respondent is now and was at all the times herein mentioned the duly appointed, qualified and acting United States Marshal for Washington Territory.</p>

<p>That this respondents as such United States Marshal took the said William Jones, William H. Doyle, Fred Williams, and Alfred Woods, and each of them together with one Peter Anderson into custody on the 11th day of February A.D. 1885 at the City of Seattle, in King County in the Third Judicial District of Washington Territory by virtue of and in obedience to the command of a certain warrant of committment in writing on said day duly issued at the City of Seattle aforesaid by

<pb...></pb...>

Eden Smith Esq. then and there a duly appointed qualified and acting United States Court Commissioner in and for said Third Judicial District of Washington Territory <del>to</del> under his hand and seal and to said respondents as such United States Marshal directed and delivered which said warrant of commitment is in the words and figures following towit:</p>

<p>"Territory of Washington}
Third Judicial District} ss.
King County}</p>

<p>In United States Commissioners Court Before Eben Smith, United States Commissioner in and for the 3rd Judicial District of Washington Territory, at Seattle in King County.</p>

<p>United States of America}
vs}
William Jamieson, Michael Daley, and William Winters,}</p>

<p>Territory of Washington}
Third Judicial District} ss
King County}</p>

<p>Whereas William Jamieson, William

<pb...></pb...>

Daley, and William Winters, have been charged on oath before me the undersigned United States Commissioner for the Third Judicial District of Washington Territory at Seattle in King County with the Crime of Conspiring to defraud the United Stated out of Certain of its public lands as in complaint of William F. Prosser special agent of the general Land office of the United States set forth, contrary to the statutes in such case made and provided, and whereas William Jones, William H Doyle, Peter Anderson, Fred Williams, and Alfred Woods, have been duly subpeonoed as witnesses in the matter of said charge on behalf of the United States.</p>

<p>And whereas upon examination had this day by me, said named witnesses then and there being present not having offered sufficient bail as

<pb...></pb...>

required by me the said Commissioner in the sum of five hundred Dollars, each for their and each of their appearance at the next regular term of the District Court for the 3rd Judicial District of Washington Territory, holding terms at Seattle in and for the Counties of King and Kitsap, to be begun and holden on the First Monday of April next then and there to testify as witnesses for and on behalf of the United States, in the matter of the charge aforesaid; were by me then and there ordered to be committed to the custody of the United States Marshal in and for Washington Territory, for want of sureties, and until they should be discharged by due Course of law.</p>

<p>You are therefore hereby commanded in the name and by the authority of the United States of America, to receive the said William

<pb...></pb...>

Jones, William H. Doyle, Peter Anderson, Fred Williams, and Alfred Woods, and them safely keep until they shall be delivered by due process of law.</p>

<p>Given