<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p> Territory of Washington </p>
<p> County of Jefferson } Ss. </p>

<p> In the matter of the application of John Cain John Brown Victor Vaucek &amp; Jose Carma for a writ of Habeas Corpus } Petition for Writ </p>

<p> To the Hon. Orange Jacobs, Chief Justice of the Territory of Washington and Judge of the 3rd Judicial District therein: </p>

<p> The Petition of John Cain John Brown Victor Vaucek and Jose Carma respectfully shows: that they are unlawfully imprisoned, detained, confined and restrained of their liberty by J.J.H. Van Bokkelen Sheriff of said Jefferson Co and Depty U.S. Marshal at the Jail in Port Townsend in the said county of Jefferson Territory of Washington </p>

<p> That the said imprisonment, detention, confinement and restraint are illegal; and that the illigality thereof consists in this, to wit: </p>

<p> The said John Cain, John Brown, Victor Vaucek and Jose Carma were and are impisoned, detained, confined and restrained of their liberty by a commitment issued by a Justice of the Peace for having deserted from the Nicaraguan Ship Halcon, without any application having been maid to said Justice of the Peace for that pur

pose by a consul or vice-consul or any other officer of the Nicaraguan Government; and without any treaty existing between the United States and said Nicaraguan Government <strike> for </strike> stipulating for the restoration of Seamen deserting; and without observing any of the requirements of law, or any of the requirements of law being observed, as prescribed in the act of <unclear> Coupers </unclear> <unclear> parud </unclear> March 2nd 1829 Sec 1; (Also 1st Brighhly page 610. Sec. 41.) </p>

<p> But said Justice of the Peace, in total disregard and defyance of said Act and every requirement thereof, and of all law, purposely <strike> and </strike> arbitrarily and unlawfully usurped the right, and prostituted the power of his office, to subserve the master of said Nicoraguan Ship, and caused the said John Cain, John Brown, Victor Vaucek &amp; Jose Carma to be arrested and taken by force, to wit: by the <unclear></unclear> Revenue Cutter "Oliver Walcott" from the  American Barken time Freamont in which they had shipped on a certain <sic> voiage </sic> and were, when arrested, outward bound and brought before him, the said Justice, upon said charge of desertion and were by him tried and condemned to be returned on board of said Nicaraguan Ship. by said Marshal whenever the Master of said ship shall

so order, and to remain for that purpose in the custody of said Marshal. </p>

<p> Wherefore, your petitioners pray that a writ of Habeas Corpus may be granted, directed to the said J.J. H. Van Bokkelen Sheriff &amp; Depty U.S. Marshal commanding him to have the bodies of John Cain John Brown, Victor Vaucek &amp; Jose Carma before your Honor, at a time and place therein to be specified, to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by your Honor, concerning them together with the time and cause of their detention, and said writ; and that they may be restored to their liberty. </p>
<p> Dated Feb. 13. 1875 </p>

<p> John Cain </p>
<p> John Brown </p>
<p> Victor Vaucek </p>
<p> Jose his X mark Carma </p>