<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p> Territory of Washington</p>
<p> County of Walla Walla</p>

<p> In the District Court of the first Judicial District Before Hon. J R Kennedy Judge </unclear> at  Chambers</p>

<p>Charles Gahres and Martha J. Gahres, Guardians of Etty Dora Cravens a minor Plffs </p>
<p> vs. </p>
<p> Isabella Sutton and W. H. Barrettt Defts</p>

<p> Charles Gahres and Marth J. Gahres (formally Martha J. Cranens) the above  and hereinafter <unclear> </unclear> plffs for complaint against Isabella Sutton and W. H. Barrett the above and hereinafter <unclear> </unclear> defts allege that they Plffs are the legal parents and maternal and lawful guardians of Etty Dora Cravens a minor child of the age of five years that said child is the child of one of the Martha J. Gahres Plffs a family marriage with one W. H. Cranen that in <unclear> </unclear> 1869 said marriage <unclear> </unclear> used and <unclear></unclear> with child <unclear> <unclear> </unclear> afterwords as a <unclear></unclear> of <unclear> </unclear>/Court of the 5th Judicial District of Oregon on <unclear> <unclear> <unclear> <unclear> </unclear> the <unclear> </unclear> in of said marriage with <unclear> </unclear>Cravens the said Plffs (to <unclear> </unclear>Martha J. Gahres) has intermarried with the other Plff herein and they Plffs are now an aforesaid the guardians of said minor child and entitled to the sole custody of said child.</p>

<p> That the said minor child of those Plffs to <unclear> wit said </unclear> said Etty Dora Cravens is wrongfully and unlawfully detained and <unclear> untrained </unclear> of her liberty by the said Defendants Isabella Sutton and W. H. Barrett at the town of Wallalo with <unclear> </unclear> County of WallaWalla and Territory of Washington</p>

<p> That the course of said restraint of said minor child by said Defts in according to the best knowledge and <unclear> </unclear> of those plffs an arbitrary determination on the part of Defts to keep said child without any <unclear> closing </unclear> right whatever to the custody thereof </p>

<p>That said retraints and <unclear> </unclear> said minor child is illegal and that the illegality <unclear> thing causiet </unclear> in the withoholding the custody of said child from those Plffs who are the lawful guardians of said minor and or such entitled thereto </p>

<p> Wherefore Plffs or guardians of said minor <unclear> pray </unclear> that a writ of Habeas Corpus <unclear> be </unclear> issue directed to said Isabella Sutton and W. H. Barrett commanded them to have the body of said minor child Etty Dora Cravens before the Honorable Judge of the Court at a time and place to be specified by said Judge and then and there to do and <unclear> revive </unclear> what shall these and there be <unclear> condoned </unclear> by said Honorable Judge- Concerning said minor child <unclear> </unclear> with the terms and course of her detention and said whit and that said minor child may be restored to the custody of these plffs and for <unclear> corte </unclear> of said</p>
<p> Charles Gahres </p>
<p> Martha J. Gahres </p>
<p> Plaintiffs</p>


<p> Territory of Washington </p>
<p> County of Walla Walla </p>

<p> Charles Gahres being first duly sworn says he is one of the Plffs in the <unclear> </unclear> and knows the conduct there of and that the same is true of his own knowledge exempt on to matters therein stated on information and belief and on to those matters he believes it true </p>
<p> Charles Gahres </p>

<p> Sumscribed and sworn to before me this 7th day of June </p> 
<p> <unclear> P </unclear> </p>
<p> Notary Publis </p>