<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>IN THE SUPERIOR COURT OF THE STATE OF WASHINGTON</p>
<p>FOR KING COUNTY.</p>

<p>The City of Seattle, Plaintiff</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>Henry Paulson Defendant.</p>

<p>No. 6353 ORDER VACATING JUDGMENT.</p>

<p>The motion of the defendant, Henry Paulson, and of Valborg Paulson and of George Sheer, sureties on bond of said defendant, in the above entitled cause, for an order vacating and setting aside the order heretofore entered by the above entitled court on the 22nd day of December, 1914, and which said order was recorded in the Clerk's office of the above entitled court in Journal Record No. 519 page 165, came on regularly for hearing on the 6th day of January, 1917, the said defendant being present in court and being represented by his attorney, Ralph Major, Esq., and the saind Bondsmen, Valborg Paulson and George Sheer being represented at said time by their attorneys, Messrs. Beechler &amp; Batchelor, and the said plaintiff, City of Seattle, being represented at said time by its attorney, T. J. L. Kennedy, Esq., Asst. corporation counsel, and the court having considered the matter and it appearing to the court that said Henry Paulson was sentenced in the Police Court of John B. Gordon, August 7, 1912, to pay a fine of $100.00 without costs, and it appearing to the court that said defendant appealed said cause to this court and that judgment by default was rendered against said defendant and his said bondsmen above named on December 22, 1914, and it further appearing to the court that said defendent did not have

<pb...></pb...>

notice of the trial of said cause and that said defendant and said bondsmen above named did not know or have nay knowledge of said judgement having been entered until on or about the <gap></gap> day of December, 1916, and it further appearing to the court that good cause has been shown in said order should be set aside the said plaintiff having been put to no expense in producing said defendant into court, therefore the court now enters its order as follows, to-wit:</p>

<p>IT IS HEREBY ORDERED, ADJUDGED AND DECREED that the said order heretofore entered in the above entitled cause on the 22nd day of December, 1914, which said order is entitled a Judgment and Sentence, and <unclear>it is</unclear> against the above named defendant, Henry Paulson and Mrs. Valborg Paulson and George Sheer and each of them and far forfeiting the bail bond put up in said cause in amount of $300.00, and which said judgment and sentence is recorded in the office of the Clerk of the above entitled court in Journal Record 519 at page 165 be and the same is hereby vacated and sat aside and held for naught.</p>

<p>Done in Open Court this 8th day of January, 1917.</p>

<p>King <unclear>DY Keiueers</unclear></p>
<p>Judge.</p>