<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0004.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Charles Gahres and Martha J. Gahres v. Isabella Sutton and W. H. Barrett. Plaintiffs Complaint.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2017</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Bring Me the Body: A Digital &amp; Print History of Marginalized Habeas Corpus Petitioners in the North American West, 1804-1912</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0004.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Charles Gahres and Martha J. Gahres v. Isabella Sutton and W. H. Barrett. Plaintiffs Complaint.</title>
<date></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Gahres, Martha J.</term>
<term>Gahres, Charles</term>
<term>Sutton, Isabella</term>
<term>Barrett, W. H.</term>
<term>Kennedy, JR</term>
<term>Cravens, Etty Dora</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Walla Walla (Wash)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Gahres, Martha J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Gahres, Charles</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Sutton, Isabella</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Barrett, W. H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Kennedy, JR</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName>Territory of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2017-06" who="#djr">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2017-06" who="#nl">transcribed</change>
<change when="2017-06" who="#djr">encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0004.001.001"/>

<p>Territory of Washington</p>
<p>County of Walla Walla</p>

<p>In the District Court of the first Judicial District Before Hon. J R Kennedy Judge <unclear></unclear> at  Chambers</p>

<p>Charles Gahres &amp; Martha J. Gahres, Guardians of Etty Dora Cravens a minor Plffs</p>
<p>vs.</p>
<p>Isabella Sutton and W. H. Barrett Defts</p>

<p>Charles Gahres and Martha J. Gahres (formally Martha J. Cranens) the above  and hereinafter <unclear></unclear> plffs for complaint against Isabella Sutton and <del>Richard</del> W. H. Barrett the above and hereinafter <unclear></unclear> defts allege</p>

<p>1st That they Plffs are the legal parents and maternal and lawful guardians of Etty Dora Cravens a minor child of the age of five years that said child is the child of one of the Martha J. Gahres Plff by a family marriage with one Wm A. Cranen

<pb facs="hc.case.0004.001.002"/>

that in <unclear>June</unclear> 1869 said marriage was <unclear></unclear> and said child <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear> afterwords as a term of the Circuit Court of the 5th Judicial District of Oregon on <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear> river the <unclear></unclear> of said marriage with said Cravens the said Plffs (to wit Martha J. Gahres) has intermarried with the other Plff herein and they Plffs are now an aforesaid the guardians of said minor child and entitled to the sole custody of said child.</p>

<p>2nd That the said minor child of those Plffs to wit said Etty Dora Cravens is wrongfully and unlawfully detained and restrained of her liberty by the said Defendants Isabella Sutton and <del>Richard</del> W. H. Barrett at the town of Wallalo in the said County of Walla Walla and Territory of Washington</p>

<p>3rd That the course of said restraint of said minor child by said Defts is according to the best knowledge and belief of these plffs an arbitrary determination on the part of Defts to keep said child without any closing right whatever to the custody thereof</p>

<p>4th That said retraints and detention of said minor child is illegal and that the illegality thereof <unclear></unclear> in the withholding the custody of said child from these Plffs who are the lawful guardians of said minor and as such entitled thereto</p>

<p> Wherefore Plffs or guardians of said minor pray that a writ of Habeas Corpus be issue directed to said Isabella Sutton and <del>Richard</del> W.H. Barrett commanding them to have the body of said minor child Etty Dora Cravens before the Honorable Judge of the Court at a time and place to be specified by said Judge and then and there to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by said Honorable Judge concerning said minor child together with the terms and course of her detention and said writ and that said minor child may be restored to the custody of these plffs 

<pb facs="hc.case.0004.001.003"/>

and for costs of said</p>

<p>Charles Gahres</p>
<p>Martha J. Gahres</p>
<p>Plaintiffs</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
