<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
Territory of Washington 
County of Walla Walla 
In? District Court 1st Judicial 
Disrict Washington Territory 
In the matter of the application 
of J H Sheffler and Josephine Sheffler 
for writ of Habeas Corpus 
Now Comes John B Montague the 
Defendant against whom the said J H 
Sheffler and Josephine Sheffler have made 
complaint in the above entitled unknown!
and for unknown! to said complainant and 
as a return to said writ on his unknown!
shows to the Honorable Court the 
following facts 
1st Defendant admits that said child
is in his custody and under his control
and that of his wife under and by virtue 
of said agreement in complaint mentioned 
and set forth, which said agreement is 
hereby refused? to and unknown! part of this 
unknown! to the same purpose and effect? 
as if herein unknown! and defendant 
alleges that he has unknown! and duly herefore? 
unknown! all the conditions and covenants 
in said agreement contained and on
his part to be kept or performed 
2 Defendant denies that said restraint was 
or is illegal; denies that he totally or 
(new page) 
otherwise disregarded his said covenant 
or any or either of them; denies that he 
has unknown! said child in or about a saloone? 
where vile or other improper language 
was used in her presence or hearing, and 
denies that he has caused her or is now 
causing her or that he has allowed her 
to associate with the vile or with
women of ill fame or other improper 
unknown! unknown!
Defendant further shows to the Honorable 
Court that some several months before 
the unknown! of said agreement the said 
Josephine Sheffler voluntarily let said 
Defendant have said child and placed 
placed the same in his family to be by 
his and his wife raised and educated 
and that said child was then sick and 
requested unknown! and medical aid, and 
that Defendant and his wife unknown! unknown!
cared for her and employed a unknown!
Physician to attend on her at a great 
unknown! to Defendant; that during all 
that time and after the time of the 
exception of said agreement Defendant 
lived and Kept said saloon where he 
now lives and Keeps the same, and that 
complainants well know? - the place of 
residence and the unknown! and unknown! 
(new page)
of the Defendants; and Defendant for unknown! 
alleges that he has during all the 
time said unknown! had been under his 
care, clothed, unknown!, cared for, and 
sent her to school and treated her in 
all aspects as he would his own child
and that he and his said wife have 
become strongly and affectionately attached 
to said child and that her attachment 
for unknown! is no less than that of an 
affectionate child for its comfort?
Wherefore Defendant prays that said 
writ is disarmed? and that the custody
of said child be unknown! back to 
the defendant and for his costs and 
unknown!
Kennedy and George
Defendants attys
Territory of Washington 
County of Walla Walla 
John B Montague having 
duly sworn says that he is the defendant 
in the above entitled case; that he 
knows? the contents of the foregoing 
unknown! and believes the same to be true
J. B. Montague
Subscribed and sworn to be true the this 13th 
day of Nov 1876 unknown! unknown!
unknown! of the unknown!