<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>United States of America</p>
<p>Territory of Washington}</p>
<p>County of King, City of Seattle}SS.</p>

<p>To the Chief of Police or any Police Officer of the City of Seattle and the Keeper of the Jail of said City of Seattle.</p>

<p>Whereas at a Justice's Court held at my office in said County, for the trial of Ah Foong for the offense hereinafter stated, the said Ah Foong was convicted of having on the 13th day of January 1886, within the corporate Circuits of the City of Seattle, one Ah Foong then and there being did unlawfully engage in the business of a peddler, without having obtaineda license therefor from the City of Seattle in this, that the said Ah Foong did, then and there, without having obtained a peddlers license from said city, go from house to house in said City with goods and merchandise to wit, vegetables, for the purpose of selling and offering for sale said vegetables, and did then there, sell and offer for sale vegetables to <sic>divers</sic> different persons whose names are to affiant unknown, by going from house to house in said
<pb.....></pb.....>
City in violation of the provisions of Sections V. 36 and <sic>of of</sic> Ordinance No. 705 ofs said City, entitled "An ordinance to license tax and regulate Auctioners, Hawkers and Peddlers," passed by the Common Council of said City on the 4th day of Jany 1886, and approved by the Mayor of said City on the 5th day of January, 1886 and against the peace and dignity of said City, and upon conviction, the said Court did adjudge and determine that said Ah Foong should pay a fine of Five dollars, and Eleven and 85/100 dollars costs, and stand committed until the same be paid and, whereas the said Ah Foong has made default in the payment of the same, Therefore, you the said Chief of Police or Police Officer, and said Keeper, are hereby commanded in the name of the United States forthwith to convey and deliver the said Ah Foong to the said Keeper, and you, the said Keeper, are hereby commanded to receive the said Ah Foong into your custody in said Jail, and him there keep at hard labor for the space of sixteen days, unless
<pb....></pb....>
said five and costs be sooner paid or he shall thence be discharged by due course of law.</p>

<p>Dated this 19th day of January 1886.</p>
<p>Geo G. Lyon <figure>seal</figure></p>
<p>Justice of the Peace</p>