<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p> Probate Court of Whitman County W.T.</p>

<p> In the matter of the adopting of Daisy Geneva Departte } order </p>

<p> An order of the court having been made on the 24th day of January 1888 appointing S.J. Chadwick next friend for said Daisy Geneva Departte and also granting consent of said Court for the adoption of said Daisy Geneva Departte a minor by Amos Gustin and Cathering Gustin and that the said child to be the child of said last name and persons and changing the name of said minor. </p>

<p> And aforesaid to wit on the 25th day of January AD 1888 being a day of the same term at which said order was made.</p>

<p> The mother of said Daisy Geneva Departte to wit Elizabeth Departte peition this court a motion to have said decree opened up to the said <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear> the said Elizabeth Departte might be allowed to appear and oppose said petition of said Amos Gustin and Catherine Gustin said motion being supported by the affidavit of said Elizabeth Departte, setting forth among other matters that she has no notice or knowledge of said proceedings and denying all the allegations in the petition of said petitioners and asking that said order be set aside and a new hearing

granted</p>

<p> and now on this day the same being the day set for hearing on said motion said matter coming on to be heard on the <unclear> evidence </unclear> and the <unclear></unclear> and the argument of counsel, Mark A Fullerton appearing for said Elizabeth Departte and Sullivan Wolfordant Brorn appearing for said petitioners and in said hearing it appearing to the satisfaction of the Court that there is sufficient ground for opening up said decree and setting the same aside and granting a new hearing on said petition</p>

<p> It is hereby ordered that said decree be and the same is hereby set aside and the 16th day of February 1888 at 9 AM be and the same is hereby set is the time for rehearing of said petition</p>

<p> Done in open court the 27th day of January AD 1888 </p>
<p> WN Ruby </p>
<p> Probate Judge</p>