<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p> Territory of Washington </p>
<p> County of Walla Walla </p>

<p> The District Court </p>
<p> 1st Judicial District </p>
<p> At Chambers before </unclear> </p>
<p> J. K. </unclear> Judge </p>
<p> Habeas Corpus </p>

<p> Charles Gahres &amp; Martha J. Gahres Plffs </p>
<p> vs </p>
<p> Isabella Sutton &amp; W. H. Barrett Defts </p>
<p> </unclear> </p>

<p> Defts for a </unclear> to the complaint herein filed and return to the court is said cause </unclear> say.. that they have the child in said and described now in court. Defts say as they are informed and believe that said Plffs are not the parents of said Ella Dora Cravens and </unclear> that said Plffs are the lawful guardians of said minor etta Dora Cravens.</p>
<p> Defts </unclear> that they or either of these wrongfully or unlawfully detain or restrain said Etta Dora Cravens of her liberty at the court of Wallula County of WallaWalla Territory of Washington or elsewhere</p>

<p> Defendants </unclear> that said minor child has been in the posession of said defendants for about three years that the said child has been sickly that </unclear> defendants have been at great appease and trouble in the rearing so for of said child that they have taken great care pain and trouble with said child and have watched over the </unclear> and have become greatly attached thereto</p>

<p> That the mother of said child Martha J Cravens had no home and no means of procuring one and did not posess the ability to take care of and provide for said child and expressing great hate and disgust for the father of said child and </unclear> of removing from her gaze. the child that would <unclear> </unclear> her of one so hateful to her and also expressing hate for her father besenghe these defts to take and rear said Etta Dora Cravens promiseing and agreeing to leave said child in the </unclear> possession of these Defts if they would agree so to do. Defts over that they did on the day of August  AD 1868 take said child from its mother Martha J Cravens under said arrangement and have kept and provided for the </unclear> ever since defts </unclear> that the disposition manifested toward said child by its mother aforesaid </unclear>  her an improper person to have control of said child</p>

<p> Defts </unclear> that said Plffs are residents of the state of Oregon and have it in </unclear> and threaten to take the said minor child Etta Dora Cravens out of and beyond the jurisdiction of this court</p>

<p>Defts </unclear> that they are proper </unclear> to have the care control and custody of said child that they have no childrenof their own that they are willing able and anxious to keep and take care of rear and educate said child</p>

<p> that no demand has been made of them for the custody of said child</p>

<p> Wherefore Defts ask that said petition of Plfss be dismissed and the prayer thereofre be devoid and that said child be rewarded to the custody of these Defts and for </unclear> </p>

<p> W. A. George </p>
<p>N. T. Caten attrns for defts </p>


<p> Territory of Washington </p>
<p> County of Walla Walla</p>

<p> W H Barrett being first duly sworn says he is one of the defts above that he has heard the forgoing </unclear> had and <unkown> the </unkown> thereof that the <unclear> </unclear> as he </unclear> believes </p>
<p> W H Barrett</p>

<p> Subscribed &amp; sworn to before and this before June 30th 1871</p>
<p> W S </unclear> </p>
<p> Notary Publis </p>