<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>In the district court of the third judicial district of Washington Territory holding terms at Seattle.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of Alice McKay to obtain the body of Mary McKay} No. 5662.</p>

<p>Testimony offered on behalf of the Respondent.</p>

<p>Mrs. DELLA KEEVIN, called and sworn.</p>

<p>Q. [Gilman] Mrs. Keevin, you are one of the Respondents in this case, that is you have been ordered to bring this child into court. have you?  A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. This is the child referred to in the petition, Mary McKay or Mary Keevin?</p>

<p>A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. How long has this child been living with you?  A. Five years and three months.</p>

<p>Q. Go on and state to the judge Mrs. Keevin how the child has come to you, under what circumstances you got her?  A. There was a lady living next door to me, Mrs. Latimer, and told me that there was a child to be adopted at the sisters. so I went up to Sister Sebastine. I asked her if there was a child to be adopted. Yes, she said that there was a little girl that her mother came and asked them to take care of her: that she was left at the door. The mother told her to give it to a family.</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: We object.</p>

<p>The COURT: I will hear the lady's story.</p>

<p>A. She told me, the mother told her to give it to some good family. That she could keep her. I said I will take her. They sent and looked for the mother arounbd town. They cold not get her. They gave me the child, and I took her home. We were to take papers. She says this is my child, and she says I will bring the papers.</p>

<p>Q. Who came to you? A. Mrs. McKay?</p>

<p>Q. What did she say to you? A. She told me that she would bring the papers a week from that Wednesday.</p>

<p>Q. What did she mean by bringing the papers? A. That she would have them settled and left at the sisters. With Sister Sebastine, that she did all her business. I went down to the sisters at the time, and there was no papers, and the woman did not come near me I guess it might have been seven or eight or nine months.</p>

<p>Q. Now at the time she came to you and told you she would give papers, did she say anything about whether or not she was willing for you to keep it as your own?</p>

<p>A. She said she was gald the child was with me because it would have a good home. She told me all her troubles about home and her husband.</p>

<p>Q. What did she tell you about them?</p>

<p>RONALD: We object to that as immaterial. This is five years ago. Now, if your Honor please, this writ of habeas corpus for the custody of the child -- they have a right if they can show this woman at the present time is unqualified, improper and morally incompetent woman. Now as to this woman five years ago, what she said to Mrs. Keevin about her home and her husband or her home, we submit in all fairness if your Honor please. It is incompetent, irrelevant and immaterial and nothing to do in this case whatever.</p>

<p>The COURT: I propose to hear this whole story, you can take your exceptions as you need them.</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: We will take an exception.</p>

<p>A. I did not know who the woman was at all, if I had I would not have had the trouble. She was sick and was crippled [referring to the little girl] She could

<fw>[Mrs. Keevin, D-EX. <gap></gap> 1. M<gap></gap> 73--23.</fw>
<pb...></pb...>

could not stand up. I nursed her and everything, and I thought it a pity that the child should go back to this woman.</p>

<p>The COURT: Aske the question again. She has not answered it.</p>

<p>Q. What did she say about her home and her life at that time? A. She told me she did not know what kind of man he was, that he was married in the old country and had three children.</p>

<p>Q. When did you next see Mrs. McKay? A. She might have come twice a year. She was quite contented with the child being where she was. She has seen her every time until the last time, I said no you cannot see her. She said she did not want to see her. It is the childs own fault she gets nervous.</p>

<p>Q. Did she ever demand possession of the child of you before? A. She would say in a kind of a way, I dont know whether she would mean it or not. One time she said I will have the child when I cannot come to see her. I will have the child in the court. I thought it was all right. I did not think I would have any trouble again.</p>

<p>Q. Did she ever bring the child into court before? A. I had her here about three years ago I think.</p>

<p>Q. Now, Mrs. Keevin, has the mother during that time provided any support for the child? A. She has never given her two cents, she has giver her a dollar once to my knowledge.</p>

<p>Q. Has she ever offered to? A. No, never.</p>

<p>Q. How have you treated this child since the time you took her? A. I could not tell the difference between her and mine.</p>

<p>Q. Have you any children of your own? A. Not living.</p>

<p>Q. You had a child die about the time you adopted this one? A. Yes, it was for her place I took her.</p>

<p>Q. Has she been with you continuously since that time? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. What are you doing toward educating the child, Mrs. Keevin? A. Doing all I can for her education.</p>

<p>Q. Does she go to school? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Where does she go to school? She goes to the school below our house, in Denny's school house.</p>

<p>Q. At the public schools? A. Yes Sir.</p>

<p>Q. In Seattle? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Did you ever notice Mrs. McKay's condition as regards sobriety when she would come to see the child? A. I always thought she was more or less under the influence of liquor. She knew it. I would turn pale and faint when she would

<fw>[Mrs. Keevin, D-EX. <gap></gap> 2. <gap></gap> 76 -- 29.</fw>
<pb...></pb...>

come to the door.</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: We move to strike the answer out.</p>

<p>The COURT: Motion overruled and exception allowed.</p>

<p>A. I know the smell of liquor on her breath.</p>

<p>Q. You could smell the liquor on her breath? A. Yes.</p>

<p>Q. What are your feelings toward this child, Mrs. Keevin?</p>

<p>A. My feelings are as a natural mother. If I was her mother I could say nothing more.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know of your own knowledge anything about Mrs. McKay's character other than what you have <del>heard</del> said that she was a drinking woman? A. I know nothing else except reports.</p>

<p>Q. Is it your desire to still retain the child and keep it and train it up? A. Yes sir. It would be tearing my heart out to take it away from me. now.</p>

<p>Q. What is your husband's ability financially? A. He works at plastering.</p>

<p>Q. Has he any property? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Where is it? A. We have a good home in Belltown.</p>

<p>Q. You have your home, do you? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Has he employment all the time? A. When it is scarce he works at other things.</p>

<p>GILMAN: Take the Witness.</p>

<p>CROSS-EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>Q. [Ronald:] Mrs. Keevin, how long did you have this child before Mrs. McKay came there and told you she would give papers? A. I had it about a week and a half.</p>

<p>Q. And you now swear on your oath Mrs. Keevin that Mrs. McKay told you she would give you papers? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Is it not a fact that you asked for papers and she told you she would not give them? A. She told me she would leave <sic>theg</sic> at the Sisters, or Sister Sebastine, that Sister Sebastine done her business.</p>

<p>Q. So you went to the Sisters two or three times to try and have the sisters endeavor to influence Mrs. McKay to give you papers? A. I went there to see if she had left them there. The Sisters said she would not tell the truth.</p>

<p>Q. You did not go there to try to influence Mrs. McKay? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You say you kept the child for a couple of years without objection c from Mrs. McKay, is that true Mrs. Keevin? A. It was a long time before she came around after she told me she would give the papers. The child was sick and weak and my heart went to her. I could not part with her.</p>

<p>Q. Dont you suppose her heart went to her? A. She could not--</p>

<p>Q. You dont know only what you heard. A. The sisters nursed her for nine nights.</p>

<fw>[Mrs. Keevin, C-EX. <gap></gap> 3. <gap></gap> 76--36.</fw>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>Q. Do you know anything about leaving this child at the door except what you heard? A. The sisters, sister Sebastine--</p>

<p>Q. [Interrupting] Do you know she left it at the door? A. I dont know anything at all about it.</p>

<p>Q. All you know is what some one told you about leaving it at the door? A. It was proved in the court before.</p>

<p>Q. Is that all you know about it, just what somebody told you about leaving it at the door? A. It was left at the Sisters.</p>

<p>Q. You swear that she brought it at the door step of your own knowledge? A. I wont swear any such thing.</p>

<p>Q. All you know then ---</p>

STOPPED AT PAGE 21 IN DOC kng 5662