<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0064.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Alexander S. Hughes Et Al v. Lewis V. Wycoff. Civil</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie R." xml:id="nrl">Natalie R. Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0064.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Alexander S. Hughes Et Al v. Lewis V. Wycoff. Civil</title>
<date when="1875-05-14">May 14 1875</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1875-05"></date>May 1875</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Sunth D.S.</term>
<term>Gellerson Josiah</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County Washington </term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hughes David, Hughes Alexander S, Brannan Joseph, Boyd James, and Hart David</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Wycoff Lewis V.(Territory of Washington)</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Last, First</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Last, First</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>J.R. Lewis</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#KA">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2018-06" who="#NRL">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0064.001.001"/>

<p></p>

<p> In the District Court of the 3rd Judicial District of Washington Territory holding terms at Seattle in and for the counties of King Kitsap and Snohomish </p>

<p> In the matter of the application of David Hughes Alexander S Hughes, Joseph Brannan James Boyd and David Hart, for a writ of Habeas Corpus against Lewis V. Wycoff, Sheriff of King County Washington Territory</p>

<p> To the Hon.  J.R. Lewis Judge of the District Court of the 3rd Judicial District of Washington Territory holding terms at Seattle </p>

<p> The petition of Alexander S Hughes David Hughes Joseph Brannan James Boyd and David Hart respectfully show </p>

<p> That they your said petitioners are unlawfully imprsoned, detained, and restrained of their liberty by Lewis V. Wycoff Sheriff of King County Washington Territory at the county jail of said County in the city of Seattle in the Territory of Washington </p>

<p> That according to the best of the knowledge and belief of your petitioners the cause or pretense of said restraint is that an order was made on the 14th of May 1875 by one D.S. Sunth as Justice of the Peace in and for Seattle Precinct in said County of King, which said order has been served on your petitioners and requires Alexander Hughes to recognize to keep the peace towards one Josiah Gellerson on all of the people of said Territory for and during the term of six months now next <unclear> ensuring </unclear>, in the sum of $500 and the other petitioners in the sum of $300 each to the same end , and to pay the costs of said proceeding equally . and to stand committed in said County Jail until said recognizance are given and costs paid an indefinite period of time, </p>

<p> Your petitioners say that said imprisonment is illegal in this . that your petitioners are sentenced to prison for an indefinite period of time. </p>

<p> Your petitioners further say that they nor neither of them have at any time threatened to commit an offense against the person or property of Josiah Gellerson or any other person </p>

<p> David Hughes Alexander S. Hughes Joseph Brannon James Boyd David Hart</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>