<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<note>#135</note>

<p>In The DISTRICT COURT of the SECOND JUDICIAL DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON TERRITORY, Holding Terms at Montesano, in, and for the County of Chehalis.</p>

<p>The TERRITORY of WASHINGTON, PLAINTIFF. vs. Leander Brown DEFENDANT. ) INDICTMENT.</p>

<p>We Leander Brown as Principal, and Charles H Byles and T.H. Shamley as Sureties, acknowledge ourselves to owe and be indebted to the Territory of Washington, in the just and full sum of Four Hundred Dollars, lawful money of the United States of America, to be levied of our Goods and Chattels, Lands and Tenements, upon the following conditions:</p>

<p>WHEREAS, The said Leander Brown has been duly indicted by the Grand Jury of Chehalis County, in the Second Judicial District of Washington Territory, for he following crimes <del>of</del> to wit, on three separate indictment, one for riot, and two for malicious mischief, in said County, and is now under arrest upon <del>a</del> warrants duly issued upon each of said indictments</p>

<p>Now, therefore, it the said Leander Brown shall be and appear in his proper person at the next regular term of said Court, to be holden in and for said Chehalis County, and from term to term thereafter, and answer the above mentioned indictments and shall obey all orders and processes of said Court, made and issued in that behalf, and shall keep the peace and be of good behavior toward all the people of Washington Territory, then this recognizance to be void, otherwise to remain in full force and virtue.</p>

<p>Witness and approved by me this 19th day of October A.D. 1887 WH Bush Sheriff.</p>

<p>Lender Brown Charles N Byles T J Shernley</p>

<p>TERRITORY OF WASHINGTON, County of Chehalis }SS.</p>

<p><gap></gap> and <gap></gap> being first duly sworn, each for himself, say, that he is a resident of Washington Territory; that he is not a counselor, attorney-at-law, sheriff, clerk or other officer of the District Court, and that he is worth the sum of <gap></gap> Dollars, over and above all debts and liabilities, and property exempt from execution.</p>

<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this <gap></gap> day of <gap></gap> A.D. 188 <gap></gap> Sheriff.</p>
