<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p> vs. </p>
<p> Barett </p>

<p> Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p> Motion to <unclear></unclear>. </p>

<p> On the <unclear></unclear> of the writ in this case before the Judge the defendants <unclear></unclear> his plea of former adjudications </p>

<p> The plea was held good and the writ discharged </p>

<p> In taxing the cost the defendants included therein Attorneys for                   $10.50</p>

<p> The plaintiff <unclear></unclear> filed his <unclear></unclear> to stike this <unclear></unclear> fierce the bill</p>

<p> <unclear> sec</unclear> 459 provides "that case shall be allowed to the party in whose forever a judgment is rendered <unclear> excepting </unclear></p>

<p> <unclear> sec </unclear> 467 when allowed to either party, case to be called the Attorney <unclear></unclear> shall be as follows. </p>

<p> In all actions <unclear></unclear>

It would seem that it will <unclear></unclear> by the <unclear></unclear> that case should be allwed only in <unclear> actions </unclear> but looking at <unclear> sec </unclear> 458-464-465 <unclear></unclear> may reach the conclusion that cases shall be allowed to the party in whose favor a judgement is rendered and that the prevailing party shall be allowed for all necessary disbersments <unclear></unclear> free of affairs <unclear></unclear> fees <unclear></unclear> </p>

<p> The disbersments shall be <unclear></unclear> in detail <unclear></unclear> by <unclear></unclear> and filed. </p>

<p> <unclear></unclear> it is clear that the Atty for is no part of these disbersments. for the statue declares that these disbersments are to be allowed in addition to the allowance as provided in <unclear> sec </unclear> 464. </p>

<p> There may be and is some question as to what was intended by the provisions 

of section 404. The words are "when allowed to either party" vs. the Attorney fee in all actions shall be $5 </p>

<p> If <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear> this to mean this to wit; where <unclear></unclear> are allowed to either party vs that <unclear> sec </unclear> 458 is of no effect because that section declares that costs shall be allowed to the party in whose favor a judgement is rendered $5 </p>

<p> Would it not be the <unclear></unclear> reasonable <unclear></unclear> to render the <unclear></unclear> <unclear></unclear> this </p>

<p> 458 costs shall be allowed to the party in whose favor a judgement is rendered </p>

<p> 464 and when attorneys fees are allowed to either party the fee shall be $5 </p>

<p> 465 and the prevailing party shall be allowed his necessary disbersments in addition to this Attys fee these disbersments shall include the officers cost $5 </p>

<p> This said of the law would leave it in the <unclear></unclear> of the court to allow Attys fee or not in the <unclear> obscure </unclear> of special <unclear></unclear> </p>

<p> But <unclear> sec </unclear> 477 <unclear></unclear> that in all actions and proceedings other than those <unclear></unclear> when no <unclear></unclear> is made. Costs may be allowed or not and if allowed may be opporutioned in the discretion of the court </p>

<p> As a ground rule <strike></strike> Attys fees are not part of the costs in any case. </p>

<p> It is only by reason of the statute that they are taxable in any case and hence a party <unclear></unclear> entitled thereto <unclear></unclear> being himself <unclear></unclear> the provisions of such statute </p>

<p> I am of opinion that <unclear></unclear> 464 is applicable to the trial is <unclear></unclear> in open court. <unclear> of herein </unclear>

and that by section 477 it is in the discretion of this court to allow or not allow costs in all proceedings in <unclear></unclear> and in the exercise of this discretion. I am not of opinion that this is such a proceeding as will warrant me in requiring the Plaintiff to pay a counsel fee to the Defendant in addition to the other costs. </p>

<p> the <unclear></unclear> will be sustained </p>

<p> JR Suirs </p>
<p> Judge </p>