<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>In the U.S. District Court holding terms at Olympia. In the matter of the petition of Willaim Jones, William H. Doyle, Fred Williams and Afred Woods for a writ of habeas corpus.</p>

<p>To the Hon. John P. Hoyt</p>

<p>Associate Justice of the Supreme Court and Judge 2nd District.</p>

<p>Your petitioners above named most respectfully show to your Honor that they and each of them are illegally restrained of their and each of their liberty. That they and each of them are now and have been since on or about the 12th day of Feby 1885 confined in the Pententiary situated on McNeils Island in Pierce County Washington Territory in the custody of one Jesse W. George United States Marshall of said Territory.</p>

<p>And your petetioners further show that such confinement is by virtue of a committment issudeby Eben Smith U.S. Commissioner in and for the 3rd District of Washington Territory a copy of which is hereunto annexed and made a part hereof, together with a copy of complaint upon which said commission acted which is also made a part hereof.</p>

<p>That at the date and before the said commissioner had ordered your and each of your petetioners to be committed to the custody of said U.S. Marshall asin the commitment recited, your and each of your petetioners offered to enter into their and each of their personal recognisance for their and each of their appearance at the next term of the District Court holding terms at Seattle and are now ready to do so, but they and each of them are too poor to give other sureties than their personal recognisance and can not give secureity as required</p>

<p>That said Commissioner refused to accept said

<pb...></pb...>

offer and thereupon made the order recited in <del>said</del> the annexed Commitment. That they and each of them are Citizens of the United States and of the Territory of Washington. That they and each of them were not and are not now charged with having committed any crime or violated any of the laws of the United States before said Commissioner.</p>

<p>That they were not committed by virtue of any final judgment or decree of any court in the United States. That your petitioners are advised by their counsel and believe that they and each of them are illegally confined in said Pententiary and unjustly deprived of their and each of their liberty, and that such illegality consists in this to wit:</p>

<p>1st: That said Commissioner had no authroity by law to commit your petitioners or any one of them.</p>

<p>2nd: For the reason that they and each of them <del>ever</del> were not and are not charged with <del></del> the violation of any law or accused of any crime before said Commissioner.</p>

<p>3rd: That no warrant of arrest against any one of your petetioners was ever issued by said Commissioner.</p>

<p>4th: That your and each of your petetioners have been and are deprived of their and each of their liberty without due process of law.</p>

<p>Wherefore your petetioners pray that a writ of Habeas Corpus may be granted, directed to the said Jesse W. George U.S. Marshall in whose custodywe and each of us are, commanding him to have the bodies of each and <del>any</del> every of your petetioners before your Honor at a time and place therein to be named, to do and receive what shall then and there be ordered by your Honor</p>

<pb...></pb...>

<p>and with time and cause of our and each of our detention, to the end that we and each of us may be restored to liberty.</p>


stopped pg 17