<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p> Territory of Washington</p>
<p> County of Walla Walla</p>

<p> In the District Court of the first Judicial District <unclear><unclear> Kennedy Judge <unclear> at  </unclear> </p>

<p>Charles Gahres and Martha J. Gahres, Guardians of Etty Dora Cravens a minor Plffs </p>
<p> vs. </p>
<p> Isabella Sutton and W. H. Barrettt Defts</p>

<p> Charles Gahres and Marth J. Gahres (formally Martha J. Cranens) the <unclear>  and <unclear> <unclear> </unclear> for complaint against Isabella Sutton and W. H. Barrett the <unclear> and <unclear> <unclear> </unclear>allege that they <unclear> are the parents and maternal and lawful guardians of Etty Dora Cravens a minor child of the age of five years that <unclear> child is the child of one of Martha J. <unclear> <unclear> a family marriage with one W. H. Cranen that in <unclear> 1869 <unclear> marriage <unclear> used and <unclear> with child <unclear> <unclear> afterwords as a <unclear> of <unclear> Court of the 5th Judicial District of Oregon on <unclear> <unclear> <unclear> <unclear> the <unclear> in of said marriage <unclear> <unclear> Cravens the void <unclear> (to <unclear> Martha J. Gahres) has intermarried with the other <unclear> <unclear> and they <unclear> are now an </unclear> the guardians of said minor child and entitledto the sole custody of said child.</p>

<p> That the said minor child of those <unclear> <unclear>said Etty Dora Cravens is wrongfully and unlawfully detained and <unclear> of her liberty by the said Defendants Isabella Sutton and W. H. Barrett at the <unclear> <unclear> <unclear> </unclear> County of WallaWalla and Territory of Washington</p>

<p> That the <unclear> of said merchant of said minor child by <unclear> <unclear> in according to the best knowledge and <unclear> of those <unclear> an arbitrary determination on the part of <unclear> to keep said child <unclear> any <unclear>right whatever to the custody </unclear> </p>

<p>That said <unclear> and <unclear> said minor child is illegal and that the illegality <unclear> <unclear> in the <unclear> the custody of said child from those <unclear> who are the lawful guardians of said minor and or such entitled </unclear> </p>

<p> Wherefore <unclear> or guardians of said minor <unclear>thats a writ of Habeas Corpus <unclear> <unclear> directed to said Isabella Sutton and W. H. Barrett commanded them to have the body of said minor child Etty Dora Cravens before the Honorable Judge of the Court at a time and place to be specified by said Judge and then and there to do and <unclear> who shall these and there be <unclear> by said Honorable Judge- Concerning said minor child <unclear> with the terms and course of her detention and said <unclear> and that said minor child may be <unclear> to the custody of <unclear> </unclear> and for <unclear> of said</p>
<p> Charles Gahres </p>
<p> Martha J. Gahres </p>
<p> Plaintiffs</p>


<p> Territory of Washington </p>
<p> County of Walla Walla </p>

<p> Charles Gahres being first duly sworn says he is one of the <unclear> in the <unclear> <unclear> and knows the conduct there of and that the same is true of his own knowledge exept on to matters </unclear> stated on information and belief and on to those matters he believes it true </p>
<p> Charles Gahres </p>

<p> <unclear> and <unclear> before the <unclear> 7th day of </unclear> </p> 
<p> <unclear> P <unclear> <unclear> </unclear> </p>