<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>As I See It</head>
<byline>By A.K. Yerkes</byline>
<p>As one who knew the late James Hamilton Lewis while he was a resident of Seattle, I have always regarded the story which definitely linked him with a stevedore job on our waterfront, as a fictitious as well as a fanciful bit of ballyhoo. Senator Lewis was altogether unfitted by nature for a job which requires a strong back, and as long as I knew him, not once was he clothed in the garb of one about to move the lawn, or work on the flower beds. In the first, place he had a small frame, of slight build in fact, and was in no way inclined to engage in any form of strenuous exercise. It may be possible that Lewis cultivated the friendship of the dock workers, and was often seen on the waterfront, which in his day, especially during the Klondike rush, was the scene of untiring activity, day and night. Perhaps, too, he was occasionally called there to to make a speech, in time of political stress. It may be true that before my day in Seattle, Jim Ham had taken a clerical job on the wharf, but that he used a hook and took part in the job of loading and unloading a vessel, in those days when machinery was not so much in evidence for this purpose, is hardly within the bounds of reason. However, the myth strengthened Lewis' hold on the working-men's vote.</p>
<p>Many of the numerous stories now being printed relative to Lewis' life in Seattle are somewhat exaggerated, and some without any foundation whatsoever. One, however, which gave Lewis much uneasiness, and even aroused his indignation, has so far failed to find its way into print. In the eyar 1900, with a hot political campaign in the offing, a young man of Lewis's stature and cast of countenance, issued from a logging camp with a prolonged growth of whiskers. He attracted as much attention on Second Avenue as did Lewis himself; indeed, there were those who actually believed that Lewis was masquerading. A bright young lawyer who, by the way, was himself a party associate, but strongly aligned against Lewis, became possessed of a novel idea. He would rig this young lumberjack with clothes so nearly like those which Lewis wore&#8212;cutaway, striped trousers, white spats&#8212;then instruct the imitator in the manner of Lewis' Chesterfieldian manifestations and turn him loose on the street as the dude's twin brother. The make-believe Lewis was an apt pupil, and for almost a week, bowed his way up and down First and Second Avenues, from Lou Cohn's cigar store to Pike Street. It was a joke that cost the perpetrator much more than was intended, for it was carried too far. Friends finally protested and denounced the jocular public display as despicable. It was noticed at the time that the real Lewis was conspicuous by his absence, on the streets. And those of his intimates who called to express their disgust over the affair, found that this was one instance when J. Ham's dignity was sorely hurt.</p>
<p>As owner of the <hi rend="italics">Ballard News</hi>, I occasionally referred to Mr. Lewis editorially, sometimes in a manner which might have annoyed one tender to the touch. Imagine my suprise when I met him face to face at the old Rainier-Grand hotel, to have him approach with extended hand, and express his great pleasure at the opportunity to inform me personally that he read every work of editorial comment in my paper; in fact, regarded the paper as among the best in this part of the state. Of course, I was rather pleased and said so, even though I had learned from an intimate friend of Lewis' that J. Ham read but few newspapers, and certainly not my rather obscure sheet published at Ballard. However, praise from James Hamilton Lewis had a dulcet appeal. He did it so nicely, elegantly and completely: so much like Sir Rupert form whom praise was praise indeed. And, when all is said of James Hamilton Lewis, it must be acknowledged that he was the prefect gentleman; the last of those chivalrous and imposing statesmen of the U.S. Senate, whose pictures still adorn the pages of history.</p>