<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

The Stroller
---
For a long time The Stroller has been waiting for J. Willis Sayre to write a book or otherwise stick his neck out to give me a chance to catch him up on a slip of the pen or other inaccuracy. He's always right on the job with a Bronx cheer when we pull a boner and it would be fun to give him some of his own medicine. Well, he's written the book&#8212;<hi rend="italics">This City of Ours</hi>&#8212;and I searched its pages in vain for some error I could pounce on. They may be there, but I couldn't find one. Nor, incidentally, could I find any mention of The Argus, for which Mr. Sayre was dramatic editor for several years.

Anyhow, <hi rend="italics">This City of Ours</hi> provided The Stroller with a couple of hours of good entertainment and it is hereby recommended for your reading list. You'll learn things you never suspected about your town. It's chock full of believe-it-or-nots. For instance, time was when sea-gulls walked on the snow covered surface of Elliott Bay. Flying fish have been seen in the same waters. A bucket of water started the fire that destroyed the city in 1889. A train of freight cars lies in Lake Washington off Madison Park and a sailing vessel lies intact under Western Avenue. There was a time when you could travel from Seattle to Auburn by steamer. These and other strange things will be found in Mr. Sayre's book, which, by the way, was written as a text book for Seattle schools.
---
Mr. Sayre's reference to the first long distance telephone line between Seattle and Spokane recalls a story that was printed in thsi column some forty years ago&#8212;not, however, the work of the present Stroller, who was then much more interested in nursing bottles than columns. Here's the story, as it appeared in The Argus of September 5, 1896. Stop me if you've heard it:

It was during J.T. Ronald's term as mayor that the long distance line between this city and Spokane was opened up. The telephone company invited Mayor Ronald to send the first message&#8212;to the major of Spokane. Quite a little party gathered at this end of the line. When the proper time came Mayor Ronald grasped the ear piece and sent a "hello" over that wire that for force and power never has been and never will be equalled.

There was no answer and the major was about to repeat the dose when the general manager edged up and, catching the mayor by the coat, remarked in a low tone, "Much obliged, old man. They could hear that anyhow, but there really is a wire there and you won't have to speak so loudly."
---
And while we are on the subject of the dean of the King County superior bench, here's another one from The Stroller column of 1896: In 1888 Mr. Ronald went to Bothell to address a Democratic meeting. Now it happened that at that time there was not a Democrat in the whole town of Bothell. When it came time to address the meeting Mr. Ronald mounted the platform. A large audience had gathered, but there was no chairman.

"Ladies and gentlemen," said Mr. Ronald, stepping to the front of the platform, "it is necessary to have a chairman for this meeting...I know of one good Democrat who is in the house, and I nominate him. His name is J. T. Ronald." After the question had been carried the speaker commenced:

"Now, ladies and gentlemen, as chairman of this meeting it becomes my duty to present the speaker of the evening. The Democratic county committee have prepared a rare treat for this assemblage. They have sent here a speaker who stands without peer on the stump of the state of Washington&#8212;I can almost say the nation; a man who is both able and conscientious; a man who is thoroughly posted on the issues of the day, and whose word is as good as his bond. Gentlemen, it falls to the lot of comparatively few men to hear as able a discussion of the issues of the campaign as you will hear tonight. Ladies and gentlemen, permit me to present to you that able speaker, that eminent lawyer and learned gentleman, J. T. Ronald of Seattle." When the applause subsided Mr. Ronald started his speech.
---
Still fiddling around with Vol. III of this paper, I find a Stroller story about Judge William Hickman Moore (now deputy prosecuting attorney). He had recently been elected superior court judge to succeed Samuel J. Humes but had notyet taken office when this appeared in December, 1896. Incidentally both judges later became mayor of Seattle. Here's the story:

Judge-elect Moore dropped into Judge Humes' chambers a while ago and found that gentleman busily engaged in packing his library and effects, prepatory to moving downtown.

"Aren't you a little premature, Judge?" asked Mr. Moore. "You know some of us new judges may not qualify."

"There may be some doubt about your qualifying," said Judge Humes, as he paused in his task of trying to crowd a copy of Blackstone into his fish creel, "but I'll bet my library against a counterfeit dollar bill that you'll take the oath of office."
---
Back in those days Seattle's James Hamilton Lewis (now Chicago's) furnished more newspaper copy and Stroller material than any other man in the state. But The Stroller of 1897 had never heard of Marion Zioncheck when he wrote:

Col. Lewis is attracting more attention in the East than any member of either house of Congress who has ever gone to Washington from this state.
-The Stroller