<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

As I See It
By A. K. Yeekes

The strategy of handling people is something <unclear/> should all endeavor to acquire, but there are only <unclear>a</unclear> few who make the effort. Ben Franklin was a <unclear/> summate diplomat in his contact with his <unlcear/> men. he never lost an opportunity to make a <unclear>friend</unclear> and a customer, even the arisocrats of Philadelphia where Franklin was classed with the plebeians <unclear/> reason of his lowly birth. Franklin took note of <unlcear/> personal interests of his fellow citizens and <unclear/> them accordingly: "How were their gardens coming along?" Would the gentleman lend him the <unclear>popular</unclear> book he possessed? Franklin talked about the <unclear/> his adversary was interested in.

Theodore Roosevelt made devoted followers by informing himself of their affairs and encouraging the <unclear/> to talk about themselves. Mark Hanna, no <unclear/> how hard he'd been blasted by a political opponent when he met that individual, there was never a <unclear/> of reproach from Hanna. "How is your <unclear>charming</unclear> sister?" "I met her several years ago and was <unclear>p?ly</unclear> impressed by her musical accomplishments." <unclear/> was Hanna's idea that "Molasses catches flies." <unclear>Then</unclear> there was President Taft, amiable and bulky, <unclear/> found the Pilipinos ill-humored and suspicious <unclear/> made them his warm friends by adopting some <unclear/> their customs, one being the Rigadon, which he <unclear/> night after night with dusky beauties. Elbert <unclear/> Gary always put a personal not in his business letter.

And our own J. Hamilton Lewis should not <unclear/> omitted in this catagory of statesmen who know <unclear/> to win friends and hold them by keeping in <unclear/> their habits and hobbies, the things they had <unclear/> hoped to do and their wants and needs. Like Theodore Roosevelt, when making his campaign <unclear/> Senator Lewis sometimes kept a local friend at <unclear/> to advise him as to the stranger's name and a <unclear/> characterization of the man he was about to <unclear/>. However, the congressman needed little <unclear/> he had an almost uncanny gift of recalling names <unclear>and</unclear> faces. He is a pastmaster in the art of making <unclear/> think well of themselves.

The last U.S. Senator Knute Nelson of Minnesota, while not profuse in his greetings, was nevertheless the most sympathetic and earnest of <unclear/> Years might elapse to an extent that would seem <unclear/> defy the Senator's gift of memory, but amazed, <unclear/> of course delighted, one would find himself addressed by his first name and eagerly questioned of his <unclear/> and his family's health. How was So-and-So getting along? The senator could recall the occassion <unclear/> the two last met and so on down the line of <unclear/> which the close friend of years before had <unclear/> been interested. There was a wide difference in friendliness of Nelson and the cold austerity of Senator Cushman Davis whom Nelson succeeded in <unclear/> Senate, after Nelson had served the great commonwealth of Minnesota as governor. "Cush" Davis, <unclear/> was known at home, was a brilliant and a big successful corporation lawyer, but he took little <unclear/> interest in the common run of humanity.

This phase of Davis' make-up was brought <unclear>for?</unclear> to my notice by a close-up instance happening <unclear/> I was traveling to Washington on a train that <unclear/> stalled by snow for two days and nights, about a <unclear>hundred</unclear> miles from the national capital. The dining <unclear/> had been sidetracked a few miles back, and except a few dozen eggs procured from a farm house, <unclear/> was nothing at all to eat. Senator Davis occupied private car of this particular train and not once <unclear>?ing</unclear> the time we were snowbound did he <unclear>evincee?</unclear> slightest interest in our plight. His car was stocked with food, warm and comfortable. He two colored men to administer to his wants. <unclear/> then, should he worry? It would have been <unclear>easy</unclear> him to have furnished hot coffee at least to the numbed and hungry passengers from the supplies <unclear/> his car, but he took no interest whatsoever <unclear>in?</unclear>

situation, except to express impatiently his displeasure at the delay. I mention this to indicate the wide difference in the characteristics of Davis and Nelson to vindicate my belief that great leaders show a respect for the other fellow, though it may not always be sincere. Few, if any of us, can resist the charm of those who raise our ego by respecting our special interests. Nelson's name will be cherished for many years to come. Cushman Davis has been utterly forgotten.