<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>The Wilson vs Wilson Case.</head>
<ab>Elizabeth D. Wilson, Pl'ff.
vs
Frederick A Wilson, Def't</ab>
<p>In the United States District Court for the 2d Judicial District, holding terms at Olympia, W.T. Action for divorce.</p>
<p>The plaintiff Elizabeth D. Wilson, a resident of Olympia, Thurston county, Washington Territory, complainted Frederick A. Wilson, a resident of Port Townsend in said Territory, defendant; and for cause of action alleges alleges as follows:</p>
<p>That, on or about the first of July, A.D. 1861, the plaintiff was duly married to the defendant on the Territory of Washington, adn that the plaintiff continued to live with the said defendant as his wife until about the 28th day of May, A.D. 1867. That, at the time of the said marriage the plaintiff and the said defendant were and now are inhabitants of this Territory. That during the time plaintiff lived and co-habited with the said defendant she had two children by him, now living, <unclear>to wit</unclear> Edward aged five years in August next and Frederick, aged about fifteen months; and that during all that time she conducted herself with propriety, managed the household affairs of her said husband with prudence and economy, and at all times treated her said husband with loving kindess and forhearance. That she has always demeaned herself as a good, faithful and virtuous wife, and labored to discharge her duties as a wife and mother in conformity with her marriage convenants. That the marital relation existing between the plaintiff and defendant have not been characterized by that love and affection which should exist between husband and wife; and that the defendant's conduct and deportment towards this plaintiff has been harsh and unkind, and wanting in all that kindly love and affection which should be manifested by a husband towards his wife. That the said defendant has repeatedly told this plaintiff that he did not have that love and affection for her which a husband should have for a wife.</p>
<p>That there is such an incompatibility of temper and disposition between the plaintiff and defendant as to render life burdensome, and makes it utterly impossible for them to live nad co-habit together happily as husband and wife. That in consequence of these things the married life of the plaintiff has been very unhappy for some years.</p>
<p>That the defendant has harshly and with great cruelty driven the plaintiff form his house and her home; and withdrawn from her care and control her two children, the issue of the said marriage, and this without any just or sufficient cause. That defendant took from her the small sum of money which she held in her possession and has after driving her from his home, neglected to make any provision for her support and maintenance; that she is poor, has no means of her own and is dependent upon her own efforts to make a living, except as she is aided and assisted by her mother with whom she now is in Olympia, in the said Territory. That the unkindeness, harshness and cruelty of the defendant, and the indignities which he has heaped upon her makes it utterly impossible for thme to live together, as husband and wife. That she has resided in the said Territory of Washington for more than one year before commencement of suit.</p>
<p>She therefore prays the Court to decree a dissolution of the marriage contract entered into between the said plaintiff and the said defendant; so that the bonds of matrimony entered into may be dissolved now and forever. She also prays the Court to order that the said defendant pay into the court a sum of money sufficient to support and maintain her during the pendency of of this suit, and to pay the expenses and disbursements together with counsel fees necessary to a prosecution of this suit&#8212;together with the costs. She also prays that the care, control and custody of the two minor children, Edward and Frederick, be be given to her. She also prays that she may be permitted to take her maiden-name, Elizabeth Dyer&#8212;and also for such other and further relief as may be just and equitable in the premises.</p>
<p>O.B. McFadden,
Att'y for plaintiff.</p>
----
<ab>Territory of Washington,}
County of Thurston.}
ss</ab>
<p>Before me a Notary Public in and for said Territory, personally came Elizabeth D. Wilson, who being first duly sworn, says that she is the Plaintiff in this cause, and that the facts set forth in the foregoing complaint are true of her own knowledge except as to matters stated on information, and as to those matters that she believes them to be true.</p>
<p>Elizabeth D. Wilson.</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 15th day of June, 1867.</p>
<p>O.B. McFadden,
Notary Public for W.T.</p>
----
<ab>Territory of Washington,}
County of Thurston.}
ss</ab>
<p>To Frederick A. Wilson:&#8212;You are hereby notified that unless you appear before the Hon. C. C. Hewitt, Chief Justice of Washington Territory and Judge of the 2d Judicial District, at Chambers in Olympia, W.T., on Friday the 18th day of July next, at one of the clock, P.M., this complaint will be taken as confessed and the prayer whereof granted.</p>
<p>O.B. McFadden,
Att'y for plaintiff.</p>
<p>[Sheriff's endorsement omitted for want of room.]</p>
----
<p>Answer&#8212;Filed July 13th, 1867.</p>
<p>Elizabeth D. Wilson, Plff,
vs.
Frederick A. Wilson, Deft.</p>
<p>Before the Hon. C. C. Hewitt, Judge of the U.S. District Court, 2d Judicial District, W.T., at Chambers in Olympia, July 19, 1867.</p>
<p>And now comes the defendant in this action by his counsel B.F. Dennison and S. Garfielde, and makes answer to the complaint of the plaintiff as follows:</p>
<p>1st, He admits that plaintiff was duly married to the defendant on or about the 1st day of July, 1861. And alleges that they lived together happily as husband and wife from that time until the plaintiff made the acquatinance and received the atttentions of the man hereafter mentioned.</p>
<p>2nd. The defendant also admits that they continued to live and co-habit together until on or about the 5th day of May 1867, at which time cohabitation ceased, and has never been resumed; but he <unclear>derives?</unclear> that during the last eight or ten months of said time the plaintiff conducted herself with property, and treated her said husband with loving kindness and forbearance, and denies that plaintiff demeaned herself as a good, faithful and virtuous wife, or that she labored to discharge the duties of a wife and mother in conformity with her marriage covenant.</p>
<p>The defendant also denies the allegation that his conduct or deportment towards the plaintiff has been harsh and unkind and wanting in all that unkindly love and affection that should be manifested by a husband towards his wife. And denies that he has repeatedly, or at any time told the plaintiff that he did not have that love and affection for her, which a husband should have for his wife.</p>
<p>That as to each and every other allegation in the complaint imputing to the defendant unkind, improper or unwarantable conduct towards the plaintiff, he denies the same.</p>
<p>And the defendant alleges that, during all the time since the marriage, until the facts and circumstances hereinafter set forth came to his knowledge, he has not only treated the plaintiff with kindess and attention, but has generously provided for her maintenance, comfort and happiness; and that until recently the plaintiff has invariably spoken of the defendant among her neighbors and acquaintances as a good, kind and dutiful husband as a woman could wish to have.</p>
<p>That the money alleged to have been taken from plaintiff by defendant was the sum of about $500, which he had furnished ot her upon the <unclear>reprecatauon?</unclear> that she wished to make a visit to her friends in San Francisco, and was taken from her after she had abandoned the idea of making said visit, and resolved upon the project hereinafter stated. And the defendant further alleges that the present alienation and distresses of the plaintiff are wholly attributable to causes other than those specified in the complaint.</p>
<p>3rd. The defendant further alleges that sometime in the month of July, A.D., 1866, the plaintiff formed the acquaintance of Charles B. Darwin, the trusted friend and guest of the defendant, at his house, and soon after as the defendant is now informed and believes, and so alleges, commenced receiving the attentions and addresses of the said Charles B. Darwin as a lover.</p>
<p>That these attentions and addresses continued to be received and bestowed from that time on to the present; and consisted in private interviews and correspondence, exchanging and reading novels and other books, with the more affecting passages marked&#8212;rambling through the woods together gathering flowers and other "Quidities" together with the usual amount of billing and cooing and kissing characteristic of young lovers.</p>
<p>That this course of conduct was so artfully carried on as not to awaken in the mind of the defendant any suspicions of improper intimacy until about the 1st or 2nd of May last, at which time the plaintiff boldly revealed to the defendant and others the following facts:</p>
<p>That a new-born love existed and was reciprocal between herself and Charles B. Darwin, which had supplanted her affections for the defendant, and must put an end to their matrimonial relations.</p>
<p>That her new lover had suggested and was then completing arrangements by which the plaintiff was to obtain a divorce from the defendant, and he Darwin, a divorce from his wife then in the State of Iowa.</p>
<p>That when this was accomplished, the said Charles B. Darwin was to marry the plaintiff and take her and her mother to Burlington or Des Moines in Iowa as their place of residence.</p>
<p>That for the purpose of speedily consummating this arangment the plaintiff insisted upon immediately leaving leaving the defendant's house, stating as a reason for thus divulging these plans, that she desired to obtain a divorce quietly, before the Judge at chambers, and without any opposition on the part of the defendant.</p>
<p>After this disclosure had been made, desiring to avoid public scandal, and hoping to reclaim the plaintiff from this infatuation and its consequences to herself and family circle, the defendant continued to live in the same house with the plaintiff, and made efforts to change her resolution, until the 28th day of May, 1867, when it became apparent that the arts of a paramour had triumphed over a husband's love, and a separation was inevitable, which accordingly took place. But defendant denies that he "harshly" and with "great cruelty" drove the plaintiff from his house, as alleged in the complaint.</p>
<p>4th. And for further answer and defense in bar of the plaintiff's suit. The defendant alleges, that since the said 28th day of May last, he has been informed and believes and so charges the truth to be, that the plaintiff during the last eight or ten months has committed adultery at divers times and places, and espeically, that the plaintiff on some day in the month of March last, did commit adultery adn have carnal connection with the said Charles B. Darwin, at the house of this defendant, in the County of Jefferson, W.T., and that the said plaintiff at various other times during the last two months past has committed adultery and had carnal connection with the said Charles B. Darwin. That the defendant has not cohabited with the plaintiff since the fact of adultery came to his knowledge.</p>
<p>Wherefore the defendant prays that a decree of divorce may be refused, and the custody of the children, and the rights of the parties to this suit may be allowed to remain as they now are.</p>
<p>And further, that no allowance may be made to plaintiff on account of this suit or otherwise.</p>
<p>B.F. Dennison &amp;
S. Garfielde,
Att'ys for defendant.</p>
<ab>Territory of Washington,}
County of Jefferson.}</ab>
<p>Frederick A. Wilson makes oath and says that he is the defendant in the above action, that the foregoing answer is true except as to matters stated on information and as to those matters, he beheves them true.</p>
<p>F. A. Wilson.</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me, this 1st day of July, 1867.</p>
<p>J. H. VanBokkelen,
Notary Public.</p>
----
<ab>Affidavit for Change of Venue&#8212;Filed
July 13, 1867.</ab>
<p>Elizabeth D. Wilson,
vs.
F. A. Wilson.</p>
<p>Suit for Divorce pending in Thurston county before Hon. C. C. Hewitt, Judge 2d Judicial District, Washington Territory.</p>
<p>1. Elizabeth D. Wilson, the plaintiff prays change of venue in this case to the Judge of the 1st Judicial District, sitting in Chambers&#8212;or to the term of Walla Walla, next ensuing, as your honor may direct. And I pray said change because I believe your honor is so prejudiced against me that I cannot obtain justice before you also that a fair trail cannot be had in this District by reason of a disqualification grounded in your prejudice in favor of the culpability of Mr. C. B. Darwin with me, which culpability will, as I am advised constitute to a considerable degree a question qualifying my rights in thsi controversy and these beliefs I have come to entertain since I commenced my suit.</p>
<p>(Signed) Elizabeth D. Wilson.</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 10th day of July A.D. 1867.</p>
<p>James Seavey,
Clerk U.S. Dist. Court, 3d District of W.T., holding terms at Port Townsend</p>
<p>On the back of said affidavit is the following endorsement:</p>
<p>"Change of venue granted as per stipulation on file."</p>
<p>C. C. Hewitt, Judge.</p>
---
<head>Decree of Judge Wyche.</head>
<ab>Elizabeth D. Wilson}
vs} Decree
F. A. Wilson.}</ab>
<p>The plaintiff in this case asks a divorce on the grounds that the defendant's conduct and deportment towards her has been harsh and unkind, and wanting in that kindly love and affection which should be manifested by a husband towards his wife and that there is such an incompatibility of temper and disposition between the parties as to render life burdensome and make it utterly impossible for them to live and cohabit together as husband and wife.</p>
<p>The defendant, answering, denies these several allegations, and charges that the want of affection of his wife and the estrangement between them is attributable to the acquaintance of the plaintiff with Chas B. Darwin, with whom an intimate acquaintance grew up, culminating in mutual esteem and love, and finally adultery between the parties, and prays the Court, therefore, that the divorce here asked be denied. Upon this state of case the Court finds the following facts and conclusions of law, viz.:</p>
<p>1st. That the plaintiff failed to establish the allegations in her complaint.</p>
<p>2d. That the defendant has failed to establish the charge of adultery.</p>
<p>3d. That the defendant has established the existence of an affection between the plaintiff and Charles B. Darwin inconsistent with and destructive of the marital relations between the plaintiff and defendant.</p>
<p>4th. That the present separation and estrangement between the parties is owing to the last stated fact, rather than to the allegations and charges in plaintiff's complaint, and it is now accordingly considered that the decree of divorce prayed for in this case be and the same is hereby refused; and it is further ordered and considered that the costs of this case be taxed against defendant, and execution may issue therefor.</p>
<p>(Signed) J E Wyche, Judge.</p>
----
<p>The Wilson-Darwin Case&#8212;This case which has obtained considerable notoriety was tried at Port Townsend, last week, before his honor Judge Wyche, the trial occupying nearly the whole week. We publish to-day the proceedings in the case, had previous to the change of venue being granted, and the decree of Judge Wyche. Some twenty witnesses were examined on the part of the defense, and four or five for plaintiff, and a large mass of testimony elicited. We devote much space to the matter, to the exclusion of other articles but have no room for the evidence taken, which we shall refer to hereafter.</p>