<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>The Wilson vs Wilson Case.</head>
<ab>Elizabeth D. Wilson, Pl'ff.
vs
Frederick A Wilson, Def't</ab>
<p>In the United States District Court for the 2d Judicial District, holding terms at Olympia, W.T. Action for divorce.</p>
<p>The plaintiff Elizabeth D. Wilson, <unclear/> of Olympia, Thurston county, Washington Territory, complainted Frederick A. Wilson, a <unclear/> of Port Townsend in said Territory, defendant; and for cause of action alleges alleges as follows:</p>
<p>That, on or about the first of July, A.D. 1861, the plaintiff was duly married to the defendant on the Territory of Washington, adn that the plaintiff continued to live with the said defendant as his wife until about the 28th day of May, A.D. 1867. That, at the time of the said marriage the plaintiff and the said defendant were and now are inhabitants of this Territory. That during the time plaintiff lived and co-habited with the said defendant she had two children by him, now living, <unclear/> Edward aged five years in August next and Frederick, aged about fifteen months; and that during all that time she <unclear/> herself with propriety, managed the household affairs of her said husband with prudence and economy, and at all times treated her said husband with loving kindess and forhearance. That she has always demeaned herself as a good, faithful and virtuous wife, and labored to discharge her duties as a wife and mother in conformity with her marriage convenants. That the marital relation existing between the plaintiff and defendant have not been characterized by that love and affection which should exist between husband and wife; and that the defendant's conduct and deportment towards this plaintiff has been harsh and unkind, and wanting in all that kindly love and affection which should be manifested by a husband towards his wife. That the said defendant has repeatedly told this plaintiff that he did not have that love and affection for her which a husband should have for a wife.</p>
<p>That there is such an incompatibility of temper and disposition between the plaintiff and defendant as to render life burdensome, and makes it utterly impossible for them to live nad co-habit together happily as husband and wife. That in consequence of these things the married life of the plaintiff has been very unhappy for some years.</p>