<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>


ANOTHER $10,000 BACKET.

The Sensational Scandal New Agitating the Rask and File of Society Circles.

The Campbell divorce case no longer has any interest for the citizens of Seattle. It has faced into dim obscurity by an event nearer home in the same line, which promises to be the talk of the town for some days to come. The principals in the case are J. S. m> smart, a well known policeman of this city, Smart's wife and John Anderson, an old settler in King County, and one of the proprietors of the People's Market on Commercial street.

From parties who claim to know we learn that the affiar dates back to last summer, when Anderson was running a meat market at Renton and boarding with Policeman Smart, who lived with his family in that quiet little village. The Smarts and Anderson became bery intimate during Anderson's sojourn there, so much so, in fact, that it is stated Anderson loaned Smart considerable money without security.

At times Anderson would come to Seattle on business and remain away several days, and oftentimes Mrs. Smart would on some pretext also visit the Queen City while Anderson was here. She invariably stopped at the Arlington, and, it is stated, would frequently go to the People's Market and inquire for Anderson. Affairs went on in this way for some time until last Saturday, when Anderson and Mrs. Smart both registered at the Arlington and prepared to spend the night there. Each were assigned separate rooms, but it is calimed that about midnight Mrs. Smart sought Anderson's apartment. Here is where the wronged husband comes in. Smart, suspicioning that all was not right, was laying for such a movement or vice versa, and, walking into the room, found his wife and Anderson <hi rend="italic">flagrante delicto.</hi> An encounter followed, in which both men were bruised considerably. The next day the woman returned to Renton, and Anderson departed for Squak, where, it is claimed, he has some business to attend to.

The wronged husband, through his attorneys, Messrs. Struve, Haines and McMicken, has commenced action in the District Court for $10,000 (the regulation sum) damages, and this morning Judge Greene issued an order of arrest, under the arrest and bail act of the Washington Territory code, for Anderson and placed bail at $5000, which is considered a very heavy bond. It is presumed also that Anderson's property will be attached. We are informed Anderson will make defense on the ground that Smart was aware of the true state of affairs all along and made no attempt to stop proceedings, unitl a disagreement occurred over a business transaction. The gentleman has retained Messrs. Lewis &amp; Gilman as his attorneys. The case promises to be one of sensational developments and lively interest.
