<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

GUILTY OR NOT GUILTY!
---
A Long List of Criminal Cases For 
The Consideration of the
Grand Jury

The following batch of criminal cases have been returned to the District Court from the Justices' Court and are now occupying the time of Prosecuting Attorney J. T. Ronald. This is the longest list of such cases seen for many a day, and it is needless to say that the District Attorney will have his hands full to prepare the indictments.

F.C. Kline, for shooting with a revolver G. A. Basler, the laundry man, September 12, 1888. Kline had been employed by Basler, and shot the latter because he owed Kline a small amount of money.

Ah Lin, assult with intent to murder one Qua, January 9, I889.

Harry Smith, grand larceny, stealing personal property to the amount of $49 from George Koppen, November 27, 1888.

Burt McClelland, assault with intent to murder upon one Deria Stone, October 5, 1888.

Owen M. Jones, obtaining money under false pretenses, (alleged to have attempted to obtain $1000 on sale of real estate belonging to another person), November 28, 1888.

Wm. Reed, J. Murphy, A. Harris and Richard Coulton, burglary, Henry Bode complaining witness, October 6, 1888.

John Welch, highway robbery. The famous lone highwayman of cable car holding up fame whom police officer Nick Hanna shot in both legs.

John Welch the "lone highwayman," assault with intent to murder upon I. M> Kessler, December 17, 1888.

John Welch, robbery, on complaint of C. M. Bywater, December 20, 1888.

Charles Murphy, receiving stolen proptery - watch filed as exhibit.

J. J. Venatta, grand larceny, stealing a suit of clothes and a $50 gold pin, December 22, 1888.

John Welch, assault with attempt to commit murder on complainant, I. M. Kessler.

Indian John, assault with attempt to murder upon Police Officer Terry, with a piece of scantling, December 29, 1888.

John Colman, Mike McCabe, Isaac Style and Wm. H. Miller for receiving stolen property&#8212;pieces of leather valued at $25&#8212;belonging to D. W. Davidson.

Frank White, resisting Police Officer Nick Hanna December 23, 1888.

James Wickersham, seduction of one Sarah E. Brantner, daughter of Mrs Antoinette Brantner, Oct. 22, 1887.

Joseph Dickson, attempt to commit burglary, Oct. 6, 1888.

Joe Carter, grand larceny, stealing from Edwin L. Payne, seventy five 50 cent pieces, Oct. 7, 1888.

Ah Chung, visiting the opium joint in Wa Chung's place, recently raided by Constable Caldwell, and Officer Peer.

Clarence Sheldon and Alex Consign, arson. These are the two boys who set fire to the Good Duck lodging house, Jan. 6, 1889.

George Fldridge, embezzlement, taking $3 while employed as a clerk for Charles F. Frasch, July 10, 1888.

Edward Thompson, assault with attempt to commit murder upon one Richard Roe at Vashon Island, July 5, 1888, upon complaint of Sheriff Wm. Cochrane.

Wm. Davidson, embezzlement of $10 collected from one Mrs. Counter and due H. M. Hall, July 16, 1888.

Josiah Collins, grand larceny, stealing a bundle of clothes from one J. P. Goodwin, July 15, 1888.

John Rogers, resisting Officer Nick Hanna, Dec. 23, 1888.

John McDonald, burglary, June 21, 1888, on complaint of J. W. Dobbins.

Ah Hang, grand larceny, stealing $760 belonging to Wm. Powell, July 13, 1888.

W. Billings, grand larceny, stealing a red plush cloak belonging to Ida Dolloff, Aug. 13, 1888.

John Nugent, assault with intent to commit bodily upon Fred Lewis with a knife, July 31, 1888.

J. H. Fred assault with intent to murder upon A. F. Tilford, oct. 15, 1888.

Charles F. Brown, grand larceny, stealing a silver watch and $140 in twenty dollar gold pieces from James Harvey, July 11, 1888.

B. F. Kidney, grand larceny, stealing $70 from Fannie Melville, July 18, 1888.

Alonzo McDowell, assault with intent to rob upon Samuel Freldon, June 3, 1888.

John Lee, grand larceny, stealing a gold watch and chain from N. L. Oakley, July 4, 1888.

H. Douglas et al., grand larceny, stealing $50 from F. A. Berhaur, August 18, 1888.

James Haley, James Moore and Robt. Turner, larceny.

Wm Gwin, grand larceny, stealing an overcoat and a suit of clothes from P. White, Jan. 16, 1889.

Jos. Whitchurch, resisting Officer Nick Hanna, Dec. 23, 1888.

Fred Oxley, resisting Officer Nick Hanna in December. 

Harry Diamond, burglarizing Oscar Olson's room in the Villard House, stealing a valise and 24 packages of cigarettes, Oct. 30, 1888.

F. Henderson, obtaining money under false pretences, obtaining $5 from Edgar Bryan, the pawnbroker, on an alleged check for $37 on the First National Bank; check payable to John Drew and signed by Wm. Jackson.

C. F. Reed, bribery, alleged on complaint of Sheriff Cochrane to have given $1 to a certain John Doe to influence his vote.

Joseph Bailey, burglary, on complaint of M. Brodenck, November 16, 1888.

Pat Maloney, resisting Captain Willard, August 3, 1888. 

harry Diamond, burglary, October 27, 1888, on complaint of C. E. Bewers.

James Galvin, grand larceny, stealing gold watch and chain from Peter Lee in the Idaho saloon, January 23, 1889.

C. H. Row, grand larceny, stealing $35 from Thomas Merino, August 17, 1888.

Andrew Burns, obtaining money under false pretenses, on complaint of R. E. Holm.

William Hammond assisting prisoners to escape from the County Jail, November 13, 1888.

John Williams, assault with intent to commit murder. Williams is alleged to have assaulted Mr. B. F. Shaubut, of the Seattle Transfer Company, September 21, 1888.

H. A. Dunbar, exhibiting a pistol in a crowd, and with a threatening manner. This is the employe of Detective A. J. Lucaw, who was deputized to make the first raid on the gamblers.

John Shanghurry, burglary, on complaint of J. L. Mears.

Lewis Boden, burglary, breaking into the room of Max Schmidt in the Levetta House and stealing money and clothing Nov. 17, 1888.

John Williams and James Burns grand larceny, stealing $70 from an Indian woman, Oct. 21, 1888.

Charles Parker and Edward Worley, grand larceny.

C. F. Reid, obtaining money under false pretenses from one John G. Derungs, October 14, 1888.

George A. Godirey et al., burying stolen property.

John McCarty and John McEntire, robbery.

George Watson, grand larceny.

Henry Snith, petit larceny.

Peter McDonald, resisting an officer.

Edward Weaver, attempting to obtain money under false pretenses.

F. P. Morrow, perjury against C. F. Reid, August 4, 1888.

L. Dubean, grand larceny.

G. W. Johnson, assault with a deadly weapon.

George Collins et al., burglary.

Nicholas July, assault and battery.

Theresa Strager and V. P. Weisenthal, adultery.

Henry Gray, burglary.

Fred Smith, grand larceny.

A. E. Cone, obtaining money under false pretenses.

C. F. Reed, obtaining monoy under false pretenses.

Henrich Michel, assault with intent to murder.

Daniel Fergusen and Jesse Danielson, resisting an officer. The two youthful gamblers who pulled a revolver on Capt. Willard near the Grotto saloon, December 20, 1888, and who finally got away on a straw bond.

GAMBLING CASES.

Following are the gambling cases, the witnesses for the Territory being generally Sheriff Cochrane and Deputies M. M. Dominick, R. V. Lea, E. R. Clark and F. P. Carmichael.

Tom Tilden, dealing faro.

James E. Griffin, carrying on faro game.

Eugene W. Way, permitting faro to be dealt in his premises.

T. B. Daley, dealing faro.

Charles Mullen, permitting gambling on his premises.

H. Taylor, dealing faro.

E. C. Huntley, permitting faro to be dealt upon his premises.

T. B. Guthrie dealing faro.

Hank Carleton, conducting a game of faro.

H. H. Thompson, carrying on a wheel of fortune.

Barney Hay, dealing stud poker.

Councilman J. F. McDonald, permitting gambling on his premises.

Morris Johnson, conducting a gambling game.

J. H. Foster, permitting faro to be dealt on his premises.