<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

DISTRICT COURT CONVENES.

The Mills of Justice Have Started Grinding a Very Large Grist of Cases

From the Daily of February 4.

"Oyez! Oyez!" cried out the United States Marshal, as he rapped his desk and the February term of the District Court for the third Judicial district, which is also the United States district court, convened as the clock struck 11 at the Court House to-day, Chief Justice Thomas Burke presiding.

Nearly every official and attorney interested was present, and the rather large assemblage was made all the more interesting by the familiar faces. Col. White, Attorney General Metcalfe, Prosecuting Attorney Ronald, Marshal Hamilton, Sheriff Cochrane, Mr. L. C. Gilman, Mr. John Arthur, Mr. Eben Smith, United States Commissioner Emery, and others of the judiciary, too numerous for any extended mention.

Clerk W. E. Ledgerwood has succeeded in getting up a very large and elaborate docket of cases, both criminal and civil, United States and Territorial, with an extensive civil calendar of private cases that may not be reached this term. It gives the following list of officers all of whom are on hand and able for duty: Thomas Burke, Judge; W. E. Ledgerwood, Clerk; H. T. Hannon, Deputy Clerk; Wm. Cochrane, Sheriff of King County; M. Padden, Deputy Sheriff; J. T. Ronald, Prosecuting Attorney; S. H. Piles, Assistant Prosecuting Attorney; T. J. Hamilton, United States Marshal; W. H. White, United States Attorney; C. F. Munday, Assistant United States Attorney.

The terms of court for this district this year are to be held as follows:
Seattle&#8212;On the first Monday of February, last Monday in May and last Monday in August.
Whatcom&#8212;On the second Monday in March and the second Monday of October.
Port Townsend&#8212;On the Fourth Monday of March and October.
LaConner&#8212;On the fourth Monday of April and the first Monday of December.
Snohomish City&#8212;On the third Monday of May and the Third Monday of December.
Port Madison&#8212;On the third Monday of April and November.

The following members of the Grand Jury were excused for various reasons: James Campbell, A. J. Charleston, John Collins, D. E. Durie, Jacob Furth, Jacob Franenthal, Joe Green, John Kewan and Thomas Oakley. This left only George W. Hall, who was absent; Thomas Brennan, Benjamin Cade, George Charleston, Ed Guthrie, J. C. Masel and A. Smidt of the original service. It was found necessary to order another service of eighteen grand jurors, returnable at 1:30 p. m. United States Attorney White asked for a separate venire for the United States, owing to the long list of United States cases, and an order was made accordingly, the venire made returnable at 1:30 p. m. to-morrow.

Mr. Ronald Crawford was appointed court crier, and the following were made bailiffs: Ed. Clark, Frank Paul, D. C. Kennedy, James Quilter, Bion Brockwav, W. H. Johnson, D. H. Hawley and J. D. L. McGaughey.

Before recess attorneys were admitted to practice as follows: Mr. C. H. Huobell, on Minnesota Supreme Court papers, proposed by Mr. Eben Smith; Mr. Robert McMahon, upon Supreme Court certificates from New Hampshire, proposed by Mr. L. C. Gilman; Mr. Michael Phillips, on Supreme Court papers from New York, proposed by Attorney General Metcalfe.

A change of venue was granted in the case of the Territory against H. F. McKay, docketed as "John Doe McKay," and charged with assault with intent to murder. McKay is said to have been a Northern Pacific detective, and is reported to have shot at Mr. Guye about a year ago at the Snoqualmie pass.

Moses Loree, an honorably discharged soldier from the First Michigan Mechanics' and Engineers' Corps. was allowed his full citizenship papers, on Colonel White's suggestion.

Recess was then taken until 1:30 p.m.

