<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<title>EQUAL SUFFRAGE.</title>
<p>The Elective Franchise and Jury Duty.</p>
<p>An Able Discussion of the late Decision of the Supreme Court by Hon. John J. McGilvrs.</p>

<p>The recent decision of two of the judges of hte Supreme Court of this Territory in the case of Jeff J. Hanlan vs. the Territory of Washingotn, has caused much comment and criticism. They hold that the Legislation, whereby it was attempted to confer the elective franchise uon the women of this Territory over twenty -one years of age, who are citizens of the United States or who have declared their intention to become such according to law, is void: because it does not properly set forth the object of the act in the title, as required by Sec. 1024 of the Revised Statues of the United States,</p>
<p>No more important question could be presented to any court than that of the right to exercise the privilege of the elective franchise, and especially when it effects nearly one-half of the citizens of the Territory, who have been or supposed they were enfranchised. There is no question as to the power of the Legislature to confer upon women the privilege of the elective franchise. "All persons born or naturalized int he United States and subject to the jurisdiction thereof are citizens of the United States and the State wherein they reside." [See. 14, amendment ot the Constitution of the United States.]</p>
<p>That there is no question as to the power of the Legislature to prescribe the qualifications of voters, except as otherwise provided by Congress. (See Minor vs. Happersett, See 21 Wallace, 162.) Prior to November 23, 1883, the right of suffrage was confined to male citizens. On that day the Legislature passed an act entitled, "An Act to amend Sec. 3030, which act, if valid, conferred the right to vote and hold office upon women as well as men. The code to which this amendment relates was adopted by the Legislature in 1881 and although imperfect in some respects, and obnoxious to the objection that it embraces more than one object, not stated in the title, and in fact has no title within the intent and meaning of said section 1924, still it has been ever since its adoption the accepted law of the alnd, and the court itself derived its power to sit as a court at the very time when the decision in question was made, by virtue of an amendment to this code, passed January 9, 1886, entitled "an act to amend chapter 135 of the code of Washington Territory entitled courts."</p>
<p>It will thus be seen that the title of the act of January 9, 1886, differs only from the title of the act of November 23, 1883, by the addition of the two words "entitled courts," while it professes to amend a whole chapter instead of a single section of a chapter. The act of November 23, 1883, commonly called the woman suffrage act, was accepted by the people as valid, and under it the women of Washington have ever since exercised the privilege of the election franchise. The amendment in question was again amended and amplified by the succeeding Legislature, January 9, 1886.</p>
<p>The point made as to the defective title is purely technical, the object and purpose of Congress being, as stated in said section 1924, "To avoid improper influences which may result from intermixing in the same act such things as have no proper relation to each other." In other words the object and purpose was to prevent omnibus bills and log rolling legislation. Thus we see the spirit of the law has not been violated. If there is even a shadow of a breach, it is of the naked letter not the spirit of the law. No attempt was ever made or set on foot to repeal these legislative acts and thsu exclude women from the privilege of the elective franchise.</p>
<p>This franchise is the coveted boon and crowning glory of every true American citizen. Its possessor is a sovereign. While it should be conferred with caution, it certainly should not be taken away without due cause and consideration.</p>
<p>With this preliminary statement of facts and legal principles, let us now examine into the facts and the law of the case in question, and the constitution of the court that tried it.</p>
<p>The case went up on writ of error. One of the errors assigned was, that the indictment upon which the trial was had in the court below, was found by a Grand Jury, upon the panel of which there were four married women who were living and keeping house with their husbands.</p>
<p>The statute provides that "all qualified electors and householders shall be competent to serve as Grand Jurors." (See sect. 2078 of the code.)</p>
<p>The two Judges who decided this case held, and no doubt correctly, that a married woman living and keeping house with her husband was not a householder within the intent and meaning of the law, and therefore not a competent Grand Juror That disposed of the case and therefore it was not necessary for the Court to pass upon the question of the legality of the act of November 23d, 1883, conferring the elective franchise on women, or the subsequent act of January 9th, 1886, amendatory thereof. There was no other case before the court involving the suffrage question; the Legislature would meet before another session of the Court, the point raised was as hereinbefore stated purely technical, if not extremely hypercritical, and the Court as a whole equally divided in opinion on the main question. More than that. It is a serious question, as that court is constituted, whether it is not necessary that three of the Judges should concur in order to render a valid judgment.</p>
<p>Section 9 of the act of Congress of July 4th, 1884, reads as follows: "That hereafter the Supreme Court of the Territory of Washington shall consist of a Chief Justice and three associate Justices, any three of whom shall constitute a quorum, but no Justice shall act as a member of the Supreme Court in any action or proceeding brought to such Court by writ of error, bill of exceptions, or appeal from a decision, judgment, or decree rendered by him as Judge of a District Court."</p>
<p>This act, like all <unclear></unclear> should be so constructed as to make it valid and effective if possible. Suppose four cases, one from each district, is before the Supreme Court for trial at the same term, each case involving a single point, and that point the same in all; the suffrage question for instance, and two of the Judges decide the question one way, and the other two directly the opposite way, what will the judgment of the court be? It is impossible to have two judgments of the same court at the same term directly overruling each other and yet be valid. The usual rule would prevail, viz.: When the Court is equally divided in opinion the judgment of the court below is affirmed. (See Curtis Com. Sec. 394; also Etting vs. Bank, of the United States; 11 Wheaton 59.) It will be said, however, that the act provides that any three of the Judges "constitute a quorum." True, and a quorum may transact business, but it is quite another question whether a majority only of a divided quorum can render a valid judgment. Under such circumstances prudence as well as precedents would seem to have requiredthe Judge to go no farther than was aboslutely necessary, and not reach out and decide a question so important as this, when the case was already disposed of on other grounds. (See Fellows vs. Blacksmith et al., 19 Howard, 372; Brown vs. Duchense, 19 Howard, 199; also Simpson vs. Brown Bros., 1 Washington Teritory Reports, 249, and various other cases.) In the last case cited, one reason assigned by the Court for not deciding a second point where the first disposed of he case, was "that it might leave a bad taste in the mouth." While there are two sides to the question of female suffrage as with most others, it is contrary to the spirit of the age and our political institutions to take a step backwards and deprive a citizen of a political privilege so important as this, after it has once been conferred. If the elective franchise ahd been conferred upon Darwin's original progenitor of man it is very doubtful whether the American people would even entertain the proposition to disfranchise him. No one dreames of disfranchising the liberated slave and other colored citizens of the land, then why the women? If, however, it is to be done, let it be done openly, boldy and manfully, if such an act can be considered manful. Every manly man in the land who deserves, himself, to have th eright to exercise the privilege of the elective franchise, will protest against that privilege being taken from women by judicial legislation or legal legerdemain. Court as Courts are entitled to the greatest respect, but judicial legislation and the habitual disposal of causes on technical and captions grounds, instead of on the merits, cannot be too severely critiised and condemned.</p>
<p>The administration of justice in both civil and criminal law is brought into dispreute, and the confidence of the people in the courts destroyed in this very way more than in any other. The Code was adopted with a view and for the purpose of simplifying the practice of the law both civil and criminal,, and meeting out to suitors substantial justice on the basis of common sense. It was intended ot do away with the technicalities of the old common law system, and so it would if it was administered in the spirit in which its framers intended it should be. But what is the fact. The writer of this article has been at the Bar more than thirty-three was at a Bar where the common law practice with alight statutory modifications prevailed.</p>
<p>It is safe to state that in all that period of ten years there was not as much wrangling at the Bar, in the matters of settling pleadings, as ordinarily at a single term of court here. If technical questions and hair-splitting decisions were confined to the pleadings alone, it might be bearable; but no, the same kind of wrangling and decision continues through the whole progress of the cause in the nisi prius courts, and if the cause should be unlucky enough to get to the Supreme Court of the Territory, the same fate follows it there. Lest it might be thought by some who are not well informed that the foregoing is an exaggerated statement of the facts, attention is called to the reported cases of the decision sof the Supreme Court for the past fifteen or twenty years. It will be found upon examination of these cases that a large number of them if not a majority, have been disposed of otherwise than on the merits. It may seem strange that this is a fact but such is the case. It arises no doubt mainly from two cases; namely:</p>
<p>First-- The code practice is an innovation and comparatively new. No substitute and comparatively new. No substitute for a well defined and settled practice can well be an improvement on the old practice, until the new practice itself is defined and settled y a long course of judicial and settled by a long course of judicial investigation and decision; a fact which the original advocates of the code system no doubt failed to take into consideration.</p>
<p>Second-- It seems that the average lawyer when he gets on the bench is disposed to assume that what he does not know is not worth knowing; and not unfrequently he is seized with an irrepressible impulse to exhibit his legal lore by delivering long opinions upon a majority of the technical questions raised by the ingenuity of counsel and sometimes when the ingenuity of counsel fails the judge himself will raise such questions. An impanneled jury is thus not unfrequently dispensed with entirely or ignored in an ordinary common law case. This is all wrong and there is entirely too much judicial legislation for the good of the country. Courts ought to be respected and must be respected or the community cannot prosper. What the people want and must have is good substantial common sense justice. No matter about the Bar. If its members cannot make a living except by snaps and quirks let them turn their attention to some other calling. But the true lawyer, guided by an honest and sensible judge, will grapple with the strong points in his case and try it upon its merits. This criticism is not made in any unfriendly spirit, nor with any disrespect to the courts, but as duty that an old practitioner owes to his profession and the community at large.</p>
<p>Allow me to say in conclusion that it is to be hoped, as a matter of common decency, that our next Legislature will correct the technical errors in our legislation upon which the decision of the two judges was based in the case of Haslan vs. the Territory of Washington. If the privilege of the elective franchise is to be withdrawn as to women or any other class of citizens, let it be done advisedly and openly and by the legally constituted authority.</p>
<p>There have been many contests between the Supreme Court and the Legislature, but the Legislature usually wins in the long run. That court has even condescended to arrest a judgment and discharge a prisoner upon the motion of the Legislative Assembly. At east so the record resds. (See Corbett vs. Washington Territory, 1st W.T. Rep. p. 434.)</p>
<p>Ladies, your battle round is the Legislative halls.</p>
<p>John J. McGilvra.</p>


