<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

DISTRICT COURT CONVENES.

The Mills of Justice Have Started Grinding a Very Large Grist of Cases

From the Daily of February 4.

"Oyez! Oyez!" cried out the United States Marshal, as he rapped his desk and the February term of the District Court for the third Judicial district, which is also the United States district court, convened as the clock struck 11 at the Court House to-day, Chief Justice Thomas Burke presiding.

Nearly every official and attorney interested was present, and the rather large assemblage was made all the more interesting by the familiar faces. Col. White, Attorney General Metcalfe, Prosecuting Attorney Ronald, Marshal Hamilton, Sheriff Cochrane, Mr. L. C. Gilman, Mr. John Arthur, Mr. Eben Smith, United States Commissioner Emery, and others of the judiciary, too numerous for any extended mention.

Clerk W. E. Ledgerwood has succeeded in getting up a very large and elaborate docket of cases, both criminal and civil, United States and Territorial, with an extensive civil calendar of private cases that may not be reached this term. It gives the following list of officers all of whom are on hand and able for duty: Thomas Burke, Judge; W. E. Ledgerwood, Clerk; H. T. Hannon, Deputy Clerk; Wm. Cochrane, Sheriff of King County; M. Padden, Deputy Sheriff; J. T. Ronald, Prosecuting Attorney; S. H. Piles, Assistant Prosecuting Attorney; T. J. Hamilton, United States Marshal; W. H. White, United States Attorney; C. F. Munday, Assistant United States Attorney.

The terms of court for this district this year are to be held as follows:
Seattle&#8212;On the first Monday of February, last Monday in May and last Monday in August.
Whatcom&#8212;On the second Monday in March and the second Monday of October.
Port Townsend&#8212;On the Fourth Monday of March and October.
LaConner&#8212;On the fourth Monday of April and the first Monday of December.
Snohomish City&#8212;On the third Monday of May and the Third Monday of December.
Port Madison&#8212;On the third Monday of April and November.

The following members of the Grand Jury were excused for various reasons: James Campbell, A. J. Charleston, John Collins, D. E. Durie, Jacob Furth, Jacob Franenthal, Joe Green, John Kewan and Thomas Oakley. This left only George W. Hall, who was absent; Thomas Brennan, Benjamin Cade, George Charleston, Ed Guthrie, J. C. Masel and A. Smidt of the original service. It was found necessary to order another service of eighteen grand jurors, returnable at 1:30 p. m. United States Attorney White asked for a separate venire for the United States, owing to the long list of United States cases, and an order was made accordingly, the venire made returnable at 1:30 p. m. to-morrow.

Mr. Ronald Crawford was appointed court crier, and the following were made bailiffs: Ed. Clark, Frank Paul, D. C. Kennedy, James Quilter, Bion Brockwav, W. H. Johnson, D. H. Hawley and J. D. L. McGaughey.

Before recess attorneys were admitted to practice as follows: Mr. C. H. Huobell, on Minnesota Supreme Court papers, proposed by Mr. Eben Smith; Mr. Robert McMahon, upon Supreme Court certificates from New Hampshire, proposed by Mr. L. C. Gilman; Mr. Michael Phillips, on Supreme Court papers from New York, proposed by Attorney General Metcalfe.

A change of venue was granted in the case of the Territory against H. F. McKay, docketed as "John Doe McKay," and charged with assault with intent to murder. McKay is said to have been a Northern Pacific detective, and is reported to have shot at Mr. Guye about a year ago at the Snoqualmie pass.

Moses Loree, an honorably discharged soldier from the First Michigan Mechanics' and Engineers' Corps. was allowed his full citizenship papers, on Colonel White's suggestion.

Recess was then taken until 1:30 p.m.

THE GRAND JURY CHARGED.
Judge Burke Explains to it What Its Duties are Regarding Vice and Crime.

When the court came to order again in the afternoon it was 1:45. The names of the following new venire of jurors were called:

Patrick Hayes, John B. Randall, Joseph Clark, J. G. Allan, Richard Ashworth, W. G. Young, Salem Formaugh, Stephen Niblock, J. W. Farnham, J. W. Hunt, Samuel Twiss, P. J. Smith, J. W. Maryott, L. Pattison, L. J. Burr, Stephen Berry, Robert Calligan and Carl Nelson, Messrs. Allan, Hunt and Calligan were excused.

After the customary formality of bringing in the prisoners to challenge the Grand Jury, Judge Burke empannelled a jury and gave the following charge:

Gentlemen of the Grand Jury: The law provides that the Grand Jury shall be charged by the court as to the nature of their duties. This the court now proceeds to do, as directly and in as few words as possible.

The Prosecuting Attorney will attend you for the purpose of examining witnesses and giving you such advice as you may ask for.

The law makes it your duty to inquire into the cases of parties in custody or under bail charged with the conmission of offenses against the laws of the United States or of this Territory, and duly returned by a committing Magistrate, Justice of the Peace or United States Commisssioner, or upon a complaint sworn to before an officer authorized to administer oaths and presented by the Prosecuting Attorney, or under the instructions of the court. If one of your number knows, or has reason to believe, that a public offense, triable within this county, has been committed, he must declare the same to his fellow jurors, who may thereupon investigate such offense if a majority so order.

You will in no case permit a complainent who may have instituted a prosecution to be present at your deliberations or to vote for the finding of an indictment. The law makes it you duty especially to inquire as to the offense of any person confined in prison on a criminal charge; as to the condition and mismanagement of the public prisons in the county, and as to the wilful misconduct in office of public officers. You may in your discretion examine the public records of the county. And, as I am required by law to do, I give you especially in charge chapter CLIII of the Code of Washington, in relation to fees and costs. If you find that any officer has violated any of the provisions of that chapter you will proceed against him accordingly.

You are not bound to hear evidence for the defendant, but it is your duty to weigh all the evidence submitted to you, and when you have reason to believe that other evidence which may be within you reach will explain away the charge, you should order such evidence produced, and for that purpose you may cause process to issue for the witnesses.

If you should ignore a bill of indictment, you will also find whether the prosecution is malicious and frivolous, and whether the complainan or the county shall pay the costs, and return such findings with your proceedings into open court. An indictment cannot be found without the concurrence of at least twelve grand jurors, and when so found it must be indorsed "a true bill" and such indorsement signed by the foreman of the Grand Jury; and the names of the witnesses examined before the Grand Jury must be inserted at the foot of the indictment, or indorsed thereon before it is presented to the court. When you find an indictment it must be presented to the court by yoru foreman in presence of the Grand Jury.

No grand juror shall disclose the fact that an indictment for a felony has been found against any person not in custody or under recognizance, until such person has been arrested; nor should any grand juror disclose any fact concerning an indictment while it is not subject to inspection.

In addition to what I have already said to you. I wish briefly to call your attention to one or two other matters of grave importance to this community. When two or more persons combine, on any pretext whatever, to prevent a man from working at any lawful calling, or to prevent him from getting employment, or to interfere with him in his lawful pursuits, they are guilty of a conspiracy and indictable under the law. In this country it is the right and privilege of everyman while acting within the law, to pursue his happiness in his own way, without hindrance or molestation from any one. He may seek employment from whom and where he pleased. He ahs the right to earn a living for himself and for his family in any line of honest endeavor that to him seems best. In this the law guarantees to him absolute freedom of choice, and if it did anything else he would cease to be a free man.

In the United States of America, it can never be made a condition of man's employment that he must first join any particular society or any particular organization. Every individual is at perfect liberty to do in that regard as he pleases.

Whenever, therefore, any body of men, society, or organization, undertake to deprive any man of the right to earn an honest livelihood for himself or his family because he does not belong to such society, or organization, they not only invade his dearest rights, but they violate the fundamental law of the land; the law which forms the basis of all our liberties; and any organization, society or body of men, whatever their professions may be, that make fellowship in their organization a condition upon which they will allow other men to obtain employment, or earn a living, are conspirators against the law of the land and should be promptly punished as such. Men composing such organizations and who support such arbitrary conduct, are ignorant of what true freedom, means, and have yet to learn the first principles of American liberty. Their idea of freedom seems to be to starve or destroy all those who differ in opinion from them. When you prevent a man from earning a living you destroy him. This is a power not possessed by the most despotic governments, and in the United States the exercise of such a power by any body of men must not be tolerated for a moment. This, it must not be forgotten, is a country governed by laws consitutionally enacted, and not by men.

The events which have recently occurred in this county make it my duty to call your attention to these matters and to direct you to inquire whether in point of fact the offence herein referred to has been committed; and if it has, you will indict all such persons as have so participated therein as to be guilty of the offence.

I feel it my duty also to call your attention to the laws against gambling and against the running of gambling houses. It is a matter of common report that gambling resorts abound in this city, and that emboldened by long immunity, the gamblers play their games with such impudence and such ostentatious contempt for public opinion that a stranger, at least, might be led to think there was no law against gambling in this Territory. This is not the fact, however. The laws against gambling and the running of gambling houses, are plain and strict; the trouble is that they are not enforced. If the officers of the laws and courts and juries do their duty there will be but little cause to complain on this score. In a rapidly growing community like this, the laws against gambling, and against the selling to liquor to minors, should be enforced vigorously and vigilantly; because such laws operate as a shield and protection for the young. As you well know, young men are now coming to this part of the country in greater numbers than ever before. They are attracted here by the opportunities which a new country offers to them to make homes and careers for themselves. Under the very best conditions; in communities where law and order are the most rigidly enforced. the temptations that beset young men and tend to lead them astray are sufficiently numerous. It is therefore our solemn duty to those that are here and to strangers coming to seek homes amongst us, to throw around them every safeguard which the law affords. If, instead of seeking thus to guard the young and inexperienced against such pitfalls of vice and crime, we allow the laws against gambling and selling liquor to minors, to remain dead letter, we shall be doing a great wrong to those whom we are bound by every consideration of justice and humanity to shield and protect.

It is notorious that there is no vice more captivating to the young than that of gambling and equally so that there is scarcely one more utterly demoralizing; for when the passion for gambling once fairly takes possession of young or old, his usefulness in any lawful calling is generally at an end. You owe it to the community to make a most thorough and searching investigation into these matters; and if in point of fact, you find that the laws against gambling and against selling liqour to minors are being violated, you should promptly indict all persons committing such offences.

The Seattle Bar Association took pos-