<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>JUDGE M'GILVRA NO MORE</head>
<ab>Venerable Jurist and Pioneer of Seattle Died at Noon Today.</ab>
<ab>Members of His Family at His Bedside When End Came.</ab>
<p>JUDGE JOHN J. M'GILVRA, one of Seattle's oldest pioneers and as well one of the city's best known public men, died at 12:15 o'clock this afternoon at his home on Lake Washing at the age of 76 years, after an illness of about one month's duration. The death was not unexpected. He began sinking last night. This morning his condition was much worse and his friends and relatives gave up all hope. At a few minutes after 12 o'clock he passed peacefully away.</p>
<p>Death was mainly due to jaundice with which Judge McGilvra was attacked one month ago. For two weeks his condition became very alarming, but suddenly it took a turn for the better, and the sufferer apparently was rapidly recovering.</p>
<p>One week ago he began feeling so much better that he planned on a trip to California, where he intended to spend the winter. It was his intention to leave Seattle about Christmas. Four days ago he suffered a relapse, and again took to his bed. At first his relatives did not suspect that the relapse was serious.</p>
<p>Thursday night, however, it was seen that he was in a bad condition, and yesterday morning those who watched closely at the bedside knew that the end was near at hand.</p>
<ab>Members of the Family Present.</ab>
<p>The jaundice left the patient with a very weak stomach. That, coupled with his advanced years, left his system in such condition that permanent recovery was despaired of.</p>
<p>All the immediate members of Judge McGilbra's family were present when the final summons came. They were his widow, his two daughters, Mrs. Thomas Burke, and Miss Lillian McGilvra, and Mr. Oliver C. McGilvra, the latter a member of the law firm of Burke. Shephard &amp; McGilvra. Besides those mentioned, two brothers, C. C. McGilvra and Duncan McGilvra, of Iowa, survive Judge McGilvra.</p>
<p>Judge McGilvra first came to the State of Washington in 1861. He settled at Olympia. it was the first term of President Lincoln's administration. Mr. Lincoln and Judge McGilvra for many years had been close friends. In Chicago they had law offices adjoining. When Lincoln was elected he asked Judge McGilvra to accept the post of United States attorney for the Territory of Washington. He accepted it, and for two years acted in that capacity.</p>
<ab>Retired From Practice.</ab>
<p>He resigned to take up the practice of his profession, which he had followed continuously until ten years ago, when his age and failing health compelled him to give it up. Since then he has
<pb/>
been retired from business, but had always taken an active interest in all public affairs. The Lake Washington canal proposition had been his pet for many years.</p>
<p>One year after he resigned as United States attorney, in 1864, he moved from Olympia to Seattle. In this city he has lived continuously ever since. The public office mentioned is the only one he ever held. For years he was one of the city's foremost attorneys. For many years he was engaged in the practice with his son-in-law Judge Thomas Burke, now a member of the firm of Burke, Shepard &amp; McGilvra. For fifteen years Judge McGilvra occupied the same office in the Boston Block, on Second Avenue.</p>
<p>Thirty-five years ago Judge McGilvra moved into his home on Lake Washington and there has always lived. It was the judge's desire that when the time came for him to die that that event might occur at the place he so long had made his home. That wish was gratified. At that time the beautiful home-sites on Lake Washington were dense wildernesses. Judge McGilvra always left his office in the city early in the afternoon so that he might reach home before dark, for he said he feared the bears that were numerous in those parts.</p>
<ab>Site for the Pioneers.</ab>
<p>Judge McGilvra owned valuable real estate on the lake front that he acquired at the time he secured his home. Recently Judge McGilvra donated a site and building for a meeting place of the Washington Pioneers' Association. Among the pioneers of the state there were none better known and few if any better liked than Judge McGilvra. It can be truthfully said also that there are not half a dozen men living today who know more about the early history of the State of Washington than did Judge McGilvra. He grew up with it. He helped to make Seattle what it is.</p>
<p>In public enterprises Judge McGilvra was nearly always consulted. His advice was sought. For many years he was an active member of the chamber of commerce and, in fact, up to a few weeks before his death, he attended the meetings of that body and took part in the debates.</p>
<p>Judge McGilvra was not a member of any secret society. Neither had he associated with any church.</p>
<p>The date of the funeral is not yet fixed but it will take place either on Monday or Tuesday afternoon and will be held form the family residence.</p>