<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<title>JUST COGITATING: James Hamilton Lewis Was An Exotic Early-Day Figure</title>
<byline>By C.T. CONOVER</byline>
<figure><caption>JAMES HAMILTON LEWIS</caption></figure>
<p>JAMES HAMILTON ("DUDE") LEWIS came up from the deep South, and the first time I ever saw him he was registering at the old Carlton House in Olympia, where I had gone to report the last session of the Territorial Legislature for The Tacoma Ledger in the winter of 1887-8. He was an exotic figure, with pink whiskers, flowing locks, a fancy waistcoat, Prince Albert coat, mauve spats and a high silk hat, and his signature took up four full lines. I found he was a member of the upper house from King County and he was a source of copy for me throughout the session. He loved it, whether laudatory or satirical didn't matter, so long as I wrote about him.</p>
<p>Desperately hard up, he first worked on the docks in Seattle, and ever after throughout his political career, he carried a card in the longshoreman's union. We sent him to Congress, where he added to the joy of the nation. Later on he removed to Illinois, became United States senator, a national figure in the Democratic party, and once was talked of for the vice presidency.</p>
<p>In 1887 Lewis was taken into a legal partnership by L. C. Gilman, and one of his highest virtues was an absolute confidence in Gilman's knowledge of the law. One day a working man asked Lewis how long the law allowed for filing a lien for labor in shoveling earth from a railroad roadbed to the right-of-way.</p>
<p>"Ninety days," said Lewis.</p>
<p>"I'm glad of that," said the man. "Mr. Gilman said 60 days."</p>
<p>"What did you say you were doing, my dear fellow?" asked Lewis, and the man repeated his statement.</p>
<p>"Oh, I thought you said you shovelled earth from the right-of-way to the roadbed. Mr. Gilman is absolutely right&#8212;you have 60 days."</p>
***
<p>CLAYTON CRAWFORD, stepson of my old partner, Samuel L. Crawford, was once a prize winner in an essay-writing contest in school and the essay was printed in one of the Seattle papers. The next day Mrs. Crawford was walking near Pioneer Place when she met Colonel Lewis, who doffed his silk hat with a flourish and said, "Oh, Mrs. Crawford, I'm so glad we met. I cannot tell you how much I enjoyed that wonderful essay of Clayton's. He has extraordinary talent. Why, madam, he is a logician, a regular logician, and a poet laureate in embryo. When he finishes school I want you to let him come into my office. He will make a great lawyer."</p>
<p>Sam heard this so often that he got a little weary of it. Out Madison Street way one day he dropped in to see Bill Gross, a beloved old-time Negro who had swelled up to such proportions from some malady that he couldn't get through the house door. "Oh, Mr. Crawford, I'm all of a titter." exclaimed Mrs. Gross. "Ain't 'Dude' Lewis the politest man. The other day I met him and he took off his hat and shook hands and said, 'Mrs. Gross, I've been watching that boy George of yours. There's a boy for you, and he'll go far. He has a most 'strordinary bright mind, why he's a regular logishun, (yes, sah, regular logishun, he says,) and when he finishes school I want you to let him come into my office. He'll make a great lawyer.' Yes, sah, he's the politest man I know and when he runs for office again Ole Bill is going to vote for him if I have to take out the side of the house."</p>
<p>Sam told the story at the dinner table and after that relative values in the Crawford family were restored.</p>
***
<p>"JIM HAM" went into the Puget Sound National Bank one day to ask Ed Terry, the pay teller, what his balance was. Ed considered the fact that two society belles were standing close by and after looking up the account said, "Your balance this morning is $4,684, Colonel." As an apparent after-thought, as he was leaving, Lewis stopped at another window and whispered, "What is it really, Ed?"</p>
<p>"You are overdrawn $9.67"</p>
<p>"I'll fix that at once," said Lewis, and he wrote a check for $9.67 and handed it in. Ed never disclosed what he did with it, but there were ladies present and he was tactful.</p>
<p>In Police Court one day, the prisoner spoke a language no one could understand, but believed to be French. Colonel Lewis, reputed to be a French linguist, was called in. He addressed the prisoner in what sounded like Chinook and the prisoner responded voluably in a strange tongue. Finally Lewis said, "Your Honor, this man speaks a dialect from the south of France unknown to me&#8212;my French I acquired in Paris. I regret that I cannot help you, sir," and with a flourish he was gone. A spectator asked, "Your Honor, does an interpreter have to be a lawyer?"</p>
<p>"No, certainly not."</p>
<p>"Then I'll act. The man is speaking Spanish."</p>
<p>Before his death a few years ago, Colonel Lewis made a final visit to Seattle, a little, faded man, his whiskers gray and his features drawn, but his habiliments as gay and exotic as ever.</p>