<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<title>JUST COGITATING: Judge Burke Was Peerless Leader in Crucial Times</title>
<byline>By C. T. CONOVER</byline>
<figure><caption>THOMAS BURKE</caption></figure>
<p>On DECEMBER 4, 1935, Judge Thomas Burke collapsed in Carnegie Hall, New York, while making an impassioned plea for racial tolerance before the board of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, of which he was a mbmer and expired in the arms of Dr. Nicholas Butler, president of the endowment. Later, as the funeral party moved down Fifth Avenue to entrain for Seattle, traffic was halted to allow its passage. At St. Paul the sorrowing little group and the honored de3ad were transferred to the private car of the president of the Great Northern Railway and for the remainder of the journey an official of the company accompanied the remains. Through the State of Washington men stood at attention and at the journey's end foreign governments laid floral tributes upon the casket which was received into the arms of friends, weeping and unashamed.</p>
<p>Thomas Burke was born in Northern New York of humble parentage, but with a heritage somewhere in his lineage of the aristocracy of intellect and culture.</p>
<p>The family removed to the Middle West. Small in stature and slight in figure, Burke's life from 12 years on was what he made it. By manual labor he earned the means for an occasionall term of schooling and by alternate periods of labor and attendance, graduated from the law department of the University of Michigan. With money borrowed from a classmate, which he repaid from his first earnings, he came to Seattle.</p>
***
<p>HIS FIRST home in Seattle was a small back room of his modest office. Within two years he was elected probate judge, reelected and declined a third term. He early acquired leadership at the bar and in the affairs of the little community. He was a deep student of law, history, science and literature, and throughout his life added to the treasures of his richly stored mind. In 1880 and 1882 he was the unsuccessful candidate of the minority party for Congress. He married the daughter of John J. McGilvra, friend of Lincoln, who came to Washington Territory as United States district attorney.</p>
<p>In 1889 he yielded to the pleas of Democrats and Republicans alike, abandoned a lucrative law practice, and accepted an appointment as chief justice of the Supreme Court, to clean up a badly congested docket. His profound knowledge of the law, his passionate love of justice, his eloquent voice and great personal charm made him an irresistible advocate, and there were few cases of importance with which he was not associated. He devoted himself unselfishly to the public service and no man was more truly the inspiration and guardian of "the Seattle Spirit," a proud phrase endeared to us by long years of splendid tradition.</p>
<p>He was the patron of education in the Seattle schools, the University of Washington and Whitman College, or which he was long an overseer, and to which he left a bequest of $100,000.</p>
***
<p>WHEN THE death sentence was pronounced on Seattle, he led the fight for relief, pledged his personal fortune to secure a rail outlet and with his associates brought about unconditional surrender.</p>
<p>The Great Northern came, made him its Western counsel and Seattle, largely through his efforts, its Western terminus. In the franchise for the railway's entrance his first loyalty was to the public welfare and he stipulated that it was not an exclusive franchise, leaving the way open for the entry of other roads.</p>
<p>He was the last surviving founder of the Seattle Chamber of Commerce and its first secretary and later its president, president of the Associated Chambers of the Pacific Coast, and a director of the United States Chamber of Commerce. He had been decorated by the governments of France, Belgium and Japan, for his labors for world peace and international amity and understanding.</p>
<p>As an after-dinner speaker, as toastmaster and on any occasion calling for fine and lofty sentiment, noble thought garbed in the persuasive charm of cultured and felicitous phrase, and the sparkle of brilliant wit and humor that left no sting, he was held by his fellows to have been supreme.</p>
<p>He had a great tenderness for little children, and perhaps the chief joy of his last few months was a last visit to the French orphans whom he was maintaining and educating. He was simple, unaffected and entirely unspoiled. He loved his fellow men and was the animating center of any group in which he was present. His hand was always out in helpfulnesss, his purse open in aid to every worthy cause and every movement for the betterment of his world.</p>
<p>Such in honest outline was a man who lived nobly, served unselfishly died as he had lived and an was greatly beloved.</p>
<p>A symbolic statue, designed by an eminent sculptor and provided by his friends and neighbors stands in Volunteer Park.</p>