<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>PUGET SOUND MARITIME HISTORICAL SOCIETY SKETCH</p>
<!--image-->
<caption>A contemporary drawing depicts the hanging of three suspected murderers in 1882</caption>

<title>Vigilantes meted out 'justice'</title>
<p>The accompanying sketch depicts the hanging of three suspected murderers by Seattle vigilantes on Jan. 18, 1882. A contemporary drawing, it is unusual because of its caricatures o prominent citizens and representatives of three minority races.</p>
<p>At the extreme lower right is "Big Bill" Grose, a black pioneer who arrived in Seattle in the 1860s. In 1876 he opened Our House restaurant and did well. In 1882 he purchased 12 acres for $1,000 on Madison Street in many of the city's first black families purchased property on which to build their homes.</p>
<p>To the left of William Grose are two Chinese men and two Native American Indians. To their left, whittling as usual on a block of wood, is Henry Yesler.</p>
<p>The executions took place on scantlings placed between two trees on James Street adjacent to the Yesler hoe, seen on the left, now the site of the Pioneer Building.</p>
<p>The day before the executions, a popular Seattle merchant, George B. Reynolds, on his way back to work after supper, was accosted by two "footpads" who demanded his wallet. He resisted, was shot through the lungs and died two hours later.</p>
<p>Some of the citizens, concerned about the apparent increase in lawlessness and the seemingly weak response of law enforcement officers, formed a vigilance committee to hunt down the murderers.</p>
<p>Late that night, on Harrington and Smith's wharf, two transients were found hiding in a haystack. On one, the vigilantes found a revolver with one empty chamer; the other had a box of shells in his pocket. The two, James Sullivan and William Howard, were turned over to Sheriff L.V. Wyckoff, who promised he would charge them in court the next morning.</p>
<p>Later a restless mob returned to the jail and demanded the prisoners be turned over to them, but Wyckoff, with the help of Police Chief McGraw and others, managd to dissuade the ringleaders from acting.</p>
<p>However, the next morning in the crowded courtroom of Justice Samuel Coombs, just after he had announced the evidence against the two suspects was sufficient ot hold them for trial, the mob pushed the lawmen aside, grabbed the prisoners, marched them down the alley to the small trees and hanged them.</p>
<p>It so happened that the chief justice of the territory, Roger S. Greene, alerted to the activity, rushed to the scene just as the two men were strung up. With his pocketknife he tried desperately to cut the rope of one of them, bu twas wrestled aside.</p>
<p>The mob returned to the jail, knocked down the doors, grabbed prisoner Benjamin Payne, who earlier had been accused of murdering a policeman, dragged him to the same site and hanged him beside the other two.</p>
<p>While the immediate reaction, including that of the local press, was supportive of the vigilantes, many later viewed the action as a step backward in a town seeking to shed its frontier image.</p>
<p>James R. Warren is director of the Museum of History and Industry. To receive his book, "Highlights of Seattle's History," send $3 to the museum, 2700 24th Ave. E., Seattle 98112. All proceeds benefit the museum.</p>


