<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>Nostalgia</p>
<p>By William R. Hunt
For The Post-Intelligencer</p>

<title>The 1891 Willy Mason Murder
The victim died less than a minute after he was shot</title>


<p>THE DINING table groaned with good victuals on Thanksgiving night, 1891, as Willy Mason, boarder, a schoolteacher, prepared to dig in.</p>
<p>A bright light illuminated the window, the ham, eggs and supds; and the farmers of Cedar Mountain near Issaquah ate steadily, not saying much.</p>
<p>Then came the sharp report of a rifle,. A shot shattered the curtainless window. Willy Mason dropped his fork and fell from his chair. The bullet from a 45-70 Winchester had hit his left shoulder and passed through his heart. He died in less than a minute.</p>
<p>The diners ran outside but could not see the assailant. Soon the sheriff reached the Mason farm. Even in the dark, with the aid of lanterns, he could see where the killer stood just five feet outside the window. Prints in the damp ground showed his line of retreat from the house.</p>
<p>Early next morning the sheriff followed the tracks until they were lost, then tracks made by stocking feet were discovered. These led to a deserted cabin in the woods. In the cabin the sheriff found a pair of rubber boos with soles fitting the impressions left in the mud near the Mason window.</p>
<p>Tracks made by leather boots with peculiar markings led away from the cabin over a seldom used forest path which passed another deserted cabin. A hat and a memo book were found in the cabin.</p>
<p>Two days later a deputy arrested Charles W. Nordstrom as he walked along the ties of a Northern Pacific Railroad branch line. Nordstrom was carrying a 45-70 Winchester and wearing leather boots with a sole pattern that fit those officers had followed from the deserted cabin. Nordstrom's cap was identified as one taken from the cabin, after leaving his own there. His stockings were muddy, as if he had walked some distance without shoes.</p>
<p>Folks know Nordstrom as a former miner a Gilinan (now Issaquah) who quit the mine and wored at odd jobs. After digging ditches for the Masons, he received less pay than he had expected. Witnesses recalled that he had threatened Willy Mason, the 21-year-old son of the ranch owner.</p>
<p>Nordstrom did not speak much English. He denied shooting Mason and expressed a sullen contempt for the officers. No one around Issaquah had anythign good to say about Nordstrom, who was closemouthed and unfriendly. They called him "the ignorant Swede."</p>
<p>But for all the lack of a winning personality on Nordstrom's part, or any aspects of the crime compelling particular interest, the Nordstrom case became the most celebrated one in early Northwest history.</p>
<p>The trial opened in Seattle on Jan. 8, 1892. John Miller, later elected mayor, prosecuted. Attorneys N. Soderberg and Ed Palmer defended the penniless immigrant.</p>
<p>In defense the lawyers argued that Nordstrom had gotten drunk on the afternoon of the murder and wandered across Mason's farm enroute to the abandoned cabin he had been aquatting in.</p>
<p>Attorney Palmer asked Nordstrom to try on the leather boots the prosecutor brought to court. As the jury watched, Nordstrom did his best--or seemed to. He struggled and struggled, but just oculd not get either of his big feet into the boots.</p>
<p>Miller was not amused by this charade. Hastily he called for a shoemaker who measured Nordstrom's feet as the accused sat in the witness box. When the shoemaker measured the sheriff's feet and those of his deputy, he announced that their feet exceeded Nordstrom's in size. Thereupon each officer slipped into the famous leather boots with ease.</p>
<p>Nordstrom's alibi, that he had bough whiskey in an Issaquah saloon about 8 p.m. on Thanksgiving, was rebutted by the testimony of the saloonkeper. He had not seen the accused that night.</p>
<p>The jury got the case a few days later and decided that Nordstrom was a dam liar, and that he killed Mason. In April Judge Tom Humes sentenced Nordstrom to hang, but did not fix the date.</p>
<p>Hangings were not common in Washington. The last one had been in 1877. And some prosperous members of the Scandinavian community in Seattle felt sorry for a countryman who could not even understand the language. Did Nordstrom get a square deal? They were not sure, so they raised a purse and hired James Hamilton Lewis, the region's best-known defense lawyer.</p>
<p>Lewis, a young, slight, dapper fellow, who was easily recognizable for his bushy, pink whiskers, possessed a shrewd legal mind and fierce tenacity. Later he would serve as U.S. representative from Washington (1896-1900), and later still he would represent Illinois in the U.S. Senate with distinction.</p>
<p>Fourteen hundred dollars was a lot of money at the time, and Lewis believed in earning the fee tendered him. Thus the lawyer prepared to contest the conviction of Charley Nordstrom and test the zeal of his prosecutors. In so doing, Lewis fought the longest legal battle for the life of a condemned man in American history.</p>
<p>Initially Lewis asked for a new trial. On refusal he petitioned the state supreme court, alleging trial errors. The court refused a new trial on May 15, 1894. In June Judge Humes set the execution for Aug. 31.</p>
<p>Lewis had only begun to fight. He petitioned Judge Cornelius Hanford of the federal district court, alleging that a grand jury should have charged Nordstrom. Hanford said no. Lewis appealed the decision to the U.S. Supreme Court and Judge Humes had to 

<!-- next page -->
stay execution until the Supreme Court considered the case.</p>
<p>Legal processes have ever been slow. It was February, 1897, five-and-one-half-years after the murder, before the King County Superior Court could fix the execution again after the Supreme court affirmed Judge Hanford. Execution was set for April 23.</p>
<p>For all this time Nordstrom had been a fixture at the King County Jail, where he occupied a private cell, and maintained his sullen reputation. Seattle gamblers were willing to take bets on the outcome of the case. Smart money figured that Lewis would eventually wear down the state.</p>
<p>Many citizens considered the situation disgraceful. Law should be observed, they snorted. Why should the taxpayers support a convicted killer indefinitely just because a crafty lawyer thinks up new tricks to forestall justice? Maybe the system is all wrong.</p>
<p>The system was all wrong, argued a few, passionate opponents of capital punishment, who cheered on Lewis' efforts. These people did not want to empower the state with the right to take human life. Judicial killing violated the aspirations of humanity and civilization, they insisted.</p>
<p>Lewis tried a habeas corpus petition once more. First-degree murder had not been named in Miller's original charge, yet the jury convicted for first-degree murder. The state supreme court found no merit in this argument, so Lewis appealed to the U.S. Supreme Court.</p>
<p>On May 15, 1899, the high court dismissed the</p>

<P>The accused was apprehended two days later, and thus began the longest legal battle in U.S. history for the life of a condemned man</P>

<p>appeal. Once more the King County judge set and execution date: Aug. 6th. Seven-and-one-half years had passed since Willy Mason's dining on ham and eggs had been so crudely and tragically disrupted.</p>
<p>Lewis now decided that the long incarceration of Nordstrom at the King County Jail had made him insane. Lewis wanted a jry to decide on sanity, but the judge appointed a board of physicians. The doctors reported that Nordstrom was sullen and detached -- yet sane.</p>
<p>Since the judge had neglected to honor Lewis' petition for a formal sanity hearing, he suffered the embarrassment of another delay. Lewis had grounds for an appeal to state and federal supreme courts again.</p>
<p>In April 1901 prosecutor Walter Fulton journeyed to D.C. for the court hearing on Nordstrom, as had several of his predecessors. Fulton was as good a lawyer as Lewis, and determined that the Nordstrom case should finally be closed. It had become a disgrace. Too many people in the Northwest and elsewhere in the country had become accustomed to mocking the prosecutor and the courts over their ability to finish Nordstrom off.</p>
<p>Newspapers noted that "the veteran murderer" had been 10 years in jail and had been "sentenced to death seven times."</p>

<p>Fulton won his case in D.C. and the King County court sentenced Nordstrom to be hanged on Aug. 23, 1901.</p>
<p>Lewis demanded a sanity hearing. Fulton had seven prominent physicians declare favorably on Nordstrom's mental capacity.</p>
<p>Lewis cried that Fulton had no authorization from the court to examine Nordstrom against his will. The prisoner's Constitutional rights had been violated</p>
<p>The state supreme court declined to consider this argument.</p>
<p>Lewis tried to appeal to the federal courts. Judge Hanford wrote the defense attorney a letter explaining why the federal court lacked interest. Lewis treated the letter as a federla court ruling, and asked the U.S. Supreme Court to reverse the "ruling."</p>
<p>Fulton cautioned the superior court against Lewis' "frivolous" strategems. There was no ruling to appeal from: The execution must go forward.</p>
<p>By this time the King County court was weary of Lewis'' ingenuity. Sheriff Ed Cudihee was instructed to build a fallows in the garage adjoining the courthouse. From his cell Nordstrom could mark the progress of the carpenters.</p>
<p>Lewis and his businessman backers asked the governor to stay execution and pardon Nordstrom. The governor refused to intervene.</p>
<p>Lewis asked the Swedish Consul to interfere, but the diplomat knew better.</p>
<p>On Aug. 22, Lewis withdrew from the case, admitting that he had exhausted all possibilities for reversal or delay. A collective sigh of relief issued from the

law enforcement community. Nordstrom sobbed in his cell after Lewis' last visit. Lewis was sick, too.</p>
<p>On Aug. 23, execution day, six Scandinavian businessmen from Seattle called up on Gov. John R. Rogers for a last try. They argued that Nordstrom had only a child's intellect at the present time. "Well," replied the governor, "if a child had done the same deed, he would be hanged."</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the official invitations required by law had gone out. Merely curious spectators could not attend, only court officials, police, and doctors.</p>
<p>Although Nordstrom was only 37 years old, newsmen described his as aged. Apparently he looked about 60.</p>
<p>At long last, Nordstrom, after a god breakfast and fortified by a bottle of whisky, stepped into the gallows' trap.</p>
<p>The P-I disdained to report details of the execution. Instead, the paper editorialized on the value of the execution: "It showed that the law had not become an empty form."</p>
<p>It was clear that Nordstrom's guilt or innocence had not been an issue. "About this case has developed a desperate struggle to abolish capital punishment through indirection." The King County judges had been at fault in not resisting Lewis' efforts earlier, and insiting upon their right to complete the sentence. But finally, "the supremacy of law had been established."</p>



