<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<title>Charles Was Young, Black and Running...
by Murray Morgan</title>


<p>ON THE EVENING of September 23, 1860, the U.S. mail boat, Eliza Anderson, lay against the wharf in Olympia. A handsome craft, launched only two years earlier at Portland for service on the Columbia but diverted ot Puget Sound when her engine proved unable to outpush the river, the Anderson was usually a magnet for the curious. But a week of Indian summer weather had pulled in a southwest wind freighted with moisture; clouds screened the new moon, there was occasional rain and the dock was all but deserted. Sometime during the night a boy named Charles was able to slip undetected aboard the ship and hide.</p>
<p>Charles was about 14, and black. Born in Maryland, the son of a white father and a slave girl belonging to the R.R. Gibson family, he had been brought to Washington by James Tilton, the territorial surveyor general, a relative of the Gibsons. Territorial law did not allow slavery but neither did it abrogate the title of slaveholders. Charles remained the chattel of the Gibsons, a condition he hoped to change. If he could reach British territory in the Eliza Anderson he would be free.</p>
<p>We can imagine the emotions of the stowaway, solitary in the darkness, as he listened to the creaking and rubbing, the slap of waves, the approach and retreat of footsteps, the occasional murmur of voices. After dawn, the sounds increased as passengers, and those of the crew who had spent the night ashore, came aboard. The last of the freight was taken on. At 6:30 the whistle sounded warning, at seven blew departure.</p>
<p>The Indian stokers tossed blocks of cedar into the furnace to build quick heat. From the bridge Captain John R. Fleming shouted ot the deckhands to cast off. The walking beam began its slow pulsation, the blades of the paddlewheels stroked the green water, and the Eliza Anderson glided down Budd Inlet, away from the cluster of houes, out into the Sound, carrying Charles toward Victoria and freedom.</p>
<p>But slowly, oh so slowly. On a typical voyage, the Anderson paused at Nisqually to load livestock from the old Puget Sound Agricultrual Company range for delivery to the Hudsons Bay Comapny at Victoria, swung across the channel close to Anderson Island to see if anyone ahd left messages or goods with the Indians camped beside the clambeds, then thrashed back across the channel to Steilacoom.</p>
<p>She always stopped at Steilacoom, the prettiest town on the Sound and the oldest, with painted houses, a new brick jailhouse
<!--next page-->
and a pair of churches -- one Catholic, the other Methodist, the first north of the Columbia. The street was even cobbled in places, and beside some of the houses there were flowers still in late bloom.</p>
<p>Steilacoom's charm was lost on Charles. To him the town was a point of great danger. The military road ran from Olympia for Fort Steilacoom. If he had been missed by the surveyor General and his whereabouts suspected, a horseman galloping north would have time to intercept the Eliza Anderson here. But none came.</p>
<p>The sidewheeler pushed north, riding the ebb tide through the Narrows and, not pausing at Commencement Bay, cutting into the East Passage. At Seattle she tied up for the night at Yesler's Wharf, which stuck out into Elliot Bay from the low ground where the sawmill crouched at the tail of the skid road. The air was heavy with the raw smell fo sawdust, the new sounds penetrated Charles' hiding place --  the clink of winches, the hwine of saws, the grunt of the cookhouse which served Seattle as theater, hotel courtroom and church as well as boarding room.</p>
<p>Just before the Eliza Anderson was to leave the next morning, Captain Fleming received the next morning, Captain Fleming received word that a soldier had gone AWOL and might be hiding on the ship. He ordered a search. No soldier, but they found Charles.</p>
<p>The boy was taken before Captain Fleming, a man noted for his size, temper and profanity. Charles begged to be allowed ot work his way to Victoria but Fleming wanted no trouble with a territorial official; he may have been doubly cautious since Acting Governor Henry McGill happened to be on board. The Captain told Charles he could work his passage all right --  to Victoria and then back to Olympia, where he would be returned ot Surveyor General Tilton.</p>
<p>When Eliza Anderson docked at Victoria that afternoon, Charles was locked in the lamproom, a deckhand stationed to guard the door. Through the cabin window he could see the wooden bastion built by the Hudson's Bay Company and, sprawling around it, the town of sheds and tents that had mushroomed around the harbor following the discovery of gold on the Fraser River. A steady rain was falling. The hills behind the town were lost in the gloom, like the boy's hope of freedom.</p>
<p>Charles was not as friendless as he felt. Word of his detention was carried ashore by the passengers. In Victoria at the time were a considerable number of Negroes from the United States; some had come to hunt gold, others to get out of California where racial tension ran high. Accompanied by some English opponents of slavery, a party of blacks went to the dockand demanded that Charles be put ashore. They were ordered away by the first mate.</p>
<p>Away they went, but no farther than the office of Attorney General George HUnter Carey, whose legal advice they sought. Carey took affidavits from two witnesses, W. Gerome and W. Davis, attesting that Charles was being held illegally aboard a boat in Victoria harbor. The delegation then presented the petitions to Chief Justice David Cameron, who after studying them issued a writ of habeas corpus, directing the shriff of the Crown Colony to bring Charles to court in order that it might be decided whether his imprisonment was legal.</p>
<p>Sheriff Thomas Harris was a burly Irishman of considerable determination. He braced Captain Fleming on the Anderson, produced the writ and demanded that Charles be delivered to him. Fleming replied that the deck of the Eliza Anderson remained American soil even in a British port. He refused to unlock the lamproom door. Harris said he'd break it down. Fleming said he'd break Harris down.</p>
<p>Territorial Governor McGill, a lawyer by profession and a former private secretary to President James Buchanan, interceded. He protested that the attempt to take Charles was a violation of international law and an insult ot the flag. Besides, he argued, it was improper ot issue a writ of Habeas corpus on the basis of "frivolous testimony."</p>
<p>Sheriff Harris was unimpressed. He might not be versed int he niceties of international law, but he could count the numbers on his side. He suggested the Americans count their forces and decide whether resistance was in order.</p>
<p>Captain Fleming, in an affidavit he made out later the same day, declared that "to prevent the destruction of property and in all probability much bloodshed I opened the door of said room, and upon doing so the Sheriff took Negro from on board said vessel. Now, therefore, the undersigned protests against the whole proceeding as illegal and a breach of international law and demands the immediate delivery of said Negro that he may be returned ot his master."</p>
<p>Charles was taken to the Victoria jail for safe keeping. The next morning he was escorted to the Supreme Court Room for a hearing on his status. When Judge Cameron had adjusted his wig and taken his seat, Attorney General moved that the writ of habeas corpus be filed. He read the affidavits alleging that Charles was being held against his will on the Eliza Anderson. Such detention in itself was illegal. But even if there were doubt in Judge Cameron's mind about the right of the Court to order Charles freed from the ship, there could be no question of returning him to the ship. For, Carey pointed out, Charles was in the courtroom and on British soil, and British soil could be in bondage to another. He cited numerous authorities, especially the case of Somerset versus Steuart, in which "a gentleman from the West Indies returned to England with his slave, only to have the slave declared free."</p>
<p>Captain Fleming was called to testify. He claimed the removal of Charles from the ship was a violation of international law and warned that the case "would probably be brought under the notice of the United States government."</p>
<p>Judge Cameron ruled that the law aws clear: No man could be held slave on British soil. He held that there was no doubt about the jurisdiction of the court. He declared that the detention of Charles by Captain Fleming was illegal. He ordered that Charles be forthwith set at liberty.</p>
<p>There was applause in the courtroom, cheers and a few hisses. Charles left the court in the company of several other blacks. There is no record of what became of him. But the dispute did not end with the judge's decision.</p>
<p>The Victoria Colonist concluded a long report on the case by praising the outcome as "righteous." The Olympia Pioneer and Democrat responded with an apologetic editorial which all but declared war. Charles, said the Pioneer and Democrat, was not a runaway slave but an ungrateful protege who had been led astray by free blacks living in the Territory. "A number of black ingrates about here. who have lsot not only that respect of our citizens which was due them as niggers but were despised by people of their own color have been assiduous in their attentions to Charley and constant in their endeavors to bring about a rupture between the boy and his benefactors."</p>
<p>As for the action of the Attorney General and Chief Judge of the Crown Colony of Vancouver Island, "we are clear that the Colonial authorities and their negro constituents or masters have added another to the arbitrary and illegal acts by which they evince their hatred of the United States and its institutions. But this is a matter with which the United States Government will deal...Had there been a United States vessel of war there at the time, the affair would not have so terminated."</p>
<p>The Colonist replied urbanely that "the leading journal of that inland village" (Olympia) thought that Victoria "barely escaped annihilation through the total absence of an American naval force in our waters. Had they been here," the Colonist went on, "possibily Vancouver Island would have been towed over to Puget Sound as a fugitive from manifest destiny."</p>
<p>Surveyor General Tilton, in a formal letter of Governor McGill, "entered a respectful request that you bring the case before our Government at Washington City, to the end and that the owner of the slave may have justice and the flag of our country be vindicated and relieved from the assumption of right of search, thus made and enforced in this case."</p>
<p>Nothing came of the letter. Before it reached Washington, D.C. Abraham Lincoln had been elected. The Following April the Civil War began. The Pioneer and Democrat forgot about Charles.</p>
<p>Not so, Captain Fleming. On the Fourth of July he attached a caliope to the boilers of the Eliza Anderson and from an anchorage in the harbor serenaded Victoria with a steam-driven rendition of Yankee Doodle Dandy.</p>

<fw type="footer">Seattle Post-Intelligencer. NORTHWEST TODAY Sun., April 9, 1972 5</fw>

