<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

Letter from Seattle.

Seattle, Jan. 13, 1869.

Ed. Republican: There has been considerable excitement in this place during the past few days on account of several robberies and burglaries that have been committed in this place, and vicinity. The principal portion of which was perpetrated last Saturday night. In the early portion of the evening a cabin in the suburbs of the town, occupied by some wood-choppers, was broken open, and a revolver and some other articles stolen therefrom, and in a short time after the thieves visited the Seattle Hotel and supplied themselves with provisions, and afterward between the hours of midnight and morn they broke into the saloon of B. Crosson and abstracted what change was left in the till, some bottles of wine and brandy, cigars and a revolver. They then repaired to the bakery on the hill, broke out a pane of glass and would have entered the room had not a watchful dog been inside as it was, they obtained a supply of eggs, after which they repaired to the house of John McDonald, broke a pane from the door and reached in and unlocked the same, and stole therefrom five hundred dollars in gold coin, three pairs of boots, a pair of pants, a vest, a coat, two hats and a pair of suspenders. The room they entered, is occupied as a boot and shoe-shop: the rest of the building being occupied as a residence by his family. When Mr. McDonald became aware of the presence of some one in his house, he struck a light and repaired to the room, to find himself robbed of the money and articles before named. He immediately dressed himself, and went to the dwelling or Sheriff Wyekoff and reported his loss. Suspicion fell upon two desperadoes who have been prowling about town the past few days. Early on Sunday morning, the Sheriff summoned a posse and started in pursuit. The track of the thieves was finally found by four men P. H. Lewis, John Ross, J. Frisbe and Robert Elliot, and followed by them, by means of their footprints and the many egg-shells scattered along the trail. After following the trail about a mile and a half, they came upon a deserted logging-camp, and on examining the house found the men they were in search of asleep within. They surprised and captured them before they were fairly awake, and no doubt that it is well that they succeeded, as each thief had two revolvers and a large sling-shot, and judging from the countenances of the men, they would shoot a man at the drop of a hat, and if necessary drop the hat themselves. They were evidently sleeping off the effects of their previous night's labors and the heavy potations of wine, brandy and raw eggs that they had indulged in previously. Everything that had been stolen the night previously was found on, or about their persons except the money, one hat and one pair of boots stolen from McDonald&#8212;those things as yet, are <hi rend="italic">non est.</hi> The prisoners go by the respective names of George Bargeman and Daniel Brown. The one styling himself Geo. Bargeman is a man of low stature, heavy set with dark hair, mustache, and whiskers upon the chin. He is recognized by J. G. Saunders, lately from Oregon, as the accomplice of Sutton, in the attempt at robbery, committed by them at Independence, in Polk Co., Oregon, for which Sutton is now serving out his sentence in Oregon Penitentiary. The other, styling himself Daniel Brown, is a tall, slim man, with sandy, bushy hair, sandy mustache, &amp;c. He is supposed to be Mike Maloney, who was concerned in the murder and robbery of a milkman, near Portland; and take the two together, they are as desperate looking a pair as the eyes of man often behold.

The prisoners, on Monday, were arraigned before Justice Smith, upon four separate charges. The first charge was preferred by Young, who lives between Seattle and Salmon Bay. The charge was for breaking open his house, and taking food and apples, and killing a pig and carrying away the carcass. The court found the prisoners guilty, and sentenced them to pay a fine of $10 each and costs of court. The second charge was for breaking open the cabin of the wood-choppers and stealing articles therefrom. Found guilty of charge and sentenced to pay a fine of $25 and costs of court, (I neglected to state that the second charge was sustained only against Daniel Brown) and to stand committed until said costs and fine were paid. The third charge was preferred by B. Crosson for burglary and theft, for which they were bound over in the sum of $500 each for their appearance next term of court to be held at Seattle. The fourth charge preferred by J. McDonald, for burglary and theft, for which charge they were mulcted in bonds of $1,000 each, for their appearance in next term of court. As they will not be able to give the required bonds, they will have to remain in the custody of the Sheriff until that time, unless a requisition from Oregon should take them away from teh hands of justice here. When arrested, they had upon their persons two large bunches of sheleton keys, and a fair appointment of burglar's tools.

The Hon. Elwood Evans delivered an address before the Seattle Library Association, last evening. Subject&#8212;Puget Sound, its present and future. The address was a master effort. The delineations of history, for two centuries past were appropriately connected, and the language used was faultless, and taken as a whole reflects great credit upon the author.

Suffern &amp; Hornbeck's new steamer <hi rend="italic">Phantom</hi> came into port this afternoon. She is said to be the finest model upon the Sound. She was built to run daily between Seattle, Blakely, Orchard and Freeport. Today was her first trip upon the route. She made the trip in good time and with satisfaction to her owners. Report says that Capt. Hill's scow, <hi rend="italic">Lies Yankes</hi> was suck a few days ago, between Whatcom and Port Madison. She was loaded with thirty tons of coal and sunk in sixteen fathoms of water, and will prove a total loss. Business is brisk, and every body busy. Weather fine and the goose hangs high.

Yours, Tryon.