<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
To Port Townsend and Back.

Ed. Republican&#8212;Having just returned from a trip down the Sound, as far as Port Townsend, I have concluded to to give you the benefit of a few items picked up in the course of my journey. It was court week in Townsend, and the newly appointed popular Judge of the 3d Judicial District presided to the entire satisfaction of members of the bar and the public. The docket did not present a large amount of business. The case of Smith, charged with the murder of the mate of an English bark&#8212;brought to Port Townsend by a change of venue, was sent back to Seattle from whence it came. F. A. Wilson's application for divorce was summarily granted&#8212;no counsel appearing in the behalf of the defendant. Fred is himself again. Isaac Thurston, head lawyer at the Teckalet Mills, both of whose legs were broken and badly bruised last June, has nearly recovered under the efficient care and treatment of Dr. G. V. Calhoun. The generous attention of Mr. M. S. Drew, business manager at Teckalet, and the liberality of the mill company in bearing all expenses in this case are spoken of in terms of highest praise, by all acquainted with the circumstances. I learn that Port Discovery mills are now doing a larger business in the manufacture of lumber, than ever before, under the able management of Charley Wood&#8212;that indefatigable good fellow, whom every body likes. Charley is a P.B., which is, a perfect brick.&#8212;Long may he wave.

I found friend Pettygrove of the <hi rend="italic">Message</hi> in a box&#8212;not a bad box, but a Jury box. He got nipped on the Grand Jury&#8212;all becausd printers are known to be sensible fellows, and of such are the kingdom of Jury-men usually made up. If you havn't received the last <hi rend="italic">Message</hi>, you can charge it to the Grand Jury of Port Townsend. I doubt if friend Pettygrove receives the patronage he deserves in Jefferson; but he will do so, by and by, you bet. Al., old boy, you have my best wishes.

I have another item of information which I cannot refrain from giving the public through your paper: J. G. Swan, Esq., well known as the author of an interesting book on Washington Territory, is about to publish another work on the same subject, under the auspices of the Smithsonian Institute. I cannot doubt but this new book, now in press, will fully sustain Mr. Swan's well earned reputation as a historical and statistical writer. Success to the enterprise.

Among the legal fraternity in attendance at the Port Townsend Court was the old gentleman "with the large and generous heart" from Saunders Bottom. He did not seem to be overfraught with legal business, any more than the other members of the bar, and had I not known, as everybody knows, that he "never talks politics" I might have thought that his mission down the Sound was of a political character. He was observed to be "sloshing around" quite actively among the Cops, very much like a man trying to run away from a nomination for Congress; but how this is, I don't pretend to say. It may be safe however, for old Newell and his Excellency to keep their eyes peeled; for the movements of Saunders Bottom are at least suspicious and somewhat ominous&#8212;if not more so. The worthy Governor should "swing round the circle" from Swinimish to Walla Walla as often as possible.

The ocean steamer <hi rend="italic">Geo. S. Wright</hi>, Capt. Langdon, arriving at Townsend on Thursday evening at 5 o'clock, I concluded to return on her to Olympia; and I am very glad I did so, as I had a most pleasant trip, and had the satisfaction of seeing any old friend Sutton, first engineer, and forming the acquaintance of Capt. Langdon and Purser Turbell, the gentlemanly and accommodating officers of the vessel. Mr. Tarbell informed me that it is the intention of the owners of the <hi rend="italic">Wright</hi> to make monthly trips between Portland and Olympia, in case sufficient business offers to warrant the undertaking. The people of the Sound are interrested in a direct communication with the Columbia river, and it is to be hoped the necessary encouragement will be given to make this enterprise a permanent thing.

Among the passengers of the <hi rend="italic">Wright</hi> I had the pleasure of receiving an introduction to Mr. Philip Ritz from Walla Walla, an active friend of the Northern Pacific Railroad. Mr. Ritz is the gentleman who addressed a letter to Congress last session on the subject of this great work, which received the attention and commendation of Gen. Grant and other prominent men at the National Capital. Mr. R. is on a tour of inspection, for the purpose of collecting information in regard to this most interesting subject. He left the <hi rend="italic">Wright</hi> at Steilacoom, but I understand will be here in a few days.

Yours,
S.
