<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
How it was done in King County.

The following graphic account of the doings of Hon. John J. McGilvra, late U.S. Attorney of this Territory, who urged the nomination of B. F. Dennison as Delegate so that he might secure the succession to the Judgeship; who voted in the Vancouver Convention for the nomination of Hon. S. Garfielde, and then supported Gov. Moore through the canvass and at the polls, illustrates the unserupulous career and humiliating fall of one bolter. It is from the pen of one of the most staunch and reliable of the Republicans of King County, who labored zealously to defeat the machinations of Howe, the Dennys, Lord of the Custom House, and McGilvra, whose labors reduced the Union majority of King County from about 50, which it could have given, to 10:

Seattle, June 23, 1869.

Editor Territorial Republican: A few facts concerning out late election in this county, and I am done with politics for this year at least. It is well known to all, that we have in our midst a certain little attorney who is extremely egotistical, selfish, ambitious and unscrupulous. He it was who headed the bolters Convention in this county and by shrewd wire-pulling with the bolters and a promise to secure thirty Republican votes for Moore, he managed to get himself nominated on the bolters' ticket for Representative, and a blank left on the Democratic ticket, which was to be filled on the day of election with his (the attorney's) name. Such was the programme, and of course, our little attorney was sanguine of his election by a large majority. But to make his majority double and to defeat the entire Republican ticket, which he avers was the most corrupt ever offered to an unsuspecting people, he must make a canvass of the County, which he did by making his appointments at the several precincts throughout the County, with a modest request that the opposing candidates meet him on the stumpt, but from fear or some more plausible reason, he had no opposition from his opposing candidates, but was let down a peg by a few of the citizens who happened to hear him misrepresent&#8212;and took him to task with the results as will soon appear. But time rolls on and the day of election is at hand. Never was our attorney so sanguine as then&#8212;the battle commences by our said attorney rolling up a barrel of beer to his office, where he can be found all day manufacturing tickets and treating or standing treat for all who would promise to be faithful. By noon our attorney calculated that he had secured enough votes to in sure his election provided he did not get another vote during the day, but he did not relax his efforts, for 200 majority would only serve to show his great popularity. But the polls must close and at 6 o'clock the efforts of our attorney ccase. Of course, the count by the Judges will show him the most popular man in King County. My pledge to the Democracy to carry thirty Republican votes for Moore, besides my stand taken (squarely on the Democratic platform) and the assistance of the whole delegation of bolters must secure me the heaviest majority ever given mortal man from this County. With these reflections our attorney mounts his fiery charger and retires to the quiet retreat of Laurel shade, there to exult over the overwhelming defeat of all his opposers. But alas, how apt are the calculations of men to be upset. At 2 o'clock that night the judges had finished their count, and in this, Seattle precinct, our little attorney had just one minority. Ye Gods! what rascality has been at work&#8212;but still I am elected, for the country precincts have been canvassed by myself in person and they will go unanimously for me. But precinct after precinct is heard from, and after they are all counted, our little attorney receives just twenty-nine votes outside of Seattle precinct. Thunderstruck and humiliated he retires again to the quiet retreat of Laurel Shade, never to be seen again before the people of King County a candidate for any office. But having suffered financially he, with the shrewdness pecular to himself, resorts to measures to make himself whole. There is that keg of beer not all drunk up, about four gallons left, which I will take down to the brewery and get credit for that amount; which he does and saves two dollars. There we left him, and what other dodge he will resort to, remains to be seen, and thus perishes the ambitious hopes of our pet of the bolters' Convention. Let it teach the honest of that deluded class to come squarely up to the rack, and stand the result like men, and not strive to break up the party that has honored them with office from their first settlement in the County until now.

Republican.
