<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>Pioneer Judges and Lawyers</head>
<ab>Introduction:</ab>
<p>The Northwest frontier shaped everything and everyone that came in contact with it, including the law, lawyers and judges. Jurists and lawyers faced discomfort and danger as they "rode the circuit" through the sparsely settled region, bringing both justice and entertainment to isolated communities. Courtroom facilities were often crude, and standards of justice then were often very different from those of today. Knowledge of the law was sometimes lacking, but frontier justice was not always based on what the law said.</p>
<p>John J. McGilvra had more legal training than most lawyers in the area when President Lincoln appointed him U.S. Attorney for Washington Territory in 1861. McGilvra was also an astute observer of men and events. In the early 1890's he wrote the following article about some of the pioneer judges and lawyers of Washington. It was published as a chapter in Rev. Harvey K. Hines' Illustrated History of Washington.</p>

<head>Early Washington Bar</head>
<p>In ascending the Columbia river from Vancouver to Walla Walla on the old steamer "Okanogan," we were wrecked at the John Day's Rapids, and had to lie there for three days and until the steamer "George S. Wright" came up the river. In making a sharp turn in the river at that point, the current caught the bow of the boat, and threw it around and back down stream, where one of the compartments in the hull was caught on a sharp protruding rock, and the vessel was there held careened sidewise at an angle of over thirty degrees until after we left her. Stil, we had plenty to eat and plenty of blankets, so that all hands were made comfortable on board or on shore, as the passengers chose. We had a boat and spent much of the time fishing in the John Day's river. Colonel A.C. Gibbs, a member of the Portland Bar and afterward Governor of the State of
<pb/>
Oregon, was the Izaak Walton of our party.</p>
<p>In due time we arrived at Walla Walla, at that time a veritable mining town. Every public house was a gambling saloon, and gambling was as open as daylight. In fact, the foreman of the jury was Colonel Stone, of the firm of Stone &amp; Ball, the principal gambling house in town. Colonel Stone was not only a good member of the grand jury in general, but when the question came up of indicting the gambling houses he voted for it every time.</p>
<p>The court was held in the second story or loft of one of these gambling houses, approached by outside stairs, and it was one of the most, if not the most, primitive temples of justice that ever existed in any country. The building was constructed of hewed sticks of timber, clapboarded on the outside but entirely unfinished on the inside. The naked, hewed logs at the sides, and the rought joists and rafters overhead was the inside finsih.</p>
<p>Some Indians had killed a Frenchman six or seven miles from Walla Walla few days before court convened, and while court was in session one of the Indians arrested confessed, and offered to conduct the sheriff
<pb/>
to the spot where the body was buried. As the event was an important one, the court adjourned, and the sheriff, judge and prosecuting attorney, and others, accompanied the Indian to the spot indicated, where, sure enough, we found the body buried at the roots of a tree, about a foot under ground.</p>
<p>The Frenchman was a returned miner who had been camping near where his body was found, and the motive for the killing was money; but we found $500 in gold coin fastened under one arm, beneath his clothing which the murderers had failed to find.</p>
<p>There was no jail in the county then and the accused Indians, two in number, were manacled and chained to staples driven in the walls of the court room. The attorneys' seats were common benches, and there was one small table in the room, which in the evening was sometimes used by the attorneys for a social game of cards. The cards were deposited for safe keeping during the day one the judge's desk, which was an old-fashioned wash-stand.</p>
<p>One day, during the session of court, one of the Indian prisoners, by getting the length of his chain from the wall, and reaching well out, got possession of the cards, and during the balance of the day's session the Indians
<pb/>
enjoyed themselves in a series of social games. A cut of that scene would make a good view for one of our magazines.</p>
<p>The United States attorney and his immediate predecessor, Butler P. Anderson, in September, 1861, traveled together from Olympia to Vancouver to attend that term of the court. At Burbank's Hotel, at Monticello, the shipping point for Portland and Vancouver, they met some returning miners who had two Cayuse ponies with saddles and bridles for sale at twenty-five dollars for each horse, with the saddle and bridle. The horses had been turned out to pasture, but as the saddles and bridles were worth about that sum, the ex-United States attorney and successor purchased the outfits. Anderson returned first, and of course had his choice as to ponies; whether he got the best one or not was never known, but the one left was not of much account, and on the return, at Jackson's, a half day's ride from Monticello, gave out and the attorney traded him off for another, giving five dollars to boot. At Pumphry's twelve miles further on, he again traded, getting seven and a half dollars to boot, and at Van Warmers', thirty miles from Olmpia, sold his poney for twenty-five dollars,
<pb/>
took his saddle and bridle and went on to Olympia in the stage for $2.50, having cleared the saddle bridle in the operation.</p>
<p>Anderson, who was a Mississippian and a brother of General Patterson Anderson, soon returned to the South, also, and it is believed entered the Confederate army, but the writer is not certain as to that.</p>
<p>The winter of 1861 and two was the hardest ever known in this country, either before or since that time. Snow commenced to fall on Christmas, 1861, and lay on the ground until April, 1862.</p>
<p>The terms of court were so arranged at that time with reference to the convenience of the United States Marshal and attorney that the last term in the spring and the first terms in the fall should be held east of the Cascade mountains. Consequently the writer, as United States attorney, was required to spend the summer in Eastern Washington.</p>
<p>A light, covered spring-wagon and a good span of Indian ponies were considered the best means of transporation for himself and family consisting of a wife and two small children, as there was no rail and but little water transportation on the lines to be traversed. Conse-
<pb/>
quently, about the middle of March, thus equipeed, we started from Olympia to make the portage to Columbia river through snow and mud. At about thirty miles from Olympia we had to employ an extra team, and at Pymphry's Landing, on the Cowlitz, we had to ship the wife, babies and wagon on two canoes lashed together, taking through the deep snow, and meeting again at Monticello, at which point we shipped on board a steamer for Vancouver, landing, however, about six miles below Vancouver at a point opposite the mouth of the Willamette, as the steamer was bound for Portland.</p>
<p>After attending a term of court at Vancouver, we again shipped for the Dalles, and from that place followed the old stage road to Walla Walla.</p>
<p>At Butter creek our horses were stolen, and we went into Walla Walla with a mule and a sore-backed poney hired for the occasion from some miners en route for the Boise and Oro Fino country. A reward was offered for the ponies, and while attending the court at Walla Walla they were returned to use not much the worse for wear, but plainly marked by packsaddles. They had been packed to the Powder River mines.</p>
<pb/>
<p>We afterward went to Lewiston and the Lapwai Indian Reservation, and also to Colville, with this same outfit, and finally traded it off for a house and lot in Walla Walla and went to housekeeping. We bought a cook-stove, carpet, and some old-fashioned wooden-bottomed chairs, all we could obtain in Walla Walla; out bedsteads, tables, etc., we made ourselves, and with calico window curtains, and such other things to match as we could make or purchase, we were not only comfortable but cozy.</p>
<p>Wehn we arrived at Walla Walla, being a United States official, we were invited to take possession of some vacant officers' quarters, which we gladly did, and on starting out for Lewiston at the close of the term of Court, the Quarter Master loaned us a good wall-tent with a fly, and after that we had comfortable quarters whenever we camped.</p>
<p>At Lewiston, which was then literally a city of tents, we had one of the best houses in town.</p>
<p>Lewiston, which was a mining town, was situated upon the Lapwai Reservation, but spirituous liquors and wine, as well as malt liqours, were brought in by the cargo, notwithstanding the Indian intercourse act making 
<pb/>
it a crime punishable by both fine and imprisonment to take spiritous liqour or wine into the Indian country.</p>
<p>Early in July, 1862, Judge Oliphant, Selucius Garfielde, Shell Fargo, Chalie Allen, the butler at Walla Walla military post, and myself started from Walla Walla to Colville for the purpose of holding a term of the district court, the first ever held at the latter place. We had the ponies and wagon already described and two riding mules. The distance was 210 miles, and there was no inhabitant on the road except a ferryman at the crossing of the Snake river and another at the crossing of the Spokane, about eighteen miles below the present city of Spokane.</p>
<p>We carried our grub and slept under two small fly tents. Garfielde was a good cook, having had more experience then the rest of us. A frying-pan and coffee-pot composed our cooking outfit. We baked our bread in the frying-pan, broiled our bacon before the fire on sharpened sticks, catching the drippings on our fresh-baked bread, and settled our coffee with cold water, using buffalo chips mostly for fuel. The bread, bacon and coffee on that trip had a relish that 
<pb/>
it has seldom been the good fortune of the writer to enjoy.</p>
<p>On the route, and somewhere near Medical Lake, we met the Colville garrison, consisting of regular troops ordered east, having been relieved by Oregon and Washington volunteers. The officers, of course, had some good commissary whisky along, of which we were invited to partake.</p>
<p>Shell Fargo was the teamster, and although it was not observed that he had appropriated more than his share of the commissary, it was not long after we had parted company with the soldiers before he upset the wagon and spilled out his passengers, Judge Oliphant and Salucius Garfielde.</p>
<p>Garfielde was smoking at the time, and Fargo always insisted that he never lost his hold or ceased to puff on that old pipe; Garfielde was a man not easily disturbed; but not so with Oliphant; although not hurt, his nerves were considerably shaken up.</p>
<p>Upon arrivign at Colville we were offered quarters at the military post. Park Winnan was appointed clerk of the court; the sheriff summoned a grand and petit jury and the business of the term commenced. No court
<pb/>
having been before organized and this being the first term, of course there were no cases on the docket. The people of Colville had looked forward to the first term of the court with a good deal of interest and were anxious to make a good showing with a view to regular terms thereafter. Consequently the grand jury indicted every one suspected of doing wrong, and all the people who had disputes to settle came into court, waived the service of process, made up the issues in their causes and went to trial. The result was that several criminal and civil cases were tried, two or three divorces granted, and Garfielde andy myself made about $750 each.</p>
<p>Shell Fargo was appointed United States Marshal.</p>
<p>During this term of court all hands went over to the Hudson Bay Post, about fifteen miles north of Colville, then in charge of McDonald. This Hudson Bay Post was near the Kettle Falls in the Columbia river, and at these falls were the principal fisheries of the upper Columbia, from which several tribes of Indians derived their main sustenance.
<pb/>
When we were there several acres of ground were occupied by drying and smoking the salmon already caught.</p>
<p>On the return trip from Colville to Walla Walla Judge Oliphant was very anxious to get sight of a coyote, as we could hear them in the distance nearly every night. The last night before reaching Walla Walla, we camped on the Touchet, where we got some oats in the sheaf for our horses, which were picketed out near our tents. In the night we heard a racket among the horses and I got up and went out to see what the trouble was. I found several Indian ponies, called "cayuses," taking the feed from our own ponies, which intruders I drove away and then returned to bed. Garfielde asked what was the matter, and I replied that there were a lot of cayuses around, when up jumped Judge Oliphant and enquired, "Where are they? where are they?" I replied that they were just outside not far from our animals. Out the Judge went, half dressed, but after a short time returned saying that he could not see any cayuses. Garfielde remarked that probably they had gone away, and that "you never could find that breed of Indian ponies when you wanted 
<pb/>
them, anyway!" At that, Oliphant, who had gotten into bed again, raised up and shrieked "Ponies! Ponies! I though you said they were [coyotes."] When Oliphant finally saw the joke that had been played on him, he was as much out of humor as such a good soul could be, and didn't speak to any of us for several days, unless he was obliged to!</p>
<p>Judge Oliphant was an elderly man, of large frame and equally large heart, unaccustomed to the rough ways of the Western wilds, and he soon tired of his position as Judge. After holding terms of court at Oro Fino and Boise City among the miners, who carried their revolvers in the court-room as elsewhere, the Judge resigned to take a clerkship in the General Land Office in Washington city, where he could live in peace and quiet, and there spent the balance of his days.</p>
<p>In consequence of the obliging disposition of Judge Oliphant and his desire to please everyone, and especially the attorneys, he sometimes got himself into an awkward predicament.</p>
<p>During the fall term of 1862 at Walla Walla, Judge Lander^2 and General Bridges were
<pb/>
pitted against each other in a cause that came up for hearing on demurrer. Judge Lander made a speech in support of the demurrer, and the Judge promptly decided in his favor with out waiting to hear Geenral Bridges; but Bridges as promptly jumped to his feet, saying. "Hold on, Judge; I have a right to be heard!"</p>
<p>"Well," says the Judge, "what have you got to say?" Whereupon the general launched out upon an argument that soon convinced the Judge that his first ruling was wrong, whereupon he as promptly decided in favor of the general; but Lander, of course, was not satisfied and claimed his right to the closing argument and proceeded with his side of the case. At the close of Judge Lander's argument, Judge Oliphant threw himself back in his chair and with his arms hanging lossely by his side in despair exclaimed; "Gentlemen, I wish I could please you both!" adjourned the court and took the case under advisement. . . .</p>
<p>The next session of court was the annual session of the Supreme Court for 1862 '63. It was during this term of the Supreme Court that B. F. Kendall was shot and killed by a young man by the name of Howe.</p>
<p>Kendall was an able man but a bitter partisan and relentless foe. At the time of
<pb/>
his death he was Superintendent of the Indian Affairs for Washington Territory, and was also the propritor and editor of a newspaper published in Olympia. Kendall took occasion, with or without cause, to attack most bitterly young Howe's father in his newspaper. The elder Howe, meeting Kendall on the streets of Olympia, undertook to castigate him with a cane, but Kendall defended himself with a revolver and wounded Howe, though not seriously. It was after this that young Howe espoused the quarrel of his father, and, as it was understood at the time, demanded of Kendall a retraction of the article containing an attack upon the elder Howe. The final meeting was in Kendall's office, without the presence of any third person, with the result that Kendall was shot dead. Public sentiment was divided as to the merits of the Kendall Howe controversy and as Kendall had many bitter enemeies, although young Howe was committed for murder, the grand jury failed to indict him, and he was liberated after almost three months' imprisonment in the Thurston county jail. Young Howe removed to California where he soon died of consumption.</p>
<pb/>
<p>At the fall term of court, 1862, several indictments were found by the grand jury at Port Townsend against Victor Smith, then collector of customs for the Puget Sound district. Smith had previously procured the removal of the customhouse from Port Townsend to Port Angeles, and of course the feeling was very bitter at Port Townsend against him. Smith procured a change of venue from Port Townsend to Olympia, and when the proper time arrived, boarded the revenue cutter with his witnesses and set sail for Olympia. The people of Port Townsend, not to be outdone by Victor Smith, chartered a streamer, which they designated as "Revenue Cutter No. 2." and with the attorneys, witnesses, etc., for the prosecution, also set sail for Olympia.</p>
<p>The indictments against Smith contained numerous counts for all sorts of crimes and misdemeanors, most of which were no doubt imaginary. After considerable skirmishing on the part of the respectively attorneys, these cases were continued until the spring term of 1863, and were then dismissed by order of the Secretary of the Treasury.</p>
<p>The war upon Victor Smith was not wholly confined to Port Townsend. Smith was the 
<pb/>
warm personal friend and protege of Salmon P. Chase, Secretary of the Treasury, and was disposed to run the politics of the Territory.</p>
<p>Dr. Anson G. Henry, Surveyor General of the Territory, was an old personal friend and former family physician of President Lincoln, and he was also disposed to assume the rule of political boss.</p>
<p>There was, therefore, an irrepressible conflict between Smith and Henry, which could end only with the absolute defeat of the one or the other. After the dismissal of the Smith indictments, the war was transferred to Washington city. Henry having the ear of Lincoln, and Smith that of Chase. Finally, in the winter of 1864 '65 Henry and Smith both went to the city of Washington in person, and the final result was the removal of Smith from the office of collector of customs.</p>
<p>A sigular circumstance connected with this contest was that both Henry and Smith, on their return trip home, were fellow passengers on the ill-fated steamer, "Brother Jonathan,"^3 which was lost in the early spring of 1865 off Crescent Harbor, on the California coast, and both perished in the wreck.</p>
<pb/>
<p>Some funny things happened in connection with the administration of justice in these early days.</p>
<p>In 1864 or 1865, the sheriff of Island county and one of his deputies were indicted for murder. They were charged with killing an Indian at Coupeville, on Whidby Island. They were arrested and held in bail, but in the meantime, beween their examination and the next term of court, continued to perform the duties of the sheriff's office, which in part consisted in summoning a portion of the grand jury and petit jury for the next term at Port Townsend when and where are they to be tried. They were duly indicted, and patiently awaited their turn to be tried, the sheriff, in the meantime, acting as one of the bailiffs of the court, until the judge's attention was called to the fact, when his service at the term of court was dispensed with, notwithstanding his vigorous protest.</p>
<p>There were several murder cases on the docket of that term. One was against a man by the name of Martin for killing one Kelly at Port Ludlow. Wyehe presided, Judge Dennison and myself prosecuted, and Judge Mc-
<pb/>
Fadden and Frank Clarke defended.</p>
<p>It was during thsi trial that Franke Clarke objected to a very popular question asked the witness by Judge Dennison, and the presiding Judge in surprise asked Clarke what his objection was, when Frank replied that his objection was not so much to the question itself as to the very grave and solemn manner in which it was asked!</p>
<p>The result of the Martin case was a prompt acquittal by the jury, much to the disgust of the judge, who, after repremanding the jury, announced that the balance of the capital cases would be continued to the next erm. Thereupon, the attorney for the Island county sheriff undertook to argue the matter with the court as to the sheriff's case, and finally the sheriff, himself, no doubt thinking the attorney was not making much headway, arose and announced to the court that he was now present and read to be tried, and that he did not propose to dance attendance at the next term of court, which would convene about harvest time, a very busy season for him. The court, however, ordered the sheriff itno custody and continued the cases. It is needless to say the sheriff was never convicted.</p>
<pb/>
<p>Charles Ben Darwin was the successor of Judge Oliphant, and held his first term at Seatle. . . .</p>
<p>It was at his term that the celebrated case of James Crow vx. Thomas Alvord was tried before Darwina ned a jury. Alvord had killed a female pup belongin to Crow, that was supposed to be the making of a good bear dog, a valuable animal in those days.</p>
<p>The case was first tired before Justice McMillan near where Kent now is, by the partities without attorneys, but as the jury failed to agree, Crow employed the writer to go up adn re-try the case, and Alvord employed Dick Ward on his side.</p>
<p>The only law book, aside from the Territorial Statutes, used in this trial, was a couple of leaves cut from an old number of Peterson's Magazine containing a fine steel engraving of a beautiful hound, and a poem descriptive of his many good qualities!</p>
<p>Having to ride on horse-back some twenty miles over a rough trail, it was impracticable to carry much of a law library, even if it had been at hand, and would not have been of great use in any event.</p>
<pb/>
<p>The scene of the poem and engraving was laid in the Highlands of Scotland. Luarth, the high-bred and noble greyhound of Chieftain Cameron, had been shot by some miscreant and had come home to die on his master's hearth-rug. Chieftain Cameron sits by the open fire-place with his trusty fire-lock across his knee, looking down into the appealing of vengeance, while his daughters, Jenny and Cathleen, stand on either side, giving vent to their grief in a shower of tears. The poem was a pathetic description of the worth, attachment and fidelity of the expiring victim of some secret enemy.</p>
<p>This engraving and poem settled the question with that jury, and the plaintiff obtained a judgement for $20, and defendant appealed. At the trial in the district court, Judge Dennison was employed as assistant counsel for plaintiff, and Judge McFadden and Frank Clark employed for the defense. In the argument to the jury, Judge Dennison read Byron's inscription upon a monument to a Newfoundland dog. I again exhibited the engraving and read the poem, while Judge McFadden made some
<pb/>
quotations from Shakespeare not quite so complimentary to the dog and exhibiting some of his worse qualities.</p>
<p>This was the great case of that term, and resulted in a verdict of ten cents for the plaintiff, which, however, carried the costs, amounting to over $300, besides the attorney's fees.</p>
<p>At the last term of the court held by Judge Oliphant in Seattle, in 1863, I think during the trial of a cause, the writer had occasion as he thought, to criticize very severly some act of the auditor of King county, when he was interrupted by the Judge, who thought the criticism too severe! but the attorney persisting, the judge finally screamed out: "Sit down, Mr. McGilvra; sit down! I want you to understand when the court is 'roused, it's ______ 'roused!" The strong rising inflection upon the first " 'roused", and the marked following inflection upon the last " 'roused," made the scene so ridiculous that the bar commenced to laugh, and, finally seeing the humorous side of the affair, the judge joined in the laugh, and so the matter ended. . . .</p>
<pb/>
<p>McFadden was another Judge who made a success in his practice upon retiring to the bar. . . .</p>
<p>Soon after Judge Jacobs had ascended the bench, McFadden had occasion to appear before him to settle the pleadings in a certain cause, when Jacobs was particularly severe in his criticism of McFadden's answer in the case. Jacobs intimated that an office boy ought to draw a better pleading. Judge McFadden arose, and in his blandest manner said: "May it please the Court, when I occupied the position your Honor now fills with so much grace, I never had any difficulty in knowing what the law was; but I find it very different when I get down here," and sat down! That is the only time I ever saw Judge Jacobs blush, and he lost no time in calling the next case. . . .</p>
<p>These are only a few of the incidents of the olden times that come floating down on memory through the lapse of many years.</p>
<p>While the country was new and rough, and sparsely settled, there was really a great deal of important business for the 
<pb/>
courts to do, and so far as ability and integrity is concerned, the bench and bar of those days will compare favorably with the bench and bar of to-day.</p>
<p>One marked difference is that it required mroe nerve then than it does now on the part of both bench and bar to perform the respective duties of their office in good faith and fearlessly.</p>
<p>I once prosecuted a defendant in this town for assault with intent to kill, and convicted him, too, when I knew a drunken attorney for the defense had a pistol in his pocket for my benefit and had threatened to use it.</p>
<p>In those days it required true courage to enable a man to live up to the standard of his convictions. . . .</p>
<pb/>
<p>Footnotes</p>
<p>1. James Patton Anderson was appointed U.S. Territorial Marshal when Washington Territory was established in 1853. Two years later he was elected delegate to Congress. In 1857 he was appointed Governor of the territory, but did not take office. During the Civil War Anderson served briefly as a Confederate Congressman and as a Major-General in the Confederate Army.</p>
<p>2. Edward Lander, a justice of the Territorial Supreme Court during the Indian Wars of the 1850's, was arrested for defying Gov. Stevens' declaration of martial law. He then fined Stevens for being in contempt of court, but the governor pardoned himself. Lander was later a prominent attorney in Washington for many years.</p>
<p>3. The Brother Jonathon, one of the first steamships to operate on the west coast, struck a rock and sank near Crescent City, California July 30, 1865. More than 200 persons were drowned, including Gen. George Wright, Victor Smith and Anson G. Henry. Treasure seekers have tried without success for more than a century to recover a $200,000 Army payroll that was on the ship.</p>