<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

[From the Marysville (Cal.) Appeal.] 

Who Introduced the Chinaman?

The Democratic party are not pleased at the result of the work of their own party. They are making a great ado about Chinese immigration, when the Chinaman, if he owes anybody anything, is indebted to the Democratic party for the blessings of life on American soil. If the Chinaman was a voter to-day, how quick the Democratic organs would print, in Chinese characters, how much the Democratic party had done for him? An aggregated account of the treaties of "peace, amity and commerce" with the Emperor of China, under Buchanan's administration, would be scattered like leaves in October, through the land as an electioneering document. And as the Democratic leaders now labor to secure the African vote, so they would fish for the Asiatic. If the presence of Chinese is a "curse" to California Democrats, let the Democratic party stand sponsor to the cursed brats. But a few years ago all the newspapers, Whig as well as Democratic, were boasting of our navy in the Chinese waters. An American Commodore had been sent by Buchanan to China to break inside the Chinese wall, let in the American traders and let out the Chinese laborers. We wanted to buy teas for the million, and silks for the aristocracy, direct from the Celestial Kingdom, instead of buying of Johnny Bull, and paying him a big profit. We wanted a more extended field for our Yankee ships, and a direct trade was opened with China by a Democratic administration. This trade led to Chinese immigration. The Democrats burglariously entered the Celestial Kingdom (the only one many of them will ever reach) and the Chinamen began to go out to America. Before California was acquired from Mexico, the Chinamen visited New York, Boston, Philadelphia and New Orleans. During the administration of James Buchanan we recollect seeing a small Chinese junk lying near the Battery in the Bay of New York. This was the first "Democratic importation" from the land opened to trade and commerce by the acute statesmen about the White House. The sourthern nabobs wanted to silks to wear. "Cotton was King" about those days. Niggers were "no whar" and "white folks somebody!"

Now we are not saying that Buchanan did not show wisdom and statesmanship by breaking up the exclusiveness insisted upon by the Chinese nation&#8212;by knocking a hole through the great wall through which John Chinaman might make his exit to the United States. It was a commercial enterprise creditable to our government and to the party at its head. Subsequent administrations have followed in the steps of its illustrious predecessor, until China is at our door. We are now sending steamships in the path of our ships of war. We think so much of these "Democratic prodigies" that we subsidise our vessels and send them every month after a load of Chinamen, rice, silks and opium. We have built a railroad across the continent, to run in connection with our vessels on the Pacific and China sea. The Chinaman is going "overland" to America, England, and France. It will not be long before he will be lumbering in Maine, picking cotton in South Carolina, and weaving cloths in Massachusetts. These Democratic "curses" are numerous enough to go around; and we are bringing over those Democratic "curses" by the thousands. We are carrying out the treaties made by Buchanan, and it seems to us that Democratic papers exhibit a wonderful degree of impudence by endeavoring to make the Republican party responsible for the legitimate results of their own party's acts. When will Chinamen cease to be eyesores to the Democracy? When they are naturalized on the wholesale principle, and vote the Democratic ticket to a man.