<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

ROUTINE OF THE COURT.

Various Watters which Occupied the Time of Judge Burke and The Attorneys To-day.

When Judge Burke ascended the judicial desk this morning he saw a well filled court house before him, and everything looking like business. The following petit jurors were excused: T. M. Boone, W. G. Latimer (Treasurer elect), M. McDougall, Patrick Walsh, Henry <unclear>Sheehan</unclear> (policeman), F. D. Spragne, F. W. Wusthoff, H. B. de, Wm. Jordan and ex Mayor W. H. <unclear>Shoudy</unclear>. It was found necessary to order another venire, returnable in the afternoon.

Mr. A. C. Bowman was appointed court reporter for the term.

In the $277 damages case of Washington C. Rutter against the Northern Pacific for refusing to carry J. W. Rutter and J. H. Rutherford on their tickets beyond Spokane Fails to Portland last May, and which was appealed from Justice Jones' court, where the jury awarded plaintiff $100 damages. Attorney Ashton for defendants secured leave to amend the answer, and put in some additional facts. 

Mr. B. J. Tallman was appointed to take testimony in the case of William Selby vs. Mary Selby, and report findings of fact.

Messrs. White &amp; Munday for plaintiff in the case of the Pacific Metal Works against the Columbia Cannery Company, entered a motion for judgement for default the time allowed defendant in which to answer having expired.

Mr. M. W. Lovejoy, was admitted to practice on motion of Fred <unclear>Rice</unclear> Powell, Mr. Lovejoy presenting Maine Supreme Court papers.

The court allowed a change of venue to Tacoma in the cases of the United States against George H. Lathrop and Snyder, Steven &amp; Co., for recovery of saw logs alleged to have been cut upon Government land in Pierce County.

Adjournment was taken at 11:45 until 1:30 p.m.

On motion of Mr. Trusten P. Dyer this afternoon, Messrs. George B. Chapin, presenting a certificate form the Phillips County District Court of Kansas, and John Parker Gale, from the Supreme Court of Massachusetts, the later being associate of Messrs. Burke &amp; Haller, were admitted to practice.

PETIT JURORS.
Sheriff Cochrane returned the following special venire of 28 jurors: Michael Eagan, Robert Fitzhenry, M. V. Stewart, W. W. Parker, David Monroe, George O. Elliott, J. A. Peabody, James Campbell, Charles Robinson, Eugene Cullity, J. E. Bennett, I Code, M. McAndrews, David Ross, J. H. Griswold, Robert Parker, W. W. Easton, J. McRedmond, J. D. Malarkev, Ben Murphy, George Foster, A. P. Truman, J. G. Saglien, J. G. Allen, John W. Huff, Thomas Hood, W. Carter and J. v. <unclear>Taylor</unclear>.

This venire was accepted, except J. H. Griswold, A. P. Truman and W. Carter. The following gentlemen of the old venire were added, making the number from which to select a jury 37: C. M. Templeton, L. M. Parker, A. <unclear>Becktrum</unclear>, John Lannigan, Alfred Thurlow, O. G. Rose, Philo Rutherford, S. Tickner, Emil Holm, Ed Langton, John Graf and W. M. Maxwell. The jurors were all sworn for Territorial petit jurors, and were subsequently personally <unclear>summoned</unclear> by Marshal Hamilton as a United States petit jury, also to appear at 9 a. m. Monday.

The two men, <unclear>Kilney</unclear> and McDowel, against whom true bills were not found by the Grand Jury, were duschared. Vendetta's case will come up to-morrow. Diamond's case was taken up about 3:30. He was originally arrested for a "vag," but a watch and some jewelry discovered upon his person, was traced <unclear/> a Front street jewelry store which had been burglarized so a charge of burglary was preferred against him. Billings, charged with stealing a cloak from a girl of frailty, escaped from McNeil's Island about two months ago. Attorney Costello has applied for a commission to examine Welch's sanity.