<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

THE COURT VERSUS CRIME.
Indictments by the Grand Jury---Verdict of Guilty---Three Men Discharged.

"We, the jury, in the case of the Territory of Washington, plaintiff, against Harry Diamond, defendant, find the defendant guilt.
W. W. Easter, Foreman."

Such was the first verdict of the petit jury for this term. It was returned late yesterday afternoon. The circumstances of Diamond's case were published in yesterday's Press.

True bills were returned yesterday afternoon, by the Grand Jury, against Joseph Dukson and George Watson for burglary. The Grand Jury refused to indict Watson for grand larceny too. Watson was arrested by Police Officer Holden, a short time ago, for having stolen property forma  second hand gun store in his possession. Watson had an opium pipe in his lodging room, also, and after being locked up he begged for the use of his pipe. He was arraigned soon after being indicted, and pleaded not guilty, Mr. J. E. Costello being appointed his counsel.

Jame Galvin was indicted for grand larceny. He is the man arrested by Officer Peer, for stealing a gold watch and chain from a man named Peter Lee, in the Idaho saloon. Galvin, when arraivned, was given until to day to plead. This forenoon he was given until 1:30 p.m. to plead. Mr. L. C. Gilman being appointed to defend him.

George Watson this forenoon withdrew his plea of not guilty and pleaded guilty.

The Grand Jury failed to indict Geo. Collins, Geo. Monroe and A. C. Mulligan, afor grand larceny: They were charged with entering a woman's room at the La Veta House, last August, and stealing some articles. The court discharged these men.

This morning the larceny case of L. Duhean, for stealing a watch from a Tacoma lodger, and who was arrested a week or so ago by Policeman Ben Thompson, came up for trail. He was found guilty.

Venatta's case, for grand larceny, was taken up next.

The watch stolen by Dubeau from T. L. Reader was ordered returned to the latter.

The Grand Jury did not indict Fred Smith for grand larceny, so he was discharged.

James Galvin entered a plea of not guilty this afternoon.