<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>Chinese Life on the Pacific Coast.</head>
<byline>By James Peter Macintyre.</byline>
<p>It may be that if you have seen one Chinese village you have, in a sense, seen all of China; nevertheless, the principle, as far as it relates to the Chungwos resident on the Pacific Coast of Canada, allows of indefinite expansion even in a superficial sense. The mysticism of manner which seems an essential motive in the Chinese existence, is far less opaque in ordinary everyday affairs than when applied in connection with religious worship, or in guarding the ulterior workings of their masonry.</p>
<p>Impassive and taciturn as to the kaolin clay and glazed image representing an abstruse being, insensibly inuring to a ritual of worship, clouded in incense-laden smoke, it is not strange that the Cathayans of the coast are an almost unknown quantity in the gregarious element which occupies the centres of population.</p>
<p>Their bent in religion is towards a latitude which allows them a multifarity of gods, and the practice of polytheism; the doctrines adhered to mainly leading the Chinese mind to propagate elusive and, it may be maintained, ludicrous means of escaping the evil spirit. To attain the passive, semi-conscious state, which they esteem the goal of the spirit at immolation, they practice active religious rites which are inspired with the view of outwitting the devil. In this connection the phase of proceedings during their lives, which, according to the gospel of morals, inclines to noisomeness, is attained by the agency of brazen instruments. No sound which is produced by the use of vellum, as in the beating of a drum, is tasteful to the oriental ear. The gulf in this manner is more noticeable to the pronounced Caucasians because of the ridicule with which the Chinese receive the sonorous instrument in almost otherwise universal favor. But they are as opposite to us in ways innumerable, and as apparent in their customs as the Japanese appear in using mechanical tools, and obeying forms, exactly the reverse of that which habit has confirmed in the people of most other nations.</p>
<p>No other class of cosmopolitans on the coast carry with them kin qualities which, in the routine of their lives, act with such opposite effects. At the same time that they emulate the Aztec Indians in grateful, if undemostrative worship of the sun, the warmth of which is congenial to the oriental physique, the idol of the Indians finds sweltering masses of decaying garbarge to simmer down, and from whence to free to the air the germs which are incipient of epidemic diseases.</p>
<p>Their idolatry of body is more than offset by the filthy condition of their surroundings, although the latter effect is now more prevalent where the coolies are isolated, as in rural districts.</p>
<p>In the aggrandizement of wealth, the most potent factor observed in aiming at a competency is frugality in their mode of living; although the Hermic tendency in their nature looks contradictory when their innate love of gambling is exposed. In the pursuit of chance gaming a nervous avidity and interest are disclosed in the process that are entirely opposite to the former trait of character. It is not a very common occurrence when a Chinaman tries conclusions with a white man in a game of cards. But on one occasion a celestial entered a poker game with a resident white man on the Coast, to offset whom, in his own game, he carried an extra pack of cards in his sleeve. A full hand of aces turned up for the white man, who drew Chew's attention to the fact with the exclamation, "I have four aces, Johnny." "Velley good," replied the Chinaman, to whom the game was a little foreign, "you see, me got five acey."</p>
<p>In this channel, thorugh which they vent a great amount of excitement, the passion for play, which is under the ban of civic ordinances, brings them under the raiding system of the police authorities. On one occasion not very long ago, when passing through a Chinese quarter in Westminster, the police of the city were engaged in capturing a den of gamblers, who nightly resorted to one of the "hells" for play. At convenient points near the resort, preparatory to entering the building at a signal, were several officers. The gamesters were playing in an upper room of the building, into which the raiders entered by the street door, but which they no sooner passed aware of the presence of the police than they sprang towards the windows, through which some of them came crashing to the wooden sidewalk underneath, bringing the glass with them. Being hard to detect them as individuals excepting on acquaintance, a number of them escaped to the labyrinthine alleys, from whence they returned calmly to watch the outcome of the encounter.</p>
<p>Those penned up in the room engaged in a desperate fight for liberty, but, the avenues of escape being cut off, their efforts proved futile. It was during the re-encounter that one of the officers called upon the white bystanders to enter the premises and aid in securing the prisoners for conveyance to the 'cangue.'</p>
<p>At the moment of entering, with the intent of helping, a bystander felt himself arrested through a hand being placed on his shoulder. Turning sharply around, he found, by the dim</p>