<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>Just Cogitating: Early Days of State's Courts Recalled</head>
<byline>By C.T. CONOVER</byline>
<p>95-Year-Old Seattle Pioneer</p>
<p>Here are some interesting excerpts from an address by Judge John J. McGilvra before the State Bar Association, July 26, 1895:</p>
<p>"When I came to the Coast in 1861, Seattle was a little town of 250 persons and Tacoma was only a logging camp. I was the first attorney in Seattle.</p>
<p>"Our trip from New York to Olympia via the Isthmus of Panama took one month and seven days. The Territory of Washington then consisted of the present area and the panhandle of Idaho, and had a population of less than 1,200 whites. On the road from Colville to Walla Walla there was only one white man, the ferryman on a crossing of the Spokane River.</p>
<p>"The courts were held only twice a year at Port Townsend, Olympia, Vancouver and Walla Walla. The Supreme Court consisted of a chief justice and two associates, and held one annual term at Olympia. The territory was divided into three judicial districts and one of the judges was assigned to each.</p>
<p>"On the Sound one traveled in canoes, unless one was lucky enough to strike the Eliza Anderson, a weekly steamer from Olympia to Victoria and way points and the only passenger steamer on Puget Sound.</p>
<p>"THE WALLA WALLA Courthouse was the loft of a log building reached by an outside stairway. The building was entirely unfinished inside. Below a saloon was running full blast. The courtroom seats were wood slabs. The judge's desk was an ancient washstand. I recall when two Indians were arraigned for murder and as there was no jail. They were manacled and chained to the courtroom wall.</p>
<p>"Colonel Stone, a saloonkeeper, was foreman of the grand jury at that term. None of the saloonkeepers had bothered to take out a license. When the question of indicting them came up, it was suggested that Stone be excused. But he declined the favor and voted to indict all of the saloonkeepers, including himself. He promptly paid the fine imposed.</p>
<p>"Virtually the entire country was a wilderness inhabited only by Indians. But we had a good time."</p>