<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>TIMBER AND THE LAW: A CIVIL WAR CHAPTER</head>
<byline>IVAN DOIG</byline>
<p>...There is now and has been for years past great and continued trespass upon the government lands, in the cutting and removing of timber by mill companies and those who supply said companies with logs....</p>
<p>&#8212;U.S. District Attorney McGilvra to Solicitor of the Treasury. July 11, 1861</p>
<p>We'll be arguing the questions of timber until the last sprinkle of sawdust has dribbled from the last stump. How much wilderness, how much harvest? Multiple use of national forests or the lone goal of conserving green mountains? Clearcutting, or no? The lumberman will continue to deride the environmental druid whose heart bleeds every time someone steps on a pine cone. The environmentalist will keep on denouncing the lumber glutton who would attack his mother's rhododendron bush with a chainsaw to earn another nickel. One way or another, disputes about mankind and the tree have spluttered in the Pacific Northwest ever since the Civil War.</p>
<p>In the east of that earliest chapter were the forests along Puget Sound, the region's pioneer lumber entrepreneurs, and one district attorney.</p>
<p>First, the trees: In the mid-nineteenth century, tremendous stands of Douglas fir, red cedar, and western hemlock crowded thickly along the shores of Puget Sound, while up the mountain slopes the green pattern of forest ran on and on toward snowy peaks. Fed by mild climate and more than ample rainfall, trees rose 200 feet and more. Look at them with a view to counting masts and board feet of lumber, and you saw one of the world's grandest bonanzas of wood.</p>
<p>Next, the lumbermen. As early as 1847, a power sawmill bought secondhand from the Hudson's Bay Company was set up on Puget Sound near the present site of Olympia. Henry Yesler's sawmill at Seattle began cutting in March 1853, the month Congress created Washington Territory. In September, four partners from Maine established the mill at Teekalet (now Port Gamble) which burgeoned into the giant Puget Mill Company &#8212; Pope and Talbot enterprise. Sawmill towns sprang on inlets &#8212; Seabeck, Port Ludlow, Port Orchard, Utsalady, Port Madison. The census of 1860 counted 32 lumber mills and one shingle mill in Washington Territory, nearly all on or near Puget Sound, with products valued at $1,194,360.</p>
<p>Comes now the law in a frock coast. John J. McGilvra had been a lawyer in Chicago. When Abraham Lincoln was elected President in 1860, McGilvra hustled into line with the throng of politicians seeking jobs from the first Republican administration. He gathered 24 letters recommending himself for the post of U.S. district attorney for Washington Territory and went to the nation's capital to lobby on his own behalf. In April 1861, McGilvra won his job. In June, the 33-year-old lawyer arrived at the territorial capital of Olympia with a wife, two children, and a salary of $250 a year.</p>
<p>McGilvra promptly dug into the usual legal fare of his job, which was roughly a skimpy version of the present office of U.S. Attorney. On the dockets were constant cases of selling liquor to Indians and usually a few smuggling offenses. But the new district attorney discerned that the most chronic law-breaking in his entire jurisdiction lay with the Puget Sound lumber industry, which was illegaly removing timber from the public domain. Trespass, to be polite. In less genteel language, thievery. And perhaps not incidentally, prosecuting the lumbermen would add to the legal fees which supplemented the district attorney's basic salary. After his first few weeks in the Territory, McGilvra wrote to his superior in Washington, D.C., noting the "great and continued trespass" and announcing that he intended to prosecute under an 1831 federal law against cutting any trees which grew on "any lands of the United States."</p>
<p>He carried out his intention by pressing charges against several surprised lumbermen when the district court held session at Port Townsend in August 1861.</p>
<p>As you are doubtless aware the principal resource of this section of country is its lumber. These mills which employ from 25 to 175 or 200 men each besides those necessary to supply the mills with logs, are undoubtedly of much advantage and benefit to this sparsely settled region and to stop these mills would injure the prosperity and prospects of the Territory very much.....</p>
<p>Now the question arises what are we to do in the premises?</p>
<ab>&#8212;U.S. District Attorney McGilvra to Solicitor of the Treasury. August 31, 1861</ab>
<p>The loggers and mill men of Puget Sound could offer a simple reason for swiping trees from the public domain: It was the only way they could get them. As is not unusual in human history, legislation and administration were lagging dispiritedly behind the conditions of the moment.</p>
<p>At the time, the U.S. land laws provided that if timber land had been surveyed, it could be offered at public auction the same way as other land held by the government. But where land was not yet offered for sale or perhaps was not even surveyed, lumbermen had no legal route into the public trees. True, there was preemption, a legal device of the time to secure ownership rights on public lands not yet offered for sale &#8212; a stopgap used as settlement of the frontier outraced the federal suveying teams. But preemption was expressly intended for use by settlers who occupied and improved the land &#8212; that is, farmers.</p>
<p>Overall, the situation boiled down to this: The forest land couldn't be bought for lumbering until it had been surveyed and put on the market. And the Lincoln administration was too busy fighting the Civil War to worry about financing teams of surveyors in the remotest corner of the country.</p>
<p>Rather than twiddle away years until government tidied up matters, the lumbermen behaved according to venerable American tradition and simply ignored the law. The frontier history of this country is writ large with such behavior. The British colonial administrators in 1763 drew a boundary along the crest of the Appalachians to keep white settlers 
<pb/>
out of the Indian lands west of the mountains. It worked no better than the American laws to keep the white flood out of the Sioux lands of the Dakotas more than a century later. As for the stalwart pioneer modestly asking only a few acres to till, there is a tremendous body of folklore about the fraud involved in filing for farm acreage &#8212; the boy standing on the number 21 and truthfully assuring the land office clerk that he was of legal age to file for a homestead because he was "over 21;" or the dry land farmer who would dig a hole and pour a barrel of water in it so he could swear he had a well when the day came to prove up his homestead claim.</p>
<p>McGilvra considered his 1861 epidemic of scofflaws with care. Nothing in his records shows that he had firm and clear instructions from higher echelons about how to handle timber trespass. McGilvra's first gambit, to bring lumbermen to trial and fine them, produced four convictions and $1550 in fines during the Port Townsend court session. But when he tried it again in a court session at Olympia, none of the five indicted lumbermen were convicted. Obviously, timber country juries might have their own version of whether it was improper to cut down a tree. McGilvra wrote to Washington, D.C., to say that he couldn't shut down the offending sawyers and mill men without wrecking the economy of the Territory, and that he had one more idea for enforcement.</p>
<p>You will please make an affidavit of the amount of lumber cut by your mill or for the mill on Government land since the date of our last settlement, and forward the same to me at Olympia.</p>
<ab>&#8212;U.S. District Attorney McGilvra to mill owner Marshall Blinn, July 12, 1864</ab>
<p>McGilvra spent most of his second year on the job &#8212; 1862 &#8212; away from Puget Sound, on a circuit of courts in eastern Washington. Washington Territory at the time included what is now Idaho and part of Montana west of the Continental Divide. For all this expanse, roughly the size of Spain, McGilvra was the sole federal prosecutor. He spent several months in court sessions at Walla Walla, Colville, and the mining boomtowns of Idaho. But when McGilvra got around to the Puget Sound lumbermen again, he had the next enforcement plan in mind.</p>
<p>McGilvra's notion was called a stumpage fee, although he collected it from the sawmills on the basis of board feet of lumber. From McGilvra's viewpoint, the policy of settling without a trial got around the problem of balky juries. To sweeten the proposition for the lumbermen, McGilvra advised them that waiving the service of process would reduce their 
<pb/>
court costs. Although McGilvra's correspondence shows no more than hints, there also seems to have been the unspoken bargain that McGilvra would negotiate "reasonable" fees instead of trying to dun them for every stick of wood cut on public land.</p>
<p>In any event, McGilvra pegged the stumpage rate at about 15 cents a thousand board feet, and apparently included court costs in that amount. He would ask a mill owner for an estimate of the amount cut in his mill man then would attend the next term of the district court &#8212; at that time, the court sessions for the Puget Sound region rotated among Port Townsend, Olympia, and Steilacoom &#8212; to pay what he owed and receive a receipt. Since district court terms were held twice a year, stumpage fees in effect were a semiannual timber tax.</p>
<p>His report to the General Land Office for April 1863 not only gives some idea of the sums involved, but of the district attorney's flexible system. Pope and Talbot paid $325 for 2,510,000 board feet; Arthur Phinney and his two partners paid $140 for their 950,400 board feet &#8212; both fees at roughly the proclaimed rate of 15 cents per thousand feet, plus small court costs. But for some unexplained reason, Charles E. P. Wood and his partners ponied up only a dime per thousand board feet &#8212; 3,000,000 feet of lumber for $300.</p>
<p>This stumpage fee policy is another exhibit in the array of federal land laws broken freely and almost universally. Such fines for logs cut on the public domain were supposed to have been imposed nationally since the early 1850s, but enforcement was desultory. McGilvra's rather modest enforcement of stumpage fees until he left office in October 1865 comparatively was a fabulous success. A success for him and the public coffers, that is; the lumbermen were busy dissenting.</p>
<p>...You have inferred....that you were authorized to travel, and explore the Territory of Washington, for the purpose of hunting up trespassers before process issued, and settle with them as District Attorney, when no such authority was given nor designed to be conferred.</p>
<ab>&#8212;Commissioner of General Land Office to U.S. District Attorney McGilvra, May 19, 1863</ab>
<p>All the while McGilvra was working out his timber policy, the lumbermen had been mulling their McGilvra policy. The district attorney's early attempts to convict and fine them for timber trespass had dwindled away because of stubborn juries in the lumber towns. But the spring of 1862, the territorial delegate to Congress was in touch with the Commissioner of the General Land Office in the national capital. His request, unmistakably at the urging of Puget Sound lumbermen, was that McGilvra be told to drop his timber trespass cases.</p>
<p>The General Land Office passed along the message to McGilvra, but the district attorney had another ploy. Throughout McGilvra's term in the Civil War years, a U.S. district attorney worked by alliance instead of allegiance within the bureaucratic chart. He did chores for several government departments, but received no regular instructions from anyone. There was not yet a Department of Justice; it was formed in 1870, and only then did the U.S. attorney general gain clear supervision of federal attorneys. McGilvra reported regularly to the Solicitor of the Treasury, but could perform duties involving other government offices as weel. A highly contentious man, McGilvra took the view that his job in Washington Territory embraced the administration of the public forests.</p>
<p>In passing along the message to lay off the lumbermen, the Commissioner of the General Land Office had made the mistake of telling McGilvra to charge a stumpage fee if the mill men wished to settle the cases McGilvra had already begun. This casual go-ahead for a few cases was promptly sretched by McGilvra into his general policy of charging for timber cut on public land from then on.</p>
<p>In the spring of 1863, when McGilvra was back in the Puget Sound country after his sojourn in eastern reaches of the Territory, the lumbermen apparently prodded the territorial delegate to prod the General Land Office again. A miffed letter came to McGilvra from GLO Commissioner James M. Edmunds telling him to rein in: "...it was not intended that you should take the initiative in arresting trespassers &#8212; that you should traverse the woods for the purpose of detecting offenders...." The Commissioner concluded that the matter of public timber was in the hands of the territorial land officers in Olympia. Since those officials had shown no inclination to collect for lumbering, this solution would have soothed the mill owners nicely.</p>