<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>Mrs. Legg Remembers Fire and Ham Lewis</head>
<byline>By LUCILE McDONALD</byline>
<p>THE MOST glamorous person Helen Jenner Legg, 91, remembers from her Seattle girlhood was the "Silver Knight with the Auburn Whiskers," James Hamilton Lewis.</p>
<p>Mrs. Legg's father, Charles K. Jenner, was an attorney and so was Lewis, when the latter wasn't vote-hunting.</p>
<p>Lewis was a perennial candidate for office, a spell-binder whose mauve spats, fancy waistcoats, flowery speeches and eccentric doings were the talk of the town. He was a young Virginian of 22 when he moved to Seattle in 1885 after having attended several universities in the South and having been admitted to the bar. His sartorial splendor was dazzling and he speedily became known as the Dude.</p>
<p>HE had been here four years when Seattle's business district was destroyed by fire on June 6, 1889.</p>
<p>"I was going home from school that day," Mrs. Legg says, "and got as far as Washington Street when I heard the fire engine and walked up to look. I'm not very clear about what I did because of the excitement, but I know in the evening I stood watching from a bedroom window. Our house was at 11th Avenue South and Washington Street where the Yesler Housing Project community hall stands.</p>
<p>"The Chinese district had burned out and Father let two Chinese couples camp in our yard. The wives slept in an unused cow shed and cooked over a bonfire. They were grateful afterward for the help and sent us some large silk handkerchiefs. Mother lined a silk patchwork quilt with them that is still in beautiful condition.</p>
<p>"Next day my cousin, Ed Worthington, and I were watching the work of cleaning up the ruins when I heard someone behind me say, 'Helen, do you want to keep this rig for me?'</p>
<p>"It was Mr. Lewis. He had a horse and buggy and was offering me the reins. I started to say I couldn't drive, but my cousin spoke quickly, 'Yes, we'll take care of it for you.'</p>
<p>"We had that horse for a week. Ed staked it out somewhere in a vacant lot, I guess. He cared for the outfit, and I went riding with him. We were having a fine time one day, driving out First Avenue, when a nice-looking man hailed us and said, 'I'll take it now.' Evidently he was the owner and had lent it to Lewis or maybe the stable where it belonged burned down. I never knew, but it was an odd experience. We walked home speechless with astonishment."</p>
<p>PERSONS who knew Lewis better than Helen Jenner expected things like that. He was a man with no financial sense and once when a banker told him his account was overdrawn Lewis pulled out his checkbook and started to write a check on the same bank, saying, "Oh, I can remedy that right now."</p>
<p>His willingness to be in the spotlight sometimes resulted in comical situations. During a trial an interpreter was required for a man who spoke, supposedly, only French. Lewis chanced to pass in the corridor and it was suggested that he be pressed into service because, with his college education and travels, undoubtedly he knew the language. Lewis was glad to oblige.</p>
<p>He rattled off a strange lingo and the witness replied at great length. Lewis then turned to the judge and said the man was from the south of France and spoke a dialect unintelligible to him because he had learned his French in Paris.</p>
<p>After Lewis departed from the court room a spectator rose and volunteered to interpret. "Your Honor," he said, "the witness is speaking Spanish."</p>
<p>Mrs. Legg says another story circulated in Seattle crediting Lewis with a burst of oratory at a public meeting where, with appropriate gestures, he referred to "the sword of Damascus."</p>
<p>A listener interrupted, "You mean the sword of Damocles."</p>
<p>"It doesn't make any difference," Lewis retorted "They make steel in both places."</p>
<p>The late C.T. Conover wrote that "Ham" Lewis furnished more news copy than any man who ever lived in Seattle. "He did not care what you said about him as long as you did not ignore him. He saw to that."</p>
<p>When Lewis was elected to the territorial legislature of 1887-88, his signature on an Olympia hotel register occupied four lines.</p>
<p>Two years later he went to London to present Pacific Northwest claims as a member of the Joint High Commission on Canadian and Alaskan Boundaries. In 1892 he ran unsuccessfully for governor and in both 1896 and 1900 his efforts to win the Democratic nomination for vice president of the United States were defeated. However, his presistence won out and he was sent to the 55th Congress as representative from Washington in 1897. He tried for re-election on the Funsionist ticket and lost.</p>
<p>IN Seattle, where the Republicans dominated politics for years, he relied heavily on the labor vote, as he kept a card in the longshoreman's union, having qualified by working on the docks the first year he was here.</p>
<p>Always eager to be in the public eye, he led the opposition to woman suffrage. Yet he was ingratiating to mothers and wives of voters. Any woman considered that meeting him on the street was an occassion.</p>
<p>He had been a private in Seattle's Home Guard regiment, but by the Spanish American War he wangled the rank of colonel and was inspector-general on the staff of General Brooke in Cuba and Gen. Frederick D. Grant in Puerto Rico. Back home again he ran on the Democratic ticket for the United States Senate and lost.</p>
<p>Perhaps deciding that in spite of his showy raiment, inventive mind and oratory he was getting nowhere among so many "black Republicans" he moved to Chicago in 1903 and resumed law practice. He was later elected to the Senate from Illinois, represented this country on several commissions abroad, and was still in the Senate in 1939, when he died. He was the Democratic whip in the Senate.</p>
<p>Mrs. Legg said, "If this had been a big place, I suppose he would never have had a speaking acquaintance with me. But in those days, everybody knew everybody else.</p>
<p>"I grew up in exciting days in Seattle&#8212;the Chinese riots, the hangings in front of my father's office at Second Avenue and James Street&#8212;but nothing impressed me more than James Hamilton Lewis and his pink whiskers. If this city ever had an unforgettable character, he deserves the honor."</p>