<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

For Prosecuting Attorney.

The election of E. F. Blaine as District Attorney is of material interest to every taxpayer in King, Kitsap and Snohomish Counties. It would be hardly less than a public calamity to elect his opponent, W> W. Newlin. Mr. Newlin has reached middle life without manifesting ordinary ability at the bar. The causd is well knowsn to those acuainted with his fast habits of life. That he has permanently reformed is seriously to be hoped. But so important an office as District Attorney should not be intrusted to a man unless his habits and ability are beyond question. The people might be willing to overlook some of the shortcomings in Mr. Newlin, if it were not for the fact that after he was turned out of the office of City Attorney of the city of Walla Walla for failure, through excesses, to perform its duties, he had the audacity to sue that city for his year's salary, and carried that suit to the Supreme Court of the Territory. This cause against the city of Walla Walla was decided against him about a year ago, or since his reformation.

This reformation, if complete, should have led him to have dismissed that case. This persistency in carrying it on does further in condemning him in the eyes of the tax payers than his dissolute habits. Mr. Blaine, on the other hand, is a man of a family, and his habits of life are of a high order, and his energy is such that he has rapidly advanced in his profession, until he is looked upon as one of the foremost of the young lawyers at the Seattle bar. There is no danger ahead in the election of E. F> Blaine as Prosecuting Attorney. His time will be given to the performance of the duties of the office, and he will carefully guard the rights of all.

That Mr. Blaine is a man of ability, and yet a person considerate of the instersts of all, is best proven by the fact that, since he does business for a number of the richest men in the city of Seattle and shares their utmost confidence, he is receiving the active support of the laboring classes who in him have a true advocate of the cause of the tolling masses.

The fitness of Mr. Blaine for the office to which he aspires is also shown from the fact that the Seattle Daily and Weekly Press, the Seattle Tribune, (German), the North Seattle Advocate, the Snohomish Suna nd Snohomish Eye, all indpendent papers, are active in his support, and he also has been endorsed by the People's party of King and Kitsap Counties while mr. Newlin can hardly get the rabid partisan papers, only two in number, of his own party, to speak in his praise.