<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>Benefits of the Chinese Exodus.</head>
<p>From the Tacoma News.</p>
<p>There were eight hundred of the pigtailed serfs in Tacoma, in the holiday season of 1884. Then there was not a day passed in which appeals for charity were not numerously made; widows and children were dependent on sympathy for help, and working men ate bread watered with tears. The Chinese were withdrawing from circulation over $8,000 a month, on the most moderate of computations, and were performing services at less than one-half the rates which would enable a white person to live. There were absolutely hundreds of white men, women and children seeking work which could not be obtained. Cheap labor was weighing its heaviest on the community.</p>
<p>In the holiday season of 1885 there was not a single Chinaman in the city. What was the consequence? Not an idle man, woman or child. Everyone who wanted to work had it, at remunerative prices. The wages earned were not hoarded for transportation to China, but the hundreds who had taken the places vacated by the Chinese had money, and with it bought wearing apparel, household effects and the comforts and little luxuries which make the white man's existence tolerable. The merchants of Tacoma felt the beneficial effects of several thousands of dollars passing from hand to hand, which else would have disappeared forever from the ordinary channels of trade. Not a charitable call was made. Fairs for society and church purposes were successful. Christmas feasts were spread, and every citizen profited by the happy change.</p>
<p>Can anything be plainer? The prosperity, nay, the preservation, of the whites is menaced by the presence of "the little yellow man." His absence means our enhancement. He does not wear our clothes, he eats but little of our produce except pork and flour and the rejected portions of carcasses of beef cattle, sheep and game. Most of his food and all his clothes come from China, and he buys meanly and sparingly even of these. He is a leech.</p>
<p>Our friend says it looks like an injustice and an outrage to drive this class from "their homes." He little imagines the satire of his comment. Homes? They have non; no element of that institution which makes society a permanent possibility, attaches to the coolie on the Pacific Coast. In a very ordinary frame building, a story and a half high, and containing six or seven rooms, there would be half a hundred of these beings packed in the midst of dirt and squalor, breathing an atmosphere which would sicken the denizens of the foulest quarters, and a slaughter house heaven, to them. No wives, no children, no kin, not even the sympathy of race to touch whatever of heart or ambition they may possess. The "homes" they left in Tacoma, which are still standing, are unoccupied; they are not fit habitations for respectable beasts.</p>