<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>JUST COGITATING: Judge McGilvra's Reminiscences of Pioneer Years</head>
<byline>By C. T. CONOVER</byline>
<p>The following are odds and ends of a speech devlivered by Judge John J. McGilvra, formerly United States attorney for Washington Territory, at a meeting of pioneers in Tacoma, August 14, 1894:</p>
<p>"The winter of 1861-62 was the hardest winter ever known in Puget Sound country. Snow began falling on Christmas and lay on the ground from a foot to 18 inches deep until the middle of March. The Columbia River was frozen over and more than 50 per cent of the stock east and west of the Cascades perished from cold and hunger.</p>
<p>"All communications between the eastern and western portions of the territory were cut off. In that era it took at least six weeks to go or return from the Atlantic Coast. Early in 1862 telegraph communication was established between Portland and the East Coast, which relieved our isolation.</p>
<p>"In 1864 the wires were extended to Puget Sound. in 1869 the Union and Central Pacific Railroads were completed in San Francisco, and time for mails and travel to the East was reduced to about 30 days.</p>
<p>"In 1861 Washington Territory, which then included the Idaho Panhandle, had a population of less than 12,000.</p>
<p>Judge McGilvra's speech continued:</p>
<p>"Looking back 32 years, what do you see? True, we had our mountains, lakes, forests and extensive plains, but all else has changed. We had no steamboats except the Eliza Anderson. We had no railroads and hardly a wagon road, certainly no good one.</p>
<p>"Port Townsend, Steilacoom, Olympia, Vancouver on the Columbia, and Walla Walla were the only villages in the territory worthy of the name, and Steilacoom was by far the largest and liveliest of them all.</p>
<p>"The principal means of transportation on both tide and inland waters was the Indian canoe, with two or three natives as the propelling power. In such a craft, with blankets and grub and by taking advantage of tides, eddies and currents, we could make about 40 miles a day, and camp on the beach when night or storms overtook us. We were contented and generally comfortable and always indpendent since we made our own time tables.</p>
<p>"About the only wagon road in Western Washington was the so-called stage road from Olympia to Monticello, and a trip over that was something to remember."</p>
<p>Discussing the trip to Eastern Washington, Judge McGilvra said:</p>
<p>"For Eastern Washington we shipped for the Cascades by way of Vancouver. At the portage of the Cascades our baggage was transported over a tramway by mule power, and we walked.</p>
<p>"At The Dalles we made another portage of 16 miles by stage. From Celilo to Wallula there were several rapids to ride, and then trip from Wallula to Wallace, 30 miles, was by stage over and alkali desert, where pounding high winds had cut out sections of the road and the grades and curves were so fantastic that the stage would sometimes turn bottom-side up and occasionally topple over into the Walla Walla River.</p>
<p>"Walla Walla was a mining town close to the military post. Every public house was a gambling saloon and the courtroom was in the loft of one of them. The building was of hewn logs clapboarded, but unfinished on the inside.</p>
<p>"There was no jail, and two Indians accused of murder were chained to the wall of the courtroom.</p>
<p>"In July, 1862, Judge Oliphant, Selucius Garfield, Marshall Fargo, myself and others went to Colville to hold the first term of court there&#8212;a distance of 210 miles. Where Spokane, Waitsburg, Colfax and other towns now stand, excepting Walla Walla, Lewiston and Colfax, the country was entirely inhabited by Indians."</p>
<p>Judge McGilvra had high praise for the Nez Perce Indians. He said:</p>
<p>"The Nez Perce Indian was one of the finest specimens of the Indian race, physically, mentally and morally, that ever existed on the American continent. It was their proud boast that the blood of a white man never had been shed by them. Still, they were not exempt from the contaminating influence of so-called civilization.</p>
<p>"First came the gold hunters in large numbers to invade the home reserved by solemn treaty stipulations, adn with them came large quantities of liquor. No attempt was made by the federal government to prevent the wanton trespass upon the property and rights of this friendly tribe, or to protect them from these demoralizing influences.</p>
<p>"In addition, instead of protecting the rights of this loyal and defenseless race, the government forced the reluctant assent of a majority of this tribe to a treaty further reducing the area of their reservation and surrendering a valuable mining area, including Chief Joseph's home.</p>
<p>"I am well aware of the prevalent race prejudice, but candor requires me to state that after 33 years of experience on the frontier, I consider the native races as a rule friendly and true to those who are friendly to them. Practically all Indian wars have been caused by long, continued and cruel wrongs."</p>