<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>CHINESE MERCHANTS IN TACOMA.</head>
<p>Tacoma has determined to raise the embargo on the Chinese so far as to admit to residence in the city merchants of that nationality. The matter was discussed at public meetings, and while the change in policy was opposed by a few politicians who cater to the labor vote it was approved by all influential business men. For more than four years no Chinaman has ventured to take up his abode in Tacoma, because of the hostile sentiment of the people. Now it is found that if the new line of Northern Pacific steamships running to China and Japan is to have its expected results in increasing the trade of Tacoma there must be Chinese merchants on the ground to import the products of the Flowery Kingdom and distribute them to Chinamen in the interior towns, otherwise the greater part of the cargo of the vessels, outside of teas destined for Eastern cities, will be consigned to Chinese merchants in Seattle and Portland, and Tacoma will derive no advantage from this commerce. One of the Chinese merchants who will settle in Tacoma under the new condition of affairs is Seid Back, of Portland, who is said to be worth over $3,000,000. He is about fifty-five years of age, speaks English readily and ears American clothing, and is a man of pleasing address. In fact, the mercantile class of Chinamen, as represented in Portland and San Francisco, differ widely in appearance from the men of the coolie class, who do common labor and keep the wash-houses. The tradesmen are large, well-fed and well-dressed men, of considerable intellectual force and of great business ability. There houses are handsomely furnished and they live with a good deal of luxury. In every Chinese restuarant in those cities there is an upper room for the exclusive use of these gentry, fitted up with expensive teak wood furniture and fine porcelain and bronzes. In these rooms, sacred from the crowd of common customers, who are not allowed to go above the lower floor, the merchants give dinner parties, with long and curious menus, not a single dish of which would be recognized by an American palate. They eat with chop sticks, drink fine teas imported especially for their use and end the mean with a liquor distilled from rice. They are grave and dignified but can unbend on these occasions so far as to tell anecdotes and recite bits of poetry. Certainly Tacoma will not suffer from the presence of people like these.</p>