<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>JUST COGITATING: Judge Struve Helped Develop State's Economy</head>
<byline>By C.T. CONOVER</byline>
<p>97-Year-Old Seattle Pioneer</p>
<p>NEARLY 70 years ago, Judge Henry G. Struve, then one of Seattle's most distinguished citizens, John H. McGraw, later governor of Washington, and I were walking along Montgomery Street in San Francisco, after a good dinner at a French restaurant. McGraw paused and said: "My first job on the Pacific Coast was driving a horse car on this street."</p>
<p>"You haven't anything on me," said Struve. "Mine was as a waiter in Dutch Bill's restaurant over on that corner."</p>
<p>Struve was born in Germany in 1836. At the age of 16 he came to America. He studied law and was admitted to the bar in San Francisco. The next year he settled in Vancouver, Wash., and bought The Vancouver Chronicle for a song.</p>
<p>STRUVE eked out an existence for a year, and then sold the paper and began practicing his profession. In 1862 he was elected district attorney on the Republican ticket.</p>
<p>Struve's work met with such favor that he was re-elected three times. In 1869 he was elected probate judge of Clark County.</p>
<p>In 1865 Struve had been elected to the General Assembly, and served as chairman of the Judiciary Committee. In 1867 he was elected to the Territorial Council. he was re-elected repeatedly and always was named president. He had much to do with important legislation and was made chairman of the Ways and Means Committee.</p>
<p>IN 1871, Struve moved to Olympia to take charge of the Puget Sound Daily Courier, a leading Republican paper. The same year, he was appointed secretary of Washington Territory by President Grant. The next year he was a delegate to the Republican National Convention at Philadelphia.</p>
<p>With the expiration of his term as territorial secretary, Struve resumed his law practice, but his recognized ability forced another office on him. He was made a commissioner to codify the laws of the state. The demands of his law office forced him to resign a year later, however.</p>
<p>In 1879 Struve moved to Seattle, and until his death was a leading member of the bar here. In 1882 and 1883 he was elected major of Seattle. he instituted many public improvements, including the grading and opening of streets.</p>
<p>IN 1879 Struve was appointed a regent of the University of Washington. He was chairman of the board for four consecutive terms. From 1884 and 1887 he was a school director of Seattle. In 1886 he was appointed judge advocate-general of Washington Territory by Governor Squire.</p>
<p>In 1887 Struve became Supreme Court reporter. he was a member of the Board of Freeholders, which prepared Seattle's charter, acting as chairman of the committee on judiciary and tide lands.</p>
<p>Struve was one of Seattle's most distinguished attorneys and was retained by many leading mill, railway and coal corporations. He was much interested in research on the early history of the Pacific Northwest, and gathered much data about the early settlement. All was destroyed in the great fire of June 6, 1889.</p>
<p>STRUVE had an important part in developing the economic interests of the state. He was associated with the organization of Seattle's cable-car system and was president of the Madison Street Cable Line.</p>
<p>Struve was one of the founders of the Home Insurance Co., one of the directors and vice president of the Boston National Bank, and was the Pacific Northwest representative of the German Savings &amp; Loan Society of San Francisco, which made most of the rebuilding loans after the great fire.</p>
<p>In 1874 Struve was elected grand master of the Grand Lodge of Odd Fellows for Oregon, Washington and Idaho. In 1876 he became representative in the Sovereign Grand Lodge and instituted the Grand Lodge of Washington Territory.</p>
<p>Struve passed away in New York city, June 13, 1905.</p>
<p>DR. David S. Maynard, one of the founders of Seattle, was Seattle's first physician, its first merchant, first salmon packer, first blacksmith, first real-estate dealer, first justice of the peace, first notary public, first port commissioner, first Indian agent, first man admitted to practice law and the first to open a hospital. He delivered the first white baby born in Seattle, and performed the first marriage ceremony. His body was the first interred in the Lakeview Cemetery.</p>
<p>DR. Marcus Whitman, first graduate of an American medical college to cross the Rocky Mountains, established at Waiilatpu the third hospital west of the Rockies. He performed the first surgical operation by an American physician west of the Rockies. This was in 1836. He died a martyr's death from an Indian tomahawk. Whitman College was erected in his memory.</p>