<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>SUMMONS.</head>

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT OF THE THIRD Judicial District of the Territory of Washington, holding terms at the city of Seattle, in and for the counties of King and Kitsan.</p>
<p>EMMA MYSEL. Plaintiff, vs. CHARLES MYSEL.
Defendant&#8212;Complaint filed in the county of King, in the office of the Clerk of said District Court.</p>
<p>The United States of America send greeting to Charles Mysel, Defendant.</p>
<p>You are hereby required to appear in an action brought against you by the above named plaintiff in the District Court of the Third Judicial District of the Territory of Washington, holding terms at the city of Seattle, in the county of King, for the counties of King and Kitsap, and to answer the complaint filed therein within twenty days (exlusive of the day of service) after the service on you of this summons if served within said county of King, or if served out of that county but in this District, within thirty days, otherwise within sixty days, or judgment by default will be taken against you, according to the prayer of the complaint.</p>
<p>The said action is brought to obtain a decree of divorce upon the ground of failure on the part of said defendant to make suitable provision for plaintiff's support, cruel treatment of plaintiff by said defendant and habitual drunkenness on the part of said defendant. And for a more specific statement of the cause and general nature of said action reference may be had to the plaintiff's complaint now on file. And you are hereby notified that if you fail to appear and answer the said complaint, as above required, the said plaintiff will apply to the Court for the relief therein demanded and will take judgment against you for costs.</p>
<p>Witness the Hon. J.R. Lewis, Judge of said Court, and the seal thereof, this 1st day of June, A.D. 1877.</p>
<p>JAMES SEAVY, Clerk.</p>
<p>By WM. H. ANDREWS, Deputy.</p>
<p>Ellsworth &amp; Hanford, Attorneys for plaintiff.</p>