<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

A DESERVED HONOR.

Possibly no young man in the Territory of Washington since its organization has ever received from its people the great compliment which was so fittingly bestowed on Seattle's brilliant young Attorney James Hamilton Lewis, in his election to the Territorial Senate by the over-whelming majority which he received on Tuesday last in the Eleventh Senatorial District. As our readers are aware he outstripped every candidate upon the ticket, leading by several hundred in the city the Delegate to Congress, and obtaining a majority in the city of near 800 and in the county about 250; likewise in Snohonish County he secured a handsome majority over his opponent Hon. James Glinn, a gentleman of 18 years residence in our midst and who has once served a term in the Senate&#8212;living in Skagit County, in which place he alone secured a small majority over Mr. Lewis.

Taken altogether Mr. Lewis goes in the Senate by a majority between 850 and 950. Of course Mr. Lewis cannot consider his brilliant victory a Democratic one, for the District in which he ran is conceded to be near 3000 Republicans on party fight; but as was predicted by the press, he was elected, aside from party issue upon his personal merit, which as shown by his vote was recognized by Republicans, Democrats, Prohibitionists, anti Prohibitionists, anti-Chinese and pro Chinese; that James Hamilton Lewis is a lawyer and an orato in many respects without a peer at this the ablest bar in the Territory will be questioned by none, notwithstanding he is but 24 years of age; and his high integrity and sterling personal qualities were more than attested by the fact that notwithstanding the bitterness with which the campiagn was waged, not a word was breathed in either of the two journals politically opposing Mr. Lewis against him personally in any respect whatever. Observing as we have the struggles that Mr. Lewis has made in his two years resident here in our midst, it is with more than delight that the writer, who includes James Hamilton Lewis among his warmest personal friends, pen these words of congraulation to him; and in conclusion will take the liberty of prophesying that the next session of the Territorial Senate will have no more brilliant representative than James Hamilton Lewis, joint member from the important counties of King, Snohomish and Skagit.
