<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>A Chat With Mrs. John J. McGilvra</head>
<byline>By MARTHA WATKINS</byline>
<p>(Do those of us who have come to Seattle within the last score of years relize how close we are to a wonderful pioneering past?
Sometimes the glamor and rush of the new obscures the power and permanence of the old&#8212;and it is often wise to pause in review.
I know of no opportunity more fruitful for this review than a conversation with one of Seattle's pioneer women.&#8212;Editor.)</p>
<p>"Oh no, I won't be interviewed. It's too much for me to go back over all those long, early years&#8212;I am not equal to it, " said the little gray-haired lady. The words were spoken not unkindly, but a little imperiously.</p>
<p>When I suggested that I did not seek a formal interview, but only wished to recall some interesting reminiscences, I was told: "Oh, but I don't know anything particularly for stories."</p>
<p>I assured her I would love to have just a little visit and talk with her about her wonderful pioneer past, and the hour was delightfully spent. I am sure you would enjoy hearing about the chat wiht this pioneer lady, Mrs. Elizabeth M. McGilvra, wife of the Honorable John J. McGilvra of early territorial days.</p>
<p>I found her just returned from a drive and seated on a large west porch at the home of her daughter, Mrs. Thomas Burke. Picture a five o'clock summer sun playing through branches and vines, the lights and shadows corresponding to the ever-changing expression on the alert features of this woman, who had come to the far Northwest during the first administration of Abraham Lincoln in the early sixties.</p>
<p>She wore a close-fitting hat tied with a huge purple bow on one side and silken veil of the same color drooped low over the other side. Harmonizing with her plum-colored wrap were an enameled pansy brooch and amethyst beads. Blue eyes looked at me from a squarely-cut face. If the lines at times seemed deep and set, they were quickly changed by smiles which were in rapid succession, mirth-provoking, sweet or gentle. Now can't you, too, see the picture that I saw and feel as if you were in the presence of a rich experience?</p>
<p>When Mrs. McGilvra started to talk freely, her thoughts turned first to her husband. "Father," she said, "was appointed United States attorney for Washington Territory at the beginning of President Lincoln's first term." She then added reminiscently, "You see their law offices were adjoining in Springfield, Illinois. What one knew the other knew. They were in the habit of looking after each other's affairs when one was away."</p>
<p>History tells us of Lincoln that he offered no political plums to his friends in advance. When his election was assured, Mr. McGilvra called upon him to extend congratulations. It was then Lincoln said, "Mac, your tenacity and ability in legal matters is needed by the government. You are the right man to take care of our interests in Washington Territory; you can settle the troublesome timber-stealing going on out there." Thus came our first attorney-general.</p>
<p>"And were you pleased, Mrs. McGilvra, to ahve this honor and important trust given to your husband?" I asked. "Oh no, not for myself," she replied quickly, "for hadn't I come as a little girl from New York State into early Illinois? We were just getting away from seeing horses flounder in the mud of Chicago streets, saying nothing of country roads.</p>
<p>"We lived in a suburban town and my father had taken pains to give me my education under two Oberlin College graduates. I wanted to enjoy the ideals of higher education, art and then foreign travel, and all that. But," she said laughingly, "I met Mr. McGilvra again after he had graduated from law school and was practicing. Then my plans changed.</p>
<p>"I remember this time we met and talked over early school days, and I wore a pretty green beige dress very low over the shoulders," then she hurridely added, "but not low
<pb/>
under the chin. Dear me, how one remembers things of years ago better than some happenings of last week!</p>
<p>"'Well,' I said to him, 'YOU might come up to the house some time.' He did, and continued coming."</p>
<p>Again the ever-old and ever-new story, the story of love and marriage, followed. The hopes, the plans, and efforts of a man and maid became united and thus was paved the way for this fair-haired matron to leave the old home, old friends and social ties. She took the long step westward with her rising young husband, now Uncle Sam's attorney for a large district that included unknown wilds.</p>
<p>Her intuitive nature told her of difficulties ahead. She had little idea of all the hardships in store for her.</p>
<p>It may be fun for us to live a short summer season in a crude house devoid of every modern convenience&#8212;it's a different matter for the year around. Today, you may heat the household water with instantaneous gas or electrical device. She heated all hers in an iron teakettle. Today, we make preparations with infinite pains and daintiness for the stork's visit. Then, apparel was crude, neighbor and nurse remote whent he little children came into the world. Now, we equip our automobile with Pullman kitchenette and modern devices. Imagine this aspiring young woman setting forth with the Judge over the same long stretches from Olympia to Vancouver, to Fort Walla Walla, Lewiston, Idaho, and other points remotely located for holding court.</p>
<p>"Sometimes," said Mrs. McGilvra, "I served dinners, camp-fashion, to district judges, who were assembling for the trial of cases. And one time the Indians stole our horses and swam them across the Snake River. the soldiers at the fort moved us about with government mules till the horses were recovered."</p>
<p>After the death of Lincoln, Judge McGilvra declined the proffered re-appointment. He then devoted more of his energy to their personal interests and home-building.</p>
<p>The homestead site was chosen on the west side of Lake Washington. Do we realize what if meant to clear the way for that first wagon road, now Madison Street, from the lake to Elliott Bay? It was six miles through timber, brush, logs and skunk cabbage. The road was made and then widened at their own expense with the poor help of Indians.</p>
<p>"How many, many times," she commented, "have I walked every step of the way from our house to the village (Seattle) rather than endure the rough road by wagon! I usually noticed fresh bear tracks a-plenty along the way, showing the creature was nearby in search of wild berries.</p>
<p>"Oh, yes, I was afraid, although everyone told me the bear was much more afraid of me and, no doubt, was peering at me through the roadside growth."</p>
<p>I thought to myself that this incident would be interesting to recall the next time we should stop our car to admire the beautiful landscape brilliant with flowering shrubs, roses and formal flower-beds in our present-day parks and boulevard spaces.</p>
<p>In a few decades that first Madison Street road was paralleled and intersected by paved and lighted avenues bearing the names of other well-known pioneers. There is Boren, Terry, Minor, Denny Way, Yesler; still farther away Bagley, Bigelow and Burke. Near the old home on the lake, Pioneer Hall was erected on lots given by the McGilvras in 1910. The McGilvra School, of our Seattle school system, is near by on land donated by this family. The McGilvra Boulevard, connecting the Denny-Blaine with the Lake Boulevard, deserves to be called one of Seattle's beauty spots.</p>
<p>Mrs. McGilvra's little family, in growing up, was used
<pb/>
</p>