<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<p>When the city bought the plant of the Spring Hill Water Company there were three pumps, with a combined capacity of 2,500,000 gallons a day at Lake Washington station. Just twenty days after the purchase the city passed Ordinance No. 1294 providing for the purchase of two pumps with a combined capacity of 2,500,000 gallons per day. The next year, in September, 1891, Ordinance No. 1824 authorized the purchase of an additional pump of 5,000,000 gallons capacity per day, thus raising the pumping capacity of the plant to 10,000,000 gallons per day.</p>
<p>It is worth noting that the failure of the water supply during the great fire of 1889 was a strong argument for a city-owned system, with an adequate quantity of water for such emergencies.</p>
<p>The city paid $350,000 for the Spring Hill water plant in June, 1890. Since then the plant has been conducted under municipal management.</p>
<p>As early as September, 1888, Robert Moran, then Mayor of Seattle, in a letter to the City Council, recommended the investigation of a proposed gravity system. The Council Committee on Fire and Water authorized John G. Scurry, the City Engineer, to investigate and report on the cost of a system. On October 19, 1888, Mr. Scurry made his report, recommending that supply be obtained from Rock Creek, one of the tributaries of Cedar River. He proposed a thirty-inch pipe to bring into the city a supply of 10,000,000 gallons per day; enough to serve a population of 100,000 people. He estimated the cost at $764,980. The city council called an election on July 8, 1889, on a proposition to issue bonds in the sum of $1,000,000 to build a system; but the amount exceeded the debt limit and the bonds were not issued. The vote stood 1,875 for and 51 against. In the meantime Major Moran had employed Mr. Benezette Williams, a hydraulic engineer of national reputation, to make surveys and estimates for a system, and Mr. Williams made his first report on November 12, 1889. On February 21, 1890, Mr. Williams filed a report, estimating the cost of the gravity system at $1,200,793.65, and of the necessary improvements and extensions in the city distribution system at $535,053.86.</p>
<p>In a letter to the city council on August 11, 1890, Mr. Williams said "There is no alternative consistent with the safety of the city, but to enter at an early date upon the building of the Cedar River Works as proposed, or to definitely abandon this plan and begin upon the construction of entirely new pumping works, force mains, and reservoirs, to supply fully both high and low service districts from Lake Washington." It will be noticed that in Mr. Williams' report the use of Rock Creek is abandoned, and the headworks finally located in its present position in Section 19, Township 22, N. R. 7 E. W. M.</p>
<p>There is an amusing story in connection with the early discussions of the Cedar River pipe line. When Mr. Whitworth, of the engineering firm of Thomson and Whitworth, suggested that it would be necessary to go several miles up Cedar River in order to secure sufficient elevation to deliver water in adequate quantity to the reservoirs by gravity, a local 
<figure><caption><p>OLD DAM AND CEDAR LAKE</p></caption></figure>
engineer (so the story goes) declared that no such proceeding would be necessary; that if an open spout were lowered into Cedar River at Renton the tremendous force of the current would force the water up into the reservoirs at Seattle.</p>
<p>Mr. Thomson became city engineer in 1892. One of the first tasks he undertook was the development of the Cedar River water supply. In this he had the enthusiastic support of H. R. Clise, chairman of the fire and water committee of the board of aldermen in 1894. The outlook was not reassuring as there seemed to be no way of raising the necessary money. One day, in the course of the routine of his law practice, Mr. Clise was reading the reports of the State Supreme Court decision, and ran across one that prompted him to speedily summon Thomson and Will H. Parry, then city comptroller, into conference with him. This decision upheld the legality of an ordinance passed by the voters of Spokane who sought to build a water system with money obtained through the sale of warrants, redeemable from the receipts of the water itself. The court held that this was a charge against the system and did not increase the bonded indebtedness of the city. Clise, Thomson and Parry agreed that Seattle's opportunity had come, and a plan of campaign was at once decided upon.</p>
<p>Mr. Thomson appointed George F. Cotterill to make a complete report on the engineering problems involved in the construction of the Cedar River system, and work was begun on the preparation of an ordinance for submission to the council. No public announcement of any kind was made and not a dozen people in Seattle knew that any steps were being taken by the city to secure Cedar River water for Seattle. The reason for this secrecy was the activity of a private company which hoped to develop the same source of supply for itself, and sell both water and power to the people of Seattle. The company was organized by Edward H. Ammidown, who had lately arrived in Seattle from New York. He enlisted the support of almost all the financially strong men of the city, applied to the city council for an ordinance granting his company a franchise to lay its mains and authorizing the sale to the company of all the city's then existing waterworks property. James A. James, chairman of the fire and water committee of the house of delegates, had joined the Thomson-Clise-Parry alliance and the Ammidown application did not make particularly rapid progress before the council, although great pressure was brought to bear in the effort to have the city pass the necessary legislation.</p>
<p>Finally, Cotterill's report was ready. Chairman Clise called his committee together and read the report which he proposed to present to the council that night. The committee approved the report, and that evening a joint session of the board of aldermen and the house of delegates was held and Mr. Clise read his report recommending the construction of the Cedar River water system by the city.</p>
<p>A bitter struggle ensued between the Ammidown forces and the municipal ownership advocates. There were many good men on both sides of the fight, but all the money seemed to be on one side. The supporters of the private company hired halls and held nightly meetings and their opponents
<figure><caption><p>MASONERY DAM, CEDAR LAKE</p></caption></figure>
had no comprehensive methods of reaching the people with their arguments. Mr. Clise, Mr. James, Doctor Young and others did their best on behalf of the ordinance, while Mr. Thomson sat back and provided them with the ammunition.</p>
<p>Among the most earnest and logical opponents of the latter was Hon. John J. McGilvra. Between him and Mr. Thomson an intermittent discussion of the proposed plan ensued lasting more than a week when the former capitulated and became an enthusiastic supporter of the measure.</p>
<p>McGilvra then organized a number of speakers in favor of the ordinance, hired halls and bands and paid for everything out of his own pocket. A spirited campaign in favor of the ordinance was waged with the result that it carried by a vote of 2,656 in its favor to 1,665 against it.</p>
<p>Recently, as noted elsewhere, Mr. Thomson expressed his opinion that his most important service for the City of Seattle and King County was in connection with the establishment of the King County Port Commission. In this the writer does not concur.</p>
<p>The greatest service which Reginald H. Thomson performed in relation to the water supply of the City of Seattle was his tireless, unceasing struggle for the maintenance of its purity. That Seattle is today the healthiest city in the world is due primarily to the excellence of her water. Long before he become city engineer Mr. Thomson realized that of equal importance to securing Cedar River and Lake as a source of supply was the acquiring of sufficient land in the watershed to provide for all time against any contamination of the water itself. At times when it was charged that his activities were the outgrowth of an impracticable dream, he urged the purchase of lands in the watershed. In season and out of season, the relentless pursuit of the idea went on and that today Seattle owns 80,000 acres of land, which gives it control of the basin in which its water supply lies, is due soley to the foresight, determination and perserverance of Mr. Thomson. He has saved the city the many millions of dollars it would ultimately have had to spend, an expense all other great cities of the world have had to meet to keep their water pure. As other cities have grown they ahve been compelled to spend immense sums to acquire lands tributary to the water supply, a contingent overlooked at the time the source of supply was obtained. When Seattle was little more than a village Thomson saw that the time would come when it would number millions and all the work he did for its water supply was predicated on that belief. He built the foundation so well that never in the history of Seattle can its water supply give any concern.</p>
<p>The growth of the city during thirty-nine years is indicated in some degree by a comparison of the vote cast in 1889 with that cast in 1927. The total vote on the Cedar River proposition was 1,879. The vote in 1927 was 100,798.</p>
<p>The contract for the construction of Pipe Line No. 1 was let April 19, 1899. The work was executed under the direction of R. H. Thomson, City Engineer. Water was delivered in the city in January, 1901. The line will deliver 22,500,000 gallons per day. Within five years, however, this supply had become insufficient and another pipe line had to be built. The first pipe line, with the necessary intake and controlling works, reservoirs, etc., cost $1,250,000.</p>
<p>A contract for Pipe Line No. 2 was let on August 15, 1908, and water was delivered in the city reservoirs on June 21, 1909. This pipe line delivers 44,769,000 gallons per day. The cost was $2,250,000.</p>
<p>The two pipe lines give the city a supply of 67,269,000 gallons per day.</p>
<p>During the past three years this supply would have been insufficient on some hot days in summer had it not been for the building of Pipe Line No. 3 from Ginger Creek to the city, which enables the delivery to be increased about 10,000,000 gallons daily, without drawing from Lake Youngs.</p>
<p>The propostion to use Lake Youngs as an impounding basin had been discussed at various times. It was evident that if this lake could be raised twenty feet, a volume of water could be accumulated during the winter months sufficient to tide over the summer period of greatest consumption for some years to come. Two dams were built, one at the south end and one at the northeast end of the lake, to prevent overflow when the water level was raised, and a tunnel eight feet in diameter and over two miles long was constructed from the lake to a controlling works at Molasses Creek. All three of the pipe lines are connected with these controlling works, and are now available to convey water from Lake Youngs to the city, making the possible delivery to the city of 117,500,000 gallons per day.</p>
<p>The contract for the construction of Pipe Line No. 3 was let on April 4, 1922, for $1,468,602,50. This bid, however, did not cover the cost of the backfilling and pavement repairs. These costs aggregated approximately $500,000, making the total cost of the work substantially $2,000,000. The line consists of a 66-inch steel riveted pipe fifteen miles long, which is estimated to have a capacity of 50,000,000 gallons per day. This line, however, could not be made fully available until the tunnel from Lake Youngs to Molasses Creek and the controlling works at the latter point were constructed. A contract for this work was let to Jahn &amp; Bressi, on February 13, 1924, for the sum of $1,210,759. Before the work was finished defects began to appear in the tunnel lining. A difference arose as to who was responsible for these failures, whether the contractor or the city. Finally, the Board of Public Works took the construction out of the hands of Jahn &amp; Bressi and let a contract for finishing the job to J. M. Clapp. When this contract was completed and paid for the cost of the entire work, which included the intake, controlling works and the end of the pipe previously installed from Ginger Creek to the city, aggregated approximately $1,625,000.</p>
<p>The two wooden pipe lines above Lake Youngs are capable of bringing into the lake about 74,500,000 gallons per day, about 8,000,000 gallons more than they could deliver into the city reservoir. While this quantity, under ordinary circumstances, would be sufficient to supply the city, except for a short time in summer, yet if a condition should arise (which is wholly improbable) that Lake Youngs should be drawn down to its limit, and a spell of very dry, hot weather should supervene, there would be a shortage of the supply with our present population. Of course this condition would be aggravated if the population were much greater.</p>
<p>In order to get an increased supply into Lake Youngs it is intended to build a conduit from a point at or near the present headworks on Cedar River to Lake Youngs, a distance of eight and one-half miles, and having a capacity of 300,000,000 gallons per day. The survey for this line has been made, and a right of way secured. It will doubtless be built in the near future. </p>