<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>Old Records Tell How Puget Sound Customs Men Went About: Tracking the Smugglers</head>
<byline>By LUCILE McDONALD</byline>
<p>SMUGGLERS of opium and Chinese furnished exciting activity for the Puget Sound customs officers for 20 years or more. Details of how smugglers were trapped or more often, got away, are revealed in a mass of records recently transferred here from Port Townsend and now being catalogued in the Collector of Customs' office in the Federal Building.</p>
<p>By the time headquarters of the customs district moved to Seattle on July 1, 1913, Chinese no longer were so much in the news. The Exclusion Act of 1882, designed to suspend importation of Oriental laborers for a ten-year period, spurred the smugglers. Until then, coolies had been brought in freely to supply cheap labor for canneries, hop yards, mines and public works. As many as 15,000 were employed in construction of the Northern Pacific Railroad.</p>
<p>After the ban was put on the Chinese, Puget Sound was the hole in the fence through which they entered. They continued to arrive in British Columbia from Hongkong in groups of 100 to 700 on English vessels docking every three weeks. Canada gave them 90 days in which to leave the country.</p>
<p>THE United States has been advertised to the Chinese as the promised land. Some years prior to passage of the law, this country had done considerable recruiting of Oriental labor. When the door was suddenly closed against the Orientals, they continued to take a chance on getting through. No penalty was attached to any Chinese making the attempt and when caught he did not have to pay his expenses back to his starting place. Some tried so often their faces were familiar to the customs men, who at that time also constituted the immigration service.</p>
<p>In 1880, statistics showed 3,186 Chinese legally living in Washington. When smuggling commenced, the general scheme was to channel newly arrived Orientals to places where they could be lost among their brethren already in the country.</p>
<p>Small sailing vessels, ostensibly fishing boats, used to lie at anchor at a buoy off the Indian reservation at the entrance to Victoria Harbor. Chinese would be taken out to them and transported to a hiding place at James or Sidney Islands. When enough were gathered to make the run advisable, all were picked up from their camp and the sloop made for Dungeness or some place near Port Townsend, arriving after dark and departing in the night. The Chinese were instructed how to proceed from the beach to a place of security among their countrymen in a nearby town.</p>
<p>An opium cargo was a little more difficult because it would not walk to its final destination but had to be carried there by some person.</p>
<p>A REFINERY of crude opium existed in Victoria, where the poppy gum was boiled, skimmed and prepared for smoking. It could be imported by paying duty, but evading the tariff by smuggling was more profitable. Another device was to sweat off the stamps and apply them to cans on which the import tax had not been paid.</p>
<p>A feature of the illicit traffic was adulteration. A purchaser of smuggled drugs could not "squel." Some revealing entries from the customs house seizure books read like this: "June 2, 1894, New Whatcom&#8212;200 cans supposed to contain opium, upon examination found to contain a substance resembling tar."</p>
<p>"March 27, 1892&#8212;found at Howard and Bryant's wharf, Seattle&#8212;five five-tael tins of prepared opium. With them 318 five-tael tins containing molasses and flour.</p>
<p>"June 11, 1892, at Seattle&#8212;four five-tael tins of opium and 349 tins of molasses."</p>
<p>In July, 1885, more than 120 pounds of opium were confiscated on Puget Sound. Today the "revenuers" do not pick up that quantity in years. The next month 80 tins or 40 pounds of the narcotic comprised a single haul taken from a sloop at Discovery Bay. The offender, who was apprehended, had among his equipment a revolver, two different types of spy-glasses, a call whistle and a bottle of strychnine.</p>
<p>HOWEVER, smugglers seldom were caught. The seizure book is filled with entries marked "owner unknown." This was the case with four trunks containing 1,300 tins found in the Northern Pacific station at Spokane and turned over to the Port Townsend collector.</p>
<p>Instead of being destroyed, the drug was sold at auction and the lot brought more than $7,000, a fantastically low sum in terms of present values.</p>
<p>The seizure book shows frequent losses through cans being thrown overboard or floated ashore. Written in memos are such lines as "20 five-tael tins containing salt water mixed with opium and molasses"&#8212;double adulteration&#8212;and, "shipment damaged and leaking water badly."</p>
<p>THE hundreds of reports have a certain sameness. If you put them all together the details fall into a pattern. Everybody knew about smuggling. The lightkeeper at Dungeness could see Chinese arriving and being taken ashore in canoes. He saw schooners which always departed by 3 o'clock in the morning. When seized the craft invariably had a fishing net, usually rotten and worthless.</p>
<p>The Orientals landed on the beach. Maybe there was a Chinese garden nearby, where the personnel changed frequently. Some nights the dogs at Chimacum set up a mysterious barking. That meant Chinese on the run, trying to reach Port Discovery or some place where friends would push them along.</p>
<p>Bound books contain telegrams via the Puget Sound Telegraph Co., hand-written, bearing messages like these:/p>
<p>"Victoria&#8212;Boat leaving tonight for Port Discovery Bay Charley Cook's landing at hotel 400 pounds opium. Probably reach there tomorrow night. Hansen."</p>
<p>Whatcom&#8212;Kelly (doubtless Lawrence Kelly of Sinclair Island, most famous smuggler on the Sound in the 1880's) left Bellingham Bay today with stuff for his island. Also another sloop went down the Sound with stuff. W. Wheeler."</p>
<p>Victoria&#8212;Small sloop about three-ton register with white stripes on rail left here 12 o'clock last night for Whatcom 100 pounds on board two men."</p>
<p>THERE was money in the business. The Chinese were mostly agriculturists in their homeland. They paid from $50 to $100 to make the crossing from Victoria and there were plenty of boatmen ready to take the risk. The opium went along with them on the same trip. So profitable was smuggling that officials were not above dipping into it, to the scandal of the service.</p>
<p>A letter from an agent in Victoria telling of the Canadian Pacific steamer Albany in November, 1888, landing a consignment of 6,618 pounds of opium in British Columbia includes this astonishing sidelight on the trade:</p>
<p>"Singularly enough," the informant wrote, "the well-known evangelist Moody appears to be a factor in suppression of opium smuggling indirectly at least, as his conversion of Chet Terry, late holding an important position in the custom house at Port Townsend but who has been in the refuge over here for some months, and the restitution by the ex-inspector to the United States government of some $6,000 through the hand of Moody would prove, I may say, that I know this to be true."</p>