<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>Commissioner of Statistics and Emigration.</head>
<p>We have before us the bill introduced by Hon. H.G. Struve, which our Councilmen were to act upon today, creating a Commissioner of Emigration and Statistics. We have read the provisions of the bill attentively, and are of the opinion that in all essential particulars it is just the thing required.</p>
<p>The duties of the Commissioner are defined rather than prescribed, and the largest liberty of judgment is permitted as to what department of his bureau he shall devote the most time and labor.</p>
<p>The salary of the Commissioner is twenty-five hundred dollars per year, out of which sum he must pay his office rent, and for fuel and lights&#8212;a very low figure for the work expected.</p>
<p>The appropriation named in the bill for annual contingent expenses is altogether too small. Five thousand per year is the least sum that should be thought of for the important purposes set forth in the bill. The people of this Territory never paid any tax with so much cheerfulness as they will that which provides the funds to defray the expenses of this popular measure.</p>
<p>Who, if the bill becomes a law, will be the first Commissioner under the act, we do not know; but from an extensive acquaintance with our public men of all parties, we are unable to think of but one gentleman whose literary tastes and executive capacity alike fit him for this novel but responsible position. This gentleman has labored with intelligent assiduity for the last five years in unfolding the history of Oregon and Washington, and has, from love of the work, collected such abundant materials in regard to the climate, soil, forests and mineral products of Washington Territory, as would enable him at once to prepare a series of valuable papers exactly adapted to the requirements of the law, and such as no new man could gather together in the two years of his service as Commissioner. The gentleman to whom we refer has no knowledge of our views in this respect, and will probably be surprised to see us advocate his appointment, as our personal relations have not always been as pleasant as would be desirable. But the admirable fitness of Elwood Evans for the office of Commissioner of Emigration and Statistics is such that, setting aside all personal considerations, in the interests of the people, we respectfully urge upon the Legislature his appointment.</p>