<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

Constitutional Amendments and the Democracy.

The following are the Amendments to the Federal Constitution, recently ratified by two-thirds of the States, and which the Democracy&#8212;the Democracy which with rare exceptions, sympathized with the rebellion&#8212;are pledging themselves in their political platform to have abrogated. The Democracy make the abrogation of these amendments, issues in the coming campaign in Oregon and this Territory, and we gladly meet them just where they throw down the gauntlet. We ask our readers to carefully peruse these Amendments to our constitution, and make up their mind whether they will vote for or against a party that is in favor of expunging them from the organic law of the land. These Amendments are a part of the fruits of the war, a kind of fruit that has always been unpalatable to the Democracy as a party. The Democratic party, as a party, never had any sympathy with the war for the putting down of the rebellion, much less a liking for its fruits. They were opposed to the war and the measures used by the government for the suppression of the rebellion. They opposed the raising of troops to put down the rebellion, they opposed the raising and appropriating of money to pay them; they opposed the equipment of colored soldiers and putting them in the ranks of the Union army; they opposed the draft; they opposed the emancipation of slaves, who, under restraint and coercion were raising supplies for the rebel army and shooting down our patriotic boys in blue on the battle field. They mourned and groaned in spirit when the rebellion was finally crushed and it is no wonder that they are now opposed to gathering the fruits of that long and bloody struggle. It is in keeping with the record of the Democratic party since 1860 to pit themselves against the sublime and peace-preserving principles contained in these amendments. How rejoiced should every lover of his country be in the realization of the fact that the government is not now, and is never likely to be, in the hands of such a party. Read the Amendments for yourselves and decide whether you would blot out any or all of them at the bidding of a party which for the last ten years has been straining every nerve to break down the government:

Article 13.

Sec. 1. Neither slavery or involuntary servitude, except as a punishment for crime, whereof the party shall have been duly convicted, shall exist within the United States, or any place subject their jurisdiction.

Sec. 2. Congress shall have power to enforce this Article by appropriate legislation.


Article 14.

Sec. 1. All persons born or naturalized in the United States, and subject to the jurisdiction thereof, are citizens of the United States, and of the States wherein they reside. No State shall make or enforce any law which shall abridge the privileges and immunities of citizens of the United States. Nor, shall any State deprive any person of life, liberty, or property, within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws.

Sec. 2. Representatives shall be apportioned among the several States according to their respective numbers, counting the whole number of persons in each State, excluding Indians not taxed; but whenever the right to vote at any election for electors of President and Vice President and Vice President, or United States Representatives in Congress, executive and judicial officers, or the members of the Legislature thereof, is denied to any of the male inhabitants of this State, being twenty-one years of age, and citizens of the United States, or in any way abridged, except for participation in rebellion or other crimes, the basis of representation therein shall be reduced in the proportion which the number of such male citizens shall bear to the whole number of male citizens twenty-one years of age in the State.

Sec. 3. No person shall be a Senator or Representative in Congress, elector of President and Vice President, or hold any office, civil or military, under the United States, or under any State, who, having previously taken an oath as a member of Congress, or as an officer of the United States, or as a member of any State Legislature, or as an executive or judicial officer of any State, to support the Constitution of the United States, shall have engaged in insurrection or rebellion against the same, or given aid or comfort to the enemies thereof; but Congress may, by a vote of two-thirds of each House, remove such disability.

Sec. 4. The validity of the public debt of the United States authorized by law, including debts incurred for the payment of pensions and bounties for service in suppressing insurrection or rebellion, shall not be questioned; but neither the United States, nor any State, shall assume or pay any debt or obligation incurred in aid of insurrection or rebellion against the United States, or any claim for the loss or emancipation of any slave, but all such debts, obligations, and claims shall be illegal and void.

Sec. 5. The Congress shall have power to enforce, by appropriate legislation, the provisions of this Article.


Article 15.

Sec. 1. The right of citizens of the United States to vote shall not be denied or abridged by the United States, or by an State on account of race, or color, or previous condition of servitude.

Sec. 2. Congress shall have power to enforce this Article by appropriate legislation.
