<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

Washington Correspondence.

Washington City, D. C. ,
March 21, 1870.

Editor Age: Since penning my last notes from the Capital many important changes in a political sense have taken place.

Revels, The Colored Senator, has been admitted to his sent in the American Senate, as the worthy representative of the down trodden, despised,&#8212;and at one time&#8212;enslaved race. Revels' election to the United States Senate as the successor of the arch-traitor, Jeff Davis, makes a memorable page in the wonderful history of the Federal Union, and begins a new epoch in our Republican-representative form of Government.

Gen. E. S. Salomon, has been confirmed by the Senate as Governor of Washington Territory, vice Alvan Flanders, removed.

Smith Kearney&#8212;the courteous, retiring and wide-awake Kearney of Walla Walla county, W. T., left here on yesterday, for his home, as the United States Marshal of Washington Territory&#8212;<hi rend="italic"> vice</hi> Philip Ritz, <hi rend="italic">retired.</hi>

Hon. Orange Jacobs, late Associate Justice, has been duly confirmed as Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of W. T., and these changes to say nothing of others of the small import, will carry joy to the hearts of the true and tried members of the Republican party of your Territory.

The following summary will convey to your readers a knowledge, in brief, as to what the Territorial Represent-tive has accomplished since writing our last communication to the Commercial Age.

An appropriation of $8,676, covering the deficiency in the previous appropriation for defraying the <unclear>ases</unclear> of yoru Legislative Assembly, and, also, an appropriation of $6,000 for public printing, have passed the House and will beyond question pass the Senate at an early day.

The appropriation of $12,000 to your last Assembly has been made applicable.

A bill appropriating $50,000 for the erection of a Custom House At Port Townsend has been favorably considered by the appropriate committee of the House and its early passage recommended.

The Delegate has succeeded in getting the proper committees of Congress (<hi rend="italic">joint committee</hi> would be more correct) to recommend that the entire biennial Internal Revenue tax of your Territory, shall not exceed $100,000 or more than $50,000 per annum.

The sale of school lands in the Territory has been reported favorable by committee.

Fort Steilacoom and the lands occupied thereby have been donated to the Territory, by the Government for the purpose of establishing an Insane Asylum.

The mud flats at Olympia have been donated, also, for wharfage purposes.

The Superintendent of Light Houses has given the necessary official orders for surveying and buoying out the channel leading into Shoalwater Bay.

Tri-weekly mail service between Walla Walla, W. T., and Lewiston, Idaho T'y, has been established, or soon will be.

Land Office At Walla Walla.
Mr. Garfielde has been assured to an early recommendation by the committee having the matter under consideration, creating a local Land office at the above named point.

Your honored Representative has been formally chosen by the Northern Pacific Railroad Company, to make the leadign argument in the House in favor of said road, so far as it relates to Congressional action thereon.

This, to say the least, confers upon the Delegate of W. T. a high honor, and when the bill comes up before the House, and Mr. Garfielde shall have enunciated his views thereon, the citizens of Washington Territory, will then be enabled to understand and, we cannot doubt, appreciate his zeal, ability and fervor with regard to the location of this gigantic enterprise and substantial improvement&#8212;uniting the waters of Lake Superior with Puget Sound.

Political Items.&#8212;March 22d.
Senator Conkling made a powerful argument in the Senate to-day, against the admission of Gen. Ames, Senator elect form Mississippi, taking the ground that he was not a resident of the State.

General Ames is a boyish, handsome looking <hi rend="italic">chap</hi>, wears a black mustache (<hi rend="italic">dyed</hi>) and appears quite sanguine of his ultimate admission to a seat in the Senate. I am inclined to the opinion that hsi vanity and ambition for Senatorial honors will be considerably <hi rend="italic">dampened</hi> before he takes the oath of office.

O. X. Ford.