<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>DAYS OF RAGE</head>
<byline>By DAVID M. BUERGE</byline>
<ab>around 6pm on January 17, 1882, George Reynolds left his house on Marion Street and began to walk down the hill to D.A. Jennings' store, where he worked. Then 29 years old, Reynolds had not been in Seattle long, but he was beginning to put down roots. He had a good job as a clerk, was well liked by those who knew him, and had only recently gotten married. As he approached the corner of Marion and Third, two men stepped out from the shadows, one holding a .38 Colt revolver.</ab>
<p>"Put your hands up!" a voice barked, but Reynolds reached instead for his pocket, where he kept a pistol for protection. As he brought it out, the gunman's accomplice shouted, "Let him have it!" The shot knocked Reynolds back into a picket fence, wounding him fatally. It also set off an explosion that rocked the town for years and ultimately produced a social revolution.</p>
<p>Seattle was in that year about to enter a period of enormous and often painful growth, but it was still a small town of about 6,000 souls. It was one of the oldest towns on Puget Sound, and it had grown considerably since it was founded in 1851, but its growth had been slow and hard. Its pioneers had never doubted it would become a city one day, but many wondered why it was taking so long.</p>
<p>Seattle had become an important coaling port, thanks to mines dug into the hills east of town. It was a place where small steamboats&#8212;the mosquito fleet&#8212;docked to take on coal, make repairs, and load supplies before shoving off again to furrow the waters of the Sound and nose up its streams, keeping old customers happy and seeking out new ones as the country filed with settlers. Its sawmills kept the local market supplied with lumber, and its stores, shops, and saloons were rarely empty. On New Year's Day 1880, the editor of the Daily Intelligencer could write: "[L]ooking at the prospect from every side, and judging from the past, we are led to believe that we are entering upon an era of the most auspicious character, the results of which will place Seattle in the proud position her most sanguine friends have hoped to see her occupying."</p>
<p>The problem was that editors had been saying this kind of thing for nearly 30 years, and the hopes had still not materialized. Moreover, the town was changing in ways many found hard to accept. The old familiarity seemed to be a thing of the past; there were more strangers in town. In October 1881, the tough old pioneer and Seattle police officer David Sires had been shot to death by the man he was arresting. It was Seattle's first police fatality, and as the new year began, emboldened thugs held up their victims on the streets with drawn weapons. In the resultant siege mentality, many like Reynolds began carrying guns for protection.</p>
<p>As Reynolds fell against the fence, he fired his gun wildly at his fleeing assailants, hitting neither. The gunfire attracted nearby residents and passerby, who helped carry
<pb/>
him back to his house. Two hours later he gasped his life away in the arms of his grief-stricken bride. Minutes later the fire bell at the engine house rang out in alarm.</p>
<p>The crowd that gathered at the engine house formed a vigilance committee. Orange Jacobs, Seattle's major the year before, was elected chairman. Teams fanned out to look for the culprits, and an hour later two men were found hiding in a haystack on a waterfront pier. One had a .38 Colt revolver with an empty chamber smelling strongly of burnt powder. They were hauled off to jail, where Sheriff Louis Wycoff and Chief of Police John McGraw locked them up.</p>
<p>The anger did not subside. The suspects' boots were taken and matched with tracks in the mud at Third and Marion. The two were obviously the murderers, the vigilantes concluded, so why wait for a trail and let them live off the county like Ben Payne, Sires' murderer, who still sat in jail while the bereaved mourned? The crowd threatened to break down the jailhouse door if the suspects weren't released. With drawn guns and promises to present the pair promptly at the morning hearing. Wycoff and McGraw were able to keep the mob at bay, but the jail was ringed by angry men all night long.</p>
<p>At 9:30 the next morning, Justice of the Peace Samuel Coombs opened court at Yesler's Hall, Seattle's civic meeting place at Front (First Avenue) and Cherry. The accused, identified as James Sullivan and William Howard, both transient workers, heard the evidence presented against them in the tense hall. Coombs was about to send them back to jail to await trail when, at a signal, vigilantes stormed the court and overpowered its officiers. The accused men were dragged out the back door to the alley and down to James Street, where two long rails had been secured high in the bare branches of maple trees fronting a square.</p>
<p>The chief justice of the Territorial Supreme Court, Roger Greene, was in the hall to help ensure a fair hearing, but as he rose to protest the capture of the prisoners, he was knocked down and covered with a curtain ripped from the stage. He managed to free himself and find the glasses that had been struck from his face, but by the time he got to the scene, the two suspects had nooses cinched around their necks and were being hoisted into the air. They were raised with such force that their heads struck the rails, and Howard's neck was broken. Greene waded into the roaring crowd, shouting at them to desist and managing to slash at the ropes holding the two men a few times with a pocket knife before he was thrust roughly away.</p>
<p>The crowd milled about the dangling bodies until Sullivan's quit jerking, swarmed back to the jailhouse, smashed its way in, and dragged the terrified Ben Payne down to the grimly hung tree. A voice in the crowd shouted, "Did you fire the shot that killed Officer Sires?" Payne cried out, "You hang me and you will hang an innocent man." Then he too was hauled aloft to heave and convulse. The crowd remained to feast its eyes on the dead long enough for a reporter to sketch the scene. After the bodies were cut down and hauled away in a wagon, the square emptied.</p>
<p>The drawing, which appeared a few weeks later in Harper's Weekly, provides a detailed portrait of the town. There, whittling his pine stick in the foreground, is Henry Yesler, the richest man in town, and the one who donated the gallows timbers. The future first governor of Washington state, Elisha P. Ferry, is there, along with virtually every other citizen of consequence Chinese, blacks, and Native Americans are depicted, but no women like boxing and horse racing in those days, lynching was for men only.</p>
<p>The lynching of Sullivan, Howard, and Payne exposed a deep rift in the town's social fabric. Sires and Reynolds were both family men, residents who had made Seattle their home and who owned property. Both had been killed by transients, single men who drifted from town to town, from mine to lumber camp, carrying what they owned on their backs. The labor-intensive industries of the frontier West required many hands, but the boom and bust economy ensured that the workers were often on the move from one job to the next. At any time before the turn of the century, unpropertied transient workers outnumbered the propertied residents of the town by more than 2 to 1.</p>
<p>In town they worked as harness makers, soap makers, foundrymen, boiler makers, shipwrights, carpenters, rope makers, cooks, bakers, and mill workers. They were clerks waiters, meat packers, teamsters, deliverymen,a dn printers. They did the work that kept the town going and growing, 12 hours a day, six days a week. During their one day off, Sunday, their numbers were augmented by boatmen, miners, and lumberjacks who came to town to "blow 'er in" after an exhausting week's work.</p>
<p>Most of them lived in the hotels, boarding houses, and tenements that stood south of Mill Street (Yesler Way), the original Skid Road. Much of that area had been a swamp until it was filled in with sawdust and rubble, and its rough uneven surface gave it its popular name, the "lava beds." The social centers of this Rabelaisian district were its saloons, card parlors, bordellos, and opium dens. Most workers were young, so Saturday night revels were raucous affairs, often punctuated with brawls, fistfights, and shootings. Sundays were spent making the rounds or sleeping off the previous night's excess.</p>
<p>If they were inclined, workingmen could attend services in the town's churches. By 1880 there were seven denominations represented, but only one church, the Catholic Our Lady of Good help, was located south of Mill Street, where it had to compete with the area's 35 saloons. The rest of the churches were located on the hill above Mill Street, where the propertied folk lived. Here were the homes of the pioneers, chief among whom were members of the Denny Party; the Dennys and the Borens who had traveled from Illinois in covered wagons and landed at Alki Point with the Terrys. Later they were joined by Henry Yesler, by the Mercers, Bagleys, and Hortons, who came west in the Bethel Party in '52; and by the Fryes, Butlers, and Hanfords.</p>
<p>They came predominantly from the rural Midwest before the Civil War, and they ahd all the strengths and limitations that came from growing to maturity in small rural communities. They were hard working and independent, but many like Arthur Denny could not see any difference between the opportunities available to a pioneer who could claim 320 acres of free land and a mill worker making 25-cents an hour.</p>
<p>One of the benefits of being married in Seattle's early days was that husband and wife together could claim 640 acres&#8212;a square mile of land. The exigencies of frontier life underscored the value of marriage and family. Women were so crucial to the success of pioneering that there were several attempts to import groups of them from the East. Once here, the families often intermarried, creating a network of kin relationships that gave frontier society a distinctly familial cast.</p>
<p>The best lands in the townsite were quickly claimed, and as later-arriving entrepreneurs purchased lots on which to erect their mills and businesses, the value of the land increased. In the beginning the pioneers often worked as common laborers to earn scarce cash, but as the town grew and the lots they sold brought them wealth, their jobs were given over to those who arrived to work them in the hopes of earning enough money to buy land themselves. Gradually a gulf opened between those who owned the land and the businesses and those who worked the jobs. When times were good and wages were high, this gap could be crossed with relative ease, but when they were not, it yawned as a chasm.</p>
<p>Increasingly, the church-going, middle-class society that the pioneers created on the hill grew disdainful of what was developing in the lava beds, which came to be called "the vice district." After the Civil War consumed the passion for abolition, temperance resumed its position as the moral issue of the day and a favorite sermon topic. But as pastors on the hill inveighed against the evils of drink, saloon keepers in the lava beds were scurrying to keep glasses filled for the growing throngs of thirsty workers. That saloons did a hefty share of their business on Sunday, the one day workingmen had off, seemed to the pious a special affront to the holiness of the Sabbath.</p>
<p>Another cause for anxiety among the hill folk were the prostitutes. In earlier years they had been tolerated by being ignored, and by the fact that many prostitutes were native women working in so-called "squaw houses," but by the 1880s Seattle's red-light district was famous up and down the coast. There were fitful attempts to eliminate it, through legal means or through force, but it grew with the population, and its profits and taxes proved increasingly attractive.</p>
<p>The vast majority of workingmen were law abiding and wanted nothing more for the msot part than to settle down, have a family, and become property owners themselves. Inevitably, however, their numbers included what the hill folk called "the lawless element." Their numbers increased; so did hte lawlessness. On that frenzied day in January of 1882, propertied and unpropertied alike lashed out against it, but it would be a long time before their interests would again converge.</p>
<p>The gallows timbers were left in the maple branches as a warning to criminals, and for a time at least, they had the desired effect. The day after the lynchings congratulatory telegrams arrived from Olympia and Port Townsend, but not everyone was pleased. The Methodist Episcopal bishop of Portland labeled it an "outburst of savagery," and Roger Greene was outraged. A few days after the affair he appeared before a grand jury and argued that everyone involved with the lynching should be charged with manslaughter. No indictments were handed down, but 40 years later when historian Clarence Bagley interviewed him, Grenne was still fuming. "It was an outburst of lawlessness, an explosion of savagery....Like stampeded cattle, a tidal wave of emotion swept practically the whole community in a wrong direction."</p>
<p>The affair made national news. The Chicago Daily News observed: "The City of Seattle, in Washington Territory, is being governed by a committee of safety, and when a robbery, burglary, or murder is committed, the perpetrator of the crime is placed in a position in which he stands on a platform without exactly feeling what he is standing on. It is a plan which has made the city a wonderfully peaceful one for decent people and it is cheap so far as expenses are concerned, as it saved the cost of court and juries and is more effective than both."</p>
<p>But while cities in the East laughed at the antics of vigilantes out in the wild West, the mood was not so buoyant in Seattle. Two days after the lynchings, Sheriff Wyoff; an old pioneer and a man highly respected in the community, died of a heart attack, apparently brought on by the grief he felt at being unable to protect his prisoners. The lengthy editorials that vigorously justified what had happened were more revealing of a sense that things had gotten out of hand. Cow towns were governed by vigilanties. Hadn't Seattle aspired to something greater?</p>
<p>Many decided that the remedy was to get the unemployed that had flocked to town in the depressed years at the end of the '70s back to work. As 1882 wore on, there seemed to be some progress on that score. Banker Angus Mackintosh built an ice-making plant that expanded the town's capacity to prepare and store food products. After a lengthy battle with Portland, Seattle managed to capture the government contract to carry the mails to Alaska, which helped the mosquito fleet.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, there had been a change in management of the Northern Pacific Railroad, the line that had chosen Tacoma over Seattle as the western terminus of its transcontinental road. The new chairman of the board, Henry Villard, purchased the tracks that Seattle interests had built to the mines at Black Diamond and promised a connection to the NP tracks. Since 1883 was the year the NP was finally completed across the continent, the promise of a tie-in fueled a modest boom. Seattle's population neared 12,000, land sold for $500 a frontage foot downtown, and the construction boom consumed the entire output of the town's sawmills.</p>
<p>But many felt that as the town grew, so did its problems. To prevent the reappearance of a vigilante movement, attempts were made to control one of the sources of violence by seeking to restrict the operation of saloons and brothels where liquor was sold. In the spring of '83, charges were presented to a grand jury against several saloon and brothel operators. Indictments were handed down, but they had no effect on the liquor trade in the lava beds. The grand jury was recalled, more indictments were handed down, and once again the effect was so minuscule that the whole effort became the butt of jokes. It was clear to many that the police were cooperating with the owners of establishments in the lava beds.</p>
<p>Charges of municipal corruption would normally have caused no more than protests. But in the waning months of '83, the political situtation changed. In November, in response to calls from temperance advocates, a bill granting women the right to vote in territorial elections was passed by both houses of the Legislature. The protests were transformed into a full-fledged reform movement.</p>
<p>It was probably inevitable that the temperance movement would join forces with proponents of women's suffrage. The churches provided one of the few opportunities for women to socialize and demonstrate their abilities outside the home, and they were the foremost advocates of temperance. Many, like Arthur Denny, who had worked for both temperance and women's suffrage in ther territorial Legislature, believed that the two reform issues were natural allies. But this belieff, prevalent among mnay women, was resisted strenuously by suffragists like Oregon's Abigail Scott Duniway, who believed, quite rightly, that the cause of suffrage would be seriously harmed by its association with those who sought to impose their beliefs by force on a large segment of the population who disagreed with them.</p>
<p>In January the reform movement got under way with the creation of the Law and Order League founded by James Lewis, C.L. Wayland, David Denny, and his nephew, Roland Denny, who became its officers. The league dedicated itself to "sustain the regular officers of the city and county in a more strict execution of the law, to assist in prosecution of the law, to assist in prosecutions for law breaking where necessary, and to procure enactment of local measures in the furtherance of order in the community."</p>
<p>It actively sought women's votes. At one of its first public meetings, held in the Congregational Church, the women in the enthusiastic audience were asked whether they would register to vote, and every one present rose to her feet in assent. In June a call was made to all those "who favor the enforcement of existing laws and ordinances, and th eadministration of municipal affairs by sober, honest, and efficient men," to attend a meeting in the vacant lots of Fourth and Marion, a block away from where Reynolds had been shot. The 400 who showed up, most of them women, heard resolutions put forward by representatives of the league and the Young Men's Political Club, another reformist group, and helped select a slate of candidates for public office. A number of apple trees grew in the vacant lots, and they inspired the movement's members' prim christening as "Apple Orchardists"&#8212;idealists who would drive the serpent of drink and crime out of the garden and restore it to a happier state.</p>
<p>Their zeal for reform was not misplaced. Seattle in the 1880s was beset by problems made worse by the decade's rapid growth. Tacoma booster Ezra Mocker's partisan gibe that Seattle was a place one could smell long before one could see it was simple truth. In terms of sanitation and health, it was a pest hole. An abundance of privies on high ground and primitive box sewers rendered well water lower down unfit to drink. The effluent of these sewers flowed directly into the bay, where it was joined by waste from slaughterhouses and packing plants. The rafts of sewage and offal floating in the water or beached at low tide produced an appalling stink that boosters tried lamely to explain away as the odor of tide flats. As the town expanded residences was left to flow into Lake Union in three enormous
<pb/>
ditches. In an area where men worked in dangerous jobs and accidents were common, the majority of deaths came as a result of infectious disease.</p>
<p>The town had grown so quickly that it outgrew its water mains; in one instance, firemen had to watch a house burn because there was no nearby mains. Even those parts of town that had mains had poor service, and summer months often saw them completely dry. When this happened, the practice of sprinkling the dirt streets was suspended. Streets that were quagmires in the winter became avenues of dust and grit in the summer.</p>