<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>Old Records Tell How Puget Sound Customs Men Went About: Tracking the Smugglers</head>
<byline>By LUCILE McDONALD</byline>
<p>SMUGGLERS of opium and Chinese furnished exciting activity for the Puget Sound customs officers for 20 years or more. Details of how smugglers were trapped or more often, got away, are revealed in a mass of records recently transferred here from Port Townsend and now being catalogued in the Collector of Customs' office in the Federal Building.</p>
<p>By the time headquarters of the customs district moved to Seattle on July 1, 1913, Chinese no longer were so much in the news. The Exclusion Act of 1882, designed to suspend importation of Oriental laborers for a ten-year period, spurred the smugglers. Until then, coolies had been brought in freely to supply cheap labor for canneries, hop yards, mines and public works. As many as 15,000 were employed in construction of the Northern Pacific Railroad.</p>
<p>After the ban was put on the Chinese, Puget Sound was the hole in the fence through which they entered. They continued to arrive in British Columbia from Hongkong in groups of 100 to 700 on English vessels docking every three weeks. Canada gave them 90 days in which to leave the country.</p>
<p>THE United States has been advertised to the Chinese as the promised land. Some years prior to passage of the law, this country had done considerable recruiting of Oriental labor. When the door was suddenly closed against the Orientals, they continued to take a chance on getting through. No penalty was attached to any Chinese making the attempt and when caught he did not have to pay his expenses back to his starting place. Some tried so often their faces were familiar to the customs men, who at that time also constituted the immigration service.</p>
<p>In 1880, statistics showed 3,186 Chinese legally living in Washington. When smuggling commenced, the general scheme was to channel newly arrived Orientals to places where they could be lost among their brethren already in the country.</p>
<p>Small sailing vessels, ostensibly fishing boats, used to lie at anchor at a buoy off the Indian reservation at the entrance to Victoria Harbor. Chinese would be taken out to them and transported to a hiding place at James or Sidney Islands. When enough were gathered to make the run advisable, all were picked up from their camp and the sloop made for Dungeness or some place near Port Townsend, arriving after dark and departing in the night. The Chinese were instructed how to proceed from the beach to a place of security among their countrymen in a nearby town.</p>
<p>An opium cargo was a little more difficult because it would not walk to its final destination but had to be carried there by some person.</p>
<p>A REFINERY of crude opium existed in Victoria, where the poppy gum was boiled, skimmed and prepared for smoking. It could be imported by paying duty, but evading the tariff by smuggling was more profitable. Another device was to sweat off the stamps and apply them to cans on which the import tax had not been paid.</p>