<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>6 WIDOWS MAY KEEP CHIN RICHES FROM SEATTLE GIRL</head>
<p>Unexpected wealth may be laid at the door of Mrs. Margaret Chinn&#8212;Chin Yook Tuey&#8212;granddaughter and only direct descendant in Seattle of Chin Gee Hee, former Seattle merchant and contractor, afterwards Southern China's foremost railroad builder, whose death in his clan village of Look Tun, near Canton, was announced in The Times yesterday.</p>
<p>Mrs. Chinn is the wife of W. Sam Chinn, a Chinese architect and a graduate of the Franklin High School and a former student at the University of Washington.</p>
<p>While asserting that a portion of her grandfather's estate, estimated to be worth several million dollars, is rightfully hers, Mrs. Chinn in her Seattle apartment today said she would be surprised if any great sum was bequeathed her.</p>
<subhead>Six Grandmothers in China.</subhead>
<p>"I have six grandmothers in China, or, to put it differently, my grandfather left six widows over there and I don't know how many sons and daughters," she stated. "My own father, Chin Lem, son of Chin Gee Hee, died in China several years ago. My mother, Dong Oy, is living in Seattle. I have a paternal aunt working for a living somewhere on the Coast. I believe my grandfather has a nephew here, too. I don't know his name but he couldn't be considered an heir.</p>
<p>"There has been an estrangement for years between Chin Gee Hee and his daughter in America and between him and my mother and me, so none of us are hopefully looking for much. Grandfather was too shrewd. He wouldn't give us money when he 
<pb/>
<subhead>SEATTLE RELATIVE MAY SHARE RICHES</subhead>
knew we needed it while he was alive and he probably has it fixed so that we don't get any when he is dead."</p>
<p>The Canton Building, the first structure to be rebuilt after the great Seattle fire in 1889, was sold several years ago by Chin Gee Hee.</p>
<subhead>Other Seattle Holdings.</subhead>
<p>Mrs. Chinn said she thought her grandfather still retained an interest in Kung Yick building on Eighth Avenue between King and Jackson Streets and in the Quong Tuck Company, 721 King St. Fred H. Lysons, personal friend and Seattle attorney of the dead capitalist, asserted that as far as he knew an undetermined interest in Quong Tuck Company represented all of Chin Gee Hee's Seattle holdings.</p>
<p>Mr. Chinn's father, Chin Lem, was born at Port Gamble where Chin Gee Hee established a laundry in 1875 after leaving the mines of California. In 1894 he and Dong Oy were taken by their respective parents to China and there they were wed. Mrs. Chinn was born three years later in her grandfather's house in Look Tun village. Her father returned to Seattle and in 1904 brought mother and daughter to his home at Second Avenue South and Washington Street.</p>
<subhead>Father's Heart "Turns."</subhead>
<p>Chin Gee Hee left Seattle in 1905 to build his railroad through the Sunning Valley in Southern China. He insisted that his son join him and in 1907 Chin Lem took his family back to Look Tun. Mrs. Chin said it was not long before her father's heart "turned" from her mother and that he left them in destitute circumstances.</p>
<p>"Grandfather approved of my father's actions and wanted him to marry another wife and he also wanted me to marry in China," said Mrs. Chinn. "My mother's relatives in Hongkong had a little money and by disguising ourselves as much older women we got out of Look Tun village and China and safely back to Seattle.</p>
<p>"My mother worked while I went to school. After passing through the grade and high school I finished the University four-year course in art and designing in three years. I was a junior there when I left and for six years or more thereafter I was a designer for two of Seattle's leading department stores, making frequent trips to New York for them,"</p>
<p>Mr. and Mrs. Chinn were married in Seattle last March.</p>