<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>JUST COGITATING: John McGilvra Was Sent to Washington by Lincoln</head>
<byline>By C.T. CONOVER</byline>
<ab>94-Year-Old Seattle Pioneer</ab>
<p>WHEN I came to Seattle in 1888 John J. McGilvra, a pioneer of early days, was still in active life.</p>
<p>He and Abraham Lincoln had adjoining law offices in Chicago. When Lincoln was elected president, he made McGilvra United States attorney for the Territory of Washington, which then had a population of 12,000 and, in addition to its present area, also embraced the three northern counties of Idaho.</p>
<p>Twice a year young McGilvra traveled over the territory attending court and prosecuting cases for the territory.</p>
<p>In 1862 McGilvra moved from Olympia to Walla Walla, and later in the year to Vancouver. Still later he came to Seattle and remained until his death. He took up 640 acres of land on the shores of Lake Washington at the end of what is now Madison Street. This was the foundation of his large fortune. At a personal expense of $1,500 he built a road from the Sound to the lake along the general lines of the present-day Madison Street.</p>
<p>McGilvra immediately began the private practice of the law when he ended his duties as United States attorney and was soon in the top ranks of attorneys in the Pacific Northwest.</p>
<p>McGilvra was one of the earliest advocates of a Lake Washington Ship Canal, as well as the Cedar River water system. He served in the Territorial Legislature in 1866-67, and obtained an appropriation for a rough wagon road across Snoqualmie Pass, which for years was the only means of communication across the Cascade Mountains north of the Columbia River.</p>
<p>IN 1876-77 McGilvra was city attorney of Seattle. About this time the Northern Pacific abandoned its plans for a Skagit County branch, but refused to restore to the public domain the old sections of land given as a subsidy.</p>
<p>McGilvra went to Washington to present the case before Congress. He was given the privilege of the floor of both the Senate and the House. With the assistance of Judge Orange Jacobs, he obtained the restoration of 5,000,000 acres of fertile land. He spent the most of two winters working on this project.</p>
<p>McGilvra was one of the incorporators of the Seattle and Walla Walla Railroad, projected to check the Northern Pacific, which was discriminating against Seattle in favor of Tacoma at that time. The enterprise was carried through at a critical time and had a vital role in saving the day for Seattle.</p>
<p>Among those associated with McGilvra in the practice of the law were James McNaught, later chief counsel of the Northern Pacific, and Thomas Burke, his son-in-law.</p>
<p>One secret of McGilvra's success as a lawyer and his prominence as a public-spirited citizen unquestionably lay in his tenacity of purpose and his unswerving adherence to what to what he considered to be right. Once launched on what he considered the just and proper course, nothing could sway him.</p>
<p>McGilvra was the first resident lawyer in Seattle and, until he retired, he represented clients in almost every important suit.</p>
<p>McGilvra retired from the practice of the law early in the 1890's and spent his remaining years at his idyilic home on the shores of Lake Washington. He died December 19, 1903.</p>
<p>DR. JOHN W. WAUGHOP, nationally known in connection with the care of the insane, died aboard the Canadian-Australianliner Moano while returning from Honolulu late in August, 1903.</p>
<p>Dr. Waughop was born in Illinois, October 22, 1839. He was born on a farm and, like most farm boys, got his education during the winter months. He entered Europa College, but left in his second year to enlist in the Civil War. He took part in the battles of Fort Douglas and Shiloh, and afterward did hospital service in Vicksburg and Louisiana. After three years' service he was honorably discharged in 1864.</p>
<p>Dr. Waughop then entered the medical school of the University of Michigan and from there went to the Long Island College Hospital in Brooklyn, where he was graduated in 1865. He began the practice of medicine in White Cloud, Kas., where he later was elected mayor.</p>
<p>In 1871 Dr. Waughop removed to Olympia, where he practiced medicine for several years. In 1880 he accepted the position of superintendent of the Western Washington Hospital for the Insane. He instituted many reforms and improvements in the care of the insane. He was an active member of the American Medical Psychological Association and the New York Medico-Legal Society. For several years he was president of the Washington Medical Society.</p>