<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>DAYS OF RAGE</head>
<byline>By DAVID M. BUERGE</byline>
<ab>around 6pm on January 17, 1882, George Reynolds left his house on Marion Street and began to walk down the hill to D.A. Jennings' store, where he worked. Then 29 years old, Reynolds had not been in Seattle long, but he was beginning to put down roots. He had a good job as a clerk, was well liked by those who knew him, and had only recently gotten married. As he approached the corner of Marion and Third, two men stepped out from the shadows, one holding a .38 Colt revolver.</ab>
<p>"Put your hands up!" a voice barked, but Reynolds reached instead for his pocket, where he kept a pistol for protection. As he brought it out, the gunman's accomplice shouted, "Let him have it!" The shot knocked Reynolds back into a picket fence, wounding him fatally. It also set off an explosion that rocked the town for years and ultimately produced a social revolution.</p>
<p>Seattle was in that year about to enter a period of enormous and often painful growth, but it was still a small town of about 6,000 souls. It was one of the oldest towns on Puget Sound, and it had grown considerably since it was founded in 1851, but its growth had been slow and hard. Its pioneers had never doubted it would become a city one day, but many wondered why it was taking so long.</p>
<p>Seattle had become an important coaling port, thanks to mines dug into the hills east of town. It was a place where small steamboats&#8212;the mosquito fleet&#8212;docked to take on coal, make repairs, and load supplies before shoving off again to furrow the waters of the Sound and nose up its streams, keeping old customers happy and seeking out new ones as the country filed with settlers. Its sawmills kept the local market supplied with lumber, and its stores, shops, and saloons were rarely empty. On New Year's Day 1880, the editor of the Daily Intelligencer could write: "[L]ooking at the prospect from every side, and judging from the past, we are led to believe that we are entering upon an era of the most auspicious character, the results of which will place Seattle in the proud position her most sanguine friends have hoped to see her occupying."</p>
<p>The problem was that editors had been saying this kind of thing for nearly 30 years, and the hopes had still not materialized. Moreover, the town was changing in ways many found hard to accept. The old familiarity seemed to be a thing of the past; there were more strangers in town. In October 1881, the tough old pioneer and Seattle police officer David Sires had been shot to death by the man he was arresting. It was Seattle's first police fatality, and as the new year began, emboldened thugs held up their victims on the streets with drawn weapons. In the resultant siege mentality, many like Reynolds began carrying guns for protection.</p>
<p>As Reynolds fell against the fence, he fired his gun wildly at his fleeing assailants, hitting neither. The gunfire attracted nearby residents and passerby, who helped carry
<pb/>
him back to his house. Two hours later he gasped his life away in the arms of his grief-stricken bride. Minutes later the fire bell at the engine house rang out in alarm.</p>
<p>The crowd that gathered at the engine house formed a vigilance committee. Orange Jacobs, Seattle's major the year before, was elected chairman. Teams fanned out to look for the culprits, and an hour later two men were found hiding in a haystack on a waterfront pier. One had a .38 Colt revolver with an empty chamber smelling strongly of burnt powder. They were hauled off to jail, where Sheriff Louis Wycoff and Chief of Police John McGraw locked them up.</p>
<p>The anger did not subside. The suspects' boots were taken and matched with tracks in the mud at Third and Marion. The two were obviously the murderers, the vigilantes concluded, so why wait for a trail and let them live off the county like Ben Payne, Sires' murderer, who still sat in jail while the bereaved mourned? The crowd threatened to break down the jailhouse door if the suspects weren't released. With drawn guns and promises to present the pair promptly at the morning hearing. Wycoff and McGraw were able to keep the mob at bay, but the jail was ringed by angry men all night long.</p>
<p>At 9:30 the next morning, Justice of the Peace Samuel Coombs opened court at Yesler's Hall, Seattle's civic meeting place at Front (First Avenue) and Cherry. The accused, identified as James Sullivan and William Howard, both transient workers, heard the evidence presented against them in the tense hall. Coombs was about to send them back to jail to await trail when, at a signal, vigilantes stormed the court and overpowered its officiers. The accused men were dragged out the back door to the alley and down to James Street, where two long rails had been secured high in the bare branches of maple trees fronting a square.</p>
<p>The chief justice of the Territorial Supreme Court, Roger Greene, was in the hall to help ensure a fair hearing, but as he rose to protest the capture of the prisoners, he was knocked down and covered with a curtain ripped from the stage. He managed to free himself and find the glasses that had been struck from his face, but by the time he got to the scene, the two suspects had nooses cinched around their necks and were being hoisted into the air. They were raised with such force that their heads struck the rails, and Howard's neck was broken. Greene waded into the roaring crowd, shouting at them to desist and managing to slash at the ropes holding the two men a few times with a pocket knife before he was thrust roughly away.</p>
<p>The crowd milled about the dangling bodies until Sullivan's quit jerking, swarmed back to the jailhouse, smashed its way in, and dragged the terrified Ben Payne down to the grimly hung tree. A voice in the crowd shouted, "Did you fire the shot that killed Officer Sires?" Payne cried out, "You hang me and you will hang an innocent man." Then he too was hauled aloft to heave and convulse. The crowd remained to feast its eyes on the dead long enough for a reporter to sketch the scene. After the bodies were cut down and hauled away in a wagon, the square emptied.</p>
<p>The drawing, which appeared a few weeks later in Harper's Weekly, provides a detailed portrait of the town. There, whittling his pine stick in the foreground, is Henry Yesler, the richest man in town, and the one who donated the gallows timbers. The future first governor of Washington state, Elisha P. Ferry, is there, along with virtually every other citizen of consequence Chinese, blacks, and Native Americans are depicted, but no women like boxing and horse racing in those days, lynching was for men only.</p>
<p>The lynching of Sullivan, Howard, and Payne exposed a deep rift in the town's social fabric. Sires and Reynolds were both family men, residents who had made Seattle their home and who owned property. Both had been killed by transients, single men who drifted from town to town, from mine to lumber camp, carrying what they owned on their backs. The labor-intensive industries of the frontier West required many hands, but the boom and bust economy ensured that the workers were often on the move from one job to the next. At any time before the turn of the century, unpropertied transient workers outnumbered the propertied residents of the town by more than 2 to 1.</p>
<p>In town they worked as harness makers, soap makers, foundrymen, boiler makers, shipwrights, carpenters, rope makers, cooks, bakers, and mill workers. They were clerks waiters, meat packers, teamsters, deliverymen,a dn printers. They did the work that kept the town going and growing, 12 hours a day, six days a week. During their one day off, Sunday, their numbers were augmented by boatmen, miners, and lumberjacks who came to town to "blow 'er in" after an exhausting week's work.</p>
<p>Most of them lived in the hotels, boarding houses, and tenements that stood south of Mill Street (Yesler Way), the original Skid Road. Much of that area had been a swamp until it was filled in with sawdust and rubble, and its rough uneven surface gave it its popular name, the "lava beds." The social centers of this Rabelaisian district were its saloons, card parlors, bordellos, and opium dens. Most workers were young, so Saturday night revels were raucous affairs, often punctuated with brawls, fistfights, and shootings. Sundays were spent making the rounds or sleeping off the previous night's excess.</p>
<p>If they were inclined, workingmen could attend services in the town's churches. By 1880 there were seven denominations represented, but only one church, the Catholic Our Lady of Good help, was located south of Mill Street, where it had to compete with the area's 35 saloons. The rest of the churches were located on the hill above Mill Street, where the propertied folk lived. Here were the homes of the pioneers, chief among whom were members of the Denny Party; the Dennys and the Borens who had traveled from Illinois in covered wagons and landed at Alki Point with the Terrys. Later they were joined by Henry Yesler, by the Mercers, Bagleys, and Hortons, who came west in the Bethel Party in '52; and by the Fryes, Butlers, and Hanfords.</p>
<p>They came predominantly from the rural Midwest before the Civil War, and they ahd all the strengths and limitations that came from growing to maturity in small rural communities. They were hard working and independent, but many like Arthur Denny could not see any difference between the opportunities available to a pioneer who could claim 320 acres of free land and a mill worker making 25-cents an hour.</p>
<p>One of the benefits of being married in Seattle's early days was that husband and wife together could claim 640 acres&#8212;a square mile of land. The exigencies of frontier life underscored the value of marriage and family. Women were so crucial to the success of pioneering that there were several attempts to import groups of them from the East. Once here, the families often intermarried, creating a network of kin relationships that gave frontier society a distinctly familial cast.</p>
<p>The best lands in the townsite were quickly claimed, and as later-arriving entrepreneurs purchased lots on which to erect their mills and businesses, the value of the land increased. In the beginning the pioneers often worked as common laborers to earn scarce cash, but as the town grew and the lots they sold brought them wealth, their jobs were given over to those who arrived to work them in the hopes of earning enough money to buy land themselves. Gradually a gulf opened between those who owned the land and the businesses and those who worked the jobs. When times were good and wages were high, this gap could be crossed with relative ease, but when they were not, it yawned as a chasm.</p>
<p>Increasingly, the church-going, middle-class society that the pioneers created on the hill grew disdainful of what was developing in the lava beds, which came to be called "the vice district." After the Civil War consumed the passion for abolition, temperance resumed its position as the moral issue of the day and a favorite sermon topic. But as pastors on the hill inveighed against the evils of drink, saloon keepers in the lava beds were scurrying to keep glasses filled for the growing throngs of thirsty workers. That saloons did a hefty share of their business on Sunday, the one day workingmen had off, seemed to the pious a special affront to the holiness of the Sabbath.</p>
<p>Another cause for anxiety among the hill folk were the prostitutes. In earlier years they had been tolerated by being ignored, and by the fact that many prostitutes were native women working in so-called "squaw houses," but by the 1880s Seattle's red-light district was famous up and down the coast. There were fitful attempts to eliminate it, through legal means or through force, but it grew with the population, and its profits and taxes proved increasingly attractive.</p>
<p>The vast majority of workingmen were law abiding and wanted nothing more for the msot part than to settle down, have a family, and become property owners themselves. Inevitably, however, their numbers included what the hill folk called "the lawless element." Their numbers increased; so did hte lawlessness. On that frenzied day in January of 1882, propertied and unpropertied alike lashed out against it, but it would be a long time before their interests would again converge.</p>
<p>The gallows timbers were left in the maple branches as a warning to criminals, and for a time at least, they had the desired effect. The day after the lynchings congratulatory telegrams arrived from Olympia and Port Townsend, but not everyone was pleased. The Methodist Episcopal bishop of Portland labeled it an "outburst of savagery," and Roger Greene was outraged. A few days after the affair he appeared before a grand jury and argued that everyone involved with the lynching should be charged with manslaughter. No indictments were handed down, but 40 years later when historian Clarence Bagley interviewed him, Grenne was still fuming. "It was an outburst of lawlessness, an explosion of savagery....Like stampeded cattle, a tidal wave of emotion swept practically the whole community in a wrong direction."</p>
<p>The affair made national news. The Chicago Daily News observed: "The City of Seattle, in Washington Territory, is being governed by a committee of safety, and when a robbery, burglary, or murder is committed, the perpetrator of the crime is placed in a position in which he stands on a platform without exactly feeling what he is standing on. It is a plan which has made the city a wonderfully peaceful one for decent people and it is cheap so far as expenses are concerned, as it saved the cost of court and juries and is more effective than both."</p>
<p>But while cities in the East laughed at the antics of vigilantes out in the wild West, the mood was not so buoyant in Seattle. Two days after the lynchings, Sheriff Wyoff; an old pioneer and a man highly respected in the community, died of a heart attack, apparently brought on by the grief he felt at being unable to protect his prisoners. The lengthy editorials that vigorously justified what had happened were more revealing of a sense that things had gotten out of hand. Cow towns were governed by vigilanties. Hadn't Seattle aspired to something greater?</p>
<p>Many decided that the remedy was to get the unemployed that had flocked to town in the depressed years at the end of the '70s back to work. As 1882 wore on, there seemed to be some progress on that score. Banker Angus Mackintosh built an ice-making plant that expanded the town's capacity to prepare and store food products. After a lengthy battle with Portland, Seattle managed to capture the government contract to carry the mails to Alaska, which helped the mosquito fleet.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, there had been a change in management of the Northern Pacific Railroad, the line that had chosen Tacoma over Seattle as the western terminus of its transcontinental road. The new chairman of the board, Henry Villard, purchased the tracks that Seattle interests had built to the mines at Black Diamond and promised a connection to the NP tracks. Since 1883 was the year the NP was finally completed across the continent, the promise of a tie-in fueled a modest boom. Seattle's population neared 12,000, land sold for $500 a frontage foot downtown, and the construction boom consumed the entire output of the town's sawmills.</p>
<p>But many felt that as the town grew, so did its problems. To prevent the reappearance of a vigilante movement, attempts were made to control one of the sources of violence by seeking to restrict the operation of saloons and brothels where liquor was sold. In the spring of '83, charges were presented to a grand jury against several saloon and brothel operators. Indictments were handed down, but they had no effect on the liquor trade in the lava beds. The grand jury was recalled, more indictments were handed down, and once again the effect was so minuscule that the whole effort became the butt of jokes. It was clear to many that the police were cooperating with the owners of establishments in the lava beds.</p>
<p>Charges of municipal corruption would normally have caused no more than protests. But in the waning months of '83, the political situtation changed. In November, in response to calls from temperance advocates, a bill granting women the right to vote in territorial elections was passed by both houses of the Legislature. The protests were transformed into a full-fledged reform movement.</p>
<p>It was probably inevitable that the temperance movement would join forces with proponents of women's suffrage. The churches provided one of the few opportunities for women to socialize and demonstrate their abilities outside the home, and they were the foremost advocates of temperance. Many, like Arthur Denny, who had worked for both temperance and women's suffrage in ther territorial Legislature, believed that the two reform issues were natural allies. But this belieff, prevalent among mnay women, was resisted strenuously by suffragists like Oregon's Abigail Scott Duniway, who believed, quite rightly, that the cause of suffrage would be seriously harmed by its association with those who sought to impose their beliefs by force on a large segment of the population who disagreed with them.</p>
<p>In January the reform movement got under way with the creation of the Law and Order League founded by James Lewis, C.L. Wayland, David Denny, and his nephew, Roland Denny, who became its officers. The league dedicated itself to "sustain the regular officers of the city and county in a more strict execution of the law, to assist in prosecution of the law, to assist in prosecutions for law breaking where necessary, and to procure enactment of local measures in the furtherance of order in the community."</p>
<p>It actively sought women's votes. At one of its first public meetings, held in the Congregational Church, the women in the enthusiastic audience were asked whether they would register to vote, and every one present rose to her feet in assent. In June a call was made to all those "who favor the enforcement of existing laws and ordinances, and th eadministration of municipal affairs by sober, honest, and efficient men," to attend a meeting in the vacant lots of Fourth and Marion, a block away from where Reynolds had been shot. The 400 who showed up, most of them women, heard resolutions put forward by representatives of the league and the Young Men's Political Club, another reformist group, and helped select a slate of candidates for public office. A number of apple trees grew in the vacant lots, and they inspired the movement's members' prim christening as "Apple Orchardists"&#8212;idealists who would drive the serpent of drink and crime out of the garden and restore it to a happier state.</p>
<p>Their zeal for reform was not misplaced. Seattle in the 1880s was beset by problems made worse by the decade's rapid growth. Tacoma booster Ezra Mocker's partisan gibe that Seattle was a place one could smell long before one could see it was simple truth. In terms of sanitation and health, it was a pest hole. An abundance of privies on high ground and primitive box sewers rendered well water lower down unfit to drink. The effluent of these sewers flowed directly into the bay, where it was joined by waste from slaughterhouses and packing plants. The rafts of sewage and offal floating in the water or beached at low tide produced an appalling stink that boosters tried lamely to explain away as the odor of tide flats. As the town expanded residences was left to flow into Lake Union in three enormous
<pb/>
ditches. In an area where men worked in dangerous jobs and accidents were common, the majority of deaths came as a result of infectious disease.</p>
<p>The town had grown so quickly that it outgrew its water mains; in one instance, firemen had to watch a house burn because there was no nearby mains. Even those parts of town that had mains had poor service, and summer months often saw them completely dry. When this happened, the practice of sprinkling the dirt streets was suspended. Streets that were quagmires in the winter became avenues of dust and grit in the summer.</p>
<p>Despite these pressing problems, the major concern of the Apple Orchardists was the strict enforcement of liquor laws. Their blinkered zeal excited a reaction among businessmen, who protested that strict enforcement of the laws threatened the loss of the saloon trade and much other business besides. From their ranks sprang the BUsinessmen's Club, the Young Men's Indpendent Club, and the Protective Association, which cooperated in offering their own slate of candidates for the July election.</p>
<p>The apperance of the Apple Orchardists and their business opposition in the 1884 election reveals an important change in the ranks of Seattle's propertied residents. The older generation of pioneers was giving way to a new generation of white-collar professionals. By the mid-'80s most of Seattle's land was owned by fewer than two dozen families, all of them pioneers, who formed an elite called "Old Seattle." They had not changed a great deal since their arrival except to become wealthy, and their staid ways and parochial views led many to dismiss them as "old mossbacks." In 1880, the first Northwest historian of stature, Elwood Evans, would write of Arthur Denny: "His family influence and surrounding having contributed very much toward giving Seattle a narrowness similar to his own method of thinking and acting."</p>
<p>The roster of the Law and Order League was heavy with the names of Old Seattle families. The opposition's rosters included some like Henry Yesler's and John Leary's, but more common were those of newcomers like Bailey Gatzert, Daniel Gilman, and Thomas Burke. Many of thes men had also grown up in rural communities, but their world was dominated by cities and the new industrial economy.</p>
<p>Thomas Burke is a typical example. Born in 1849, just about the time when the pioneers landed at Alki, he grew up in rural, northern New York. While young, an injury to his arm enabled him to stay in school, and the extra education he received gave him the opportunity to enter a profession rather than learn a trade. In the previous generation, the choice would probably have been beween a trade and farming. He attended a teachers college in Ypsilanti, Michigan, and money earned teaching enabled him to attend law classes at Ann Arbor. After he passed the bar and was ready for a move, he read about Seattle's fight with the NP in 1874. He arrived here a year later, was appointed probate judge in 1876, and married the daughter of a pioneer lawyer, John McGilvra. Known as Judge Burke from then on, he became a popular figure in the town's social and economic figure in the town's social and economic life. He grew wealthy investing in real estate.</p>
<p>The society that coalesced around Judge Burke and his cohorts differed considerably from that represented by Old Seattle. Family was important, and most were married, but as the town grew and its economy became more complex, financial success depended less on one's family ties than it did on one's occupation. In the '80s an occupational hierarchy emerged in Seattle with businessmen and lawyers occupying the highest niches and common laborers the lowest. Reinforcing this development was the appearance of clubs and associations based on occupation and designed to further members' careers and interests. Among those at the top were charitable organizations like the Ladies' Relief Society, founded in 1884 by the wives of Seattle's eminent men to carry out social work, and the Rainier Club, founded in 1888 to provide a comfortable meeting place for the city's prominent businessmen and their guests. These were the salons for a new elite that styled itself "New Seattle." Few members of the old elite were members of the Ladies' Relief Society, and many years passed before any representatives of Old Seattle were invited to join the Rainier Club.</p>
<p>The election of '84 put these two groups in opposition. The businessmen were not against some modest reform. An individuals they might abhor the drunkenness and immorality that characterized the lava beds, but their more cosmopolitan view of the world did not incline them to intervene in another's pleasure, particularly when such activites enhanced the town's commercial growth and made money.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the Apple Orchardists insisted that a very fine line separated convenient government from corrupt government and kept ease from becoming sleaze. One of the issues that focused this concern arose because the businessmen's candidate for mayor, John Leary, was also president of the Spring Hill Water Company from which the city purchased the bulk of its supply. "I want the city to buy plenty of water and want it bought from the Spring Hill Water Company," declaimed one orator. "But I don't want John Leary, as president of the Spring Hill Water Company, for such supply."</p>
<p>But a good share of the Orchardists' animus was directed against the transient workers and the working-class society of the lava beds. Their desire for honest government was laudable, but their zeal to shut down the haunts of sin and drive the evildoers out of town recalled the vigilante spirit of '82. That king of moral arrogance troubled Abigail Scott Duniway, especially since many of its more vocal advocates were women.</p>
<p>Women were the crucial players in the election. Despite their inexperience, they campaigned as energetically as men and as capably. They got 759 registered to vote, they canvassed neighborhoods, arranged carriage rides to bring voters to the polls, and they voted. Most voted for temperance and reform, but at least one, a widow named Mary Kenworthy, voted against businessmen as pretentious parvenus and "our dog-salmon aristocrats." Murray Morgan profiled her in Skid Road. She was middle class, a socialist in politics, and resident in Seattle nearly 20 years prior to the election. Kenworthy was very much involved in the suffrage movement, and was the most vocal woman who would have been identified as radical. She was certainly not the only one.</p>
<p>When the votes were counted, John Leary was elected mayor, but the reformers won a majority of other positions and were able to carry out their agenda. The laws were strictly enforced; the hours liquor could be sold on Sunday were so restricted that it became virtually impossible for saloons to operate. "The saloon trade fell off as workers went elsewhere for a drink. As the ones who normally blew into town for the weekend also took with them the money they would have spent on groceries and supplies for the week, businesses in the lava beds began to feel the pinch.</p>
<p>In the meantime, Henry Villard's NP boom went bust. On December 17, 1883, Villard's auditors told him his immense railroad empire was about to go broke, and the next day he resigned. The news caused a panic on Wall Street, and the shock waves moved inexorably through the national economy as panic turned to depression and business after business closed its doors. In the West, where there was less diversification, the ripples grew larger as they entered the economic shallows and broke, finally, wiht devastating impact.</p>
<pb/>
<p>Far out in Seattle the effects were slow to arrive, so 1884 had actually been a good year. A horse-drawn street railway had been extended to Lake Union, tying northern residences more firmly to the business district, and a wharf was built on the lake shore to serve boats ferrying commuters to and from the new suburb of Fremont. The building boom continued. The Frye Opera House, the largest theater north of San Francisco, was built, along with several other landmarks. Streets were graded and planked, and there was even a brief spate of mansion building led by Henry Yesler, who spent $50,000 putting up a Victorian pile on the corner of Third and Jefferson.</p>
<p>After Villard stepped down as chairman of the NP's board of directors, that company resumed its hostiles attitude toward Seattle. By the summer of '84 the town had its coveted connection with the transcontinental line, but service on the narrow-gauged tracks was terrible. When representatives from Seattle led by Thomas Burke complained, the NP responded by shutting it off completely. Undaunted, Burke, Mayor Leary, and several other businessmen, like Dainel Gilman, drew up another of Seattle's transcontinental schemes. They proposed to do what that town had attempted in the famous civic outing of 1874: build a line east and hope to meet with one coming west. That first attempt had stopped 14 miles later at the New castle mines, so much scoffing attended Gilman's departure for New York to scare up funds.</p>
<p>The pessimism greeting the announcement of this venture was unusual for Seattle, but it reflected the depressed mood as the economy grew to a halt. As demand for coal and lumber fell, employers cut wages and laid off workers. By '85, wagers that had averaged between $50 and $120 a month were down to between $20 and $90. The unemployed tramped the tracks and trails to town in search of odd jobs and handouts. Their numbers in the lava beds swelled as the year wore on, but things were relatively quiet. The Apple Orchardists congratulated themselves for the calm as they met in the splendor of the Frye Opera House to select a new slate of candidates and organize another campaign.</p>
<p>By this time, however, the town had tired of reform. Bad times were made worse by the reformers' driving workers out of town. The lava beds might be quieter, but they were also a lot poorer. John Leary had done such a good job cooperating with the council, dominated by reformers, that the Businessmen's Club rejected him and he became instead the nominee of Law and Order. The business community turned to Henry Yesler, who had been mayor once before, and was about as Old Seattle as one could get. Yesler beat Leary 2 to 1 and the reformers were swept form office.</p>
<p>The political debut of reform and women had ended in a debacle. Yet, however myopic the Apple Orchardists' appraisal of the community's problems had been, the businessmen's vision, as the problems grew worse, was even dimmer. Since the outburst of violence after the murder of George Reynolds, the divisions that threatened the town grew deeper, the gulf separating propertied from unpropertied grew wider, and the specter of violence loomed larger.</p>
<p>The first warnings of the storm about to break came to the fall of 1884. On September 2, a riot took place in Rock Springs, Wyoming, where white miners drove Chinese workers out of town, brutally killing 28 and injuring 15. On October 5, Chinese laborers hired to pick hops at Andy Wold's farm near Squak (Iseaquah) were attacked as they slept
<pb/>
in their tents by a group of white and native men; three were killed. A week later, Chinese miners were driven from the mines at Coal Creek, on the east shore of Lake Washington, and on the 19th from mines at Black Diamond, where nine were severely beaten. Many of the vitims fled to Seattle to find shelter in its large Chinese community, housed in stores and tenements along Washington Street, which had grown like the rest of the transient population as the unemployed flocked to town. Even here, they became targets of violence.</p>
<p>The animosity against the Chinese was inspired by economics, long since saturated with racism. The Chinese had originally been recruited to build railroads and provide farm labor in the West in the years before and during the Civil War when labor was scarce. Many stayed, preferring legal restrictions and periodic outbursts of violence to the famine and chaos in China at the time. Although their lives and property were protected by law, most were not permitted to become citizens and could not vote. In Washington Territory, the Legislature prevented them from submitting evidence in suits against whites, and in an attempt to reduce their immigration, imposed a head tax which each paid during his or her residence. To make sure the men did not put down roots, few Chinese women were allowed to immigrate.</p>
<p>Initially, Chinese workers were welcomes, even admired. "John," as he was invariably called, worked hard, lived on very little, was self-sufficient, and obeyed authority even when it was cruel. They were paid less than whites. After the Civil War, as veterans, emancipated blacks, and poor immigrants flooded the job market in a chronically unstable economy, the Chinese were viewed in creasingly as a threat, particularly when employers fired white workers in order to hire Chinese at half-pay. In time, desperate workers who were unable to last out against powerful and distant owners turned their frustrations against a convenient and friendless target.</p>
<p>Western legislatures repeatedly called on the federal government to stem the influx of Chinese laborers, but their efforts came to nothing. In 1870, there were only 234 Chinese in Washington Territory, but workers still drove them from the NP tracks near Tacoma when the Depression of '74 hit. In 1880, a treaty restricting immigration was signed with the Chinese government, but workers were brought into the region illegally from British Columbia. By then their numbers had grown to 3,186.</p>
<p>In spite of all the animosity directed against them, the Chinese managed to develop a remarkably diverse economy of their own in Seattle. An 1879 article in the Daily Intelligencer enumerated the Chinese in various occupations in town and the number of their businesses. They worked as grocery-men (133 individuals), cigar makers (94), restaurant workers (27), druggists (26), slipper makers and salesmen (12), junk dealers (90), and coffin makers (two). There were six Chinese banks, one Chinese insurance company (and several other owned by Chinese and run by whites), three employment offices, three theaters, pawnshops, several stores specializing in imports, and an astounding 350 washhouses. This last category reflected an important niche occupied by the Chinese in a society where white men refused to do what they regarded as "women's work." By 1880, 13 percent of all working men in town were Chinese.</p>
<p>No matter: the Chinese were regarded as aliens. Unable to marry or settle down, they turned to one another for support and looked with intense homesickness to kin in China to whom many sent their earnings&#8212;this too was held against them. The real tragedy of the Chinese in the '80s was their inability to resist becoming pawns in the battle between business and labor.</p>
<p>The conditions that inspired the development of clubs and societies at the upper end of the occupational hierarchy led to the formation of labor unions and fraternities lower down. By '85 more than half a dozen unions had offices in town, and they were important enough so that when a figure like J.J. Upchurch, head of the 152,000-member Order of United Workmen, came to town, it was treated as a civic event. But the most important labor figure to visit Seattle in 1885 was Dan Cronin, an organizer for the Knights of Labor.</p>
<p>The Knights had surprised many, including themselves, by leading a successful strike against the Southern Pacific Ralroad in '84, and Cronin was sent north from Eureka to conduct a membership drive. He played on anti-Chinese sentiment with the skill of a master propagandist. The Chinese were a tool of the capitalists to keep wages down, he said; get rid of them and the bosses would have no choice but to meet workers' demands. Chinese were indeed hired to keep wages down, but this was more a response to vanishing profit margins than evidence of a conspiracy against labor.</p>
<p>Cronin pounded away at the theme of dispossession. He organized a working-class group, the Liberal League, that met on September 21 at Yesler's Hall. Cronin spoke, praising the miners at Rock Springs and the men at Squak and Black Diamond who drove the Chinese out. Then he called upon his audience to do the same here, to organize secret groups to bring about a day of reckoning.</p>
<p>The secret oaths redolent of lodge meetings, added a sense of melodrama to the affairs, and they served Cronin's purpose of troubling the imaginations of businessmen with fearful images of anarchists and dynamiters meeting in dimly lit rooms, plotting their destruction. It was unsettling enough so that two days later, a group of "concerned taxpayers and property owners" met to hear Henry Yesler, Orange Jacobs, and others protest against those who plotted attacks against property. They didn't want the Chinese either, not if it would cause problems, but they warned what would happen to Seattle's reputation as a safe place to live and invest in if the mob ruled. Whatever issues divided the old and new elites before vanished as they confronted the growing anger of the working class.</p>
<p>Cronin was delighted; class antagonisms were music to his sould. On the 28th, the anti-Chinese congress he organized assembled at Yesler's Hall. Delegations arrived from communities throughout Western Washington; seven unions were represented and the mayor of Tacoma, Jacob Weisbach, was elected congress chairman. Meetings were held throughout the day; speaker after speaker rose to attack the bosses, damn the Chinese, and defend the rights of workers. "Every socialist and anarchist who could walk or steal a ride to Seattle was a self-elected but nonetheless welcome delegate," one biased observer reported. "Long-haired men and short-haired women were noticeable by their numbers and noise." Mary Kenworthy was among them, and there were other women like her, frustrated by their defeat in the July election and looking for a way to attack business head on.</p>
<p>Cronin succeeded in getting the congress to adopt a suitably provocative list of resolutions. Most of the Chinese in the territory, it declared, were here illegaly and must leave by November 5. In the meantime the congress denied any responsibility for acts of violence against those who did not get rid of their Chinese workers with the proper alacrity. On October 3, the anti-Chinese, as they were now identified, held another mass meeting. In the evening a huge illuminated parade of an estimated 3,000 men and women, the largest in the town's history, marched up Front Street to Yesler's Hall carrying banners and shouting slogans. In the hall they elected a committee of 15 to serve notice on the town's Chinese to leave.</p>
<p>Two blocks up the hill at the Opera House, another mass meeting was held by the taxpayers and property owners who called themselves moderates to counter the appeal of the anti-Chinese Speeches by Governor Watson C. Squire. Orange Jacobs, and others repeated their earlier warnings. Sheriff McGraw deputized those present into the Home Guard. When the county's prosecuting attorney, James Ronald, voiced his intention to bring the murderers of the Chinese at Squak to justice, the council for the accused, J.C. Haines, strode into the half-filled house followed by a contingent of anti-Chinese and vehemently accused Ronald of trying the case in public. As Haines was cheered, the moderates retired in disarray.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the Chinese in Tacoma had been given until November 3 to get out, and when the day arrived, a crowd of several hundred men led by the mayor and several other officials marched the Chinese out of their houses into a bleak rainstorm. One ailing man died later of exposure during the ordeal. The next day the Chinese homes and businesses were burned to the ground.</p>
<p>When news of these actions reached Seattle, the town braced itself for violence. Mayor Yesler called a mass meeting for the 5th at the Opera House. Early that day he met with representatives of the Committee of 15 and with Gee Hee, a spokesman for the Chinese community. Yesler informed Gee Hee that if the Chinese did not go, he could not guarrantee them protection. Gee Hee bowed to this, but pleaded for time so the Chinese businessmen could dispose of their holdings, a request the committee representatives accepted.</p>
<p>The meeting later that evening began well. 
<pb/>
The anti-Chinese celebrated thei victory, as indeed did the moderates, since the Chinese were leaving without violence. In a show of good feeling, the anti-Chinese elected Mayor Yesler chairman of the meeting. Before the agreement that had been reached was announced, however, Judge Burke gave a speech berating the crowd for anti-American attitudes and castigating foreigners for bringing dissension into the community. The buoyant mood gave way to anger that nearly erupted into violence, but John Leary managed to shout out the terms of the agreement to the restless crowd.</p>
<p>The sense of cooperation had been damaged by Burke. It fell completely apart over the next few days when Governor Squire asked the secretary of war to send federal troops to Seattle. Mayor Yesler issued a proclaimation asking people to stay in their homes and warning would-be rioters of swift punishment. Rifles were passed out among the Home Guard, and on November 8, 350 infantrymen arrived in town for a nine-day stay. During that time the grand jury called by Judge Greene after the mass demonstrations in October indicted the Committee of 15 on charges of conspiring to deprive the Chinese of their rights. The anti-Chinese were furious, believing they had been double-crossed by the moderates, and they vowed revenge. The division between business and labor, between hill folk and transient worker approached a clean break. Seattle had become a house divided.</p>
<p>In January of '86 the Committee of 15 were brought to trail, but prosecutor Ronald so bungled the case that Haines was able to have charges against several dimissed and the rest were acquited. By this time several hundred Chinese had left town, so tempers might have cooled. But some 350 remained, and the anti-Chinese planned a little ruse of their own.</p>
<p>On February 6, a mass meeting held at the Bijou Theater on Mill Street was attended by 800 anti-Chinese including over 100 women. Up on the stage was the Committee of 15, heroes now after their vindication. The speakers, among them Mary Kenworthy, called upon the audience to organize politically. Taking their cue from the Apple Orchadists' concern for strict law enforcement, they elected a new committee and instructed it gto determine whether the Chinese still in town were in violation of regulations stipulating the number of people allowed in buildings. Crammed in their hovels, the Chinese were undoubtedly violating the law which had been written to cripple the saloon trade. The committee was to report it findings in a week. The moderate took heed and prepared.</p>
<p>The committee did its work in one day. The next morning, aided by the police, who supported the workers, they visited the Chinese quarters, determined that they were too crowded, and marched the offenders down to the ocean dock, where the steamer Queen of the Pacific waited to take them on board.</p>
<p>Governor Squire responded by proclaiming martial law and sending a United States deputy to read the proclamation to the crowd. The ugly reaction this provoked frightened Squire, and he eventually wired President Grover Cleveland for troops to put down rebellion. In the meantime, Judge Greene issued a writ of habeas corpus to Captain Alexander of the Queen, demanding that he show up with the Chinese who were on board his vessel the next morning at court. Flummoxed by this maneuver, the anti-Chinese decided to send the rest of the Chinese out by rail. Sheriff McGraw's countermove was to order the Home Guard to take control of the dock. These events took the better part of a day, and the Chinese and their armed sentries spent the night locked in a warehouse.</p>