<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

E. F. Blaine.

The most important office at the present time within the gift of the people of King County is that of Prosecuting Attorney. Always an important office, this year its importance is vastly augmented. In the years past a ring of plunderers was formed for the express purpose of robbing the people of the county. Their efforts were highly successful. It is known that at least a hundred thousand dollars were stolen, and it is estimated that the "boodlers" got away with probably as much more. But while the ring may have counted on perpetual immunity, they reckoned without their host. An angry, over-taxed and plundered people are dangerous in the extreme when once aroused. This the ring found out to its cost. The present Democratic Prosecuting Attorney was elected to the office he now fills by an outraged community, who demanded that he break up this infamous ring, recover the stolen property, and seud its members to the penitentiary. On this platform was J. C. Ronald elected Prosecuting Attorney. The ring has been broken up. Stolen property has been recovered, and the public plunderers are headed towards the pentientiary. J. T. Ronald has carried the cases against these public malefactors as far as he was able to do during his term of office. It but remains for his successor to complete the work he has so vigorously begun. The Democracy of King County have placed before the people the name of E. G. Blaine as a worthy successor to the present Prosecuting Attorney. A more fortunate selection could not have been made. Mr. Blaine is composed of that material which has made Martine, of New York, and Grinnell, of Chicago, the terrors of "boodlers." With him in the office of Prosecuting Attorney, the people will rest content, fully satisfied that no guilty member of the notorious ring will be permitted to escape. 

No member of the Puget Sound bar takes higher rank than E. F. Blaine. With at once keenly critical and logical, yet broad in its scope and tendencies, he is able to command the attention of courts and juries in a manner much heard of but seldom witnessed. These are not the characteristics of an ordinary man. More than such was demanded by the grave duties of the office; duties under which an ordinary man would completely fail. The people must have a man of great force of character for the most powerful influences will be brought to bear on the next Prosecuting Attorney to induce him to relax his efforts looking to a righteous punishment of the thieves. A man of the strictest integrity is needed, for the members of the ring are plentifully supplied with money, and will use it unsparingly to to escape a long imprisonment. He must be a man able to cope with the brightest legal minds of the country, for such will be employed to defend the desperate ringsters. In a marked degree these necessary qualifications are possessed by E. F. Blaine. That the ring recognizes these facts, no better evidence can be adduced than the well-authenticated command which they are sending to their lieutenants throughout the country: "We must defeat Blaine at all hazards; trade off every other man on the ticket for a vote against him." A volume of words could not express Mr. Blaine's fitness for the position more than this desperate command of a desperate band. That he would prosecute them to the bitter end; that full justice would be meted out to all, they know as well as did the Democratic party when they placed his name before the people for their suffrages. The Democrats knew he was the strongest man they could put on their ticket, and the sixth of November will demonstrate that the people have placed their stamp of approval on their selection.