<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>Old records at Sand Point tell of activities of the little-known: James Tilton, Territorial Surveyor</head>
<byline>By LUCICLE McDONALD</byline>
<p>LETTERS to Washington's first surveyor-general are among the items listed in a catalog for the National Archives, recently completed by the Federal Records Center at Sand Point Naval Air Station.</p>
<p>The center is the depository for 62 federal agencies in the Pacific Northwest. It is one of the ten field offices of the National Archives. Gradually its most important collections are being inventoried.</p>
<p>Elmer W. Lindgard, chief of the center, explained that land offices were cut down to one for each state in 1930 and the basic tract books were kept in these. Spokane has the only one remaining in Washington.</p>
<p>Offices at Seattle, Yakima, Olympia, Walla Walla, Waterville, Port Angeles and Colfax went out of business and their papers are stored at Sand Point. These have been inventoried so as to be accessible readily to researchers. Lindgard just has completed an introduction to the catalog, which will be printed in the national capital.</p>
<p>The oldest documents Lindgard uncovered in the Land Office records for this state were in a book containing copies of all correspondence received by the surveyor-general of Washington Territory from the General Land Office. It began with the appointment in August, 1854, of James Tilton, who did not reach his post in Olympia until the next March.</p>
<p>TILTON, a native of Delaware, evidently was of the same family as Dr. James Tilton, first surgeon-general of the United States Army, on the staff of Gen. George Washington in the Revolutionary War.</p>
<p>The 1860 territorial census indicates that the pioneer surveyor-general lived in New York for a time, as two of his three children were born there. Mrs. Tilton and the youngsters arrived on the ship Willimantic two weeks after her husband opened his office.</p>
<p>No information is available as to where the office was.</p>
<p>Instructions in the letter file forbade Tilton to use any explosive fuel for lighting. he was not to store records near the fireplace. He must place them in cases "of such dimensions and with handles at the ends as to be very readily portable in the event of necessity for a sudden removal of them."</p>
<p>For surveying Tilton was supplied with an improved Burt's solar compass and tripod, shipped from Washington, D.C., by Adams Express.</p>
<p>The field men he employed were required to note in their books sites of all mines, salt licks and salt springs.</p>
<p>TILTON was interviewed by The Pioneer Democrat, Olympia newspaper, which stated in the May 26, 1855, issue that he had arranged for surveying six townships in Clark County and others in Thurston and Pierce Counties.</p>
<p>These surveys were to cross the claims of the Hudson's Bay and Puget Sound Agricultural Companies.</p>
<p>American squatters were anxious to oust the British from possession. Tilton said he would exclude from public domain only the property the Hudson's Bay Co. had occupied when the treaty of 1846 was written.</p>
<p>Tilton asked Dugald Mackintosh, chief factor of the company, for an authenticated map or statement of the company's Columbia River claims in that year and was refused: The lands still were barred to surveyors in 1861.</p>
<p>Tilton soon after arrival had a hassle with his superior over location of a base meridian line. The Williamette Meridian, already surveyed in Oregon, dropped off into Puget Sound and was useless for land-location purposes. Tilton was told to offset it by surveying a guide line 18 miles east of the meridian, but pressure was put on him to do otherwise.</p>
<p>The commissioner of lands learned in May "with surprise and regret" that Tilton had "assumed the responsibility"&#8212;the commissioner underscored these words&#8212;of establishing a new meridian 24 miles east of the Willamette line.</p>
<p>The commissioner did not mince words.</p>
<p>"You are hereby given to understand," he wrote, "that all the proceedings in regard to your intended Puget Sound Meridian are illegal, null and void."</p>
<p>TILTON contended that he had placed his line on the eastern shore of Puget Sound "because the most considerable settlements were there."</p>
<p>"You are not to survey Whidbey Island until a continuation of the Willamette Meridian is surveyed from its present terminus and across the island," the commissioner ordered. "This will demand the services of your most skilful surveyor."</p>
<p>Tilton, who had been a major of volunteers in the Mexican War, was appointed adjutant-general when the 1855-56 Indian War broke out. This turbulent period interfered with surveying. When he resumed his surveying duties he received a letter dated October 17, 1857, chiding him for an "extravagant" item for "light" in his incidental-expense account.</p>
<p>"You must reduce it in the future," the commissioner ordered.</p>
<p>Two months later a second reminder arrived. Tilton was spending too much for candles.</p>
<p>"As office hours do not extend into the night, I cannot imagine why there should be so much expended for that one item. You will please explain," said the commissioner.</p>
<p>Tilton's answer is not in the books. Much of the Land Office correspondence, Lindgard said, was destroyed in a fire in 1890.</p>
<p>ENDING of the Indian War hastened opening of public lands east of the Cascades and a new base line had to be established on that side.</p>
<p>In 1860 Congress passed an appropriation for survey of the 46th Parallel so far as it constituted the common boundary between Oregon and Washington Territory. Before this could proceed the Civil War broke out and expenses for surveying were cut to an absolute minimum.</p>
<p>Tilton's appointment ended in October, 1861. he was a pro-slavery Democrat and his loyalty to the Union was questioned by John Miller Murphy, editor, of The Washington Standard, published in Olympia. Tilton challenged Murphy to a duel and the latter responded by lampooning the surveyor until he withdrew his challenge.</p>
<p>Tilton's principal identification with the slavery question was through a mulatto servant named Charlie, who had accompanied the surveyor's family to the Pacific Coast. Charlie was the son of Tilton's aunt's maid, a slave.</p>
<p>After serving the couple for six years, during which Charlie also attended school, the youth stowed away on the steamer Eliza Anderson September 24, 1860. Before the vessel reached Victoria the escapee was discovered and the captain planned to return him to his master.</p>
<p>Negro friends enlisted legal aid in Victoria, a writ of habeas corpus was issued and Charlie was taken ashore and freed. This caused an uproar, because an American vessel had been invaded. When British Columbia authorities refused to return Charlie, Tilton dismissed the matter, saying the boy was not worth his keep.</p>
<p>TILTON'S successor, Anson G. Henry, took office September 11, 1861.</p>
<p>Henry advocated doubling the survey appropriation for the territory. he was told promptly why he would have to observe the same economies as his predecessor. Fixing of the Oregon-Washington boundary, for instance, was not deemed absolutely requisite and had been postponed "for reasons demanding retrenchment in every department of the government."</p>
<p>The reasons were military.</p>
<p>Anson Henry died at sea when the ship Brother Johnathan went down July 31, 1865. Edward Giddings, chief clerk, had charge of the land office until Selucius Garfielde was appointed surveyor-general May 7, 1866.</p>
<p>Garfielde had been one of the men who branded James Tilton a Copperhead, or Confederate sympathizer.</p>
<p>TILTON was president of the Board of Regents of the University of Washington in 1864, when the school had 42 students. A majority of the regents at that time had Copperhead leanings.</p>
<p>Tilton became a candidate for delegate to Congress but lost the race. He had charge of the Northern Pacific Railroad surveys on the Pacific Coast in 1867 and in 1874 went to Georgia to engage in private engineering work. He died November 23, 1878, in Washington, D.C., while inspector of the city's waterworks. He was then 60.</p>
<p>Remarkably little is known about James Tilton in spite of his prominent roles in Washington Territory and the great files of his Indian War papers now kept in the State Library at Olympia.</p>