<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<title>SOME LAWYERS.</title>
<p>IN a town or city of the size of the city of Seattle the bar is always an influential body of men. Lawyers are usually men of learning and native ability. Their minds are sharpened and quickened by daily conflict. Their understanding is broadened and liberalized by the continuous study of the works of the masters of jurisprudence, and their judgments corrected by their almost constant examination of the motives and actions of men. The philosophy of the pulse is to the doctor what the knowledge of human nature is to the lawyer. If not eloquent, the lawyer rarely lacks the ability to make a clear and forcible statement of his views and opinions. The above and other considerations which might be mentioned, give to the lawyer influence and power. All genuine power is either intellectual or moral. True it is that there are tremendous forces, natural and mechanical, operating in the world, but behind all, and superior to all, and controlling all, is intelligence&#8212;mind.</p>
<p>The lawyer is more largely and generously trusted than any other class of men. Not only the delicate secrets of social life, but the larger and sterner secrets of the financial world, are freely confided to him. A person accused of crime and trembling with menaced danger, usually tells his counsel the truth. This is important in all cases and especially in cases depending upon circumstantial evidence, for it enables that counsel to look along the connected chain of facts and to show that a damaging fact attempted to be made criminating by the prosecution, is not a link in the chain. All facts are harmonious, and, if seen from the standpoint of truth, will appear so. Whether a particular fact is criminating or not, depends on the true theory of the case&#8212;the counsel for the defense has the true theory&#8212;the prosecuting counsel may not have it. A further amplification of this thought would be a digression and we close the discussion of the particular topic of this paragraph with the statement that not only the honor of attorneys but the policy of the law make all confidential communications between attorneys and clients, sacred.</p>
<pb/>
<p>Lawyers to a greater extent than any other class of men have been intrusted with public and official positions. One of the three great departments of government can only be filled by lawyers. The executive and legislative departments in both the state and federal governments have in them a large proportion of lawyers. This is but natural, for who are better qualified to make or administer laws than those who have made their provisions their constant study? It is not true that lawyers delight in legal uncertainty and statutory confusion. No class of men are more interested in the certainty and permanency of laws than they. Their conservatism in this regard is marked. Change with them is not necessarily a reform or a betterment of the legal conditions. While they recognize the fact that statutory law is a matter of progression and must in many matters be periodically adjusted to meet the onward march of civilization and the changed condition of affairs, yet their prudent maxim is, "to make haste slowly." Statutory law is not only the guage of practical morals, but the actual standard of personal and property rights in the age and in the community in which it exists.</p>
<p>Lawyers are the natural lovers and defenders of liberty, and why? The first books studied by them in preparation for the discharge of the important duties of their profession teach them what are the relative, as well as the absolute inalienable rights of men&#8212;teach them that the object of all just government is to secure to every person the full possession and enjoyment of these rights. The full security of these rights to the citizen is liberty ordained by law&#8212;their deprivation is, just to the extent of that deprivation, tyranny enforced by law. The lawyer is early and always taught to revere these rights as the sacred heritage of man and as having their foundation in reason and in nature. They are the gift of his Creator to man and are inherent in him as a mental, moral and responsible being. Is it strange then that the lawyer with such views early and continuously bred into his mentla and moral constitution, should be a lover and defender of liberty? Anglo-Saxon history is replete with examples where the lawyer, on the rostrum, in the forum, in legislative halls, on the bench and on the field of battle, has shown his devotion to liberty and the absolute rights of man.</p>
<p>Lawyers, as a body, are conservative on the subject of religion. Accustomed as they are to the analysis of human testimony and to the 
<pb/>
proofs of moral propositions, very few of them are pronounced sceptics. The satisfactory establishment of the great central facts of Christinaity is generally conceded by them. They are not very emotional, hence their religious practices rarely approach the line of fanaticism. Unfounded is the notion that the practice of the legal profession is inconsistent with the highest and purest sense of honor, or the faithful discharge of all the duties man owes to his Creator. In the matters of faith lawyers are and always have been tolerant and liberal in their views. No religious persecution owes its origin or its bloody devastation to them. No body of men more fully appreciates the tremendous power of religious institutions as educational and controlling forces, than they. It is a power coupled with a danger&#8212;great in the past but reaching  the present with greatly diminished force, owing to the constantly increasing constitutional and statutory guarantees in the interests of personal liberty wrought out by the lawyers.</p>
<p>But let us descend from the view of these general topics to those more local and yet germane to our subject. The surprise of eastern lawyers has often been expressed to the writer that so many men could be found at the Seattle bar who were formidable apponents in every department of jurisprudence&#8212;admiralty&#8212;equity&#8212;criminal law, federal and state&#8212;common law and commercial law. It is indeed an extended field&#8212;too great to be fully mastered by one mind in the allotted time of life. The compliment is deserved. There are quite a number of gentlemen at the Seattle bar to-day and have been in the past, who are respectable foeman in any part of this vast legal domain. But the tendency of the profession is to run into departments or specialties. This will not produce so broad but it will produce sharper men. It will give greater accuracy, certainty and proficiency. It will open a surer highway to honorable distinction, if not to fame. Concentrated light always contains more heat and power. Already members of the Seattle bar have won distinction in departmental work, among whom may be instanced James McNaught in corporation law and C.K. Jenner in the land laws of the United States.</p>
<p>It is pleasing to say that, while the great body of lawyers are not accumulators of money, there are a few of the members of the Seattle bar, present and gone, who have not only won distinction in honorable conflict but have accumulated a moderate fortune.</p>
<pb/>
<p>The Seattle bar is distinguished by the large number of its bright and promising young men. In a new country and in a young city, fast moving towards the front in wealth and population, there is no reason why their history should not become an integral portion of that country and of that city. Application, study, devotion to business and temperate habits and a laudable ambition, will surely enable them to reach the goal.</p>
<p>But some cynic may say, "your description of the legal profession is altogether too rose-colored&#8212;that there are many lawyers who do not deserve the commendation you give the profession." True enough, but what of it? Religion has its hypocrites, medicine its quacks and the law its shysters, but the day has long past when the sayings and doings of a hypocrite could cast a cloud on religion&#8212;or when the vaporings of a quack could cast discredit on the medical profession, or when the conduct of a shyster could affect the standing of the legal profession.</p>
<p>Brilliant as is the personel of the bar to-day, this article should not close without brief mention of those earlier pioneers of the profession, who laid the foundation for the present judicial system and the splendid array of talent now gracing the bar of Washington.</p>
<p>One of the territory's earliest lawyers and one of the most gifted, most distinguished and most lamented pioneers was B.F. Kendall. He was a very young man when he commenced the practice of law, but he rapidly arose in his profession and in public favor until his name was associated with the candidacy for delegate to congress, when he was treacherously assassinated in his office by a miserable semi-imbecile by the name of Howe, who, it was generally believed, was prompted to the crime by Frank Clark, a lawyer of considerable ability, who lived in Steilacoom.</p>
<p>He, too, was a pioneer, and in early days was one of our most popular criminal lawyers. In 1867 he was nominated by the Democratic party for delegate to congress and made the canvass with marked ability and at a sacrifice of most of his large material accumulations, the result of many years successful practice in his profession. He would have been elected had it not been for the spectre of the murdered Kendall, that always stood on the rostrum by his side, and mocked at his loftiest flights of oratory. The following verses published in an Olympian paper when the political canvass was at its height,
<pb/>
will give an idea of the esteem in which Mr. Kendall was held and the influence that Mr. Clark's supposed, connection with his death exerted over a portion of the public mind:
KENDALL.
Poor Kendall!
Sleeping so untimely in thy grave!
It is to thee,
Alas! I dedicate my plaintive song.
The long, lank lichens o'er thy ashes wave,
The mournful winds around thy tombstone rave
All night, lamenting o'er the grievous wrong
That sent thee so untimely to thy grave!
Ill fated Kendall!
Sleeping so untimely in thy grave!
Ah! well I know
Thy history of manly patient strife.
The midnight lamp its inspiration gave
To store thy mind with knowledge, round thy life
With manly courage that only served to pave
Life's toilsome pathway to a martyr's grave.
Lamented Kendall!
How we all deplore thy early grave!
None half so missed before!
Just when its confidence thy country gave,
And men, less great, begrudged thy legal lore,
Just as thy star of hope rose from the wave,
The base assassin planned thy gory grave!
Gifted Kendall!
Child of genius! mouldering in thy grave!
Thy hapless fate
Thy countless friends had mourned less deep and
long
If thy vile, self-conceited murderer gave
One hope that to himself might yet belong,
One single grace that ornaments thy grave
Triumphent Kendall!
Sure vengeance has begun, e'en from thy grave
Yea! thou shalt be
Thine own avenger in these latter times!
For though thy sleek assassin roar and rave
In stormy eloquence and classic rhymes,
Fairly forgetful of his proxied crimes,
Twixt him and congress looms thy gory grave!</p>
<p>The early bar of Washington knew indeed some brilliant minds, and foremost, perhaps among those who thirty years ago turned their faces toward the setting sun and sought the sequestered fastnesses of nature, where "rolled the Oregon," that heard no sweet sound save those of its own dashing, or, packing their blankets and sea-bread, wended their weary way to the Sound to hew a home out of the solid woods, was Selucius Garfield. Let us lay the white mantle of charity gently over the pale ashes of the gifted dead, for we are all brothers. When a world, it becomes a target for the poisonous arrows of envy and malice, as well as a cynosure bright mind like that of Garfield's dazzles his for the admiration of the appreciative. That the 
<pb/>
great orator was faultless, even his most ardent friends would not pretend; but his vices were negative rather than positive. They arose from moral weakness, not from natural depravity, while his heart overflowed with many sweet humanities, and his finely attuned car had caught the grand diapasons of the Infinite.</p>
<p>It seems anomalous that great talent and great weakness should or could exist in the same individual; but when bounteous Nature so lavishly endows, the recipients of her favors are not infrequently possessed of elements as incongruous as the antipodes. It would seem that she is sometimes under the unfortunate necessity of acting in accordance with the dynamics of the pendulum&#8212;that the force required to propel a great mind far along the blazing line of genius necessitates a swing equally long in the opposite direction. But this necessity exists only when force, not power, is the motor at her command. Nature always does the very best she can with the elements within her reach. Power, by its innate greatness, lifts the individual into the serene atmosphere of moral purity and sustains him there; while mere force, after expending itself, allows its victim to drop as far below as he was carried above the center of motion. Selucius Garfield swayed the minds of men with oratory's magic spell, and by its weird witchery melted the hearts of his audience down to tears. His career was as brilliant and dazzling, and almost as evanescent, as the transitory gleam that flits across the horizon when a meteor appears.</p>
<p>While a minister of the gospel, the veil of scepticism fell over his moral vision, and he abandoned the pulpit for the bar. While a member of congress he made a tour through many of the middle and Eastern states, lecturing on the resources of Washington territory, and did much to attract attention to this, then, almost unknown portion of the national domain and his political speeches everywhere elicited universal encomium form the press, and were pronounced unequaled in scope and breadth of statesmanship and marvels of eloquence. NOt a few leading journals declared him the peer, in eloquence, of the nation's finest speakers, while many others ranked him at the head of the list, and without a rival.</p>
<p>It is said that while engaged in the practice of law he acquired a passion for cards and that he came to this territory to break away from pernicious associations in order to lead a better life; but his advent into the national capital surrounded him with all the old allurements intensified, the magic spell of cards returned and 
<pb/>
the strange fascination of monte and faro dragged the statesman and orator from his enviable eminence down to the slums of the lowest gambling hells that then glittered like crystal palaces in the city of churches, political diplomacy and fashion.</p>
<p>Luck, the fickle goddess of the votaries of chance, forsook him, and, poor and prematurely old, he expired in cheerless poverty in the dilapidated attic of one of the lowest dens of vice in the city's perlieus, attended only by the wreck of what had, not many years before, been an accomplished, facinating and fashionable lady, their only tie being that spark divine that glows deathlessly on, even admist the envirous of vice, the squalor of poverty and the ruins of constitutions once superb and intellects once brilliant. Oh, genuis, how often art thou the companion of tears and solitude! How oft dost thou sit comfortless in the ashes of thine own desolation! But again I say, let us lay the mantle of charity with tender hand on the tomb of one who had only kind words for Washington, and whose highest encomious were spoken in her behalf. The eye can revel in the charming features of a landscape without dwelling on the parts that mar its beauty, and should we be less charitable to our fellowman? True nobility of soul is indicated by that fine element by which men are enabled to appropriate the beautiful and true in nature and art without assimilating their imperfections. Garfield was born to the people, and had he been true to himself, true to his God-given talents and to the nobler manhood that ever clamored for the ascendency, his influence for good would have been a mighty tidal wave, whose foam-white crest would have blossomed among the stars.</p>
<p>But alas, he has left no monument of his genius, startlingly grand behind him; and his fame will perish with the generation, that thrilled with the matchless eloquence of that "silver-tongued orator."</p>
<p>Had he not been satiated with fulsome praise, soured by fould aspersions of enemies and painfully conscious of the utter worthlessness of the tinsel-bauble men call fame, his career might have had a different termination.</p>
<p>But bonfires, bells, bunting and deafening peals of applause and boisterous demonstrations awaited him wherever he spoke from political forums, and the upturned fields of faces, with their everlasting sameness everywhere, grew monotonous, and his perceptive soul sickened and his heart wearied with the meaningless
<pb/>
gratulations that were more than offset by the malignant aspersions of tireless political enemies and envious rostrum rivals.</p>
<p>And away back on memory's wall, half hidden by the gathering cobwebs of time, hangs the mental portrait of another of those fallen favorites&#8212;Secretary Mason. And still farther back another portraiture that will be recognized by every old timer&#8212;one whom Nature had endowed with many shining graces of head and heart, and whose stately and dignified person had once been robbed in judicial ermine: I refer to Judge Munroe, who long since filled a premature grave.</p>
<p>Another of the early and most popular pioneer leaders at the bar was O.B. McFadden, a man who, while our territorial delegate to the national capital, was a conspicuous figure on the floors of congress and was an ornament to that body as well as a credit to the territory he represented. At home he was popular as judge, farmer, consellor and legislator. He was a man who gave the impression of being possessed of a great deal of reserve power. His mind was harmonial because his brain was well balanced. He was an eloquent speaker and a cogent logician. In fact his was the oritorical temperament; that is, his temperaments were so blended as to endow him by nature with a high order of lingual talent, characterized by inspirational fervor that sought and found legitimate pleasure in verbal expression.</p>
<p>As judge on the bench he was impartial; as counsellor he was the peer of the most gifted; as statesman his views were broad, comprehensive, astute and generously democratic, and as a neighbor and friend he was all that the most scrupulously exacting could desire.</p>
<p>In his death Washington lost on of her most ardent friends and gifted sons and while a pioneer lives the honored name of O.B. McFadden will remain a household word and when these will remain a household word and when these shall have passed away and most of them shall have been forgotten, his name shall shine from history's page the personation of one who nobly and well performed his part in giving permanent and beautiful form to the chaotic elements of new commonwealth.</p>
<byline>J.A. CAREY.</byline>