<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>Chinese Life on the Pacific Coast.</head>
<byline>By James Peter Macintyre.</byline>
<p>It may be that if you have seen one Chinese village you have, in a sense, seen all of China; nevertheless, the principle, as far as it relates to the Chungwos resident on the Pacific Coast of Canada, allows of indefinite expansion even in a superficial sense. The mysticism of manner which seems an essential motive in the Chinese existence, is far less opaque in ordinary everyday affairs than when applied in connection with religious worship, or in guarding the ulterior workings of their masonry.</p>
<p>Impassive and taciturn as to the kaolin clay and glazed image representing an abstruse being, insensibly inuring to a ritual of worship, clouded in incense-laden smoke, it is not strange that the Cathayans of the coast are an almost unknown quantity in the gregarious element which occupies the centres of population.</p>
<p>Their bent in religion is towards a latitude which allows them a multifarity of gods, and the practice of polytheism; the doctrines adhered to mainly leading the Chinese mind to propagate elusive and, it may be maintained, ludicrous means of escaping the evil spirit. To attain the passive, semi-conscious state, which they esteem the goal of the spirit at immolation, they practice active religious rites which are inspired with the view of outwitting the devil. In this connection the phase of proceedings during their lives, which, according to the gospel of morals, inclines to noisomeness, is attained by the agency of brazen instruments. No sound which is produced by the use of vellum, as in the beating of a drum, is tasteful to the oriental ear. The gulf in this manner is more noticeable to the pronounced Caucasians because of the ridicule with which the Chinese receive the sonorous instrument in almost otherwise universal favor. But they are as opposite to us in ways innumerable, and as apparent in their customs as the Japanese appear in using mechanical tools, and obeying forms, exactly the reverse of that which habit has confirmed in the people of most other nations.</p>
<p>No other class of cosmopolitans on the coast carry with them kin qualities which, in the routine of their lives, act with such opposite effects. At the same time that they emulate the Aztec Indians in grateful, if undemostrative worship of the sun, the warmth of which is congenial to the oriental physique, the idol of the Indians finds sweltering masses of decaying garbarge to simmer down, and from whence to free to the air the germs which are incipient of epidemic diseases.</p>
<p>Their idolatry of body is more than offset by the filthy condition of their surroundings, although the latter effect is now more prevalent where the coolies are isolated, as in rural districts.</p>
<p>In the aggrandizement of wealth, the most potent factor observed in aiming at a competency is frugality in their mode of living; although the Hermic tendency in their nature looks contradictory when their innate love of gambling is exposed. In the pursuit of chance gaming a nervous avidity and interest are disclosed in the process that are entirely opposite to the former trait of character. It is not a very common occurrence when a Chinaman tries conclusions with a white man in a game of cards. But on one occasion a celestial entered a poker game with a resident white man on the Coast, to offset whom, in his own game, he carried an extra pack of cards in his sleeve. A full hand of aces turned up for the white man, who drew Chew's attention to the fact with the exclamation, "I have four aces, Johnny." "Velley good," replied the Chinaman, to whom the game was a little foreign, "you see, me got five acey."</p>
<p>In this channel, thorugh which they vent a great amount of excitement, the passion for play, which is under the ban of civic ordinances, brings them under the raiding system of the police authorities. On one occasion not very long ago, when passing through a Chinese quarter in Westminster, the police of the city were engaged in capturing a den of gamblers, who nightly resorted to one of the "hells" for play. At convenient points near the resort, preparatory to entering the building at a signal, were several officers. The gamesters were playing in an upper room of the building, into which the raiders entered by the street door, but which they no sooner passed aware of the presence of the police than they sprang towards the windows, through which some of them came crashing to the wooden sidewalk underneath, bringing the glass with them. Being hard to detect them as individuals excepting on acquaintance, a number of them escaped to the labyrinthine alleys, from whence they returned calmly to watch the outcome of the encounter.</p>
<p>Those penned up in the room engaged in a desperate fight for liberty, but, the avenues of escape being cut off, their efforts proved futile. It was during the re-encounter that one of the officers called upon the white bystanders to enter the premises and aid in securing the prisoners for conveyance to the 'cangue.'</p>
<p>At the moment of entering, with the intent of helping, a bystander felt himself arrested through a hand being placed on his shoulder. Turning sharply around, he found, by the dim
<pb/>
light which shed its rays between the green stalks of some lily plants in the next window, that his detainer was a well dressed Chinaman. "Keep'l out. You no go, savvy? They savvy you," he continued. While being evidently a stranger he yet uttered the name of the person he had stopped, while uttering his pigeon warning. Being aware of the sinister motive which sometimes goes with the blue blouse, the procession of Chinamen and captors proceeded to the police headquarters without the aid of the mysteriously enlightened looker on.</p>
<p>Now, although the conditions of habitation and life in the northern latitudes are so different to those existent in the Straits settlements and China, incidents such as that related jog one to a belief in the reality of that component part of the Chinese colony personal, the hatchet man under all circumstances. The instrument of destruction, perhaps, is only changed to an easily concealable weapon in the first instance, in lieu of the spear which lets the blood of the traitor or enemy in the latter. A long-bladed knife or a revolver will accomplish its deadly mission with equal dispatch under circumstances which, in other climes, bring the less-concealable spear into vogue.</p>
<p>In the Straits settlements it is known that, in connection with masonry, the approaches to the inner temple where the court of pears is situated, with heaven for its dome, are well guarded. The masonry which has its meetings in the temple of God&#8212;the forest, in the South, can accommodate itself to less spacious surroundings in the North. For this reason there is no plausible cause why the mandate which requires the blood of an individual to seal it, should not be as effective in one clime as in the other. There is just a suspicion that the facts in the matter point in the direction of this theory.</p>
<p>It is noteworthy that the large cities are the arenas in which by daylight the emissaries of the high binders enact tragedies of almost startling recurrence. In the smaller cities of the North Pacific Coast, with less numerous colonies tributary to the six-legged devil fish to which they hold allegiance, the espoinage of the police is not so complete, presumably because of the more open manner of living of the Chinese inhabitants. The removal of a marked man, therefore, would be a comparatively easy matter when it is taken for granted that the hired assassin would be shielded as much as possible by his countrymen. In the first instance escape would be facilitated by reason of the crowded state of the quarters, while in the latter the mode of carrying out the project would be in accordance with the different conditions under which they exist.</p>
<p>As to the internecine fighting which occurs at times, it is limited in prevalence to cities of large magnitude, and is of less frequent occurrence, although happening, in small towns. Where strife in this way has been seen to exist, and deadly weapons used at various periods, dramatic effect seemed more the aim of the combatants than any extent of damage to either of the participants, although quarrels have led to severe cutting and maiming even if the opportunities for concealment are not so good as in cities of metropolitan aspect.</p>
<p>As an incentive to removing a man, blood money need be of nominal amount only when it is averred that a substitute for a wealthy man condemned to death for murder in China, can be procured for a few dollars. It is not likely that a change of sentiment in regard to death of so great extent can take place under the changed condition of abode, that the estimate of a hinous crime will magnify itself through residence in the Occident.</p>
<p>The system of shadowing a man by the instrumentality of a coolie, was well demonstrated in an occurrence which took place not a great time since in a Coast city. In the process of acquiring a knowledge of the habits and places of resort of a man to whom they imagined a grudge was owing, he was placed under the surveillance of a spy. Feeling ill at ease, perhaps through presentiment to some extent, for several successive nights, he turned about abruptly to find himself dogged at some distance by a villainous-looking hench-man of the highbinders. The paid emissary of the companies, finding himself under the suspicion of his intended victim, discovered the futility of further effort in his nefarious design, and changed his tactics so that his espionage seemed to cease. Whether, if a favorable opportunity afforded, advantage would have been taken to destroy the life of the object of the hatchet-man's nocturnal rambles, is not certain, but that an evil motive actuated him there can be little question. To return in the perfuctory manner of this article to qualities inhering to the Chinese, and visible in their every day life, it is observable that a Chinaman is seldom seen who is much under the influence of alcoholic liquors. Abstinence from liquors, or at least the characteristic abstemiousness of the Chinamen in the matter of drink which is apt to produce a temulent condition, is adhered, according to himself, form the physical reason of avoiding enlargment of the abdomen rather than from any apprehension of the mind.</p>
<p>Opposed diametrically to this virtue, which as much or more than any other makes the coolie a desirable servant, there stands the very baneful habit of opium smoking, which they almost universally follow. Opium joints in which the delusive and no less seductive pipe can be 'hit,' are adjucts of every Chinatown; and, as a consequence, the Government is compelled to find asylum for several score of jabbering idiots, the aftermath of inoculation with the drug years ago in their own country, by British bayonets. Among others than the celestials in the northern portion of the Coast, the habit is inoperative, being confined wihtin limits that are effected by the limited size of the cities and consequent exposure of any indulgence in the vice by the foreign devils whom the Chinese nature resolves itself into shunning associations with as far as possible.</p>
<p>With such ethics as they are possesed of it is not passing strange to see almost incredible customs attributed to them verified in the routine of their lives. For example, fatalism is a recognized principle in their beliefs which has its foundation of breadth that is irrespective of any religion or sect of one. Side by side with it is their stoical contempt for death. In the first connection their apathetic conduct in events where great danger or death is imminent, illustrates the phase in their existence.</p>
<p>A number of men a few years ago were engaged in cutting a passage through heavy ice which had formed on the Fraser River in front of the town of New Westminster. The object in view was to allow of steamboat approach to the wharves, and during the operation the ice suddenly parted, letting one of the gang of men&#8212;who happened to be a white man&#8212;into the water. Immediately a rush took place to the shore, during which stampede a man yelled at the Chinamen that the man who had gone into the water was a coolie. Not abating their pace or stopping to see if it was so, the warning only elicited from the Chinese the response, "He go to hello, me no cale," in panting breaths while he flew over the ice on his way to safety.</p>
<p>At a near distance, too, to the scene of the foregoing episode, a man who was very much intoxicated lay down on the railroad track in front of a cabin in which there lived a gang of collie railway section men. The men must have been well aware of the hours at which the trans daily passed their abode, but, although said to be at home and acquainted with the facts of the man's critical position, they made no effort to place him beyond danger. While lying unconscious of his near dreadful fate, a train sped around a curve at the end of which he lay, and before the engineer could pull up the cars they had passed over and mangled the unfortunate victim of superstition as much as of drink.</p>
<p>On the other end of the same curve is a junction where trains are made up on the main line of the railway. The coaches from Westminster City are run by a branch line to be attached to the east-going mail. It was at the depot at the junction that a Chinaman, in stepping from a car, fell between the wheels and was badly crushed. His lower limbs were fractured, evidently causing him excruciating pain. Numbers of his countrymen assembled about and carried him onto the platform of the station. One of these hastened to some cabins at a short distance, returning with a further contingent, one of them holding a glass containing a white fluid which he administered to the injured man.</p>
<p>The potion, likely an anesthetic from the formul&#230; of Shing Nung, the chemist emperor, concocted with the subtile skill of Sophania of Palermo, was hardly given when the man was picked up uncomplainingly and carried to one of the cabins. It is said of the Chinese, that in cases of extreme suffering they cure the patient by killing them, so that the information given with a perfunctory nod, "Heap good dlink; he all laight; litta time he bletter," seemed to support the truth of the idea. Heap good was inferred as being used in the same connection 
<pb/>
as when applied at the immolation of an Indian.</p>
<p>One other strange notion in the ludicrous category held by the Chinese, appertains to the translation of the women to the spirit world. It is believed by the women and fostered by the men, with some object, no doubt, similar to the comcom custom in other countries in handing down and propagating superstitious ideas, that the women who are strict vegetarians here, become changed into men on leaving this sphere. As an inducement to frugal living, the upholding of the doctrine by the feminine portion of the residents, who cater to Cyprian tastes, counter-balance the gourmet propensities of the men in their relish for chicken. It is not an easy matter, owing to the relation which inheres to the sexes of the nation in their mode of dressing, to distinguish between man and woman; and the transition metaphysically would be an evolution portended by the clothing affected by the gentler sex.</p>
<p>Following the rites which relate to the lives led by these people, come those which are attendant upon the last ordeal in their existence and burial. Any language expressive of mourning in connection with the forms followed on the death of a Chinaman of standing is misapplied. The ceremonial is simply the climax of vanity, which is looked forward to by the deceased individual as the greatest object to be attained through the efforts spent in a career of usefulness and in the accumulation of wealth. As the bulk of the Chinese are laborers, it is uncommon on the Occidental strand to view a funeral on a large scale, which but serves to make the incident indelible on the mind of one fortunate enough to behold the unique spectacle.</p>
<p>If a look is taken into the chamber of death, it is seen that, on a form at the head of the bier, there is placed six bowls of rice, the same number of bowls of wine, and yet again an equal accompaniment of dishes containing chicken. Wax candles, alight to the number of six, are arranged about the coffin, and at the entrance to the apartment there stands one on either side to guide the visitors within. The nearest relatives of the defunct, to the number of six, at one period enter the room and partake slightly of the dishes. No information in reference to this part of the proceedings can be gleaned from the coolies, who, with their usual reticence, decline to say if the form relates to, or has any connection with, the Chinese Six Companies.</p>
<p>On the thoroughfare in front of the residence a further superficial glimpse of the eccentric ceremonies is seen before the funeral cortege gets under way, in the several shoats, roasted whole, which are disposed beside the coffin. For some time the body lies in state thus on the street, where relatives and acquaintances take a farewell look at the features and accord the body a mortal leave.</p>
<p>An ordinary vehicle ahead conveying the deceased man's effects to the cemetery just over the ridge, gave warning simultaneously with a brazen din, that a funeral was under way. At the time of the appearance of the queer host an impenetrable fog was shrinking away to the base of the valley, driven by the gathering strength of the sun is ascending toward the zenith. With the retiral of the vapor appeared a mass of green growth, dew spangled and studded with the golden blossom of the broom shrub. On the terraced grounds rising upward from the finely situated and picturesque city of New Westminster, lithe young fir trees gave place here and there to a brightly-painted cottage, now and then with an ambitious, but curtailed, tower.</p>
<p>The vanguard of the parade itself, as it came out from the vapory shroud, reminded one of a fate in the far East in which the participants are clad in bright gala costume. In the front rank of the cohort which led, a large, powerful Chinaman held aloft an immense scarlet banner, the pole of which was adorned with ribbons of various hues. On either side of him walked a coolie with a four-sided transparency held aloft nearly to the level of the banner. File after file, the formation breasted the sloping hill, each mourner, from his white and gauzy head-gear of muslin to his thick-soled foot-wear, a striking anomaly to the occasion . Short tunics of divers brilliant colors surmounted white muslin nether garments which were swathed mummy fashion about the legs.</p>
<p>Various devices ranging from the triangles to polygons were carried by the division which was in front; each of them bearing perpendicular columns of hierglyphs, the word symbols of the Chinese language. A break in the ranks was occupied by a solitary Chinaman who emitted a fanfare from an ox horn, turning his head from right to left, after each effort, while he grinned at the amazed onlookers who lined the roads, or walked by the side of the funeral cortege. The second division was in different garb to that affected by the gray phalanx which had preceded it, being clad in ordinary "melican man's wear." Another section, with all the paraphernalia of the first, followed before a string of carriages and a hearse, on each side of which walked pallbearers in white.</p>
<p>Before the procession became visible a brazen din could be heard which, on near approach, was found to be made with very large cymbals. From the same carriage also came the metallic and continuous click of metallic oval drums; while the impressive, weird, and strange to the ear
<pb/>
dead march of the sect&#8212;no less peculiar than their strange customs to the other senses&#8212;issued from a vehicle behind. Up out of the dim prehistoric age in which Hwang-ti the III., ruler of the celestial empire, engaged as a pastime in inventing musical instruments, rises, it would appear, the refrain that dies away from the flute to leave a vivid impression on the imagination.</p>
<p>From the following carriage floated forth, to flutter like snow flakes in the air a moment before reaching the earth, a continuous shower of paper cut into small pieces which are closely perforated. In the wake of the cortege the devil is supposed to follow, but ere he can catch up with the hearse, according to the Chinese idea, he has to perform the acrobatic feat of tumbling in and out of each puncture in the fragments of paper which were cast to the winds. Thus the body (and spirit) is supposed to be gotten safely to the cemetery, where the bad joss, as an incentive to leaving the body undisturbed and to appease his appetite for human flesh, was treated to a collation of food. During the banquet he could sit invisible amid the odorous burning joss sticks with which the ground about the grave had been studded.</p>
<p>At the grave side, robed in pure white, knelt a figure of which a glimpse was caught in one of the carriages. It was the widow of the deceased, who arose and cast her seeming bridal robes to the flames arising from a pyre on which the effects of her husband, and all the paraphernalia of the procession, was being consumed. After the lawful period has passed, the resting place will be desecrated, the bones removed and cleaned and, further on, be shipped to China.</p>