<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>CHIN GEE HEE, NOTED SEATTLE CHINESE, DEAD
Orient's Foremost Railroad Builder Started Here as Track Laborer; Built First Brick Building After Fire of '89.</head>
<p>CHIN GEE HEE, who, after a residence in Seattle of thirty years, left in 1905 to become the "James J. Hill of Southern China," is dead in his clan village of Look Tun, in the Sunning Valley, near Canton.</p>
<p>Word that the Orient's foremost railroad builder passed away last Friday reached Seattle today.</p>
<p>Although 85 years old, Chin Gee Hee was actively engaged at the time of his death in promoting an ocean port at Tong Koo, south of Hongkong. In a letter to his old friend and lawyer, Fred H. Lysons, last winter, he declared the project would be a success.</p>
<p>Once the victim of a mob in Seattle and once owner of a small King Street store, Chin Gee Hee rose to a commanding position in his own country, receiving from the Emperor the much-coveted peacock feather. He did not lose touch with Seattle, buying his supplies here as far as possible and consulting with Seattle friends about his various projects.</p>
<p>After the completion of his seventy-mile railroad in Sunning Valley in 1917, he was made an honorary member of the Seattle Chamber of Commerce. Only two other men have been thus honored by that organization, Judge C.H. Hanford and Capt. A.B. Wyckoff, U.S.N., founder of the Puget Sound Navy Yard, both dead. Three years ago a commercial delegation to the Orient from the chamber presented to Chin Gee Hee a large album filled with portraits of his old friends and former associates in Seattle.</p>
<p>Chin Gee Hee came to this country when a boy, worked in the California placer mines for a time and then came to this section, opening a laundry in Port Gamble. He moved to Seattle and became a railroad track laborer, then a small contractor on the Columbia &amp; Puget Sound Railroad, now the Pacific Coast Railway, and was one of the contracting builders of the old Front Street cable line.</p>
<pb/>
<p>CHINESE PIONEER OF SEATTLE SUCCUMBS
Chin Gee Hee, Orient's Foremost Railroad Builder, Started Here as Track Laborer.</p>
<p>After his railroad construction work he opened the Wa Chong store in Seattle in partnership with Chin Ching Hock. Soon he started his own establishment, the Quong Tuck Company, which is still a going concern, under the management of a relative, at 721 King Street.</p>
<p>The fire of 1889 took his store along with the whole business section of the city, but before the ruins were cold. Chin Gee Hee had a new building under construction, it being the first brick structure to be erected after that disaster. It still stands on Washington Street, near Second Avenue South, bearing the inscription "Canton Building, 1889."</p>
<p>During the antichinese riots here in 1886, Chin Gee Hee and his family were rescued from the mob by a company of Home Guards composed of leading citizens.</p>
<subhead>Returns to Build Railroad.</subhead>
<p>He returned to China in 1905 to develop the dream of his younger days in Seattle&#8212;the construction of a railroad through his home district in China. This accomplished, he was decorated by the last Emperor of China with the peacock feather and supplied with a retinue of soldiers and servants for his railroad.</p>
<p>Attorney Lysons inspected the Chin Gee Hee properties on a visit to the Orient in 1913.</p>
<p>"With all the honors that had been conferred upon him," said Mr. Lysons today. "and the material progress he made in China, Chin Gee Hee treasured above them all the associations and friendships he left in Seattle.</p>
<p>"Seattle," said the late Judge Burke on one occasion, "can point to no business career of higher honor, and few of more value to it, than that of Chin Gee Hee. he never ceased to spread the gospel of Seattle throughout the Orient."</p>