<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>CHINESE SLAVERY</head>
<p>How apt and just the expressions of Mr. Justice Hoffman in the U.S. Circuit Court, San Francisco, in his very able opinion, delivered recently, when discharging from custody Tiburcio Parrott, President of a mining company, charged with the crime of having given employment to Chinese laborers.</p>
<p>In concluding the opinion, Judge Hoffman says: "The right to labor for a living is a privilege, an immunity secured to every man in civilized society."</p>
<p>It is as inviolable as the right of property, for property is the offspring of labor.</p>
<p>It is as sacred as the right of life, for life is taken if the means whereby we live be taken.</p>
<p>Had the labor of the Irish or Germans been similarly proscribed, the legislation would have encountered a storm of just indignation. The right of persons of those or other nationalities to support themselves by their labor stands on no other or higher ground than of the Chinese. The latter have even the additional advantages afforded by the express and solemn pledge of the nation.</p>
<p>That the unrestricted immigration of the Chinese to this country is a great and growing evil, that it presses with much severity on the laboring classes, and that if allowed to continue in numbers bearing any considerable proportion to that of the teeming population of the Chinese Empire, it will be a menace to our peace and even to our civilization, is an opinion entertained by most thoughtful persons.</p>
<p>The demand, therefore, that the Treaty shall be rescinded or modified is reasonable and legitimate. But while that Treaty exists, the Chinese have the same rights of immigration and residence as are possessed by any other foreigners. Those rights it is the duty of the courts to maintain, and of the Government to enforce.</p>
<p>The declaration that "the Chinese must go, forcibly," is an insolent contempt of national obligations and an audacious defiance of national authority. Before it can be carried into effect by force, the authority of the United States must first be not only defied, but resisted and overcome.</p>
<p>The attempt to effect this object indirectly by legislation will be met with equal firmness by the courts; no matter whether it assumes the guise of an exercise of the police power, or of the power to regulate corporations, or of any other power reserved by the State; and no matter whether it takes the form of a constitutional provision, legislative enactment, or municipal ordinance.</p>
<p>Conservative, dignified, true to his exalted position and eminent judicial character, he upholds with firmness that no demagogism will swerve, no prejudice against a despised race will mould the dispensing of justice; that national objections, constitutional landmarks shall not be violated; that treaties are the supreme law of the land, and no State constitution or local law dictated by prejudice shall override them; that such declarations as that "the Chinese must go," finds no lodgment with an honest judiciary&#8212;Justice Hoffman proves himself not only an able and fearless jurist, but exhibits statesmanship of a high order when he gives utterance to the great truth: "the unrestricted immigration of the Chinese to this country is a great and growing evil, that it presses with much severity on the laboring classes&#8212;if allowed to continued in numbers bearing any considerable proportion to that of the teeming population of the Chinese Empire, it will be a menace to our peace and even to our civilization." With unerring judgement he names the remedy&38212;the only panacea for the rescinded or modified is reasonable and legitimate."</p>
<p>This suggests the inquiry:&#8212;Is the presence of the great number of Chinese in the Pacific States and Territories the result of a bona fide immigration? Is it not rather an importation of laborers by Chinese capitalists, than a voluntary migration of Chinese to our shores? A Chinaman is entitled to the protection of our laws&#8212;he is entitled to labor. But it is no violation of the true intent of the Burlingame Treaty to protest against the importation of laborers who owe service to those who cause them to be brought, who derive the income of their labor. Such importation can claim no privileges under that Treaty. Slavery of every kind is abolished in the United States of America; and if Chinese companies or wealthy Chinamen can import by hundreds and thousands this class and hire them out, how true that it presses with severity upon our own laboring classes, how menacing to our peace, how repugnant to our civilization. We advocate the largest freedom for every man to enjoy the pursuit of happiness. For all we can champion "the right to labor for a living. It is as inviolable as the right to property, for property is the offspring of labor. It is as sacred as the right to life, for life is taken if the means whereby we live be taken." THe Chinaman who is a freeman, is as fully entitled to these safeguards as any other man. But Chinese slavery should not for a day be tolerated in the United States. What the Government punishes its citizens for attempting, should not be allowed by citizens or subjects of another nation. Legitimate immigration of Chinese would never cause any great difficulty. The unrestricted importation of China slave labor belonging to the importers is the real difficulty. These thoughts we feel are warranted by recent developments in the response of Secretary Evarts to a resolution of Congress. His answer was accompanied by some very interesting documents. They include three letters from Mr. Bailey, Consul-General at Shanghai, relating to slavery in China and the Chinese penal code, and copies of a recent correspondence upon this subject between Mr. Evarts and Yung-Wing, under date of Dec. 2, 1879. Mr. Bailey writes to Secretary of State, enclosing a recent decision of Sir John Small, Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of Hong Kong, "that to sell or buy or dtain a man, woman, or child as a slave or as property is contrary to the law of England, which law is imported into and forms the substance of the law of Hong Kong." The decision shows that as far back as 1845 the British Government notified all residents of the colony of Hong Kong, by royal proclamation, that slavery in the colonies must be abolished; that at that time there were 10,000 slaves in the colony, and the trade in human chattels had been continuously carried on under the very eyes of the officials, and that slavery exists in Hong Kong at the present day.</p>
<p>Mr. Bailey also enclosed editorials upon the same subject from Hong Kong papers, and the copy of a memorial by more than ten thousand of the Chinese gentry, merchants, and others, of Hong Know, to he Governor of that colony, praying that the British laws relating to slavery and the slaver trade be not enfoced. Thsi petition contains most complete and convincing proofs of the widespread existencing proofs of the widespread existence of slavery in China at the present time. The memorialists, indeed, argue that do-
<pb/>
mestic slavery is so essentially interwoven with their whole social system that it cannot possibly be dispensed with. In alluding to these various enclosures, Mr. Bailey says it is now settled that slavery exists and ever has existed as an essential feature of the Chinese political and social system, and perhaps it is worth while to query whether Chinese emigration to the United States is not thus shown to have in its every lineament the the taint of human slavery. Under date of Oct. 21, 1879, the Consul-General, alluding to a translation of certain sections of the penal code of China in regard to slavery, remarks that it is of so much importance at thsi juncture of Chinese emigration to the United States, and relates so forcibly to the question of the citizenship of this class of emigrants, that it is made the subject of a special report for the information of the department. Continuing, he says: "In this connection I have to remark that the patriarchal organization of society in China is such as to make the enforcement of this law easy and effective."</p>