<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<head>The city engineer, the judge, and Molly Maggs</head>
<p>It was in 1895&#8212;when Seattle voters were about to decide if the Cedar River water supply would be developed in municipal ownership&#8212;that City Engineer Reginald H. thomson was perturped upon reading a newspaper interview with Judge John J. McGilvra.</p>
<p>The election outlook was nip and tuck. A private company had eyes on the Cedar River, backed by most of the local business community as well as a plentiful supply of propaganda cash.</p>
<p>At that time, Seattle drew its domestic water supply from Lake Washington and numerous springs (Molly Maggs' spring among them). The private entrepreneurs had ideas of consolidating the distribution and tapping the Cedar River watershed for the main supply.</p>
<p>Thomson&#8212;along with others like H.R. Clise, L.B. Youngs, Will Parry and George Cotteriff&#8212;favored municipal development. In fact, they had operated in secrecy, behind closed doors at City Hall, to formulate a comprehensive municipal program (fearing that if they acted openly too soon, the private entrepreneurs would block them.</p>
<p>Finally, Thomson and his associates wangled the municipal plan onto an 1895 election ballot. Not surprisingly, the city fathers passed the hot chesnut to the electorate&#8212;doubtless expecting it to be chilled at the polls.</p>
<p>As Welford Beaton, an on-the-scene historian, wrote later, all the political funds were stacked against the proposition.</p>
<p>Thus Thomson was deeply disturbed when he read of Judge McGilvra's attack on the proposition. The highly influential judge had been neutral until then. His attack, Thomson mused, would be the telling blow&#8212;sending the proposition to defeat.</p>
<p>Beaton tells us how Thomson turned Judge McGilvra around. Getting the Judge on the telephone, Thomson made an offer:</p>
<p>"We are both working for the same end, the good of the city. If, after we consult, you can show me where I am wrong, I will write a letter to the newspapers advising people to vote against the proposition and will withdraw from the fight."</p>
<p>Judge McGilvra responded that he would draw up a brief outlining his reasons for opposition, and the two men would meet and judge each other's position.</p>
<p>The result was that Judge McGilvra became convinced that Thomson was right and stated his own change of position in letters to newspapers.</p>
<p>The judge did more, telling Thomson: "Don't let money stand in your way. Do everything that is necessary and send the bills to me." The judge also organized speakers, hired halls, and bands, and Beaton recalled, "paid for everything out of his own pocket."</p>
<p>By a vote of 2,656 to 1,665, the electorate approved the proposition and the city became the proprietor of Cedar River water rights&#8212;Seattle's world-famed water supply, now augumented fromt he Tolt River.</p>
<p>What about Molly Maggs' spring on the east slope of Queen Anne Hill? She and members of her family served a sizable section of lower Queen Anne from their spring for many years, the last competitiors to the Seattle Water Department.</p>
<p>The Molly Maggs spring was capped in 1950. The Water Department reports that the spring still flows&#8212;diverted into the city sewer system, as appears to be the case with the George Kinnear and other springs that served Seattle neighborhoods in pioneer Seattle.</p>
<p>&#8212;Rose Cunningham</p>