<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<title>IN MEMORIAM.</title>
<byline>G. MORRIS HALLER.
T. T. MINOR, M. D.
E. LOUIS COX.</byline>
<p>IN THIS our Christmas number of the Washington Magazine two names are omitted from the list of contributors. Two gentlemen who were firm friends of the Magazine and deeply interested in our work have been suddenly taken away from us by an untimely death. Before the first number of the Washington Magazine was issued, we received warm words of encouragement from both the gentlemen we now mourn as lost.</p>
<p>G. Morris Haller and Dr. T. T. Minor in identifying their names with the Washington Magazine proved a source of strength to the enterprise at its inception among a large circle of friends and had they lived many a valuable contribution from their pens would have appeared in its pages.</p>
<p>But it is not because we are deprived of their kindly encouragement, much as we valued it, that we mourn for them, but because as true men and good citizens, we, with others, will deeply miss their presence, and sorrow over the cruel fate that took them from us so suddenly and unexpected.</p>
<p>No men were more loved or respected than they in the community where they lived. None strove harder than they to do good and to promote the welfare of their fellow citizens. Devoted to the city of their adoption, unselfish and patriotic as only good men are, they had won their way into the hearts of all classes, rich and poor alike. Their loss to Seattle was indeed a public calamity, and was so viewed by every resident of the Queen City. The impressive demonstration on Sunday, the 15th of December, at the Armory Hall, in Seattle, when over 5000 people assembled together to do honor to their memories, proved that, though dead, the names of G. Morris Haller, Dr. T. T. Minor and E. Louis Cox, will live in the hearts of the people for many a long day.</p>
<p>To the sorrowing and bereaved relatives whose prolonged and deep anguish while uncertainty rested upon the fate of their loved ones was pitiful and heart rending, we, with the many others extend our deepest sympathy and conolence in their sad loss. May the good God lighten their sorrow, ease their pain and give them that comfort in their distress which can only come from the higher source.</p>