<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0010.005">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>H.J. Mann v. Cynthia Mann. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie R." xml:id="nrl">Natalie R. Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Young, Cory James" xml:id="cjy">Cory James Young</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0010.005</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">H. J. Mann v. Cynthia Mann. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Eastern Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>Walla Walla County Government; Clerk, Territorial Court Civil/Criminal Case Files, 1860-1889</collection>
<idno>Case No 4980</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Mann, Bessie</term>
<term>Mann</term>
<term>Mann, Willie</term>
<term>Rhea, G. A.</term>
<term>Leplin, C. B.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Mann, H. J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Mann, Cynthia</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Leurman, Edgar</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Langford, William G.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>First Judicial District</orgName>
<placeName>Territory of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc><change when="2021-09" who="#cjy">edited</change>         
<change when="2018-11" who="#lkw">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2018-06" who="#djr">transcribed</change>
<change when="2018-06" who="#nrl">encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0010.005.001"/>

<p>In the District Court of the Territory of Washington and for the First Judicial District thereof holding terms at Wall Walla W.T.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of H.J. Mann in behalf of his infant daughter Bessie Mann for a writ of habeas corpus }</p>

<p>To the Hon. William G. Langford Judge of said Court:</p>

<p>The petition of H.J. Mann respectfully shows:</p>

<p>That Bessie Mann a female child four years of age is wrongfully detained and restrained of her liberty and from her home, and from the possession, care, custody and control of her father H.J. Mann by Cynthia Mann contrary to her will and against the will and without the consent of the said H.J. Mann</p>

<p>The cause or pretense of said restraint according to the best knowledge and belief of applicant is that said Cynthia Mann is the mother of said Bessie Mann, and is living separate and apart from her husband H.J.

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0010.005.002"/>

Mann and claims the right to hold and keep said Bessie Mann in her possession to the <unclear>obtrusion</unclear> of H.J. Mann</p>

<p>That said H.J. Mann and Cynthia Mann were joined in marriage in Morgan County in the State of Indiana on the 22nd day of January 1875 and ever since have been and now are husband and wife, and there are now living three children the issues of said <unclear>naming viz</unclear>: <unclear/> Mann, Willie Mann and Bessie and that ever since said <unclear>hearing</unclear> until about the 12th day of May 1887 the said H.J. Mann and Cynthia Mann lived and cohabitated together as husband and wife.</p>

<p>That the said Cynthia Mann is not a fit or proper person to have the care custody control and education of said Bessie Mann for the reason that said Cynthia Mann is a lewd, unchased, unvirtuous, immoral and immodest woman</p>

<p>That in or about the first day of April 1885 the said Cynthia Mann while so being the wife of the said H.J. Mann and so living and cohabitating with him, disregarding the solemnity of her marriage vows and her duties 

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0010.005.003"/>

as a wife and mother and without the knowledge consent or command of said H.J. Mann, committed the act and crime of adultery with said G.A. Rhea at the residence of said H.J. Mann and Cynthia Mann, about 21 miles west of the Town of Heppner in the County of Morrow in the State of Oregon and that at various <del></del> times thereafter at the same and other places the said Cynthia Mann did have criminal and adulterous intercourse with said G.A. Rhea</p>

<p>That your petitioner becoming aware of the lewd, criminal, and adultrous conduct of his said wife Cynthia Mann, and hoping to reclaim her there from, and to avoid further disgrace upon herself and family, removed with his said wife and children to the State of Indiana.</p>

<p>That a short time afterward and about the 12th day of May 1887 during his temporary absence from home the said Cynthia Mann without the knowledge or consent of your petitioner and against the will of their said children and in persuance of a previously made private agreement and mutual understanding

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0010.005.004"/>

 between herself and the said G.A. Rhea the said Cynthia Mann took said children forcibly and against their will away from their father and their house and carried them to the City of St Paul in the State of Minnesota and then <unclear>such</unclear> according to and in persuance of said agreement the said G.A. Rhea and there and then permitted the said G.A. Rhea to have criminal and adulterous connection and intercourse with her and did then elope with the said G.A. Rhea taking all of said children with her in the state of Oregon and while journeying on the cars to said State of Oregon did permit the said G.A. Rhea to occupy the same bed with her</p>

<p>That for the purpose of <unclear>secreting</unclear> said children from their father your petitioner, the said Cynthia Mann took said children to The Dalles in the said State of Oregon and then lived with said children for the purpose of secreting them as aforesaid and was there supported and received support from said G.A. Rhea and that all money used by said Cynthia Mann

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0010.005.005"/>

for traveling and other expenses at and from the time she left the State of Indiana as aforesaid was finished and sent to her and received by her from the said G.A. Rhea in consideration of criminal and adulterous intercourse had and agreed to be had by her with the said G.A. Rhea</p>

<p>That after spending much time  and money in search of said children, in or about the 5th day of June 1887 he found them at the City of The Dalles in the State of Oregon and then and there took two of them by hand and Willie into his possession, and eversince has had and now has them in his possession care and custody</p>

<p>That afterward and on or about the 6th day of June 1887, the said Cynthia Mann took the said Bessie Mann and carried her into the Territory of Washington, and now has said Bessie Mann in her possession in Walla Walla County in said Territory and utterly refuses to deliver her to your petitioner her father, and to his house</p>

<p>That said Cynthia Mann is now and for several months last past has been

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0010.005.006"/>

keeping house for several <unclear/> <unclear>men</unclear> on the farm of C B Leplin in said Walla Walla County, with any other women or woman in or about said premises and as your petitioner believes, is living in criminal and adulterous intercourse with various men whose names are unknown to your petitioner</p>

<p>That your petitioner is a man of sober <unclear/> and industrious habits is able, willing and in every way competent to have the care and custody of said Bessie Mann and that the interests of said Bessie Mann and the community at large demand that said Bessie Mann be taken from the possession of said Cynthia Mann and away from her lewd immoral and <unclear>licitations</unclear> influence and placed in the <unclear>security</unclear> of and rised up with her said brother and sister under the <unclear/> care of a kind and virtuous parent</p>

<p>That your petitioner believes that said Cynthia Mann will carry said Bessie Mann out of the jurisdiction of this court before compliance <del>with</del>

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0010.005.007"/>

with a writ of Habeas Corpus can be enforced</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that a warrant <unclear>may</unclear> issue to bring said Bessie Mann before said Judge to be dealt with according to law</p>

<p>Edgar Leurman atty for H.J. Mann</p>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>
