<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0001.032">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Mary E. Teller v. Franklin Teller. Petition for Divorce</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Bring Me the Body: A Digital &amp; Print History of Marginalized Habeas Corpus Petitioners in the North American West, 1804-1912</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0001.032</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Mary E. Teller v. Franklin Teller. Petition for Divorce</title>
<date></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
<note type="source">Multiple case files included with habeas petition</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Eastern Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>Spokane County Government; Clerk, Territorial Case Files, 1879-1889</collection>
<idno>Case No 2083</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Spokane County (Wash.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Teller, Mary E.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Teller, Franklin</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Graves, Frank</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Houghton, Horace E.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Fourth Judicial District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Washington Territory</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-10" who="#lkw">reviewed</change>
<change when="2017-07" who="#djr">edited</change>
<change when="2017-07" who="#djr">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0001.032.001"/>

<p>Territory of Washington County of Spokane } SS</p>

<p>In District Court of 4th Judicial District Holding Terms at Cheney</p>

<p>Mary E Teller plaintiff vs Franklin Teller Defendant</p>

<p>Plaintiff complains of defendant and for cause of action alleges:</p>

<p>That her maiden name was Mary E Dugan and that on to wit the 12th day of November A.D. 1882 she was married to defendant in said county and territory and then husband was same has remained and now is his lawful wife</p>

<p>2 That during all of their married life both she and defendant lived in said county and territory and that they both now are residents thereof</p>

<p>3 That defendant is the owner of a considerable amount of personal <unclear>property</unclear> including horses and other live stock, farming implements and growing crops on the land herein after described and has lived upon and held as a homestead the following described real estate for more than five years to wit: the south east quarter of section twenty-two (22) in town ship twenty-five

<pb facs="hc.case.0001.032.002"/>

north <unclear>west</unclear> &amp; forty (40) east and situated in the county of Spokane and Territory of Washington</p>

<p>4 That during the whole period they have been married as aforesaid plaintiff has conducted herself toward defendant as a loving and dutiful wife and fully discharged all her duties as his wife to the best of her ability</p>

<p>5 But that during aforesaid time said defendant has neglected and refused to make suitable provision for plaintiff and has left her alone on their farm aforesaid for weeks at a time without money and without provisions and that during all said time plaintiff has been obligated to support herself largely by her own labor and that during said period defendant was able to properly support defendant</p>

<p>II For a second cause of action plaintiff alleges:</p>

<p>1 That she was married at the time and place mentioned in the first cause of action of this complaint to defendant and still is his lawful wife that both defendant and she have during all said period and now do resign in said county and territory</p>

<p>2 that defendant is the owner and in possession of the property mentioned

<pb facs="hc.case.0001.032.003"/>

in the first cause of action in this complaint</p>

<p>3 That during all the said married life plaintiff has demured herself toward defendant as a dutiful and obedient wife and fully discharged toward him all her duties as such wife</p>

<p>4 That at the time of said marriage and ever since and now defendant was and is impotent and unable to have complete sexual intercourse with plaintiff and has wholly failed of his duty in that aspect as her husband</p>

<p>Wherefore plaintiff prays that the defendant be restrained from selling conveying mortgaging or otherwise encumbering and of said above described property or any other property he may have until the suit is finally disposed of that defendant be required to pay to this plaintiff a reasonable sum as counsel fees in this cause and a reasonable sum for her support during the pendency of this suit and a reasonable sum for court costs</p>

<p>That on the final <unclear>hearing</unclear> of this cause the bonds of matrimony now existing between plaintiff and defendant be dissolved that plaintiff be permitted to resume her maiden name and that one half of all said property be <unclear></unclear>

<pb facs="hc.case.0001.032.004"/>

<unclear></unclear> and designed to plaintiff</p>

<p>Houghton &amp; Graves</p>
<p>Atty for plaintiff</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>

