<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>The Territory of Washington
vs.
David Aimesworth
J.S. Danford } District Court for
the first Judicial 
District of Washington
Territory, holding terms 
at Cheney in Spokane County

David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford are
accused by the grand juries of the counties of 
Spokane and Adams, &amp; the Crime &amp; maiming
<del></del> property by false pretenses comes
written as follows: The said David Aimesworth 
and J.S. Danford on the Sixth day of September
A.D. 1884 in the county of Spokane in the District
and Territory aforesaid unlawfully knowing
designedly, and with intent to defraud one
M.H. Whitney, did falsely pretend that a
certain paper writing produced by the said 
David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford to the said
M.H. Whitney and reporting to be a bill of 
exchange drawn by the Spokane County
Bank and signed by the said David Aimesworth
as Cashier thereof, under and by the name 
of D. Aimesworth Cas which said Spokane
County Bank was then and there an <unclear></unclear>
of persons consisting of the David Aimesworth
and J.S. Danford and reporting then and 
to do a general banking business at the Town of
Cheney in the County, District and Territory of 
upon the Seaboard Bank New York for the payment
to the order of M.H. Whitney of the sum of One 
Hundred Dollars was then and there a good,
genuine and available order for payment of the 
sum of One Hundred Dollars, and was then and
there of the value of One Hundred Dollars which
said paper writing was of the ten or following then
is to say:
"No. 4065," "Cheney W.T. Sept. 6th 1884"
"Spokane County Clerk"
Pay to the order of W.J. Whitney One Hundred
Dollars,
To Seaboard Bank
#100, New York, } D. Aimesworth, Cas.
and the said David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford
did then and there unlawfully knowingly designed
and with intent to defraud the said M.H. Whitney to
pretend to the said M.H. Whitney that a certain paper
writing then and there produced by the said 
David Aimesworth and J.S. Danford to the said M.H.
Whitney and reporting to be a bill of exchange</p>
