<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0067.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Chin Chung. Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie R." xml:id="nrl">Natalie R. Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0067.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Chin Chung. Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus.</title>
<date when="1882-11-18">November 18, 1882</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term>Opium Smoking</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1882-11">November 1882</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Chin Chung</term>
<term>Green, Roger S.</term>
<term>McGraw, John H.</term>
<term>Cann, T. H.</term>
<term>Woolery, J. S.</term>
<term>Haines, J. C.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County (Wash)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Chin Chung</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Haines, J. C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Green, Roger S.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>District Court</orgName>
<placeName>Territory of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#ini">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2018-06" who="#nrl">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0067.001.001"/>

<p>#3097</p>

<p>In the District Court holding terms at Seattle in King County</p>
<p>In the Matter of the Application of Chin Chung (a Chinaman for a writ of Habeas Corpus }</p>

<p>To the Hon. Roger S. Green Chief Justice of Washington Territory and Judge of the above entitled Court.</p>

<p>The petition of Chin Chung respectfully shows:</p>

<p>That he is unlawfully imprisoned, detained <del>and</del> confined and restrained of his liberty, by John H. McGraw Sheriff of the County of King in the Territory of Washington,</p>

<p>That said imprisonment detention, confinement and restraint are illegal; and that the illegality thereof consists in this, to wit:</p>

<pb facs="hc.case.0067.001.002"/>

<note>2</note>

<p>That on the 11th day of November 1882 at Seattle in said County, before T.H. Cann, Esq., a Justice of the Peace in and for Seattle Precinct in said County a sworn complaint was made by one J.S. Woolery wherein your petitioner was charged with the alleged and pretended crime of "visiting a house kept for the " purpose of opium smoking, " and had in his possession pipes " and appliances for opium smok " ing and did visit such house " or place for the purpose of smok " ing or inhaling opium;" that upon such complaint a warrant was issued by said Justice of the Peace, upon which warrant your petitioner was arrested and brought before said Justice of the Peace; that there after such proceedings were had that on the 17h day of November 1882 your petitioner was tried before said Justice of the Peace for said alleged offense

<pb facs="hc.case.0067.001.003"/>

<note>3</note>

and upon said trial was found guilty of said alleged offense and was by the judgement of Justices Court sentenced to pay a fine of twenty five dollars</p>

<p>and in default of such payment to be committed to the County Jail of said County</p>

<p>that your petitioner failing to pay said fine <del>was</del> has been by said Court committed to said Jail, and <del/> now stands committed as aforesaid to said jail, and is in the custody of said Sheriff at said Seattle, and is restrained of his liberty as aforesaid; that said trial and commandment as aforesaid were had under and by virtue of section 2073 of the Cody of Washington; that said section is unconstitutional and void, and that said arrest, commitment and trail are therefore without any authority of law.</p>

<pb facs="hc.case.0067.001.004"/>

<note>4</note>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus may be granted, directed to the said John H. McGraw, Sheriff of said King County, commanding him to have the body said Chin Chung before your Honor at a time and place therein to be specified, to do and receive what shall then <del>be</del> and there be considered by your Honor concerning him, together with the time of cause of his detention, and said writ; and that he may be restored to his liberty</p>

<p>Date on the 18th day of November 1882</p>
<p>Chin Chung by J.C. Haines his Attorney</p>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>