<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0187.021">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
    <title>Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal.</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K" xml:id="lkw">Laura Weakly</name>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2022</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0187.021</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
    <title level="m" type="main">Marie Robina Grayson vs. Henry M. White. Criminal</title>
<date when="1914">1914</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1914-08">August 1914</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>
<term>Fishburne, George P.</term>
<term>Grayson, Marie Robina</term>
<term>Lakin, Edward M.</term>
<term>Merrick, Louis A.</term>
<term>Neterer, Jeremiah</term>
<term>Shakespeare, Noah</term>
<term>White, Henry M.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Marie Robina Grayson</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Henry M. White</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Noah Shakespeare</persName>
<persName>Louis A. Merrick</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>George P. Fishburne</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jeremiah Neterer</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
    <orgName>Western District Court of Washington, Northern Division.</orgName>
    <placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2022-02" who="#xxx">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  



<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT,
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON,
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the 
Application of MARIE ROBINA
GRAYSON, alias Marie 
Robina, for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus. )
No. 2780
PROPOSED BILL OF EXCEPTIONS.</p>
<p>Front</p>

<p>This cause came on for hearing on July 3, 1914, and 
the following stipulation was entered into in open court 
between Noah Shakespeare, attorney for petitioner, and 
George P. Fishburne, attorney for respondent, to-wit::</p>
<p>"It is agreed by the attorneys for the petitioner 
and for the respondent that they may put in a general
denial to the return to the writ or such pleading as they 
may desire, at a later date, and that such pleading may be 
considered as having been put in this morning, prior to the 
hearing, and it is further stipulated that the signing of 
the return by G. P. Fishburne, the attorney for Henry M. 
White, is a sufficient verificaition of the return, and shall 
be the same as if signed by Henry M. White, and duly 
acknowledged before a proper official with seal attached.</p>
<p>Dated July 3, 1914."</p>

<p>And the following matters set forth in the 
stenographer's report also occurred in open court:</p>

<fw>II</fw>
<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>IN RE MARIE ROBINA GRAYSON,
alias MARIE ROBINA, for 
a writ of habeas corpus )
No. 2780.</p>

<p>BY THE COURT: I understand there is no testimony 
to be offered.</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: Nothing further, Your Honor.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: The matter is submitted upon the record?</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: Yest, the matter is submitted upon 
the record. The only matter that we might show is this: There 
is one thing before the stenographer goes that I would like to
call to counsel's attention. The files of the Immigration
office show the first hearing, and to sustain the return to our 
writ, we stated in there that she was arrested on a certain
date; that she had a hearing on a certaindate; that her bond 
was given on a certain date, and that she was discharged on 
a certain date. Unless the attorneys will admit that, we will 
state that the files in the Immigration office show that. At 
these hearings, as we understand the law, all the files of 
the Immigration office there are considered as bearing on the 
issue. But I expect they will admit that.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Now, I am unable to apply the 
answer to this petition because the petition is not paragraphed 
by number, and this refers to paragraphs.</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: Your Honor, I have numbered those 
in the way they come. I intended to call the court's attention 
to that before.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Well, now we have there paragraphs 
seven, eight, nine and ten denied, and then we have the 
affirmative defense all denied, and you say there is no evidence 
to be presented.</p>
<fw>--1--</fw>
<pb/>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: The only evidence, as I
understand it, is what I am just calling your attention to 
with reference to what I understand to be the evidence in 
the files in the Immigration hearing, and that is that a 
former hearing of a person who is being deported is a part 
of the records of this hearing.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: You had better introduce teh 
former, if you have anything.</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: I thought possibly that as 
having been a part of the original hearing, the files of the
former hearing would show when the bond was given, when the
petition<add>er</add> was <add>ar</add>rested, and when she was discharged, and when 
her hearing was had, and we will state that we believe that 
the Immigration files are admissable in evidence at the 
hearing here, and in addition to that, in her testimony, 
she refers to the former hearing.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Has counsel any objection to that?</p>
<p>BY MR. SHAKESPEARE: I would object to it as being 
irrelevant to any issue in this proceeding. Now it seems to 
me to be wholly irrelevant and immaterial as to what was done
prior to the proceedings under which she is now held. That 
was a proceeding which was instituted in Oregon.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Let it stand then. I will pass upon 
it later, when I pass upon the whole question. Is there anything
else to be offered?</p>
<p>BY Mr. Fishburne: That is all on either side.
I think the attorney on the other side and myself both rely 
on the record that was taken at this hearing.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: You had better identify it so there
will be no question. Have you the record here?</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: Yes, Your Honor. Now this is 
the record: The whole of the Immigration record we offer in
evidence.</p>
<fw>--2--</fw>
<pb/>
<p>BY THE COURT: Any objections?</p>
<p>BY MR. SHAKESPEARE: No, Your Honor.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Very well, admit it.</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: That is the record of this 
proceeding, Your Honor.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Is that all?</p>
<p>BY MR. FISHBURNE: Yes.</p>
<p>BY THE COURT: Very well, you may proceed with your
argument.</p>
<pb/>
<p>The files of the former hearing were offered in 
evidence by George P. Fishburne, and by an oversight were 
not marked for identification; the Court, as appears in 
the stenographic report, did not pass on the admissability 
of said files on the morning of the hearing, but admitted 
them later. They are marked "Respondent's Exhibit Two".</p>
<p>The reply of the petitioner to the return of the 
respondent by an oversight was not filed, and is now 
filed and made a part of the record the same as if it had 
been filed immediately after the filing of the return of 
respondent.</p>
<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT,
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON, 
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the 
Application of MARIE ROBINA
GRAYSON, alias Marie 
Robina, for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus )
No. 2780
BILL OF EXCEPTIONS.</p>
<p>Front</p>

<p>This cause coming on for hearing on the 28th 
day of August, 1914, the time for the filing and settlement 
of the bill of exceptions having been extended until the 
21st day of August, 1914, I, Jeremiah Neterer, Judge of 
the United States District Court for the Western District 
of Washington, now on this 20th day of August, 1914, 
and within the term of this court during which the trial
of the above entitled cause was held and within the time to 
which the settling of the bill of exceptions was extended 
DO HEREBY CERTIFY that this cause was tried before me
without a jury; and I further CERTIFY that on this day
came on for settlement and certification the proposed bill 
of exceptions of the respondent, counsel appearing for both 
parties, and agreeing that said proposed bill of exceptions 
and the exhibits therein set forth or referred to or attached 
be settled and certified as a true and correct bill of 
exceptions in said cause;</p>
<p>And I further CERTIFY that having duly settled, and 
hereby settling and allowing, the foregoing bill of exceptions
in the above entitled action, do hereby certify the 
same and do hereby certify that this bill of exceptions, 
together with the exhibits marked "Respondent's Exhibits
<fw>-1-</fw>
<pb/>
One and Two", and the exhibits made a part of the records 
of the hearings, set forth in respondent's exhibits one and 
two, therein set forth, or referred to, and hereto attached, 
contain all the evidence, exhibits and other material 
facts, matters and proceedings in said cause not already
a part of the record herein.</p>
<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF the undersigned has hereunto set 
his hand with his title of office at Seattle in the 
Western District of Washington, Northern Division, United 
States of America, this 20th day of August, 
A.D. 1914.</p>

<ab>Jeremiah Neterer <lb/>
District Judge of the United 
States, for the Western 
District of Washington.</ab>

<p><add>August 20 - 1914</add></p>
<p><add>We hereby consent to the entry of the 
above order &amp; the order allowing 
the appeal</add></p>

<ab>Noah Shakespeare <lb/>
Louis A. Merrick <lb/>
Attorneys for Petitioner</ab>

<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>
<p>2x</p>
<p>No. 2780</p>

<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT 
OF THE UNITED STATES 
FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION</p>

<p>In the Matter of the APplication 
of Marie Robina Grayson, alias
Marie Robina, for a Writ of 
Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>BILL OF EXCEPTIONS</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. District Court, 
Western Dist. of Washington, 
NORTHERN DIVISION
AUG201914</p>
<ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk,
By Ed M Lakin Deputy</ab>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>