<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0108.015"> 
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Maria Peterson v. Levica Hamilton and Levica Hume. Petition</title> 
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Brown, Sophie A." xml:id="sab">Sophie A. Brown</name>
<name n="Battaglia, Zoe C." xml:id="zcb">Zoe C. Battaglia</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">oscys.case.0108.015</idno> 

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title>Maria Peterson v. Levica Hamilton and Levica Hume. Petition</title> 
<date/>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1889-09">September 1889</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Hume, William</term>
<term>Lundvall, Ida</term>
<term>Lundvall, Hilma</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Chehalis County, Washington</term>
<term>Montesano County, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>           
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Peterson, Maria K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Hamilton, Levica O.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Hume, Levica J.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Allyn, Frank</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Second Judicial District</orgName>
<placeName>Montesano, Washington</placeName> 
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020-11" who="#lkw">review</change>
<change when="2019" who="#sab">encoded, edited transcription</change>       
<change when="2018" who="#nl">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0108.015"/> 

<note>#181</note>

<p>In the District Court of the Second Judicial District of Washington Territory, holding terms at Montesano in and for Chehalis County</p>

<p>In the Matter of the application of Maria Kristina Peterson for writs of Habeas Corpus } Petition for writs</p>

<p>To the Hon. Frank Allyn Judge of said Court.</p>

<p>The petition of Mariah Kristina Peterson respectfully represents.</p>

<p>That she is the mother of Ida Lundvall and Hilma Lundvall, minor children, of the age of eight years and <del>five</del> seven years respectively.</p>

<p>That the said Ida Lundvall is unlawfully detained and restrained of her liberty by one Levicy O. Hamilton at the residence of the said Levicy O. Hamilton about four miles east of the City of Montesano in Chehalis County Washington Territory.</p>

<p>That the said Hilma Lundvall is unlawfully detained and restrained of her liberty by <del>one</del> William Hume and Levicy Hume his wife at the residence of the said William Hume, about four miles east of the City of Montesano in said Chehalis County and Territory of Washington.</p>

<p>That the said detention and restraint are illegal; that the illegality thereof consists in this, to wit; that the said children are not detained and restrained of their liberty upon any process issued on any final judgment of a court of competent jurisdiction, nor for any contempt of any court, officer

<pb/>

or body having authority to commit, nor upon a warrant issued from the District Court upon an indictment or information</p>

<p>That your petitioner does not know and is therefore unable to state the cause or pretense of the restraint and detention of her said Children, by the said Levicy O. Hamilton and William Hume and Levicy Hume.</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that two writs of habeas corpus may be granted; one directed to the said Levicy O. Hamilton commanding her to have the body of the said Ida Lundvall before your Honor at a time and place therein to be specified; and the other directed to the said William Hume and Levicy Hume, <del>directing</del> commanding them and each of them to have the body of the said Hilma Lundvall before your Honor at a time and place therein to be specified; to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by your Honor concerning them, together with the time and cause of their detention, and the said writs respectively, and that the said children may be restored to their liberty, and to the custody of their said mother.</p>

<p>Maria Kristina Peterson</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>