<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0088.041">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Order</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0088.041</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Order</title>
<date when="1891-05-09">May 9, 1891</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1891-05">May 1891</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Budenich, Katie McKay</term>
<term>Jones, Richard A.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McKay, Alice</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, Della</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Lichtenberg, I. J.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020-05" who="#lkw">encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#nl">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the Superior Court of King County, State of Washington.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Proceedings against Alice McKay and Katie McKay Doe, whose true name is Katie Budenich.</p>

<p>No. 5662.</p>

<p>The respondents, Alice McKay and Katie Budenich, having been brought up upon the warrant heretofore issued and the court having heard the testimony adduced on the 8th day of May, 1891, and having adjourned the further hearing of the matter until the 9th day of May, 1891, and the matter having been fully heard and considered by the court on said 9th day of May, 1891, and the respondents being present in court, the court finds the following facts:--</p>

<p>I.</p>

<p>That on the 26th day of November, 1887, the Hon. Richard A Jones, Chief Justice of the Territory of Washington, presiding at a term of the District Court of the Third Judicial District, declared Mary McKay a ward of the court, and placed her in the custody of John Keevan and Della Keevan as such ward, until the final judgment and disposition in case No. 5662, an application by Alice McKay for a writ of habeas corpus to obtain the person of said infant.</p>

<p>II.</p>

<p>That in obedience to said order said infant was in the custody of said John and Della Keevan until the 17th of April, 1891, to-wit in the city of Seattle, King County, State of Washington. That on said date said Alice McKay entered the dwelling of the parties having charge of the said ward and by force abducted said infant Mary McKay, taking her to the County of Pierce and there detaining her.</p>

<fw>1.</fw>

<pb/>

<p>III.</p>

<p>That at the time of said abduction, said case No 5662 was undisposed of. That neither the parties in charge of said ward nor the ward herself nor the Superior Court of King County had given any consent to the removal of said ward. That at the time said order constituting said infant the ward of this court was made said Alice McKay was aware of the order and had full knowledge thereof.</p>

<p>IV/</p>

<p>That in the said abduction, and taking of the said ward, said Alice McKay was assisted by her daughter, Mrs Katie Budenich.</p>

<p>Whereupon it is considered by the court that the defendants, Alice McKay and Mrs Katie Budenich, are guilty of contempt of court and they are so adjudged.</p>

<p>Wherefore it is ordered, adjudged and decreed by the court that Mrs Katie Budenish be fined for said contempt of court the sum of five dollars and that she jointly with her mother, Alice McKay, pay the costs of this proceeding, and it is further considered, ordered adjudged and decreed by the court that the defendant, Alice McKay, pay a fine of fifty dollars for said contempt and jointly with Katie Budenich pay the costs of this proceeding that they both be committed to the custody of the sheriff until the sentence of the court is complied with.</p>

<p>And it is further ordered, adjudged and decreed by the court that said Mary McKay be declared and she is hereby made the ward of this court and she is hereby committed to the care, custody and control of Della Keevan, wife of John Keevan, until the final disposition of the application of Alice McKay for a writ of habeas corpus to recover the possession of said Mary McKay now pending and undetermined in this court; said Mary McKay, ward of this court, not to be taken out of the County of King without the consent of

<fw>2.</fw>

<pb/>

the court first had and obtained and all persons are hereby enjoined from intermeddling with said ward of the court.</p>

<p>Lichtenberg</p>

<p>Judge.</p>

<p>13 May/91</p>

<p>This order to be <del>entered to</del> of force &amp; effect now <unclear>protend</unclear> on May/91</p>

<p>Lichtenberg</p>
<p>Judge</p>
<p>23 May/91</p>

<fw>3.</fw>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
