<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>An inquisition having been this 25th day
of December held upon the remains of
A.L. Beardon the following sworn test-
imony was taken as:
O.J. Royes being sworn made the following 
statement as:
   On Sunday the 21st which I was at the store
of Portch Bros at Sherman W.T. there was
present at the time Light, Frank and Henry
Beardon, R.C. Welch Howard E. Portch
and Bud White. Four of them were playing
cards and as I strepped to the store Bud
White stepped aside and got into the middle
of the floor and he then asked Frank Beardon
when did you get in? Frank answered a 
few days ago. And Bud are you 
going to pay me for that revolver you 
got off me answer by Frank yes when 
I get the money I have not go it now
Bud- you agreed to pay me in 30 days
and you did not do it you then wanted
30 days more and I let you have it out
instead of paying me you went on a tour
at the east, have you got the revolver with 
you? F. No
Bud- Where is it? Answer I left it below
" Have you any other? " I have
" Let me see it: Frank then gave him a
large revolver when Bud said I guess this
will do.
will do in place off the other it was I think a
colt revolver. Light then stepped up and
said what in the Hell are you trying to
get through you Bud. Bud answered what are 
you trying to get through you. Light then got
between Bud and the door and said Bud you
are not going to take any advantage of the Boy
meaning Frank gave him back his revolver
and I will see that you are said for it
Henry also said the same to Bud then there
was considerable swearing by all of them
Light again said give him back his Revolver
and I will stand good for it Bud said 
to I wont do it Light said he would not
take it out of the door they again commenced
to call each other names Bud then stepped
into the middle of the floor away from
Henry and stood facing Light Light shook his
fist at Bud I saw Bud draw his revolver
and said to Light of you donbt back off
I'll shoot you. I believe Light stepped to-
ward Bud and then I heard the revolver go
off Questions by the Jury Bud said he had seen
him over long enough but would not have 
it any longer. Then when struggle after 
the shooting. Bud Light Henry Frank
Light doing the most of it then they
were trying to take the Revolver from
Bud
one of them said shoot him and another said
cut him I saw frank go out to him and with
a knife saying god dam him cut him
all to pieces. Said Bud with his read to the
counter Bud said he would take it all back
to let him up I then heard Light say Boys 
I am shot. Light then said I wish I had killed
him he then started to go out of the store.
Frank came out with a revolver in his 
hand saying shoot the son of a bitch and
run down towards Shermans before he got to 
Shermans Henry got Bud into the house
In the beginning and before the shooting Bud 
had the only revolver.
E. Portch being duly sworn made the 
following statement. I was in the store at 
the time of the shooting Bud ask Frank 
when he had come back and Frank told 
him about 2 weeks ago. He ask him when
he was going to pay for the revolver that he
had bought off him and Frank said as soon
as he got the money/ Have you got a 
revolver with you? Yes. Let me see it 
and then Frank gave it to Bud who said 
that will fit the bill and I guess I will 
keep it. Frank said you need not get 
on your ear about it I'll pay you for
your revolver. Light then said give the
Revolver back to him. Bud 
</p>
