<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0088.016">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Testimony</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Young, Cory James" xml:id="cjy">Cory James Young</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0088.016</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Testimony</title>
<date when="1887">1887</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Puget Sound Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>King County Government, Judicial Administration. Territorial District Court Case Files, 1867-1889</collection>
<idno>Case No 5662</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1887">1887</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>McKay, Mary</term>
<term>Sebastine</term>
<term>Latimer</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Belltown, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McKay, Alice</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, Della</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Ronald, J. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Gilman, L. C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020-05" who="#lkw">encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#nl">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the district court of the third judicial district of Washington Territory holding terms at Seattle.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of Alice McKay to obtain the body of Mary McKay No. 5662.</p>

<p>Testimony offered on behalf of the Respondent.</p>

<p>Mrs. DELLA KEEVIN, called and sworn.</p>

<p>Q. [Gilman] Mrs. Keevin, you are one of the Respondents in this case, that is you have been ordered to bring this child into court. have you?  A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. This is the child referred to in the petition, Mary McKay or Mary Keevin?</p>

<p>A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. How long has this child been living with you?  A. Five years and three months.</p>

<p>Q. Go on and state to the judge Mrs. Keevin how the child has come to you, under what circumstances you got her?  A. There was a lady living next door to me, Mrs. Latimer, and told me that there was a child to be adopted at the sisters. so I went up to Sister Sebastine. I asked her if there was a child to be adopted. Yes, she said that there was a little girl that her mother came and asked them to take care of her: that she was left at the door. The mother told her to give it to a family.</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: We object.</p>

<p>The COURT: I will hear the lady's story.</p>

<p>A. She told me, the mother told her to give it to some good family. That she could keep her. I said I will take her. They sent and looked for the mother around town. They could not get her. They gave me the child, and I took her home. We were to take papers. She says this is my child, and she says I will bring the papers.</p>

<p>Q. Who came to you? A. Mrs. McKay?</p>

<p>Q. What did she say to you? A. She told me that she would bring the papers a week from that Wednesday.</p>

<p>Q. What did she mean by bringing the papers? A. That she would have them settled and left at the sisters. With Sister Sebastine, that she did all her business. I went down to the sisters at the time, and there was no papers, and the woman did not come near me I guess it might have been seven or eight or nine months.</p>

<p>Q. Now, at the time she came to you and told you she would give papers, did she say anything about whether or not she was willing for you to keep it as your own?</p>

<p>A. She said she was glad the child was with me because it would have a good home. She told me all her troubles about home and her husband.</p>

<p>Q. What did she tell you about them?</p>

<p>RONALD: We object to that as immaterial. This is five years ago. Now, if your Honor please, this writ of habeas corpus for the custody of the child -- they have a right if they can show this woman at the present time is unqualified, improper and morally incompetent woman. Now as to this woman five years ago, what she said to Mrs. Keevin about her home and her husband or her home, we submit in all fairness if your Honor please. It is incompetent, irrelevant and immaterial and nothing to do in this case whatever.</p>

<p>The COURT: I propose to hear this whole story, you can take your exceptions as you need them.</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: We will take an exception.</p>

<p>A. I did not know who the woman was at all, if I had I would not have had the trouble. She was sick and was crippled [referring to the little girl] She could

<fw>[Mrs. Keevin, D-EX. <gap/> 1. <gap/> 73--23.</fw>
<pb/>

could not stand up. I nursed her and everything, and I thought it a pity that the child should go back to this woman.</p>

<p>The COURT: Aske the question again. She has not answered it.</p>

<p>Q. What did she say about her home and her life at that time? A. She told me she did not know what kind of man he was, that he was married in the old country and had three children.</p>

<p>Q. When did you next see Mrs. McKay? A. She might have come twice a year. She was quite contented with the child being where she was. She has seen her every time until the last time, I said no you cannot see her. She said she did not want to see her. It is the childs own fault she gets nervous.</p>

<p>Q. Did she ever demand possession of the child of you before? A. She would say in a kind of a way, I dont know whether she would mean it or not. One time she said I will have the child when I cannot come to see her. I will have the child in the court. I thought it was all right. I did not think I would have any trouble again.</p>

<p>Q. Did she ever bring the child into court before? A. I had her here about three years ago I think.</p>

<p>Q. Now, Mrs. Keevin, has the mother during that time provided any support for the child? A. She has never given her two cents, she has given her a dollar once to my knowledge.</p>

<p>Q. Has she ever offered to? A. No, never.</p>

<p>Q. How have you treated this child since the time you took her? A. I could not tell the difference between her and mine.</p>

<p>Q. Have you any children of your own? A. Not living.</p>

<p>Q. You had a child die about the time you adopted this one? A. Yes, it was for her place I took her.</p>

<p>Q. Has she been with you continuously since that time? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. What are you doing toward educating the child, Mrs. Keevin? A. Doing all I can for her education.</p>

<p>Q. Does she go to school? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Where does she go to school? She goes to the school below our house, in Denny's school house.</p>

<p>Q. At the public schools? A. Yes Sir.</p>

<p>Q. In Seattle? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Did you ever notice Mrs. McKay's condition as regards sobriety when she would come to see the child? A. I always thought she was more or less under the influence of liquor. She knew it. I would turn pale and faint when she would

<fw>[Mrs. Keevin, D-EX. <gap/> 2. <gap/> 76 -- 29.</fw>
<pb/>

come to the door.</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: We move to strike the answer out.</p>

<p>The COURT: Motion overruled and exception allowed.</p>

<p>A. I know the smell of liquor on her breath.</p>

<p>Q. You could smell the liquor on her breath? A. Yes.</p>

<p>Q. What are your feelings toward this child, Mrs. Keevin?</p>

<p>A. My feelings are as a natural mother. If I was her mother I could say nothing more.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know of your own knowledge anything about Mrs. McKay's character other than what you have <del>heard</del> said that she was a drinking woman? A. I know nothing else except reports.</p>

<p>Q. Is it your desire to still retain the child and keep it and train it up? A. Yes sir. It would be tearing my heart out to take it away from me. now.</p>

<p>Q. What is your husband's ability financially? A. He works at plastering.</p>

<p>Q. Has he any property? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Where is it? A. We have a good home in Belltown.</p>

<p>Q. You have your home, do you? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Has he employment all the time? A. When it is scarce he works at other things.</p>

<p>GILMAN: Take the Witness.</p>

<p>CROSS-EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>Q. [Ronald:] Mrs. Keevin, how long did you have this child before Mrs. McKay came there and told you she would give papers? A. I had it about a week and a half.</p>

<p>Q. And you now swear on your oath Mrs. Keevin that Mrs. McKay told you she would give you papers? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Is it not a fact that you asked for papers and she told you she would not give them? A. She told me she would leave <sic>theg</sic> at the Sisters, or Sister Sebastine, that Sister Sebastine done her business.</p>

<p>Q. So you went to the Sisters two or three times to try and have the sisters endeavor to influence Mrs. McKay to give you papers? A. I went there to see if she had left them there. The Sisters said she would not tell the truth.</p>

<p>Q. You did not go there to try to influence Mrs. McKay? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You say you kept the child for a couple of years without objection <sic>c</sic> from Mrs. McKay, is that true Mrs. Keevin? A. It was a long time before she came around after she told me she would give the papers. The child was sick and weak and my heart went to her. I could not part with her.</p>

<p>Q. Dont you suppose her heart went to her? A. She could not--</p>

<p>Q. You dont know only what you heard. A. The sisters nursed her for nine nights.</p>

<fw>[Mrs. Keevin, C-EX. <gap/> 3. <gap/> 76--36.</fw>

<pb/>

<p>Q. Do you know anything about leaving this child at the door except what you heard? A. The sisters, sister Sebastine--</p>

<p>Q. [Interrupting] Do you know she left it at the door? A. I dont know anything at all about it.</p>

<p>Q. All you know is what some one told you about leaving it at the door? A. It was proved in the court before.</p>

<p>Q. Is that all you know about it, just what somebody told you about leaving it at the door? A. It was left at the Sisters.</p>

<p>Q. You swear that she brought it at the door step of your own knowledge? A. I wont swear any such thing.</p>

<p>Q. All you know then ---</p>

<p>The Court: It is perfectly apparent that she only knows what was told her</p>

<p>Q. Now, she has frequently asked for this child has she not? A. Never except once or twice. She told me the last day she was up there she would be revenged and this is the revenge now.</p>

<p>Q. You know she wanted this child always? A. I did not know any such thing. <del>Q</del> what would she want with her??</p>

<p>Q. You dont know then that she wanted the child. She has been there frequently?</p>

<p>A. She has never asked only to come and see the child and kiss her, and the child dont take to her.</p>

<p>Q. You have taught the child not to kiss her? A. I never told her, the child, she was her mother, because I did not think she was a reasonable woman.</p>

<p>Q. You did not want her to know she was her mother? A. No sir. I love her too much.</p>

<p>Q. Do you think it was more than a mother's love? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Were you ever a mother? A. Yes, I was.</p>

<p>Q. Do you think your love for that child is any more than a mother's love?</p>

<p>A. I always thought to love the child the same as my own.</p>

<p>Q. Is it any more than a mother's love that you have for it?</p>

<p>A. When she is sick I cannot find any rest or peace.</p>

<p>Q. Do you mean to say that you have never refused this woman to see that child but once? A. Not to my knowledge but twice in five years.</p>

<p>Q. You mean to say that you have never even sent the child out of the room when its mother was about to take it up? A. Yes, I have sent her out.</p>

<p>Q. Why did you do that Mrs. Keevin? A. Because I loved the child too much.</p>

<p>Q. You did not want the child to learn to love its mother? A. No. I did not.</p>

<fw>[Mrs. Keevin, C-EX. <gap/> 4. <gap/> 76--42.</fw>

<pb/>

<p>Q. You have been trying to make that child love you as a mother? A. I want to be the child's mother -- I thought I was.</p>

<p>Q. You did not want the child to learn to love its mother or know it? A. If <del/> she was respectable woman I would.</p>

<p>Q. You dont want the child to recognize its own sisters? A. Yes I would, I would take one of the sisters into my house, and she ought to be taken.</p>

<p>Q. You dont want the child <sic>to learn to learn</sic> to love or know its mother, or know this woman? A. I would if she was not so bad -- a good woman.</p>

<p>Q. All you know about that is what you hear? A. I have seen enough.</p>

<p>Q. Tell me what you know or seen about her. You say you have seen her drunk?</p>

<p>A. She brought a bad woman to my house and every body knows it, Mrs. Corlis.</p>

<p>Q. You are not very friendly toward Mrs. Corlis? A. I did not know the woman, except to see that she was drunk.</p>

<p>Q. When was that Mrs. Keevin? A. Some years past.</p>

<p>Q. And Mrs. McKay was drunk at that time? A. I wont say she was drunk, but she was with drunken Company.</p>

<p>Q. The other woman was drunk? A. I wont say anny one was drunk, but I always thought that they were under the influence of liquor.</p>

<p>Q. How? A. I wont say any person was drunk.</p>

<p>Q. You wont say Mrs. McKay was drunk or ever did come there drunk? A. No, I wont say it.</p>

<p>Q. Now, you say that you are sending the child to the public schools? A. Yes, I am until she is of an age to go to a better school.</p>

<p>Q. When did you commence sending her to the public schools? A. I gues s I had her a year and we taught her at home, she could go through the first reader, then we sent her to school.</p>

<p>Q. Which school? A. Next our hous.</p>

<p>Q. Public school. A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. How long did she go to the public schools? A. Four years.</p>

<p>Q. She never went to the Sisters school? A. No sir, I would not let her go so far.</p>

<p>Q. She never lived with them or went with the other one she left up here? A. No sir, not when she came to my possession.</p>

<p>Q. Now Mrs. Keevin, you got that child from the Sister's hospital? A. From the Academy.</p>

<p>Q. That is the only authority you have got for the child? A. Sister Sebastine said Mrs. McKay begged for any good woman to take charge of her.</p>

<fw>[Mrs. Keevin, C-EX. <gap/> 5. <gap/> 76--49.</fw>

<pb/>

<p>Q. That is the only authority you ever got for keeping the child? A. She had abandoned the child.</p>

<p>Q. Is that the only authroity that you have? A. I had the child at the same time and was going to adopt her.</p>

<p>Q. Answer the question, is that the only authority you have for keeping the child?</p>

<p>A. But twice I never refused her. She squeezed the child and says I am your mother, her face scared her, and she said she did not want to see that woman any more.</p>

<p>Q. So is that what made you refuse to let her see the child, because the poor mother squeezed its hand? A. That did not make the mother good.</p>

<p>Q. Because she did that? A. I would let her see her. I did not want her to come between me and the child.</p>

<p>Q. Then your only object in <sic>ekeeping</sic> this woman away from the child was to keep its own mother from coming between you and the child? A. I did not do it for that..</p>

<p>Q. What did you do it for. I told you that the child loved me and that I loved her. I did not want to let her know that she had another mother. I was afraid it might worry her.</p>

<p>Q. Were you <sic>nota</sic> afraid that the natural instincts of the child would cause it to cling to its own mother? A. I never dreamed of such a thing. She did not.</p>

<p>Q. If she did not why did not you let Mrs. McKay see her?. I was afraid she would talk too much to her.</p>

<p>Q. If you were not afraid that the child's natural instincts would cling to its own mother, why were you afraid of her talking to much to the child Why did you object to her talking to the child?. <del/></p>

<p>The COURT: She says she did it for the purpose of preventing the affection of the child going to its mother instead of herself.</p>

<p>Q. Did you not call Mrs. McKay an old brute? A. Never. I do not use such language.</p>


<fw>[Mrs. Keevin, C-EX. <gap/> 6. <gap/> 76--55.</fw>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>