<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0087.001">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Wong Sam et al. v. E. V. Rugar. Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie R." xml:id="nrl">Natalie R. Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0087.001</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Wong Sam et al. v. E. V. Rugar. Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1888-04-10">April 10, 1888</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1888-04">April 1888</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County (Wash.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sam, Wong</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Gee, Foke</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Moke</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Sam, Chin</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Zee</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Hing, Wong</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Rugar, E. V.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Quong</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Osborn, Richard</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jones, Richard A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>   
<change when="2019-01" who="#lkw">reviewed; edited</change>      
<change when="2018-01" who="#ka">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2018-06" who="#nrl">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0087.001.001"/>

<note type="curatorial">#5911</note>

<p>Territory of Washington}<lb/>
County of King} SS</p>

<p>In the District Court holding terms at Seattle</p>

<p>In the Matter of the application of Wong Sam Foke Gee Ah Moke Chin Sam Ah Zee and Wong Hing for a Writ of Habeas Corpus}</p>

<p>To the Hon Richard A Jones Chief Justice of the Territory of Washington and Judge of the Third Judicial District sitting for the trial of cause under the Laws of the United States.</p>

<p>The above named plaitiffs by Ah Quong on their behalf and on behalf of each of the said plaitiffs show unto your Honor:</p>

<p>II That each of the said plaintiffs to wit: Wong Sam, Foke Gee, Ah Moke Chin Sam Ah Zee and Wong Hing are each unlawfully imprisoned detained confined and restrained of his liberty by E.V. Rugar <del></del>

<pb/>
board the "Steamer Premier" which said steamer is now moored and lying at the wharves in the City of Seattle in said King County, and that said E.V. Rugar has so detained the said plaintiffs on said steamer for the period of about one day</p>

<p>II II That the cause or pretense of said imprisonment according to the best of the knowledge and belief of this applicant is the arbitrary will of the said Rugar and without any just or lawful cause or excuse.</p>

<p>II II II That the said above named plaintiffs are Chinese persons and are each entitled under the laws of the United States to be and remain in the United States, but that said Rugar refuses to allow the said plaintiffs to leave said steamer and go whether they please as they each by law are entitled to do.</p>

<p>II V That the said imprisonment and restrain of each of said plaintiffs by the said E.V. Rugar on board the said Steamer Premier is illegal and that the illegality thereof consists

<pb/>
in this: That each of the said plaintiffs heretofore are lawful residents of the United States, and departed from the Home and to wit about June 1884, and each received from the Collector of Customs at Port Townsend in said Territory, upon said departure a due and lawful certificate as provided by law, entitling each of said plaintiffs to reenter the United States upon producing and delivering such certificate to the collector of customes in the district</p>

<p>V That each of said plaintiffs have produced and <del/> delivered up such certificate to the said collector of customs of this district but that the said E.V. Rugar acting as Deputy Collector refuses to allow the said plaintiffs or either of them to depart from said "Steamer Premier" and now holds them imprisoned thereon and now threatens to and is about to transport each of said plaintiffs beyond the jurisdiction of this court and out of the United States</p>

<p>VI That said plaintiffs are not held

<pb/>
and imprisoned for any other or different cause or pretense than under the facts and circumstances above stated</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner on behalf of each of said plaintiffs prays that a writ of Habeas Corpus may be granted directed to the said E.V. Rugar commanding him to have the bodies of each of the said Wong Sam Ah Moke Foke Gee Chin Sam Ah Zee and Wong Hing before your Honor at a time and place therein to be specified to do and receive what shall then and there be ordered concerning him or each or either of said plaintiffs respectively and to have then and there the said writ and the said return certificates herein mentioned and make due return as to the time and cause of the detention of said plaintiffs respectfully and that each of said plaintiffs be restored to his liberty</p>

<p>Ah Quong</p>
<p>Richard Osborn</p>
<p>Attorney for Plaintiffs</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>