<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0090.010">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Sarah McDonough v. William Murphy. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
<name n="Young, Cory James" xml:id="cjy">Cory James Young</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0090.010</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Sarah McDonough v. William Murphy. Petition</title>
<date when="1888">1888</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Puget Sound Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>King County Government, Judicial Administration. Territorial District Court Case Files, 1867-1889</collection>
<idno>Case No 6006</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1888">1888</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Soderberg, N.</term>
<term>Willimsin, Georgia</term>
<term>Cochrane, William</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McDonough, Sarah</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Murphy, William</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Osborn, Richard</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jones, Richard A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Third Judicial District</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020-10" who="#lkw">reviewed; encoded</change>
<change when="2020-09" who="#nrl">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<note>#6064</note>

<p>Territory of Washington}</p>
<p>County of King} SS</p>

<p>In the District Court holding terms at Seattle</p>

<p>In Re Petition of Sarah McDunnoh for Writ of Habeas Corpus}</p>

<p>To the Honorable Richard A Jones Judge of said Court.</p>

<p>The Petitioner Sarah McDunnoh would most respectfully show unto your honor that she is now imprisoned in the Jail of King County this Territory and held and detained therein by William Cochran Sheriff of said County and has been so imprisoned and restrained of her liberty since the 4th day of June 1888.</p>

<p>That said imprisonment is illegal and unjust and is the result of passion and prejudice by one N Soderberg who was at the date of said imprisonment to wit June 4th 1888 a Justice of the Peace in and for the Seattle precinct in said

<pb/>

County and Territory.</p>

<p>That the cause or pretense of said imprisonment is shown by the docket entry of the said N. Soderberg and three warrants of commitment all issued in the one cause herein stated. The said docket entry is in words and figures as follows to wit:</p>

<p>(Docket entry)</p>

<p>Territory of Washington}</p>
<p>County of King} No 294</p>

<p>Now on this 4th day of June 1888 Mrs Georgia Willimsin files in this court written verified complaint charging defendant with committing the crime of threatening to burn down affiants dwelling house in Seattle WT on the 31st day of May 1888. On the same day the defendant is produced in court arraigned and pleads not guilty. She is now admitted to bail in the sum of $1500 Said cause is now continued in the 5th day of June 1888 at <gap/> oclock.</p>

<p>Defendant fails to give bail and is now ordered to be committed to the custody of the Sheriff King County

<pb/>

in Jail.</p>

<p>That the bail required of petitioner in said cause to wit $1500 is excessive unjust and oppression.</p>

<p>That the said N. Soderberg has in consequence of certain criminal proceedings against him in this court become disqualified to act as Justice of the Peace and is not now competent to proceed further in said cause against petitioner and is not now a Justice of the Peace.</p>

<p>That the docket containing the entry in the cause against petitioner is in the custody of this court and that said N Soderberg has no power or control over the same.</p>

<p>That by reason of the premises the said N. Soderberg has lost all jursidiction over petitioner and she cannot now be legally held or imprisoned by any order of commitment issued by him</p>

<p>That petitioner is poor old infirm and in very feeble in body and mind and is not guilty of the charge made against her</p>

<p>Wherefore petitioner most</p>

<pb/>

<p>The last above from the words "Docket Entry" is a true file and complete copy of the entries in said cause in the docket of the said N Soderberg</p>

<p>That there are three different and seperate warrants of commitment issued in said cause and <unclear>delivered</unclear> to the said William Cochran, of which said warrants of commitments true full and complete copies are hereto attached and respectively marked Exhibit "A" "B" and "C" and are hereby made a part of this petition.</p>

<p>That the illegality of said imprisonment consists in the following</p>

<p>That said N. Soderberg has failed and refused to proceed in said alleged cause against petitioner, as by law directed: that he has failed and refused to give to this petitioner a trial and hearing in said cause. That petitioner has never asked for a continuance of said cause and no reason or cause has existed to prevent such <unclear>hearing</unclear> within a reasonable time except a desire on the part of the said N. Soderberg to keep petitioner

<pb/>

humbly prays this Honorable Court that a writ of Habeas Corpus may be granted directed to the said William Cochoran Sheriff as aforesaid commanding him to have and produce the petitioner in person before your honor at a time and place to be dissignated to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by your Honor concerning petitioner together with the time and cause of detention of petitioner and that petitioner be restored to her liberty and that she have such other further and general relief as to your Honor may seems just lawful and equitable</p>

<p>Sarah McDunnoh her X mark </p>

<p>Richard Osborn</p>
<p>Atty for Petitioner</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>