<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0083.009">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Elnora Cline by B. M. Cline v. Ella Cline. Return of Writ of Habeas Corpus from Defendant</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie R." xml:id="nrl">Natalie R. Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Young, Cory James" xml:id="cjy">Cory James Young</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0083.009</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Elnora Cline by B. M. Cline v. Ella Cline. Return of Writ of Habeas Corpus from Defendant</title>
<date></date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Puget Sound Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>King County Government, Judicial Administration. Territorial District Court Case Files, 1867-1889</collection>
<idno>Case No 5349</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1887-05">May 1887</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Gilman, Luthene Claremont</term>
<term>Lewis</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County (Wash.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Cline, Elnora</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Cline, B. M.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Cline, Ella</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Peterson, Fred H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jones, Richard A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Third Judicial District</orgName>
<placeName>Territory of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019-01" who="#lkw">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2018-06" who="#nrl">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0083.009.001"/>

<p>In the District Court, holding terms at Seattle in King County, Washington Territory.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of Elnora Cline by B.M. Cline, her father for a writ of Habeas Corpus} No. 5349. Return to writ</p>

<p>To the Honorable Richard A. Jones, Judge of said Court:</p>

<p>The Respondent, Ella Cline, for a return to the writ served on her in this proceeding, respectfully shows to your Honor:</p>

<p>I.</p>
<p>This respondent denies that the said Elnora Cline is by her restrained of her liberty or that the said Elnora Cline is restrained of her liberty at all.</p>

<p>II.</p>
<p>This Respondent denies each and every allegation contained in the third paragraph petition of the petitioner herein, except that she left her home in Sidney, Kitsap County, on or about the 15th day of April, A.D. 1887 and came to Seattle for the purpose of procuring medical attendance and that she has remained in said Seattle ever since, and except that she has said Elnora Cline in her custody and insists upon retaining her therein.</p>

<p>III.</p>
<p>And this respondent further avers that she is legally and rightfully entitled to the custody of said Elnora Cline; that she is the mother of said Elnora Cline, and as such mother she claims that she has the right to the custody and possession of said child. That said Elnora Cline is <unclear>a sick and</unclear> an infant of tender years, to wit: of the age of

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0083.009.002"/>

four years, and is now in delicate health, and is of a frail constitution, and constantly requires a mother’s attention and constant care and nursing, and said child is liable to sicken and die if taken from this Respondent, its mother and placed in the care of strangers. That she said Elnora Cline is the only child of this respondent, and this respondent is deeply attached to her, as is also said child to this respondent. That this respondent has and can procure the means to properly support, maintain and educate said child, and can and will do so. That said child has not been placed under any restraint, illegal or <del/> otherwise by this respondent or any other person, and the said father has ever been and now is at perfect liberty to visit said child and to exercise all his parental rights over the same, this respondent only requiring that said child be allowed to live with her and that she be allowed to care for and protect her And this respondent further avers that she has not deserted or abandoned her said husband, nor has she without cause refused to live with him. That for more than one year last past, this respondent has been in delicate health from female troubles and has sought medical advice from her attending physician, Dr….. Baker of the City of Seattle, by whom she was advised that it was absolutely necessary in order to preserve her life and health that she refrain absolutely from cohabitation with her said husband, and for the purpose of being treated for her said sickness and following the advice

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0083.009.003"/>

of her said physician, she came to Seattle to live, bringing her said child with her, all of which was done with the knowledge and by the consent of her said husband. That when this respondent left her said home, she then intended and she now intends to return to her said home, as soon as her health will permit, provided her said husband desires and will allow her so to do, but her said husband has since she has come to Seattle stated to this respondent that he did not desire to and would not live with her again and that he intended to get a divorce from her, and has endeavored by threats to induce her to give up her said child, Elnora Cline, and on one occasion forcibly and <choice><sic>vioently</sic><corr>violently</corr></choice> took said child from her possession and attempted to abscond with he and was only prevented from so doing by the interposition of the officers of the law.</p>

<p>That this respondent by reason of her being the mother of said child and from the fact of its tender years, <del/> and delicate health is better fitted and qualified to have the custody of said child than any other person. And your respondent avers that by reason of this foregoing facts stated in this return, she is legally and rightfully entitled to the custody of said child, Elnora Cline, nevertheless, she here produces the body of said Elnora Cline, before the Court, in <choice><sic>obdience</sic><corr>obedience</corr></choice> to the writ issued herein, and prays that this Honorable Court will remand said child to her custody.</p>

<p>Lewis &amp; <unclear>Gilman</unclear></p>
<p>Attorney for Respondent.</p>

<p>Ella Cline</p>
<p>Respondent.</p>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>