<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0177.007">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Tonka Bajlo vs. United States. Affidavit of Ivan Skorich</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Paredes" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0177.007</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Tonka Bajlo vs. United States.  Affidavit of Ivan Skorich</title>
<date when="1913-04-15">April 15, 1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-04">April 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Bajlo, Jack</term>
<term>Bilin, Paska</term>
<term>Fisher, Thomas M.</term>
<term>Skorich, Ivan</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Bajlo, Tonka</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Ennis, Charles H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName> 
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
        
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#lkw">review</change>       
<change when="2021-10" who="#rp">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>EXHIBIT D</p>

<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Tonka Bajlo for the Writ of
Habeas Corpus. )</p>

<p>2459
No. 1328</p>

<p>AFFIDAVIT OF IVAN SKORICH</p>

<p>STATE OF WASHINGTON
COUNTY OF KING ) ss.</p>

<p>Ivan Skorich being first duly sworn on oath deposes
and says: that I live at 815 Charles Street, Seattle, Washington;
that I am a laborer by occupation and work wherever I can obtain
work and at the present time am not doing anything; that Paska 
Bilin is my partner in paying for and keeping the house expenses
paid up at 815 Charles Street; that we have as our housekeeper
and cook in our employ Tonka Bajlo; that she has been in our 
employ since the first of February; that we agreed to pay her 
and do pay her the sum of $10.00 per month and her board and
her lodging; that we have paid her this amount because she has
been sickly, and unable to do the work part of the time; that we
had two borders who slept in a separate room apart from Paska
Bilin and myself. We had the middle room and Tonka Bajlo slept 
in the front room which faces directly on the street; that there
are two entrances to the house, one to the middle bedroom which
leads to a sort of an alley and the other to the kitchen which 
leads to the street in front along on the East side of the house; 
that the house is above grade and we have to go up steps to get
into it; that we pay $10.00 a month for the house.</p>
<p>That I testified in the hearing had before Thomas M. 
Fisher, Inspector and Examiner, on April 7, 1913, Seattle, 
Washington, and the testimony alleged to have been given by me
is as follows:</p>

<pb/>

<p>Q. "How long have you know her? (referring to Tonka 
Bajlo.) A. About a year."</p>
<p>Q. "Where was she living when you first knew her? A. She 
used to live at 917 Addition Street between 9th and 10th Streets."</p>
<p>Q. "Who was she living with there? A. Living there
with a crowd of men."</p>
<p>Q. "Which particular one was she living with if you
know? A. She was living with a fellow by the name of Paska
Bilin."</p>
<p>Q. "Did she sleep with him? A. I don't know."</p>
<p>The answers wherein I have been made to state that
she was "living with a crowd of men" and "she was living with
a fellow by the name of Paska Bilin," have been misinterpreted
by the interpreter. What I did say and meant to say was that
she was living at this boarding house as cook and housekeeper
and that Paska Bilin was at the head of the boarding house.</p>
<p>I never heard any one say that they had slept with
her, nor have I ever heard any one say anything against her
character until this hearing on April 7, 1913; that while at
my house she was sickly and unable to do much work; that I 
have heard her state that her husband was very cruel to her
and often beat her and had injured her health and that she
could not live with him because he beat her so much; that I 
do not believe there was ever anything wrong between Paska
Bilin and Tonka Bajlo, and I never heard from any of the
boys that anything ever existed between her and any of the
men boarders; that on or about the first week in February,
1913, Jack Bajlo came to my house at 815 Charles Street and 
broke in the door and I refused to let him in the house and
he went away, and he came back two or three times after that
and I refused to let him in the house because Tonka Bajlo had
told us that her husband said he would kill her.</p>
<p>The house we lived in has a kitchen which connects
directly with the room used as a bedroom by the two boarders and

<pb/>

Paska Bilin, and this room has a door leading into the middle
bedroom which I occupied alone. This room has an outside
door and a door leading to the front bedroom occupied by
Tonka Bajlo.</p>
<ab>Ivan Skorich</ab>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this 15th day of April, 1913.</p>
<ab>Chas. H. Ennis.<lb/>
Notary Public in and for the State 
of Washington, residing at Seattle.</ab>

<note>copy</note>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>