<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0088.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Young, Cory James" xml:id="cjy">Cory James Young</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0088.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Type of document</title>
<date when="1887">1887</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Puget Sound Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>King County Government, Judicial Administration. Territorial District Court Case Files, 1867-1889</collection>
<idno>Case No 5662</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1887">1887</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Farren</term>
<term>Patros, Antone</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McKay, Alice</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, Della</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Ronald, J. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Gilman, L. C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020-05" who="#lkw">encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#nl">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Mr.. FARREN a witness called on behalf of the Respondent, after being duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>Q. [Gilman] Where do you reside? A. Tacoma.</p>

<p>Q. What is your business A. Policeman.</p>

<p>Q. How long have you been on the police force? A. I have been on the police force since the 25th of last May.</p>

<p>Q. <del/> Do you know the petitioner in this case? A. Yes.</p>

<p>Q. How long have you known her? A. I have known her something a little over six years, going on seven years.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know what her character and habits are with reference to sobriety?</p>

<p>A. Well, I have seen her drunk several times.</p>

<p>Q. Where have you seen her drunk? A. Tacoma.</p>

<p>Q. In what part of the streets, or in the house, or where? A. In the street.</p>

<p>Q. Did you ever have occasion to arrest her for drunkenness? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. When? A. Along in June. I helped arrest her.</p>

<p>Q. What was she doing at that time, how conducting herself? A. She was drunk and disorderly.</p>

<p>Q. Have you at any other time seen her drunk on the public streets in Tacoma?</p>

<p>A. I have I think seen her twice before that.</p>

<p>Q. Within what time? A. Within the last seven years.</p>

<p>Q. And this was within the last year that you arrested her for drunkenness?</p>

<p>A. Sometime last June, I could not exactly say.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know where she is living? A. Yes, I know the.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know who she is living with? A. I know the house where she is living.</p>

<p>Q. Who lives in the same house? A. Antone Patros, I believe is his name -- that he goes by.</p>

<p>Q. What kind of a looking man is he? A. He is heavy set man, a man I should judge would weigh 185 pounds.</p>

<p>Q. Have you seen him in the Court room this morning? A. I have.</p>

<p>Q. Is he such a man as Mr. Hopkins described in his testimony?</p>

<p>Mr. RONALD: We object.</p>

<p>The COURT: Describe him yourself Mr. witness.</p>

<p>A. He is a man I suppose -- I dont know that he is taller than I am, but he is as tall as I am and considerably heavier, dark curly hair, moustache.</p>

<fw>[Farren, D-EX. <gap/> 12. <gap/> 76--85.</fw>

<pb/>

<p>Q. He is black, is he not? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. They are <del/> occupying the same house? A. They are living under the same roof.</p>

<p>Q. What is Antone's business, do you know? A. I have known him seven years and I never knew him to do anything but gamble. He did run some fish nets for a while. He never worked at them.</p>

<p>CROSS-EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>Q. [Ronald] You are a policeman now? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Did you ever know Antone to do anything but gamble? A. That is all I ever knew him to do.</p>

<p>Q. Did you ever arrest him for it? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Why did you not? A. Never got orders to arrest him.</p>

<p>Q. But you would arrest this poor woman, would you? A. That is what I am on the police force for.</p>

<p>Q. You are not on the police force to arrest gamblers? A. I arrest them whenever the chief orders me to.</p>

<p>Q. The Chief ordered you to arrest this woman? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. How came you to arrest her? without orders? A. I have orders to arrest all drunken and disorderly.</p>

<p>Q. But gamblers you have orders to let alone? A. No orders for gamblers at all.</p>

<p>Q. You have orders to enforce the ordinances have you? A. I have.</p>

<p>Q. Is not that against the city ordinances? A. I think it is.</p>

<p>Q. Why dont you enforce it? A. They have given no orders.</p>

<p>Q. Did you take an oath when you went on the police force? A. I did.</p>

<p>Q. An oath to enforce the ordinances of the city? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Well sir you have not lived up to your oath, have you? A. I have lived up to it the best I knew how.</p>

<p>Q. You have deliberately allowed gamblers to go without arresting them have you? A. We had no orders.</p>

<p>Q. You deliberately allowed them to do it? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. In the face of the oath you have taken, do you consider sir that you have done your duty? A. I consider I have.</p>

<p>Q. You consider that you are perfectly an honest man after all that? A. I consider I am.</p>

<fw>[Farren, C-EX. <gap/> 13. <gap/> 76--90.</fw>

<pb/>

<p>Q. You have no prejudice against this woman? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Still on the police force? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Still you let gamblers alone. Why dont you go before the grand jury and have the men indicted? A. I had no occasion to.</p>

<p>Q. Do the gamblers pay you anything per month sir? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You just let them go for mere honesty's sake? A. I am paid by the city</p>

<p>Q. You never gamble yourself? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Now sir, how did you come to come to Seattle? A. I was subpoenad here.</p>

<p>Q. Who subpoenad you? A. I dont exactly know <sic>the the</sic> man's name. I dont remember that now.</p>

<p>Q. Would you know him if you say him? A. He said he was a deputy Sheriff I think that his name was Coombs.</p>

<p>Q. How much do they pay you for coming here? A. Well, I was not paid <sic>anytring</sic> for coming here yet.</p>

<p>Q. Have you been promised pay? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You say she and Antone lives under the same roof? In the same house.</p>

<p>A. Under the same roof.</p>

<p>Q. You and <sic>mMurphey</sic> arrested <del/> her did you? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Arrested her for drunkenness? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. You know she was drunk? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. You dont know that that woman has been working hard for a living for the last two or three years? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You do not. A. No sir.</p>

<p>REDIRECT EXAMINATIOn:</p>

<p>Q. [Gilman] You are a mere subordinate, you could not control the Chief of Police? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>The COURT: If we were to invertigate all the officers for not prosectuing all criminals, we would commence at home.</p>

<p>----0----</p>

<fw>[Farren, RD-EX. <gap/> 14. <gap/> 76--96.</fw>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
