<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Territory of Washington
County of Spokane}ss
In the District Court of the 4th
Judicial District holding terms
at county seat of Spokane County

Territory of Washington
vs. Plaintiff
Ray Raymond Defendant
Territory of Washington
Spokane County}ss I Thomas C. Griffiths being
first duly sworn state: I am one of th attorneys of the
defendant Ray Raymond in this cause and have
been such attorney since the charge was first made
against Defendant June 26, 1886 and have had
principal charge of the case for her, I believe the de-
fendant cannot have a fair trial in this cause in
this county of Spokane on account of and owing
to the prejudice and entitlement of the in-
habitant, against her. That among other reasons
and sufficient reasons for such belief and as
showing such indictment and buy in this I state
the following truth:
It has been stated throughout the county that
at time of the killing of such defendant was a 
common woman of the town and the keeper of 
brothel known in the "Bay Window" situated
on Fourth Street in the city of Spokane Falls in this
county, and that she was an unusually bad, dan-
gerous and horrednous woman of her kind
and very handy and wonton in the use
of firearms, all of which but alley actions of her very
dangerous and quarrelsome, or applicant, from his
own knowledge believes to be untrue, and that
from such statements, being to him and representedly
made a general belief in the truth thereof seems
to exist among the inhabitants of the city
of Spokane Falls and of this county generally,
and then statements and the belief in their truth
have tended greatly to excite the purposes of the people
of the county against the defendant. That at the
time of the killing <del>known</del> and ever since, it
was and has been repeatedly affirmed, and
states that therefore Defendant has
murdered her husband, and has also mur-
dered two men and one woman in Mon-
tana and as perilously and repeatedly, have their
statements been made there against belief in
their truth appears to be made the people of
the county, and affiace has conversed with 
many people of the county who believe such
charges and repeat them as true, that each and
all of said statements and charges are untrue
as affitant verily believes and affiant has
has a letter from the prisoner to us bond of
defendant since that killing and knows
he was there and believes he is now alive,
that the presentation of these statements and
their general belief has tended greatly to prejudice
the people of this county against defendant
and to incite and influence the perceptions of the people
of the county.
At the time immediately following the killing and before
the coroner's inquest, and while the deceased man Finch
lay dead in the hallway of the "Bay Windows" and de-
fendant was a close prisoner therin and in a bed
under constant charge of a  
</p>
