<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0177.014">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Tonka Bajlo vs. United States. Brief of Government</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Paredes, Rosalia" xml:id="rp">Rosalia Paredes</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2021</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0177.014</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Tonka Bajlo vs. United States.  Brief of Government</title>
<date when="1913-05-10">May 10, 1913</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1913-05">May 1913</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Bilin, Paska</term>
<term>Crosby, Frank L.</term>    
<term>Miler, Joe</term>
<term>Skorich, Ivan</term>
<term>Miler, Mari</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Austria</term>
<term>Europe</term>
<term>Pittsburg, Pennsylvania</term>
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Bajlo, Tonka</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>United States</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Riddell, C. F.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Brockway, E. B.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>United States District Court, Western District of Washington, Northern Division</orgName>
<placeName>King County, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2021-11" who="#lkw">review</change>       
<change when="2021-10" who="#rp">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  


               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>
<p>UNITED STATES DISTRICT COURT
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON
NORTHERN DIVISION.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the Application
of Tonka Bajlo for the Writ of
Habeas Corpus.</p>
<p>No. 2459</p>

<p>BRIEF OF GOVERNMENT.</p>

<p>If the Court has not already, either in connection 
with this case, or the accompanying habeas corpus case of
Marie Miler, examined the following statutes and cases, we
respectfully ask that he glance through them, where he will
find the legal principles governing this case more clearly
stated than I could hope to do.</p>

<p>Act of February 20, 1907, as amended by Act of March 26,
1910, Sections 20, 21 and 22;
DeBruller v. Gallo, 184 Fed. 566, and cases there cited;
United States v. Ju Toy, 198 U. S. 253, 49 L.Ed. 1040;
Chin You v. United States, 208 U. S. 8, 52 L.Ed. 369;
Bottlier v. Donseuguey, 130 U. S. 238;
Zakonaite v. Wolf, 226 U. S. Sup. Ct. Rep., 272.</p>

<p>The record in this case under the principles there laid 
down presents the following questions for determination by
the court:</p>

<p>I.</p>
<p>Was there anything "unfair", arbitrary or despotic in
the executive proceedings under which the alien has been
ordered deported? The only matters in which it is claimed
that there was any unfairness are the following:</p>
<p>(a) The warrant of arrest gave prostitution as the ground

<pb/>

for deportation, while the findings of the officer
gave in addition the commission prior to immigration
of an offense involving moral turpitude, and liability
at time of entry to become a public charge; and the 
finding fo the Secretary of Commerce, included in the 
warrant of deportation, is based upon prostitution and 
liability at time of entry to become a public charge.</p>
<p>(b) The findings of the local officer to the Secretary, included
in the report on which the Secretary acted, stated
a material conversation with the alien in which she 
admitted illicit relations with other men and also his
judgment that she was a prostitute, based in part on
his observation of the condition of her room.</p>
<p>(c) Errors in translation of the evidence embodied in the 
return on which the Commissioner of Labor acted.</p>

<p>II.</p>
<p>Was there any evidence on which the findings of the 
Commissioner could be based, or were they clearly without 
foundation, arbitrary and despotic?</p>
<p>The vice of petitioner's whole brief is an assumption
that the proceedings are a trial on a criminal charge or
analagous thereto, and that similar rules will prevail.
The requirement of the law is merely this — that the
Commissioner shall be "satisfied" that the alien is subject 
to deportation. No manner in which he shall so satisfy 
himself is laid down. If, as in this case, by his decision 
he announces that he is satisfied, that ends the matter
unless it clearly appears that his alleged "satisfaction" 
is an unfair, arbitrary and despotic thing, arrived at without
giving the alien any fair opportunity to show the facts.</p>
<p>See statutes and cases cited at beginning of brief.</p>
<fw>-2-</fw>
<pb/>

<p>I. (a)</p>
<p>Applying these principles to the alleged unfair procedure
in failing to include in the warrant the commission of
crime before entry and liability to become a public charge
at that time, we see at once that unless it appears that the
alien was unfairly deprived of some opportunity by this
fact, no review will lie. This is not a case of indictment
where every thing must be pleaded. It is not even
like a civil case at law, though there a pleading will
in this state be considered as amended to correspond with 
the facts. It is a summary proceeding and unless essentially
unfair methods have been adopted, the writ will not lie. 
Obviously there is nothing essentially unfair in deporting
an alien for matters brought out at the hearing at which
she was present, and where she was given an opportunity 
to have counsel and present any and all matters she might 
have, even though such matters were not known to the officers
when the investigation started and hence were not included
in the formal warrant for her arrest. The technical rules
of criminal pleading cannot be injected into this procedure.</p>
<p>For a further reason petitioner's objection in this
respect must fail. The order of deportation and the warrant 
of Commissioner on which he expresses his satisfaction 
recited that the alien is one found practicing prostitution,
sufficient in itself to justify deportation, and the very
ground stated in the original warrant (page 5 of Record
included in return). Therefore, even though the Secretary 
had no authority to consider anything else, yet the fact
that he did so, would be immaterial, since his action
within the limits of his admitted authority justifies the
holding of the alien and her deportation.</p>
<fw>-3-</fw>
<pb/>

<p>I. (b)</p>
<p>Was it proper for the inspector to include as a part
of his return to the Secretary of Labor, his personal
observation and conversation with the alien? Most certainly
it was. He would have been derelict in his duty had he 
not done so. And it was proper for the Secretary to consider
such matter in reaching his conclusion. The alien had a 
full opportunity to explain her relations with the men in 
the house and the circumstances surrounding her residence
there. The matters referred to in the inspector's report
were fully gone into at the hearing, and she denied that
there was anything immoral in relation thereto. Nevertheless
it was eminently fair and proper that the inspector
state his ideas in which he had gained from personal conversation
and observation. Of course in a court of law he 
would have been sworn to these matters, but these proceedings 
were not in a court of law, and where the alien has been 
given a change to show her version of the facts it is
obviously not improper or unfair for the inspector to include
his own personal observations in the report.</p>
<p>I. (c).</p>
<p>Is the report submitted to the Secretary unfair and
distorted in that a material part of the statements were
omitted or distorted by the interpreter? It may be admitted
that since the decision of the Secretary is the 
vital matter in these proceedings, any substantial discrepancy
in the report, by which the Secretary is misled 
as to material matter, is a very serious charge, not only 
as to the fairness of the hearing, but also against the
local officers personally, and a charge not to be inferred
<fw>-4-</fw>
<pb/>

unless its truth is firmly established. These matters are:</p>
<p>(1) That Tonka is reported as saying that she worked for
$2.00 per month, while by her affidavit she says that
her statement showed $2.50 and $5.00 per month from
each of several men. Your Honor well knows how frequently 
a witness will fail to express on the stand all that
he has on his mind. This is clearly such a case, but 
even if the witness did say what she now claims she
meant to say, we fail to see how she has been injured. 
Vaska Belen, or Joe Miler, to use his English name, 
testified to practically the same thing (Record p.22).
However the question as to whether she received $2.50
or $10.00 per month in addition to her board is entirely 
immaterial in determining whether she was a prostitute
or liable at time of entry to become a public charge.
It would not even be evidence on which to grant a new
trial in criminal action — much less will its 
accidental misinterpretation (if indeed it was misinterpreted)
justify habeas corpus in this proceeding.</p>
<p>(2) The alien now says that she did not have an illegitimate
child before marriage. She denies this child in her 
affidavit, but she does not deny having said so at the
hearing. But if she means her affidavit in that
particular to deny also her statement  to the effect at
the hearing, then as she herself points out, it was
corrected by her husband's subsequent testimony where 
he says (p. 18) that Tonka's only illegitimate child
(the one that died) was born during her marriage. However,
the exact number of illegitimate children which 
she has borne, and particularly whether she had one
over twelve years ago is entirely immaterial, and could
<fw>-5-</fw>
<pb/>

not have influenced the Secretary in his decision.</p>
<p>(3) That she did not state at the hearing that she wanted
to go back to Austria to her children. This also is
immaterial. Her wishes could have had nothing to do
with the decision of the Secretary, as to whether she
was a prostitute. If anything, her wish to go back 
to her children would indicate that she was not a prostitute.
But her deportation could in no manner hinge
on her wish, and therefore her statement, even if mistranslated
was entirely immaterial.</p>
<p>(4) Was affiant's waiver of counsel misinterpreted in the
report? We respectfully contend that it was not. The
report (p. 17) shows that she stated that she waived such 
right. In her affidavit she only says that she did
not mean to waive her right to counsel if she could get 
one. There is nothing in the record to show that any
different interpretation was ever put on her answer.
Indeed, the fact is that as soon as she obtained counsel
he was shown every consideration by the Department. 
But the officers were under no obligation to themselves
employ counsel for her. The answer in the record is
obviously just what she stated since it fairly states
what she now says she meant to say.</p>
<p>(5) The alleged misinterpretation referred to in the
affidavit of Ivan Scarich is obviously only a case 
where the witness when on the stand did not fully
express himself and afterwards thinks that he said
everything that he then had in his mind. At any rate
the full interpretation of his testimony (p. 20 of the
<fw>-6-</fw>
<pb/>

(record) does not leave room for any misconception as
to the meaning of the phrases objected to in the 
affidavit. He now objects to being reported as saying
that Tonka was living "with a crowd of men", and "living 
with a fellow by the name of Paska Belin", on the
ground that he did not say she was living with them in
any improper relation. His further testimony shows that
the language of the report, even if not <add>an</add> absolutely
correct translation, could not have prejudiced the
alien, for such further testimony was to the effect
that the witness did not know of any improper relations
between her and the borders. His testimony in the
report, taken as a whole, is the same as his affidavit
as to what he actually meant to testify.</p>
<p>II.</p>
<p>Was there any evidence to justify the finding on the
Secretary that the alien was:</p>
<p>A. One found practicing prostitution after entry:</p>
<p>B. One likely to become a public charge at the time
of entry.</p>
<p>On the first point is the evidence and record showed or
tended to show that prior to her entry and after her
marriage and while her husband was living in America she 
had an illegitimate child; that after reaching America, she
went out with another man under such circumstances as to 
provoke an assault from her husband; that within a year
after landing she deserted her husband in Pittsburg to
follow another "gentleman friend" to Seattle; that for the
past year she has been living in Seattle in the same house
<fw>-7-</fw>
<pb/>


with him and other men under circumstances and with sleeping
accomodations difficult to reconcile with any feelings of
modesty; that she has received a love letter addressed to 
her as "wife" from another one of the boarders; that she
is now, and for years has been suffering from a disease,
the result of gonorreheal infection; that about the time
of her arrest she declared to her husband in the presence of
a witness that she would practice prostitution if she
wished to do so. In addition to this the report shows that 
she expressly stated to the inspector that she was living 
with a certain man as his wife and that she had been
intimate with numerous other men and that from all the
surroundings in her room, etc., he had no doubt but that
she was a prostitute. There was also a good deal of 
hearsay evidence about several other men having told the
husband that she was a prostitute. While this last would 
not be admitted in a court of law in this country, it was
proper enough in a summary proceeding of this sort. Indeed
it we may credit the newspaper accounts of foreign trials
it would have been entirely proper in a criminal trial under
the Code Napoleon. It was not unfair or arbitrary to consider
it and give it such weight as it may be entitled to.</p>
<p>We do not care and do not need to argue that all these
matters tend strongly to show that the alien is a prostitute. 
Their weight is in no manner for this court. There being
evidence on which to base the finding it can not be considered
as purely arbitrary and must stand.</p>
<p>On the second point as to the probability of the alien
becoming a public charge at time of entry, we find the
following additional facts. She had for years been suffering 
<fw>-8-</fw>
<pb/>

from a venereal disease; her husband and his relatives
had abused and mistreated her and her minor children;
nevertheless they left them in Europe, presumably because
there was no money to bring them along; at the time of her 
entry with her husband he was just out of an insane asylum
where he had been confined for several years and was of
 such a jealous and brutal nature that it was almost certain
 that a violent clash would result with her loose sexual nature
and that the normally to be expected thing has now happened, 
to-wit: her elopement with another man, subsequent illness,
prostitution and inability to earn enough to pay her bills. 
If the alien is not now a public charge she is evidently
on the verge of becoming one, and everything that has
happened was certainly in exact line with the reasonable
probabilities attending the circumstances of her entry. 
There is certainly nothing arbitrary or unfair in such a 
finding.</p>
<p>We do not discuss the positive proof of adultery before
entry showing that the alien had at that time committed
an offense involving moral turpitude since the Secretary
did not see fit to base his order of deportation thereon.
But in view of counsel's argument we cannot forbear the
suggestion that if sexual intercourse of a married woman 
with a man other than her living husband is not considered
as both adultery and an offense involving moral turpitude
among every people under the canopy of heaven, then we have
entirely misread both history and law.</p>
<p>Nor do we consider the affidavits submitted for the 
first time with the brief tending to show the husband's 
cruelty, or how promiscous living of men and women under the
<fw>-9-</fw>
<pb/>

same roof may be regarded by foreigners. These matters in
no manner effect fairness of the hearing before the
Department, or the fairness of the ruling of the Secretary, 
and therefore are not properly before this court for consideration. 
We will only say that if they are true we hope 
that the husband also may be deported.</p>
<p>Respectfully submitted,</p>
<ab>C. F. Riddell<lb/>
United States Attorney.</ab>
<ab>E B Brockway<lb/>
Assistant United States Attorney.</ab>

<pb/>

<note>2x</note>

<p>No. 2459</p>
    
<p>IN THE DISTRICT COURT
OF THE UNITED STATES
FOR THE 
WESTERN DISTRICT OF WASHINGTON</p>

<p>In the Matter of the 
Application of Tonka
Bajlo for the Writ of
Habeas Corpus.</p>

<p>Brief of Government.</p>

<p>FILED IN THE 
U. S. District Court, 
Western Dist. of Washington.</p>
<p>May 10, 1913</p>    
<ab>FRANK L. CROSBY, Clerk,
By EML Deputy</ab>
</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>