<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Territory of Washington
County of Spokane}ss
In the District Court of the
Territory of Washington and for the fourth Judicial
District thereof, holding terms at the county
seat of Spokane County.
In the matter of the
application of Ray 
Raymond for a writ 
of Habeas Corpus}
To E.F. Whittier, Sheriff of Spokane County
Greeting:
In the name of the United States you are 
hereby commanded that you have the body 
of Ray Raymond by you imprisoned and
detained as it is said, together with the time
and cause of such imrpisonment and
detendtion, by whatsoever name said Ray 
Raymond shall be called or charged before
Hon. George Turner Judge of the District Court
of the Fourth Judicial District of Washington
Territory, holding terms at the county seat
of Spokane County, in said Territory at
his chambers in Spokane Falls, Washington 
Territory, on Tuesday the 6th day of July
A.D. 1886 at the hour of one o'clock P.M. to
do and receive what shall then and there
be ordered concerning the said Ray 
Raymond and have you then and
there this writ.
Witness the Hon. George Turner
Associate Justice of the Supreme 
Court of Washington Territory and
Judge of said Court and the seal
thereof affixed this 6th day of
July A.D. 1886
D.A. Clement, Clerk

Return on Habeas Corpus
Territory of Washington
County of Spokane}ss
I E.F. Whittier Sheriff
<del>Sheriff</del> of said County and territory, do hereby
return to the Honorable George Turner Judge of the
4th Judicial District of Washington Territory,
that before the coming to me of this within writ,
the said Ray Raymond was committed to my custody
and is detained by virtue of a commitment a copy
of which is hereto annexed, the assigned of which
I also herewith produce nevertheless I have the
body of the said Ray Raymond before you at
the time and place within mentioned as I am
within commanded.
dated sheriff office July 6th 1886
E.F. Whittier
Sheriff of Spokane County
W.T.
Sheriff's Fees
To Serving Writ 1.00
" 3 days attended court on 9.00
' mileage from liberty to Spo-
kane Flls &amp; return 34 3.40
" mileage for prisoner 34 3.40
' 3 days board 2.00 per day 6.00
' 3 days as board 2.00 $22.80
per day 9.00
$31.80
</p>
