<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0078.008">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Foong v. William Murphy. Judgement</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie R." xml:id="nrl">Natalie R. Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Young, Cory James" xml:id="cjy">Cory James Young</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0078.008</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Foong v. William Murphy. Judgement</title>
<date when="1886-01-22">January 22, 1886</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Puget Sound Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>King County Government, Judicial Administration. Territorial District Court Case Files, 1867-1889</collection>
<idno>Case No 4784</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1886-01">January 1886</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Lyon, George G.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County (Wash.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Foong</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Murphy, William</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Rasin</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Gilman, Luthene Claremont</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Hanford, C. H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Greene, Roger S.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc><change when="2021-09" who="#cjy">edited</change>         
<change when="2019-01" who="#lkw">reviewed; edited</change>        
<change when="2018-01" who="#ka">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2018-06" who="#nrl">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0078.008.001"/>

<p>Territory of Washington,)<lb/>Third Judicial District.) ss.</p>

<p>In the District Court holding terms at the City of Seattle.</p>

<p>In the matter of the Application of Ah Foong for a writ of Habeas Corpus. ) Judgement.</p>

<p>And now on this 22d day of January, 1886, the Court having heretofore heard and considered the petition of the applicant for a writ of habeas corpus, and the return to the writ made by William Murphy, acting Chief of Police of the City of Seattle, on file herein, and the arguments of L.C. Gilman, Esq., attorney for said applicant, and C.H. Hanford, attorney for the respondent, and being now sufficiently advised in the premises, finds: That Ah Foong, the said applicant, was, on the 19th day of January, 1886, at the City of Seattle, in King County, Washington Territory, duly convicted before George G. Lyon, a Justice of the Peace in and for said County, of the offense of being engaged in the business of a peddler within the City of Seattle, without having obtained a peddler's license from said City of Seattle, in violation of a certain ordinance of said City, entitled "An Ordinance to License, Tax and Regulate Auctioneers, Hawkers and Peddlers." and sentenced by said Justice of the Peace to pay a fine of five dollars, and costs, amounting to the further sum of eleven and 85-100 dollars, and that on the same day, by said Justice of the Peace, he, the said Ah Foong, was duly committed to the custody of the Chief of Police of said City of Seattle, for his default in not paying said fine and costs, to be confined in the jail of the said City at hard labor for the space of sixteen days, unless said fine and costs be sooner paid, and the same have not been paid, and said term of imprisonment has not yet expired; and the said Ah Foong is now held in custody by said Chief of Police by virtue of a warrant of committment issued by said Justice of the Peace as aforesaid.</p>

<p>And that said Ah Foong is a subject of the Emperor of China, and one who has not declared his intentions to become a citizen of the United States, and to whom a license to peddle is not grantable under the ordinances of the City of Seattle.</p>

<p>And for the causes aforesaid the Court denies the petition of said applicant for a writ of habeas corpus.</p>

<p>Wherefore, by virtue of the law, and by reason of the premises, it is considered and adjudged by the Court, that the said Ah Foong, the said petitioner, be, and he is hereby, remanded to the custody of the respondent, William Murphy, acting Chief of Police of the City of Seattle, to be by him
<pb/>
held as commanded in the warrant of committment aforesaid.</p>

<p>And that the said respondent do have and recover of and from the said Ah Foong the costs of this proceeding, taxed dollars, and that execution issue therefor.</p>

<p>Enter</p>
<p>Greene</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>