<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.mo.0014.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Caroline Bauer. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie R." xml:id="nrl">Natalie R. Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.mo.0014.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Caroline Bauer. Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1868-01-02">January 2, 1868</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1868-02">February 1868</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Lewis, John</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>St. Louis (Mo.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Bauer, Caroline</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Bush, William</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Rombauer, R. E.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>St. Louis Circuit Court</orgName>
<placeName>State of Missouri</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-11" who="#lkw">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2017-06" who="#djr">transcribed</change>
<change when="2018-06" who="#nrl">encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.mo.0015.002.001"/>

<p>State of Missouri County of St. Louis } In Circuit Court Hm Judge Rombauer presiding</p>

<p>Petition for a writ of habeas corpus</p>

<p>Petitioner states by Wm Bush that on the 26th of December 1867 she Caroline Bauer was arrested by a police officer (at the instigation of John Bauer her husband who has for more than 4 months last past deserted her; <del/>) and brought  to St. Vincent insane asylum a private institution situated <unclear>cnr</unclear> 9th-Warien street in city of St. Louis</p>

<p>Petitioner by Wm Bush further states: that she Carolina Bauer is there now illegaly restraint and confined against her will; petitioner by Wm Bush further states that she Mrs. Bauer has about 6 children the youngest of which is about one year old from which she has been forcibly separated and for which she has all ways properly provided. Petitioner by Wm. Bush futher states that there is a divorce pending between her - her husband; and that he has prevented two certificates from 2 persons purporting to be doctors a true copy of which is here with filed pretending that she is a monomaniac, which is the only authority by which sister Julia Superior of said asylum claims to hold and confine her.</p>

<p>Petitioner by Wm Bush further states that said arrest was illegal and against the statute law in such cases provided in that there has not been a judicial examination in the probate or county court of St. Louis to inquire in her sanity - <del/> or insanity as is required by statute. Petitioner by Wm Bush therefore prays this honorable court to grant a writ of Habeas Corpus to inquire her cause of confinement. Petitioner by Wm Bush further states that there has not been made any application to any court or officer superior

<pb facs="hc.case.mo.0015.002.002"/>

to the one now applied to; Petitioner by Wm Bush further states that said Mrs Bauer is not insane which he is able to prove by witnesses in trial</p>

<p>Petitioner by Wm Bush therefore prays the court to liberate her from confinement if facts appear as set forth in this petition and to make such further order as the Court may deem proper</p>

<p>Caroline Bauer by Wm Bush her Atty</p>

<p>The above named <del/> Wm Bush being duly sworn says that the facts stated in above petition are true according to his best knowlege and belief</p>
<p>Wm Bush</p>

<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me Jany 2nd 68</p>
<p>J Lewis Clk</p>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>