<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0084.003">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Nan Oy v. Washington Territory. Judge's Decision</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie R." xml:id="nrl">Natalie R. Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Young, Cory James" xml:id="cjy">Cory James Young</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0084.003</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Nan Oy v. Washington Territory. Judge's Decision</title>
<date when="1888-02-25">February 25, 1888</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Puget Sound Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>King County Government, Judicial Administration. Territorial District Court Case Files, 1867-1889</collection>
<idno>Case No 5843</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1888-02">February 1888</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Wood, Oliver</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County (Wash.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Oy, Nan</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Kam</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Jenner, C. K.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>White, W. H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jones, Richard A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Third Judicial District</orgName>
<placeName>Territory of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc><change when="2021-09" who="#cjy">edited</change>         
<change when="2019-01" who="#lkw">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2018-06" who="#nrl">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0084.003.001"/>

<p>In the District Court holding terms at Seattle.</p>

<p>In the matter of Ah Kam for a writ of Habeas Corpus for Nan Oy, a Chinese woman, in the custody of the U.S. Marshal for Washington Territory} 5843</p>

<p>The United States Marshal for Washington Territory having made return to the writ of Habeas Corpus heretofore issued herein. Now on this 25th day of February AD 1888 came on to be heard the petition in said cause C.K. Jenner Esq. appearing on behalf of the petitioner and W.H. White Esq. on behalf of the United States as well as on behalf of said U.S. Marshal. After the <del/> introduction of testimony and on the statement of the attorney for the petitioner and on the return of said U.S. Marshal the Court finds as facts in this matter.</p>

<p>That said Nan Oy is a Chinese person and that she came to the United States from the Province of British Columbia by water on or

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0084.003.002"/>

about the <gap/> day of February AD 1888 and that she had never theretofore been in the United States, and that she is not of the class of persons mentioned in Section 13 of an Act of Congress approved July 5th 1884, 23 Statutes at Large page 118 and that said Nan Oy on coming into the United States did not produce the certificate required by Section 6 of said Act of Congress and that she has no such certificate and that on coming into the United States she was arrested by said U.S. Marshal, by virtue of a warrant duly issued by Oliver Wood U. S. Commissioner for said Washington Territory on a complaint filed with him charging her said Nan Oy with being unlawfully in the United States and that said U.S. Marshal now has her in his custody by virtue of said arrest under said warrant.</p>

<p>Now therefore in consideration of the law and the premises it is by the Court ordered that the petition of said Ah Kam be and the same so denied and it is further ordered

<pb facs="hc.case.wa.0084.003.003"/>

that the U.S. Marshal for Washington Territory forthwith deport <del>said</del> and remove said Nan Oy. from the United States to British Columbia and she said Nan Oy is hereby remanded into the custody of said U.S. Marshal to carry this order into execution.</p>

<p>R.A. Jones</p>
<p>Judge</p>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>