<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0088.000">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Type of document</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Young, Cory James" xml:id="cjy">Cory James Young</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0088.000</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Type of document</title>
<date when="1887">1887</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Puget Sound Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>King County Government, Judicial Administration. Territorial District Court Case Files, 1867-1889</collection>
<idno>Case No 5662</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1887">1887</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Senter</term>
<term>Hanford, C. H.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McKay, Alice</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, Della</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Ronald, J. P.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName>Gilman, L. C.</persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2020-05" who="#lkw">encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#nl">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>Judge SENTER, a witness called on behalf of the petitioner, after being duly sworn, testified as follows:</p>

<p>Q. [Ronald] You are a Justice of the Peace at Tacoma? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. How long have you resided there? A. About four years, I guess.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know this petitioner, Mrs. McKay? A. I do.</p>

<p>Q. Where abouts does she live? A. She lives in Tacoma, in the part called the old town.</p>

<p>Q. Have you known her pretty well, or seen her much since she and her husband <sic>secarated</sic> some three or four years ago? A. Well, considerable.</p>

<p>Q. What does she do for a living? A. Well, she seems to be always doing some thing, I cannot exactly say what.</p>

<p>Q. Is she lazy? A. No sir, she is an industrious woman.</p>

<p>Q. Judge, from what you know of her, do you think she is a fit and competent person to raise a child or have the care and custody of a child? A. Well, by what I have known <sic>if</sic> her by rumor and reputation for the last two years, since her husband has left, I think she is able to take care of her <sic>iwn</sic> children as well as any mother in the circumstance she is <del/> placed could take care of them.</p>

<p>Q. Do you know anything of her affection for her children? A. What I see myself She always appears to be kind and affectionate to her children. I have seen her <sic>qsite</sic> frequently. I generally see her children with her, and I judge from that and from appearances of the children <sic>aus</sic> to dress and looking healthy and contented.</p>

<p>Q. <sic>Ho w</sic> do her children seem or appear to be dressed, Judge? A. They always are dressed well.</p>

<p>Q. Neat and tidy? A. As <sic>dfar</sic> as I have seen. I have never seen them at home I have seen them with her and some times when she comes to my office she generally brings them. She comes to consult me about business, that is my means of knowledge, that is all I have.</p>

<p>Q. You never had her arrested before you? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You dont know anything about her getting drunk? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. You have seen her frequently in Tacoma? A. I have quite often.</p>

<p>Q. Is she keeping a saloon? A. Not that I know of.</p>

<p>Q. Has she been different entirely different woman <sic>usince</sic> she and her husband separated than she was before? A. She seems so to me. I believe that is the general rumor, that she is a much better woman than when she lived with her

<fw>[Senter, D-EX.<gap/> 76--199.</fw>

<fw>14</fw>

<pb/>

husband.</p>

<p>Q. Has she a good reputation in Tacoma since her husband went away? A. Reputation to that extent, that she is far better woman since her husband left <sic>thay</sic> before, that is people generally talk in that way, that her husband was to blame for her misconduct if misconduct it was.</p>

<p>Q. She is regarded by people as doing well? A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. Industrious? A. Industrious</p>

<p>Q. Honest hard working woman. A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>Q. From what you know of her and see of her, you consider she is fit and proper person to raise one of her own children? A. One of her own children, yes.</p>

<p>Q. As good as the average? A. As good as a mother placed under the circumstances. That is the same rule that would deprive her of her child would deprive many another woman.</p>

<p>Q. She is competent then as a good many other mothers? A. Yes.</p>

<p>Q. As other poor women you mean A. Yes sir.</p>

<p>CROSS-EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>Q.[Gilman] You dont see very much of this woman except in a business way? A. Oh, yes I see her <sic>preduently</sic>--see her not in a business way, meet her on the streets.</p>

<p>Q. She might be drunk on the streets frequently and you not see her? A. Oh yes, that might be.</p>

<p>Q. The only reputation that she now has is as you understand is that she is a better woman than she was when her husband was with her?</p>

<p>A. Yes, that is the general talk.</p>

<p>Q. General talk. A. That Mrs. McKay is doing a great deal better <sic>sincce</sic> her husband left.</p>

<p>Q. Her reputation now is hardly that of a good woman, is it Mr. Senter? A. Only so far as I state. I state just what I hear, that they give her credit on account.</p>

<p>Q. That it is better than it was? A. I give her credit for her conduct now. The general talk is that her husband was responsible for her misconduct than she herself. She is a woman more sinned against than sinning herself.</p>

<p>Q. You have never been to her home? A. No sir.</p>

<p>Q. Dont know how she lives? A. No sir.</p>

<fw>[Senter, C-EX.<gap/> 76--205.</fw>

<fw>15</fw>

<pb/>

<p>Q. Dont know who lives there with her? A. No sir</p>

<p>Q. You say she is as capable and as fit a person to have the custody of this child as any woman who has been in her circumstances. Explain what you mean by that? A. Well, her financial condition is not that that would rear a child and educate a child as I would think a child should be reared and educated, of course she cannot do that.</p>

<p>Q. One of the circumstances of her condition is a life of crime that she has lived Dont you consider that one of the circumstances? A. A circumstances that is not of her own making, but that has been made against her, her unhappy domestic relations with her husband. that she is probably a better woman than her deeds make her out to be.</p>

<p>Q. Her reputation of the past has been pretty bad, has it not? A. In that way I suppose it has.</p>

<p>Q. Been frequently before the Courts? Well, now, I dont know. I dont know of her ever being in Court but once.</p>

<p>Q. She at that time was convicted was she not? A. I think she was, this time that Hanford related here, I have remembrance of it, that is all.</p>

<p>REDIRECT EXAMINATION:</p>

<p>Q. [Ronald] From what you know of her, then she is as competent to raise her children and educate and school them as other poor women? A. That is wha.t I mean, that is, that the same rule that would deprive her of the child would rob a great many women that are considered competent to rear their children.</p>

<p>----------0----------</p>

<fw>[Senter, C-EX.<gap/> 76--209.</fw>

<fw>16</fw>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
