<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>Territory of Washington
County of Spokane}ss
In the District Court of the 4th
Judicial District holding terms
at county seat of Spokane County

Territory of Washington
vs. Plaintiff
Ray Raymond Defendant
Territory of Washington
Spokane County}ss I Thomas C. Griffiths being
first duly sworn state: I am one of th attorneys of the
defendant Ray Raymond in this cause and have
been such attorney since the charge was first made
against Defendant June 26, 1886 and have had
principal charge of the case for her, I believe the de-
fendant cannot have a fair trial in this cause in
this county of Spokane on account of and owing
to the prejudice and entitlement of the in-
habitant, against her. That among other reasons
and sufficient reasons for such belief and as
showing such indictment and buy in this I state
the following truth:
It has been stated throughout the county that
at time of the killing of such defendant was a 
common woman of the town and the keeper of 
brothel known in the "Bay Window" situated
on Fourth Street in the city of Spokane Falls in this
county, and that she was an unusually bad, dan-
gerous and horrednous woman of her kind
and very handy and wonton in the use
of firearms, all of which but alley actions of her very
dangerous and quarrelsome, or applicant, from his
own knowledge believes to be untrue, and that
from such statements, being to him and representedly
made a general belief in the truth thereof seems
to exist among the inhabitants of the city
of Spokane Falls and of this county generally,
and then statements and the belief in their truth
have tended greatly to excite the purposes of the people
of the county against the defendant. That at the
time of the killing <del>known</del> and ever since, it
was and has been repeatedly affirmed, and
states that therefore Defendant has
murdered her husband, and has also mur-
dered two men and one woman in Mon-
tana and as perilously and repeatedly, have their
statements been made there against belief in
their truth appears to be made the people of
the county, and affiace has conversed with 
many people of the county who believe such
charges and repeat them as true, that each and
all of said statements and charges are untrue
as affitant verily believes and affiant has
has a letter from the prisoner to us bond of
defendant since that killing and knows
he was there and believes he is now alive,
that the presentation of these statements and
their general belief has tended greatly to prejudice
the people of this county against defendant
and to incite and influence the perceptions of the people
of the county.
At the time immediately following the killing and before
the coroner's inquest, and while the deceased man Finch
lay dead in the hallway of the "Bay Windows" and de-
fendant was a close prisoner therin and in a bed
under constant charge of a play union. Crowds of
men gathered on the city of Spokane Falls and
about said building and heard what purported
to be the facts connected, with the killing of plea
repeated and discussed among them, and unto
of the accounts of the killing I then heard among
them were untrue, His help colored and
greatly executed and very unfair to de-
fendant, and I also heard many false ru-
mors of and concerning defendant circulated
among them greatly to her prejudice and I heard
many expressions of bitter prejudica
against her from among them, such as
"she ought to be here" and the like pro-
nounced with vehemence and propensity
and calling defendant a "whore" and other
offensive names and for many days
thereafter I heard similar expression of
bitter prejudice and intense baling against
defendant from and among the people of the
city of Spokane Falls and of Spokane
County, and I also heard many bitter complaints
of the office having defendant in charge for
for with taking her from this house in the condition de-
scribed and incarcerating her in te "city-jail"
a nasty, dirty, filthy, unhealthy place totally un-
fit for the confinement of a well man, an
known to be such, and I am inferred and 
believe and upon such information and
belief allege that epense of this county went to
the offices having her in charge and de-
manded that she be placed in said jail, and
answered the officers for with doing so.

That on the morning following the killing and
coroners inquest the "Morning Review." The city
daily paper then published in Spokane County, and
a paper of general circulation in said
County, published what purported to be the facts
of such killing as disdond before said coro-
ners jury a copy of which said publication is
attached hereto marked B. and made part
of this affidavit. That in said publication 
it was stated that defendant stated the 
facts of the killing as there given befre the coroner's
jury, which statement was wholly untrue
for in truth and in fact defendant did not
appear before her many any statement to
the said Coroner's Jury, and the said publication
failed to state the fact, of said, killing truly, and get
they were greatly auditor being given as the
confession of defendant before the Coroner's
Jury, and by reason of the premises such
publication greatly injudicious defendant
case with the people of the county, that said
Reiew is case a weekly paper of general cir-
culation in this county and the same publication
was again published in its weekly edition
of about the date of July 3d 1886.
That on June 26, 1886, defendant was arrested by
a warrant issued by J.J.L. Paul Esquire of
the Justice of the Peace of Spokane County, charged
with the crime of murder in the first
degree in te killing of said Finch
and on the following week a preliinary ex-
amination in this charge was had before said
Paul under Jonathan Boyd, and there of the Justices
of the Peace of said County, which lasted
about four days and was held in the
city of Spokane Falls with open doors
and attended constantly by a large 
number <del>crowd</del> of the inhabitants and ideas
of Spokane County. That during said
examination the prosecuting attorney
frequently denounce of defendant and the
class of women to which it was stated
she belonged vehemently asserted that
the offense she had committed was a crime
wonton, unprovoked and cold-blooded
murder, and this to and discribe prej-
udice against defendant by repeatedly pointing
to the offense as the underigned of what he turned
the "wide open system" of dealing with
saloons and the serial evil in Spokane Falls
and which he therein to be convoy by condemned 
and insighted against by many good
people of the county, and further sought to
inflame the passions and excite the
prejudices of the working men of the
county by repeatedly and vehemently charging
during the ecamination that defendant
that deceased because he were there verified
and that her reader was ascented by
gentlemen with doe skin pants on, and
that had deceased worn doe-skin
pants he scored not have been shot and
so vehemently and insistently was this
urged by the public prosecution through
on evidence whatever supported it
that the working men were greatly
excited and prejudiced afainst de-
fendant thereby and as affiant has gre-
atly been informed and verily believes
true are greatly excited and prejudiced
against defendant and are watching
this case with a great deal of intention.
</p>
