<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0085.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Mary LeFebvre v. T. LeFebvre. Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie R." xml:id="nrl">Natalie R. Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0085.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Mary LeFebvre v. T. LeFebvre. Application for Writ of Habeas Corpus</title>
<date when="1888-02-21">February 21, 1888</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository></repository>
<collection></collection>
<idno></idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1888-02">February 1888</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>LeFebvre, Henry Luke</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>King County (Wash.)</term>
<term>Ellensburg (Wash.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>LeFebvre, Mary</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>LeFebvre, T.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jones, Richard A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2019-01" who="#lkw">reviewed; edited</change>      
<change when="2018-01" who="#ka">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2018-06" who="#nrl">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0085.002.001"/>

<p>In the Third Judicial District of Washington Territory holding terms at Seattle.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of Mary LeFebvre for a writ of Habeas Corpus}</p>

<p>To the Hon. R.A. Jones Judge of the above entitled Court. The petition of Mary LeFebrve shows.</p>

<p>I</p>
<p>That she is the wife T. LeFebvre they having been married in the year 1884.</p>

<p>II</p>
<p>That they have a minor child. a boy named Henry Luke LeFebvre now aged three years.</p>

<p>III</p>
<p>That an action is now pending in the District Court of this Territory holding terms at Ellensburg, between your petitioner as plaintiff and her husband T. LeFebvre as defendant in which your petitioner seeks to attain a decree dissolving the bonds of matrimony existing between her and her said husband on the ground of neglect and refusal of her
<pb/>
<fw>2</fw>
said husband to make suitable provisions for his family and on the further ground of cruel treatment by her said husband of your petitioner. And petitioner in said action further asks that the care and custody of said minor child be awarded to her on the ground that her said husband is not a proper person to have the care and custody of said child.</p>

<p>IV</p>
<p>That for a long time prior to the commencment of said action your petitioner had by her own labors supported herself and said child. and that after the commencement of said action petitioner continued to so support herself and child.</p>

<p>V</p>
<p>That after the commencement of said action and about six weeks ago said T. LeFebvre came to the restuarant in Ellensburg where petitioner was working and <del>forcibly</del> by force took said minor child from the custody of petitioner and since then has been traveling about the country with said minor child and said T. LeFebvre now has said child concealed

<pb/>
<fw>3</fw>
and confined in some place to petitioner unknown, in the city of Seattle</p>

<p>VI</p>
<p>That said T. LeFebvre is unable to properly care for said child and has since so taking said child neglected him and said child by reason of said neglect has contracted disease and is now as petitioner is informed sick and greatly in need of a mothers care. That said T. LeFebvre refuses to inform petitioner where said child is confined and concealed and refuses to allow petitioner to see said child</p>

<p>VII</p>
<p>That said T. LeFebvre is a man of violent and <unclear>ungovernable</unclear> temper and is shiftless and improvident and is not a proper person to have the custody of said child.</p>

<p>VIII</p>
<p>That petitioner believes that said T. LeFebvre so conceals and confines said child as a means of inducing petitioner to dismiss her said action for divorce</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays a writ of habeas corpus to deliver said Henry Luke LeFebvre from the custody of said T. LeFebvre and that he be restored to the custody of petitioner</p>
<p>Mary LeFebvre</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>