<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<p>An inquisition having been this 25th day
of December held upon the remains of
A.L. Beardon the following sworn test-
imony was taken as:
O.J. Royes being sworn made the following 
statement as:
   On Sunday the 21st which I was at the store
of Portch Bros at Sherman W.T. there was
present at the time Light, Frank and Henry
Beardon, R.C. Welch Howard E. Portch
and Bud White. Four of them were playing
cards and as I strepped to the store Bud
White stepped aside and got into the middle
of the floor and he then asked Frank Beardon
when did you get in? Frank answered a 
few days ago. And Bud are you 
going to pay me for that revolver you 
got off me answer by Frank yes when 
I get the money I have not go it now
Bud- you agreed to pay me in 30 days
and you did not do it you then wanted
30 days more and I let you have it out
instead of paying me you went on a tour
at the east, have you got the revolver with 
you? F. No
Bud- Where is it? Answer I left it below
" Have you any other? " I have
" Let me see it: Frank then gave him a
large revolver when Bud said I guess this
will do.
will do in place off the other it was I think a
colt revolver. Light then stepped up and
said what in the Hell are you trying to
get through you Bud. Bud answered what are 
you trying to get through you. Light then got
between Bud and the door and said Bud you
are not going to take any advantage of the Boy
meaning Frank gave him back his revolver
and I will see that you are said for it
Henry also said the same to Bud then there
was considerable swearing by all of them
Light again said give him back his Revolver
and I will stand good for it Bud said 
to I wont do it Light said he would not
take it out of the door they again commenced
to call each other names Bud then stepped
into the middle of the floor away from
Henry and stood facing Light Light shook his
fist at Bud I saw Bud draw his revolver
and said to Light of you donbt back off
I'll shoot you. I believe Light stepped to-
ward Bud and then I heard the revolver go
off Questions by the Jury Bud said he had seen
him over long enough but would not have 
it any longer. Then when struggle after 
the shooting. Bud Light Henry Frank
Light doing the most of it then they
were trying to take the Revolver from
Bud
one of them said shoot him and another said
cut him I saw frank go out to him and with
a knife saying god dam him cut him
all to pieces. Said Bud with his read to the
counter Bud said he would take it all back
to let him up I then heard Light say Boys 
I am shot. Light then said I wish I had killed
him he then started to go out of the store.
Frank came out with a revolver in his 
hand saying shoot the son of a bitch and
run down towards Shermans before he got to 
Shermans Henry got Bud into the house
In the beginning and before the shooting Bud 
had the only revolver.
E. Portch being duly sworn made the 
following statement. I was in the store at 
the time of the shooting Bud ask Frank 
when he had come back and Frank told 
him about 2 weeks ago. He ask him when
he was going to pay for the revolver that he
had bought off him and Frank said as soon
as he got the money/ Have you got a 
revolver with you? Yes. Let me see it 
and then Frank gave it to Bud who said 
that will fit the bill and I guess I will 
keep it. Frank said you need not get 
on your ear about it I'll pay you for
your revolver. Light then said give the
Revolver back to him. Bud said he would 
not do it P Light said I will search good
for the $9.00. Henry also ask Bud to give 
Back the revolver saying he would also 
go searching for the $9.00. Bud picked back
saying if you run over me I'll shoot you
and the next time I heard a shot.
Frank leaped back into the corner and pulled
out his pocket knife I'll cut him all to 
pieces. question by the jury light did not 
take a hold of <del>light</del> Bud until after the
shot was fired. Frank had a small 
pocket knife it was a common pocket 
knife. Light grabbed a hold of the revolver
I think light was trying to defend himself
by Bud I mean Bud white by light
Light Beardon also Frank Henry 
Beardon.
H.S. Beardon being unduly sorn made the 
following statement
The row commenced as follows. Bud White ask 
Frank when he had got back. Frank said about 
two weks ago Bud ask Frank when he in-
tended to pay him the two he owed him on a Re-
volver Frank said I have been sick all <unclear></unclear>
and unable to work and could not raise any 
money and will pay you as soon as I can,
Bud ask have you got the revolver away then.
Frank said he had Bud ask to look at it
Frank gave it to him when Bud said I guess
this will settle it Light then got up and
said give him back his revolver and I'll
see that is paid. I also said the same to
Bud telling that we would make it all right
He kept his hand into his right hand pocket
and the revolver he took form Frank into the 
left. He then turned his head towards me
and told me to step back. Light stepped 
toward him Bud jumped up right when
Frank had said stand back. light stepped
towars him about 3 steps Bud then shot. I 
jumped on to Bud I wanted to take the revolver
away from him and get him Bud out of doors
I then took Bud to Sherman's house
Question by the jury I did not notice light
attempt to strike him I saw no knife used
Frank Beardon being duly sworn made
the following statement
The first of the quarell was this way 
Light said we dont want any trouble
about this revolver Bud give it back to 
him and I will make it all right Henry 
also said that they would make it good
Bud said god dam you I dont wan 
any thing out you Light said give the pistol back
and we will settle this like men ought
to setle any thing. Bud pulled out his
Pistol making motions towards Bud Light 
and at the second motion (describing the
motions) he fired at Light I went to take
the pistol away Henry he wtepped in bet-
ween Light &amp; Bud Henry and Light also tried
to take Pistol away from Bud I saw he was 
trying to get the other revolver out of his pocket
when I struck him on the head before he threw
the last revolver I had a knife open and in 
trying to take the revolver away, the knife 
went into his hip at the same time I drew the
revolver away from him, Henry then took Bud
out and took him down to Sherman's
question by the Jury
It happened last Sunday on the 21st Dec at
Porteh's store at 2 o'clock P.M.
I struck him but once with the knife
When he shot Light Bud had two revolvers
one 32 cal and one 38 cal he shot him with
the 32 cal and was trying to get the 38 cal
out.
Question by the coroner did Light make any
threats at Bud before the shooting. 
No, none at all
I took the 38 cal Rvolver from him 
R.C. Welch was duly sworn and testified
as follows.
Light Henry and Frank were advancing
towards Bud and began negotiating and while they
were negotiating I heard a revolver go off. I saw the 
revolver in Bud's hands before the shooting
and Right after the shooting I saw the Rvolver
in Light Beardon's hand I grabbed Light and
tried to take the revolver away from him
and while I was holding him Bud and
Henry got out of the door after they got
out Light pulled up his shirt and said
he was shot he showed me where he was
shot.
Question by the Jury.
It happened on Dec. 21st last Sunday at
Sherman's in Porteh store question by the 
Coroner. Did Light attempted to strike him before
he was shot answer yes
Q. by the Jury
Ans. Frank and Henry were holding him I did
not see Frank strike Bud with knife or
Pistol. I saw two (2) Revolvers he shot
him with the small one.
Howard Porteh was sworn and testified as follows.
Last Sunday at our store in Sherman's 
Bud White asked Frank Beardon when he 
got back he told him and Bud ask him 
when he was going to pay him for his
<del>knife</del> Revolver he said as soon as he got
some money he asked him if he had any 
with him meaning a revolver. Frank showed
him one Bud took it and put it in 
his pocket saying that this will do and
would fill the bill. Light got up and said
You are not going out of the door with it
you better give it back. Bud told Light
that he had better keep himself alone or
he would get hurt Light said the same to
Bud Light was backing Bud up to the
window when Bud said back or I'll shoot 
you he told him twice to keep back when
he shot Light. Light keep going for him
and Frank took out his knife kill the 
son of a bitch and then went to stabbing
Bud in the leg. Bud Light were in the 
middle of the floor Light was trying to 
take the revolver from Bud.
Question by the court.
Ans. I do ot know if Light struck Bud
before he shot. Question by the jury.
He shot him with the pistol it was in 
his right hand I saw two Revolvers after
the shooting No one had a hold of Bud before 
the shooting I saw the wound after the shooting
He shot him with a 32 cal Revolver. I did not face
 Frank strike Bud on the head with a revolver
he struck him more than once with a knife
The stabbing was after the shooting.
</p>
