<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0088.014">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Return</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Young, Cory James" xml:id="cjy">Cory James Young</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2019</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0088.014</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Alice McKay v. John Kevan and Della Kevan. Return</title>
<date when="1887">1887</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Puget Sound Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>King County Government, Judicial Administration. Territorial District Court Case Files, 1867-1889</collection>
<idno>Case No 5662</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1887">1887</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>McKay, Mary</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Seattle, Washington</term>
<term>Tacoma, Washington</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>McKay, Alice</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, John</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Kevan, Della</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jones, Richard A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc><change when="2021-09" who="#cjy">edited</change>         
<change when="2020-05" who="#lkw">encoded</change>
<change when="2018" who="#nl">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the District Court, holding terms at Seattle in King County, Washington Territory.</p>

<p>In the matter of the application of Alice McKay for a writ of Habeas Corpus for the body of Mary McKay. } No <del/> 5662 RETURN TO WRIT.</p>

<p>To the Hon Richard A. Jones, Judge of said Court:</p>

<p>The respondents, John Keevan and Della Keevan, his wife for a return to the writ of habeas corpus served on them herein respectfully show Your Honor; that the said child Mary McKay, otherwise Mary Keevan, when an infant of tender years, to wit: of the age of about three years and on or about the <gap/> day of August 1882 was deserted and abandoned by the said Alice McKay and by her left on the doorstep of the Sisters of Charity in said Seattle, and never has been cared for, supported or in any way provided for or maintained by said Alice McKay, since said date; that said child was supported and maintained by said Sisters of Charity for a brief period, to-wit for about two years, when she was by said sisters given to these respondents, and taken and adopted by them as their own child, and has ever since up to the present day been nourished, supported, cared for, maintained and educated by these respondents, and has lived with them in their own home in the City of Seattle and is in all respects treated by them as their own child and is being educated and reared by them to a useful, honest and virtuous life; that the whole expense of rearing said child since she was received by them from said sisters has been borne by your respondents; that your respondents are deeply attached to said child; that they have no children of their own and love said child dearly, and said child reciprocates their affection, and is content and happy with them, and has never known any other home save that of these respondents, and has come to regard these respondents as her parents; that these respondents have abundant ability financially to rear and educate said child properly and desire and intend so to do.</p>

<p>And your respondents further allege and state that said Alice McKay is a wholly unfit person to be permitted to have the care or control or custody of said child, having abandoned the same to the care of strangers voluntarily when a mere infant, and never having cared for her since. That said Alice McKay has no means whatever and is wholly unable to properly care for, maintain or educate said child.</p>

<p>And your respondents further aver that the father of said child, and its mother, the said Alice McKay, are both of a grossly immoral and intemparate character; that
<pb/>
that the father of said child is now a fugitive from justice and absent from Washington Territory; that the said Alice McKay is now living separate from her said husband and is cohabiting and living in adultery with a man, whose name is unknown to affiant; that said Alice McKay is greatly addicted to the use of liquor and is frequently grossly intoxicated; that the said Alice McKay is now the proprietor of a low saloon in the City of Tacoma, Washington Territory, to which saloon, as respondents are informed and believe she proposes to take said child <del/> should this Honorable Court award her the custody of the same; that said Alice McKay is a person of very bad moral character having been convicted of the crime of selling liquor to Indians at the November term of the District Court, holding terms at Tacoma W.T. on or about the 1st day of January 1884, and is a person wholly unfit to have the care of an infant child; that if said Alice McKay be given the custody of said child, these <del/> respondents verily believe that said child will be reared up to lead an immoral life: that said child is desirous of remaining with these respondents, and if left in their custody will be reared in a good home and to a good life.</p>

<p>By reason of the aforesaid facts, your petitioners allege that they are legally entitled to the custody of said child, nevertheless they here produce the body of said Mary McKay, and request that she be again remanded to their custody.</p>

<p>John Keevan</p>
<p>Della Keevan her X mark</p>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>