<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.wa.0089.002">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Ling Quan et al. v. Territory of Washington. Petition</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Rittscher, Grace A." xml:id="gar">Grace A. Rittscher</name>
<name n="Coronado Amaya, Melanie" xml:id="mca">Melanie Coronado Amaya</name>
<name n="Fougeron, Jillian" xml:id="jf">Jillian Fougeron</name>
<name n="Hinton, Lauren" xml:id="lh">Lauren Hinton</name>
<name n="Young, Cory James" xml:id="cjy">Cory James Young</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2020</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.wa.0089.002</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Ling Quan et al. v. Territory of Washington. Petition</title>
<date when="1888-05-11">May 11, 1888</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Puget Sound Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>King County Government, Judicial Administration. Territorial District Court Case Files, 1867-1889</collection>
<idno>Case No 5958</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1888">1888</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Brooks, Quincy A.</term>
<term>Peterson</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term></term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Quan, Ling</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Tue, Lue</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Lung, Lee</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName>Faben, Vince H.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Jones, Richard A.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Third Judicial District</orgName>
<placeName>Seattle, Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-01" who="#lkw">reviewed; encoded</change>
<change when="2020-09" who="#nrl">transcribed</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb/>

<p>In the District Court of the 3rd Judicial District holding terms at Seattle King County, Wash. Tery.</p>

<p>In the Matter of the application of Ling Quan, Lue Tue and Lee Lung for a writ of habeas corpus}</p>

<p>To the Hon R.A. Jones, Judge of the District Court of the 3rd Judicial Dist. of Wash. Tery, holding terms at Seattle W.T.</p>

<p>The petition of Ah Quan for and on behalf of Ling Quan, Lue Tue, and Lee Lung respectfully shows:</p>

<p>That Quincy A. Brooks that customs officer at Port Townsend <del/> Jefferson County, Washington Territory has unlawfully imprisoned and now does unlawfully imprison, detain, confine and restrain the said <del>Al</del> Ling Quan, Lue Tue and Lee Lung and restrain them of their liberty at said City of Port Townsend, Wash Tery.</p>

<p>That said imprisonment, detention, confinement and restraint is illegal and that the illegality thereof consists in this to wit.</p>

<p>That the said Ling Quan has resided in the United States of America for the term of six years and left this country

<pb/>

<del/> about four years ago for a short sojourn and then intended to return to this country, that Lue Tue <del>left</del> has resided in the United States of America for about three years and left this country about three years ago with the intention of returning. That said Lee Lung has resided in the United States of America for about eight years and left this country about one year ago with the intention of returning. that the former residence of said Lue Tue was <del>San Fran</del> Astoria Oregon and said Ling Quan formerly resided in California at San Francisco and said Ling Lung formerly resided at the City of Portland in the State of Oregon. that each of the said Ling Quan, Lue Tue and Lee Lung prior to leaving the United States of America had procured from the proper officers before leaving this country proper certificates of return, and that each of the said persons are on their journey to this country freely and voluntarily of their own free will and not under any contract or other restraint and that each of said petitioners is a male person, not comming into this country for immoral purposes</p>

<pb/>

<p>That each of the said Ling Quan Lue Tue and Lee Lung have in their possession the said certificates of return and are entitled to return to this country and land at the port of Seattle Wash Tery. and that the detention, restraint and imprsionment of them is unlawful and unjust.</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays that a writ of habeas corpus may be granted, directed to the said Quincey A. Brooks commanding him to have the body of the said Ling Quan Lue Tue and Lee Lung before your honor at a time and place therein to be specified, to do and receive what shall then and there be considered by your honor concerning them, together with the time and cause of their detention, and said writ and that they may be restored to their liberty.</p>

<p>Dated at Seattle W.T.</p>
<p>May 11th 1888</p>

<p>Ah Quan</p>
<p>Peterson &amp; Faben</p>
<p>Attys for Petitioners</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>