<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0012.010">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Amos Gustin and Catherine Gustin v. James G. Departte and Elizabeth Departte. Petition for Adoption</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie R." xml:id="nrl">Natalie R. Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
<name n="Appleton, Kasha" xml:id="ka">Kasha Appleton</name>
<name n="Villota, Victoria" xml:id="vv">Victoria Villota</name>
<name n="Young, Cory James" xml:id="cjy">Cory James Young</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
<sponsor>William Nelson Cromwell Foundation</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Produce the Body</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0012.010</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Amos Gustin and Catherine Gustin v. James G. Departte and Elizabeth Departte. Petition for Adoption</title>
<date when="1888-01-24">January 24, 1888</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Eastern Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>Whitman County Government; Clerk, Territorial Civil Case Files, 1862-1889</collection>
<idno>Case No 2030</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Civil</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date when="1888-01">January 1888</date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Departte, Daisy Geneva</term>
<term>Ruby, W. N.</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Whitman County (Wash.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Gustin, Amos</persName>
</person>
<person role="petitioner">
<persName>Gustin, Catherine</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Departte, James G.</persName>
</person>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Departte, Elizabeth</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName>Ruby, W. N.</persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName>Probate Court</orgName>
<placeName>Territory of Washington</placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-11" who="#lkw">reviewed; edited</change>
<change when="2018-06" who="#nrl">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0012.010.001"/>

<p>In the Probate Court of Whitman County Washington Territory before WN Ruby Probate Judge</p>

<p>In the matter of Amos Gustin and Catherine Gustin adopting Daisy Geneva Departte minor child of James G Departte and Elizabeth Dapartte</p>

<p>The above named Amos Gustin and Catherine Gustin allege that they are inhabitants of Washington Territory and now residing in Colfax Whitman County Washington Territory that during all the time hereafter mentioned they were and now are Husband and wife, that they are the owners of Two Hundred Acres of land in Nez Perce County Idaho Territory worth three thousand dollars that they have personal property worth two thousand dollars and that they and each ask leave to adopt Daisy Geneva Departte a minor child not theirs by birth and for a change of the name of said child that the present name of said child is Daisy Geneva Departte that she was born February 9th 1885 that on March 1st 1885 the mother of said child to wit Elizabeth Departte became insane and it became necessary to remove her to an insane asylum at which time the father of said child to wit James Departte placed said child

<pb facs="hc.case.0012.010.002"/>

then three weeks old in the care and custody of your petitioners where she has since that time remained That four months latter to wit July 1st 1885 said Elizabeth Departte was cured of said insanity and your petitioners and each of them at that time requested said James G Departte and Elizabeth Departte and each of them to take said child in their custody and maintain and support her- that they and each of them refused to take said child and refused to support her or in anyways provide for her and then and there abandoned said child and left her with your petitioners and moved to Utah Territory and have not since said time furnished said child any support or paid or agreed to pay for her support or in any way to provide for her that said James Departte and Elizabeth Departte have no property and that said Elizabeth Departte is partially insane and for a part of the last two years has been in an insane ansylum for treatment and that said James G Departte is now residing in Utah Territory and are unfit persons to have the custody of said child that your petitioners and each of them ask leave to adopt said child and have her named changed to Daisy Geneva Gustin</p>

<p>Wherefore your petitioners Amos Gustin and Catherine Gustin and each of them ask an order delcaring that from this date

<pb facs="hc.case.0012.010.003"/>

to January 24th 1888 said child Daisy Geneva Departte to all legal issues and purposes be the child of your petitioners and that the name of said child be changed from Daisy Geneva Departe to Daisy Geneva Gustin and for such other relief as may seen seen just</p>

<p>Amos Gustin</p>
<p>Catherine Gustin</p>

</div1>

</body>
</text>
</TEI>