<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://digitalhumanities.unl.edu/resources/schemas/tei/TEIP5.3.0.0/tei_all.rng" type="xml"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hc.case.0001.014">
    
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
<titleStmt>
<title>Territory of Washington v. Mary E. Teller. C. S. Renfield Testimony</title>
<principal n="Jagodinsky, Katrina" xml:id="kj">Katrina Jagodinsky</principal>
<respStmt>
<resp>transcription and encoding</resp>
<name n="Lucas, Natalie" xml:id="nl">Natalie Lucas</name>
<name n="Neuhaus, Madeline" xml:id="mn">Madeline Neuhaus</name>
<name n="Rubi, Diana J." xml:id="djr">Diana J. Rubi</name>
<name n="Weakly, Laura K." xml:id="lkw">Laura K. Weakly</name>
</respStmt>
<sponsor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</sponsor>
</titleStmt>
    
<editionStmt>
<edition>
<date>2018</date>
</edition>
</editionStmt>
            
<publicationStmt>
<authority>Bring Me the Body: A Digital &amp; Print History of Marginalized Habeas Corpus Petitioners in the North American West, 1804-1912</authority>
<publisher>University of Nebraska-Lincoln</publisher>
<distributor>
<name>Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</name>
<address>
<addrLine>319 Love Library</addrLine>
<addrLine>University of Nebraska–Lincoln</addrLine>
<addrLine>Lincoln, NE 68588-4100</addrLine>
<addrLine>cdrh@unl.edu</addrLine>
</address>
</distributor>
<idno type="project">hc.case.0001.014</idno>

<availability>
<licence>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</licence>
<p>Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License. Derivatives must be credited to Bring Me the Body, made available non-commercially, and distributed under the same terms. Requests for permission for commercial publication or other use should be emailed to the project team.</p>
</availability>
</publicationStmt>
            
<sourceDesc>
<bibl>
<title level="m" type="main">Territory of Washington v. Mary E. Teller. C. S. Renfield Testimony</title>
<date when="1887">1887</date>
<note type="project">Our transcription is based on a digital image of the microfilmed original.</note> 
<note type="source">Multiple case files included with habeas petition</note> 
</bibl>
<msDesc>
<msIdentifier>
<repository>Washington State Archives, Eastern Regional Branch</repository>
<collection>Spokane County Government; Clerk, Territorial Case Files, 1879-1889</collection>
<idno>Case No 2083</idno>
</msIdentifier>
</msDesc>
</sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
        
<profileDesc>
<textClass>
<keywords scheme="original" n="category">
<term>Case Papers</term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="original" n="subcategory">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="type">
<term>Criminal</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="subtype">
<term></term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="original" n="term">
<term><date></date></term>
</keywords>
    
<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="people">
<term>Penfield, C. S.</term>
<term>Teller, Franklin</term>
<term>Duggan, John</term>
</keywords>

<keywords scheme="lcsh" n="places"> 
<term>Spokane County (Wash.)</term>
</keywords>

</textClass>
            
<particDesc>   
<listPerson>            
<org role="petitioner">
<orgName>Territory of Washington</orgName>
</org>
<person role="defendant">
<persName>Teller, Mary E.</persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_petitioner">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="attorney_defendant">
<persName></persName>
</person>
<person role="judge">
<persName></persName>
</person>
</listPerson>
            
<listOrg>
<org>
<orgName></orgName>
<placeName></placeName>
</org>
</listOrg>   
</particDesc> 
</profileDesc>
        
<revisionDesc>         
<change when="2018-10" who="#lkw">reviewed</change>
<change when="2017-07" who="#djr">edited</change>
<change when="2017-07" who="#djr">transcribed and encoded</change>
</revisionDesc>

</teiHeader>
    
<text>

<body>  
               
<div1 type="case">

<pb facs="hc.case.0001.014.001"/>

<p>C.S. Renfield</p>

<p>Am <sic>Cornerer</sic> of Spokane County held inquest about 1/2 mile west of Deep Creek Falls on the body supposed to be of Frank Teller and I saw John Duggan testified before the coroner jury then on 31st of May has heard a part of his testimony this morning place I speak of is same place he spoke of   Shown Diagram and explained to him says diagram substantially correct first saw deceased Wednesday June 1/87  he was lying upon his face hands underneath him with left side of his face exposed to view  no indications that he had been moved - nothing to indicate to that he had been moved with <unclear/> house  where he was lying path was dusty - pool of blood under head having evidently come from <unclear/> nostrils - I cant say presicely how long he had been there should say <unclear/> here he was rigid no blood flowing could not state how long since it did - saw blood between front steps and houses one pool larger than other - <unclear/> mark <figure></figure> shape say 3 inches long and a little irregular notice carefully others in close proximity to the others hand say 4 or five feet from front door - Has no blood between deceased and front gate - I <unclear/> in the examination &#8212; We remove all of his clothes

<pb facs="hc.case.0001.014.002"/>

<unclear/> to <unclear/> and examine closely for bullet wounds supposing he had been shot examining for the benefit of the jury and a <unclear/> found no bullet holes any where in the body lowest mark of violence on the chest near the heart about size <unclear/> peices dark blue looked like he had been struck with something <unclear/> - <unclear/> <unclear/> I could not tell whether made by pistol or not shown pistol - not a <unclear/> in jury dont think <unclear/> <unclear/> him down - was another <unclear/> think somewhere about the shoulder  <unclear/> with not so regular nothing serious did not examine for bullet hole in clothing found small holes just behind right ear about midway first glancing supposed it to be bullet hole - took knife I made <unclear/> one from wound up one down took the two flaps and decided there up &amp; back &amp; down and back so that we might examine the skull found no trace of bullet when the skull properly smooth and intact - <del/> Wound evidently had been made by that slat and the ear had suffered from that blow that was the only mark - Examined skull and found <unclear>throughout</unclear> comminuted by that I mean broken in small pieces <unclear/> say past upon the left side large indication could almost put the back of <unclear>your hands</unclear> on left side no other mark of violence - examined nostril mouth and eye for bullet but no mark of any whether

<pb facs="hc.case.0001.014.003"/>

X 2 wounds on body might have been made by a spent bullet  Never had experience with this <unclear>hit</unclear> in that location on the heart my opinion is expertly spoken does not think if clothing on and hit sufficient to cause this mark think it would knock him down - average thickness of an adult mans skull would say from my experience say 1/4 or 3/8 and 1/2 inch - The skull varies in thickness &#8212; there is different in thickness in skull of different people</p>

<p>Re X

It would depend somewhat on the weight and momentum - supposing a man was struck sufficiently with and in as much weighing 1/2 an ounce to produce the <unclear></unclear> described would it knock him down - I think not it might knock him down - Death results from fracture of the skull producing both concussion and compression of the brain</p>

<p>C.S. Renfield M.D.</p>

</div1>
    
</body>
</text>
</TEI>

